<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_19">
<item>439 – The Vandals, led by King Gaiseric, take Carthage in North Africa.</item>
<item>1386 – The Universität Heidelberg holds its first lecture, making it the oldest German university.</item>
<item>1469 – Ferdinand II of Aragon marries Isabella I of Castile, a marriage that paves the way to the unification of Aragon and Castile into a single country, Spain.</item>
<item>1512 – Martin Luther becomes a doctor of theology.</item>
<item>1596 – The Spanish ship San Felipe runs aground on the coast of Japan and its cargo is confiscated by local authorities</item>
<item>1649 – New Ross town in Ireland surrenders to Oliver Cromwell.</item>
<item>1789 – John Jay is sworn in as the first Chief Justice of the United States.</item>
<item>1812 – The French invasion of Russia fails when Napoleon begins his retreat from Moscow.</item>
<item>1900 – Max Planck discovers Planck\'s law of black–body radiation.</item>
<item>1922 – British Conservative MPs vote to terminate the coalition government with the Liberal Party.</item>
<item>1933 – Konstantin von Neurath withdraws Germany from the League of Nations.</item>
<item>1935 – The League of Nations places economic sanctions on Italy for its invasion of Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1943 – Streptomycin, the first antibiotic remedy for tuberculosis, is isolated by researchers at Rutgers University.</item>
<item>1944 – United States forces land in the Philippines.</item>
<item>1950 – China defeats the Tibetan Army at Chambo.</item>
<item>1950 – Iran becomes the first country to accept technical assistance from the United States under the Point Four Program.</item>
<item>1960 – The United States imposes a near–total trade embargo against Cuba.</item>
<item>1973 – President Nixon rejects an Appeals Court decision that he turn over the Watergate tapes.</item>
<item>1974 – Niue becomes a self–governing colony of New Zealand.</item>
<item>1987 – Black Monday: The Dow Jones Industrial Average falls by 22%, 508 points.</item>
<item>1988 – The British government imposes a broadcasting ban on television and radio interviews with members of Sinn Féin and eleven Irish republican and Ulster loyalist paramilitary groups.</item>
<item>1989 – The convictions of the Guildford Four are quashed by the Court of Appeal of England and Wales, after they had spent 15 years in prison.</item>
<item>2003 – Mother Teresa is beatified by Pope John Paul II.</item>
<item>2005 – Saddam Hussein goes on trial in Baghdad for crimes against humanity.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>