<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_7">
<item>3761 BC – The epoch reference date epoch (origin) of the modern Hebrew calendar.</item>
<item>1477 – Uppsala University is inaugurated after receiving its corporate rights from Pope Sixtus IV in February the same year.</item>
<item>1691 – The charter for the Province of Massachusetts Bay is issued.</item>
<item>1763 – King George III issues the Royal Proclamation of 1763, closing aboriginal lands in North America north and west of the Alleghenies to white settlements.</item>
<item>1800 – French corsair Robert Surcouf, commander of the 18–gun ship La Confiance, captures the British 38–gun Kent.</item>
<item>1826 – The Granite Railway begins operations as the first chartered railway in the U.S.</item>
<item>1828 – Morea expedition: The city of Patras, Greece, is liberated by the French expeditionary force.</item>
<item>1840 – Willem II becomes King of the Netherlands.</item>
<item>1868 – Cornell University holds opening day ceremonies; initial student enrollment is 412, the highest at any American university to that date.</item>
<item>1879 – Germany and Austria–Hungary sign the \"Twofold Covenant\" and create the Dual Alliance.</item>
<item>1912 – The Helsinki Stock Exchange sees its first transaction.</item>
<item>1916 – Georgia Tech defeats Cumberland University 222–0 in the most lopsided college football game in American history.</item>
<item>1919 – KLM, the flag carrier of the Netherlands, is founded. It is the oldest airline still operating under its original name.</item>
<item>1924 – Andreas Michalakopoulos becomes prime minister of Greece for a short period of time.</item>
<item>1929 – Photius II becomes Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople.</item>
<item>1933 – Air France is inaugurated, after being formed by a merger of five French airlines.</item>
<item>1949 – The communist German Democratic Republic (East Germany) is formed.</item>
<item>1950 – Mother Teresa establishes the Missionaries of Charity.</item>
<item>1958 – The 1958 Pakistani coup d\'état inaugurates a prolonged period of military rule.</item>
<item>1958 – The U.S. manned space–flight project is renamed Project Mercury.</item>
<item>1959 – The Soviet probe Luna 3 transmits the first–ever photographs of the far side of the Moon.</item>
<item>1963 – President Kennedy signs the ratification of the Partial Nuclear Test Ban Treaty.</item>
<item>1977 – The Fourth Soviet Constitution is adopted.</item>
<item>1985 – Four men from the Palestine Liberation Front hijack the MS Achille Lauro off the coast of Egypt.</item>
<item>1987 – Sikh nationalists declare the independence of Khalistan from India; it is not internationally recognized.</item>
<item>1988 – A hunter discovers three gray whales trapped under the ice near Alaska; the situation becomes a multinational effort to free the whales.</item>
<item>1993 – The flood of \'93 ends at St. Louis, Missouri, 103 days after it began, as the Mississippi River falls below flood stage.</item>
<item>1996 – Fox News Channel begins broadcasting.</item>
<item>1998 – Matthew Shepard, a gay student at the University of Wyoming, is found tied to a fence after being savagely beaten by two young adults in Laramie, Wyoming.</item>
<item>2001 – The U.S. invasion of Afghanistan begins with an air assault and covert operations on the ground.</item>
<item>2008 – Asteroid 2008 TC3 impacts the Earth over Sudan, the first time an asteroid impact is detected prior to its entry into earth\'s atmosphere.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>