<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_8">
<item>314 – Constantine I defeats Roman Emperor Licinius, who loses his European territories.</item>
<item>451 – The first session of the Council of Chalcedon begins.</item>
<item>876 – Frankish forces led by Louis the Younger prevent a West Frankish invasion and defeat emperor Charles II (\"the Bald\").</item>
<item>1075 – Dmitar Zvonimir is crowned King of Croatia.</item>
<item>1200 – Isabella of Angoulême is crowned Queen consort of England.</item>
<item>1480 – The Great stand on the Ugra river puts an end to Tartar rule over Moscow</item>
<item>1645 – Jeanne Mance open the first lay hospital in North America.</item>
<item>1813 – The Treaty of Ried is signed between Bavaria and Austria.</item>
<item>1829 – Stephenson\'s Rocket wins the Rainhill Trials.</item>
<item>1921 – KDKA in Pittsburgh\'s Forbes Field conducts the first live broadcast of a football game.</item>
<item>1956 – The New York Yankees\'s Don Larsen pitches the only perfect game in a World Series.</item>
<item>1962 – Der Spiegel publishes an article disclosing the sorry state of the Bundeswehr, and is soon accused of treason.</item>
<item>1967 – Guerrilla leader Che Guevara and his men are captured in Bolivia.</item>
<item>1969 – The opening rally of the Days of Rage occurs, organized by the Weather Underground in Chicago.</item>
<item>1973 – Spyros Markezinis begins his 48–day term as prime minister in an abortive attempt to lead Greece to parliamentary rule.</item>
<item>1974 – Franklin National Bank collapses due to fraud and mismanagement; at the time it is the largest bank failure in the history of the United States.</item>
<item>1982 – Poland bans Solidarity and all other trade unions.</item>
<item>1982 – Cats opens on Broadway and runs for nearly 18 years before closing on September 10, 2000.</item>
<item>1991 – Upon the expiration of the Brioni Agreement, Croatia and Slovenia sever all official relations with Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>2001 – U.S. President George W. Bush announces the establishment of the Office of Homeland Security.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>