<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_26">
<item>1185 – The Uprising of Asen and Peter begins on the feast day of St. Demetrius of Thessaloniki and ends with the creation of the Second Bulgarian Empire.</item>
<item>1377 – Tvrtko I is crowned the first king of Bosnia.</item>
<item>1520 – Charles V is crowned as Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1640 – The Treaty of Ripon is signed, restoring peace between Covenanter Scotland and King Charles.</item>
<item>1774 – The first Continental Congress adjourns in Philadelphia.</item>
<item>1825 – The Erie Canal opens, allowing direct passage from the Hudson River to Lake Erie.</item>
<item>1860 – The Expedition of the Thousand ends when Giuseppe Garibaldi presents his conquests to King Victor Emmanuel of Sardinia.</item>
<item>1863 – The Football Association is founded.</item>
<item>1892 – Ida B. Wells publishes Southern Horrors: Lynch Law in All Its Phases.</item>
<item>1905 – King Oscar II recognizes the dissolution of the union between Norway and Sweden.</item>
<item>1918 – Erich Ludendorff, quartermaster–general of the Imperial German Army, is dismissed by Kaiser Wilhelm II for refusing to cooperate in peace negotiations.</item>
<item>1921 – The Chicago Theatre opens.</item>
<item>1936 – The first electric generator at Hoover Dam goes into full operation.</item>
<item>1947 – Kashmir conflict: The Maharaja of Kashmir and Jammu signs the Instrument of Accession with India.</item>
<item>1955 – After the last Allied troops have left the country, and following the provisions of the Austrian Independence Treaty, Austria declares that it will never join a military alliance.</item>
<item>1955 – Ngô Đình Diệm declares himself Premier of South Vietnam.</item>
<item>1958 – Pan American Airways makes the first commercial flight of the Boeing 707 from New York City to Paris.</item>
<item>1967 – Mohammad Reza Pahlavi crowns himself Emperor of Iran.</item>
<item>1968 – Soviet cosmonaut Georgy Beregovoy pilots Soyuz 3 into space for a four–day mission.</item>
<item>1970 – Muhammad Ali boxes for the first time after Ali\'s three–year hiatus due to draft evasion.</item>
<item>1977 – Ali Maow Maalin, the last natural case of smallpox, develops a rash in Somalia. The World Health Organization and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention consider this date to be the anniversary of the eradication of smallpox, the most spectacular success of vaccination.</item>
<item>1985 – The Australian government returns ownership of Uluru to the local Pitjantjatjara Aborigines.</item>
<item>1994 – Jordan and Israel sign a peace treaty.</item>
<item>1999 – Britain\'s House of Lords votes to end the right of hereditary peers to vote in Britain\'s upper chamber of Parliament.</item>
<item>2000 – A wave of protests forces Robert Guéï to step down as president after the Ivorian presidential election.</item>
<item>2001 – The United States passes the USA PATRIOT Act into law.</item>
<item>2017 – Royal cremation of Bhumibol Adulyadej at the Sanam Luang, Bangkok.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>