<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_17">
<item>1346 – The English capture King David II of Scotland at Neville\'s Cross and imprison him for eleven years.</item>
<item>1456 – The University of Greifswald is established as the second oldest university in northern Europe.</item>
<item>1534 – Anti–Catholic posters appear in Paris and other cities supporting Huldrych Zwingli\'s position on the Mass.</item>
<item>1558 – Poczta Polska, the Polish postal service, is founded.</item>
<item>1604 – Kepler\'s Supernova is observed in the constellation of Ophiuchus.</item>
<item>1610 – French king Louis XIII is crowned in Reims Cathedral.</item>
<item>1662 – Charles II of England sells Dunkirk to France for 40,000 pounds.</item>
<item>1771 – Premiere in Milan of the opera Ascanio in Alba, composed by Mozart at age 15.</item>
<item>1817 – The tomb of Pharaoh Seti I is discovered.</item>
<item>1827 – Bellini\'s third opera, Il pirata, is premiered at Milan.</item>
<item>1860 – First The Open Championship (referred to in North America as the British Open).</item>
<item>1888 – Thomas Edison files a patent for the Optical Phonograph (the first movie).</item>
<item>1907 – Marconi begins the first commercial transatlantic wireless service.</item>
<item>1919 – RCA is incorporated as the Radio Corporation of America.</item>
<item>1931 – Al Capone is convicted of income tax evasion.</item>
<item>1940 – The body of Communist propagandist Willi Münzenberg found in South France, starting a never–resolved mystery.</item>
<item>1943 – The Burma Railway (Burma–Thailand Railway) is completed.</item>
<item>1943 – Holocaust in Poland: Sobibór extermination camp is closed.</item>
<item>1945 – A massive demonstration in Buenos Aires, Argentina, demands Juan Perón\'s release.</item>
<item>1956 – The first commercial nuclear power station is officially opened by Queen Elizabeth II in Sellafield, England.</item>
<item>1956 – Bobby Fischer defeats Donald Byrne in the chess Game of the Century.</item>
<item>1961 – Directed by their chief Maurice Papon, Paris police massacre scores of Algerian protesters.</item>
<item>1965 – The 1964–65 New York World\'s Fair closes after two years and more than 51 million attendees.</item>
<item>1979 – The Department of Education Organization Act creates the US Department of Education.</item>
<item>1980 – As part of the Holy See–United Kingdom relations a British monarch makes the first state visit to the Vatican</item>
<item>1989 – The East German Politburo votes to remove Erich Honecker from his role as General Secretary.</item>
<item>2000 – The Hatfield rail crash leads to the collapse of Railtrack.</item>
<item>2003 – Taipei 101, a 101–floor skyscraper in Taipei, becomes the world\'s tallest highrise.</item>
<item>2018 – The recreational use of cannabis is legalized in Canada.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>