<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_24">
<item>1260 – Chartres Cathedral is dedicated in the presence of King Louis IX of France.</item>
<item>1641 – Felim O\'Neill of Kinard, the leader of the Irish Rebellion, issues his Proclamation of Dungannon, justifying the uprising and declaring continued loyalty to Charles I.</item>
<item>1795 – Poland is completely consumed by Russia, Prussia and Austria.</item>
<item>1851 – William Lassell discovers the moons Umbriel and Ariel orbiting Uranus.</item>
<item>1857 – Sheffield F.C., the world\'s oldest association football club still in operation, is founded in England.</item>
<item>1861 – The first transcontinental telegraph line across the United States is completed.</item>
<item>1871 – An estimated 17 to 20 Chinese immigrants are lynched in Los Angeles, California.</item>
<item>1889 – Henry Parkes delivers the Tenterfield Oration, effectively starting the federation process in Australia.</item>
<item>1901 – Annie Edson Taylor becomes the first person to go over Niagara Falls in a barrel.</item>
<item>1902 – Guatemala\'s Santa María Volcano begins to erupt, becoming the third–largest eruption of the 20th century.</item>
<item>1926 – Harry Houdini\'s last performance takes place at the Garrick Theatre in Detroit.</item>
<item>1929 – \"Black Thursday\" on the New York Stock Exchange.</item>
<item>1930 – A bloodless coup d\'état in Brazil ends the First Republic, replacing it with the Vargas Era.</item>
<item>1931 – The George Washington Bridge opens to public traffic over the Hudson River.</item>
<item>1945 – The United Nations Charter comes into effect.</item>
<item>1946 – A camera on board the V–2 No. 13 rocket takes the first photograph of earth from outer space.</item>
<item>1947 – Famed animator Walt Disney testifies before the House Un–American Activities Committee, naming Disney employees he believes to be communists.</item>
<item>1949 – The cornerstone of the United Nations Headquarters is laid.</item>
<item>1954 – President Eisenhower pledges United States support to South Vietnam.</item>
<item>1957 – The United States Air Force starts the X–20 Dyna–Soar manned space program.</item>
<item>1964 – Northern Rhodesia gains independence from the United Kingdom and becomes Zambia.</item>
<item>1975 – In Iceland, 90% of women take part in a national strike, refusing to work in protest of gender inequality.</item>
<item>1980 – The government of Poland legalizes the Solidarity trade union.</item>
<item>1992 – The Toronto Blue Jays become the first Major League Baseball team based outside the United States to win the World Series.</item>
<item>1998 – Deep Space 1 is launched to explore the asteroid belt and test new spacecraft technologies.</item>
<item>2003 – Concorde makes its last commercial flight.</item>
<item>2004 – Arsenal Football Club loses to Manchester United, ending a row of unbeaten matches at 49 matches, which is the record in the Premier League.</item>
<item>2007 – Chang\'e 1, the first satellite in the Chinese Lunar Exploration Program, is launched from Xichang Satellite Launch Center.</item>
<item>2008 – \"Bloody Friday\" saw many of the world\'s stock exchanges experience the worst declines in their history, with drops of around 10% in most indices.</item>
<item>2014 – The China National Space Administration launches an experimental lunar mission, Chang\'e 5–T1, which will loop behind the Moon and return to Earth.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>