<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_3">
<item>2457 BC – Gaecheonjeol, Hwanung (환웅) purportedly descended from heaven. South Korea\'s National Foundation Day.</item>
<item>382 – Roman Emperor Theodosius I concludes a peace treaty with the Goths and settles them in the Balkans.</item>
<item>1392 – Muhammed VII becomes the twelfth sultan of the Emirate of Granada.</item>
<item>1574 – The Siege of Leiden is lifted by the Watergeuzen.</item>
<item>1789 – George Washington proclaims a Thanksgiving Day for that year.</item>
<item>1863 – The last Thursday in November is declared as Thanksgiving Day by U.S. President Abraham Lincoln.</item>
<item>1918 – King Boris III of Bulgaria accedes to the throne.</item>
<item>1919 – Cincinnati Reds pitcher Adolfo Luque becomes the first Latin player to appear in a World Series.</item>
<item>1929 – The Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes is renamed to Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1930 – The German Socialist Labour Party in Poland – Left is founded.</item>
<item>1932 – Iraq gains independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1942 – A German V–2 rocket reaches a record 85 km (46 nm) in altitude.</item>
<item>1949 – WERD, the first black–owned radio station in the United States, opens in Atlanta.</item>
<item>1952 – The United Kingdom successfully tests a nuclear weapon to become the world\'s third nuclear power.</item>
<item>1957 – The California State Superior Court rules that the book Howl and Other Poems is not obscene.</item>
<item>1962 – Project Mercury: Wally Schirra in Sigma 7 launched from Cape Canaveral for a six–orbit flight.</item>
<item>1963 – A violent coup in Honduras begins two decades of military rule.</item>
<item>1985 – The Space Shuttle Atlantis makes its maiden flight.</item>
<item>1986 – TASCC, a superconducting cyclotron at the Chalk River Laboratories in Canada, is officially opened.</item>
<item>1990 – The German Democratic Republic is abolished and becomes part of the Federal Republic of Germany.</item>
<item>1991 – Nadine Gordimer is announced as the winner of the Nobel Prize in Literature.</item>
<item>2008 – The Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 for the U.S. financial system is signed by President George W. Bush.</item>
<item>2009 – Azerbaijan, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, and Turkey join together in the Turkic Council.</item>
<item>2010 – The 19th Commonwealth Games commence in Delhi.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>