<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_11">
<item>1311 – The peerage and clergy restrict the authority of English kings with the Ordinances of 1311.</item>
<item>1614 – The New Netherland Company applies to the States General of the Netherlands for exclusive trading rights in what is now the northeastern United States.</item>
<item>1767 – Surveying for the Mason–Dixon line separating Maryland from Pennsylvania is completed.</item>
<item>1811 – The Juliana begins operation as the first steam–powered ferry in New York harbor.</item>
<item>1840 – The Maronite leader Bashir Shihab II surrenders to the Ottoman Empire and later is sent to Malta in exile.</item>
<item>1852 – The University of Sydney, Australia\'s oldest university, is inaugurated in Sydney.</item>
<item>1865 – Hundreds of black men and women march in Jamaica, starting the Morant Bay rebellion.</item>
<item>1906 – San Francisco sparks a diplomatic crisis between the United States and Japan by ordering segregated schools for Japanese students.</item>
<item>1910 – Piloted by Arch Hoxsey, Theodore Roosevelt becomes the first U.S. president to fly in an airplane.</item>
<item>1944 – The Tuvan People\'s Republic is annexed by the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1950 – CBS\'s field–sequential color system for television is the first to be licensed for broadcast by the U.S. Federal Communications Commission.</item>
<item>1954 – In accord with the 1954 Geneva Conference, French troops complete their withdrawal from North Vietnam.</item>
<item>1958 – NASA launches Pioneer 1, its first space probe, although it fails to achieve a stable orbit.</item>
<item>1962 – The Second Vatican Council becomes the first ecumenical council of the Roman Catholic Church in 92 years.</item>
<item>1968 – NASA launches Apollo 7, the first successful manned Apollo mission.</item>
<item>1972 – A race riot occurs on the United States Navy aircraft carrier Kitty Hawk off the coast of Vietnam.</item>
<item>1976 – George Washington is posthumously promoted to the grade of General of the Armies.</item>
<item>1984 – Aboard the Space Shuttle Challenger, astronaut Kathryn D. Sullivan becomes the first American woman to perform a space walk.</item>
<item>1986 – Ronald Reagan and Mikhail Gorbachev meet in Iceland to continue discussions about scaling back IRBM arsenals in Europe.</item>
<item>1987 – The AIDS Memorial Quilt is first displayed during the Second National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights.</item>
<item>1991 – Prof. Anita Hill delivers her televised testimony concerning sexual harassment during the Clarence Thomas Supreme Court nomination</item>
<item>2000 – NASA launches STS–92, the 100th Space Shuttle mission.</item>
<item>2001 – The Polaroid Corporation files for federal bankruptcy protection.</item>
<item>2018 – Soyuz MS–10, launching an intended crew for the ISS, suffers an in–flight abort. The crew lands safely.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>