<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_27">
<item>312 – Constantine is said to have received his famous Vision of the Cross.</item>
<item>1275 – Traditional founding of the city of Amsterdam.</item>
<item>1524 – French troops lay siege to Pavia.</item>
<item>1682 – Philadelphia is founded in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1775 – King George III expands on his Proclamation of Rebellion in the Thirteen Colonies in his speech from the throne at the opening of Parliament.</item>
<item>1795 – The United States and Spain sign the Treaty of Madrid, which establishes the boundaries between Spanish colonies and the U.S.</item>
<item>1810 – United States annexes the former Spanish colony of West Florida.</item>
<item>1904 – The first underground New York City Subway line opens, later designated as the IRT Broadway–Seventh Avenue Line.</item>
<item>1916 – Negus Mikael, marching on the Ethiopian capital in support of his son Emperor Iyasu V, is defeated by Fitawrari abte Giyorgis, securing the throne for Empress Zewditu I.</item>
<item>1922 – A referendum in Rhodesia rejects the country\'s annexation to the South African Union.</item>
<item>1924 – The Uzbek SSR is founded in the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1930 – Ratifications exchanged in London for the first London Naval Treaty go into effect immediately, further limiting the expensive naval arms race among its five signatories.</item>
<item>1954 – Benjamin O. Davis, Jr. becomes the first African–American general in the United States Air Force.</item>
<item>1958 – Iskander Mirza, the first President of Pakistan, is deposed by General Ayub Khan, who had been appointed the enforcer of martial law by Mirza 20 days earlier.</item>
<item>1961 – NASA tests the first Saturn I rocket in Mission Saturn–Apollo 1.</item>
<item>1962 – Major Rudolf Anderson of the United States Air Force becomes the only direct human casualty of the Cuban Missile Crisis when his U–2 reconnaissance airplane is shot down over Cuba by a Soviet–supplied surface–to–air missile.</item>
<item>1964 – Ronald Reagan delivers a speech on behalf of the Republican candidate for president, Barry Goldwater. The speech launches his political career and comes to be known as \"A Time for Choosing\".</item>
<item>1971 – The Democratic Republic of the Congo is renamed Zaire.</item>
<item>1979 – Saint Vincent and the Grenadines gains its independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1986 – The British government suddenly deregulates financial markets, leading to a total restructuring of the way in which they operate in the country, in an event now referred to as the Big Bang.</item>
<item>1991 – Turkmenistan achieves independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1994 – Gliese 229B is the first Substellar Mass Object to be unquestionably identified.</item>
<item>1995 – Former Prime Minister of Italy Bettino Craxi is convicted in absentia of corruption.</item>
<item>1997 – The 1997 Asian financial crisis causes a crash in the Dow Jones Industrial Average.</item>
<item>2014 – Britain withdraws from Afghanistan at the end of Operation Herrick, after 12 years four months and seven days.</item>
<item>2017 – Catalonia declares independence from Spain.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>