<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_30">
<item>758 – Guangzhou is sacked by Arab and Persian pirates.</item>
<item>1270 – The Eighth Crusade ends by an agreement between Charles I of Anjou (replacing his deceased brother King Louis IX of France) and the Hafsid dynasty of Tunis, Tunisia.</item>
<item>1485 – King Henry VII of England is crowned, beginning the Tudor reign.</item>
<item>1817 – Simón Bolívar becomes President of the Third Republic of Venezuela.</item>
<item>1863 – Danish Prince Vilhelm arrives in Athens to assume his throne as George I, King of the Hellenes.</item>
<item>1864 – The Treaty of Vienna is signed, by which Denmark relinquishes one province each to Prussia and Austria.</item>
<item>1888 – The Rudd Concession is granted by Matabeleland to agents of Cecil Rhodes.</item>
<item>1905 – Czar Nicholas II issues the October Manifesto, granting the Russian peoples basic civil liberties and the right to form a duma. (October 17 in the Julian calendar)</item>
<item>1920 – The Communist Party of Australia is founded in Sydney.</item>
<item>1925 – John Logie Baird creates Britain\'s first television transmitter.</item>
<item>1941 – President Roosevelt approves $1 billion dollars in Lend–Lease aid to the Allied nations.</item>
<item>1945 – Jackie Robinson of the Kansas City Monarchs signs a contract for the Brooklyn Dodgers, breaking the baseball color line.</item>
<item>1947 – The General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade is founded.</item>
<item>1953 – President Eisenhower approves the top–secret document NSC 162/2 concerning the maintenance of a strong nuclear deterrent force against the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1973 – The Bosphorus Bridge in Turkey is completed, connecting the continents of Europe and Asia over the Bosphorus for the second time.</item>
<item>1974 – The Rumble in the Jungle boxing match between Muhammad Ali and George Foreman takes place in Zaire.</item>
<item>1975 – Prince Juan Carlos I of Spain becomes acting head of state, taking over for the country\'s ailing dictator, Gen. Francisco Franco.</item>
<item>1983 – The first democratic elections in Argentina, after seven years of military rule, are held.</item>
<item>1985 – Space Shuttle Challenger lifts off for mission STS–61–A, its final successful mission.</item>
<item>1991 – The Israeli–Palestinian conflict: The Madrid Conference commences in an effort to revive peace negotiations between Israel and Palestine.</item>
<item>1995 – Quebec citizens narrowly vote (50.58% to 49.42%) in favour of remaining a province of Canada in their second referendum on national sovereignty.</item>
<item>2014 – Sweden is the first European Union member state to officially recognize the State of Palestine.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>