<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_28">
<item>306 – Maxentius is proclaimed Roman emperor.</item>
<item>312 – Constantine I defeats Maxentius, becoming the sole Roman emperor in the West.</item>
<item>969 – The Byzantine Empire recovers Antioch from Arab rule.</item>
<item>1344 – The lower town of Smyrna is captured by Crusaders in response to Aydınid piracy.</item>
<item>1420 – Beijing is officially designated the capital of the Ming dynasty when the Forbidden City is completed.</item>
<item>1449 – Christian I is crowned king of Denmark.</item>
<item>1453 – Ladislaus the Posthumous is crowned king of Bohemia in Prague.</item>
<item>1492 – Christopher Columbus lands in Cuba on his first voyage to the New World.</item>
<item>1538 – The Universidad Santo Tomás de Aquino is founded in what is now the Dominican Republic.</item>
<item>1636 – The Massachusetts Bay Colony votes to establish a theological college, which would later become Harvard University.</item>
<item>1664 – The Duke of York and Albany\'s Maritime Regiment of Foot, later to be known as the Royal Marines, is established.</item>
<item>1726 – The novel Gulliver\'s Travels is published.</item>
<item>1835 – The United Tribes of New Zealand are established with the signature of the Declaration of Independence.</item>
<item>1886 – President Cleveland dedicates the Statue of Liberty.</item>
<item>1919 – The U.S. Congress passes the Volstead Act over President Wilson\'s veto, paving the way for Prohibition to begin the following January.</item>
<item>1928 – The Indonesia Raya, now the national anthem, is first sung.</item>
<item>1942 – The Alaska Highway first connects Alaska to the North American railway network at Dawson Creek in Canada.</item>
<item>1956 – Elvis Presley receives a polio vaccination on national TV.</item>
<item>1958 – John XXIII is elected Pope.</item>
<item>1962 – Cuban Missile Crisis: Premier Nikita Khrushchev orders the removal of Soviet missiles from Cuba.</item>
<item>1965 – Pope Paul VI promulgates Nostra aetate, by which the Church officially recognizes the legitimacy of non–Christian faiths.</item>
<item>1971 – Prospero becomes the only British satellite to be launched by a British rocket.</item>
<item>1982 – The Spanish general election begins fourteen years of rule by the Spanish Socialist Workers\' Party.</item>
<item>1990 – Georgia holds its only free election under Soviet rule.</item>
<item>2005 – Vice–president Cheney\'s chief of staff is indicted due to his involvement in the Plame affair.</item>
<item>2007 – Cristina Fernández de Kirchner becomes the first woman elected President of Argentina.</item>
<item>2009 – NASA successfully launches the Ares I–X mission, the only rocket launch for its short–lived Constellation program.</item>
<item>2014 – A rocket carrying NASA\'s Cygnus CRS Orb–3 resupply mission to the International Space Station explodes seconds after taking off from the Mid–Atlantic Regional Spaceport in Virginia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>