<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_14">
<item>1586 – Mary, Queen of Scots, goes on trial for conspiracy against Queen Elizabeth I of England.</item>
<item>1656 – Massachusetts enacts the first punitive legislation against the Religious Society of Friends (Quakers).</item>
<item>1773 – The first recorded ministry of education, the Commission of National Education, is formed in the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth.</item>
<item>1808 – The Republic of Ragusa is annexed by France.</item>
<item>1843 – Irish nationalist Daniel O\'Connell arrested by British on charges of criminal conspiracy.</item>
<item>1884 – American inventor George Eastman receives a U.S. Government patent on his new paper–strip film.</item>
<item>1888 – Louis Le Prince films the first motion picture, Roundhay Garden Scene.</item>
<item>1908 – The Chicago Cubs defeat the Detroit Tigers, 2–0, clinching the 1908 World Series; this would be their last until winning the 2016 World Series.</item>
<item>1910 – English aviator Claude Grahame–White lands his aircraft on Executive Avenue near the White House in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1920 – Finland and Soviet Russia sign the Treaty of Tartu, exchanging some territories.</item>
<item>1926 – The children\'s book Winnie–the–Pooh, by A. A. Milne, is first published.</item>
<item>1933 – Germany withdraws from the League of Nations and World Disarmament Conference.</item>
<item>1947 – Chuck Yeager becomes the first person to exceed the speed of sound.</item>
<item>1949 – The Smith Act trials of Communist Party leaders in the United States convicts eleven defendants of conspiring to advocate the violent overthrow of the federal government.</item>
<item>1956 – Dr. B. R. Ambedkar converts from Hinduism to Buddhism along with 385,000 of his followers.</item>
<item>1957 – The 23rd Canadian Parliament becomes the only one to be personally opened by the Queen of Canada.</item>
<item>1962 – The Cuban Missile Crisis begins when an American reconnaissance aircraft takes photographs of Soviet ballistic missiles being installed in Cuba.</item>
<item>1964 – Martin Luther King Jr. received the Nobel Peace Prize for combating racial inequality through nonviolence.</item>
<item>1964 – The Soviet Presidium and the Communist Party Central Committee each vote to accept Nikita Khrushchev\'s \"voluntary\" request to retire from his offices.</item>
<item>1966 – The city of Montreal begins the operation of its underground Montreal Metro rapid transit system.</item>
<item>1968 – The first live TV broadcast by American astronauts in orbit is performed by the Apollo 7 crew.</item>
<item>1968 – Jim Hines becomes the first man ever to break the so–called \"ten–second barrier\" in the 100–meter sprint with a time of 9.95 seconds.</item>
<item>1979 – The first National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights draws approximately 100,000 people.</item>
<item>1994 – Yasser Arafat, Yitzhak Rabin and Shimon Peres receive the Nobel Peace Prize for their role in the establishment of the Oslo Accords and the framing of future Palestinian self government.</item>
<item>2012 – Felix Baumgartner successfully jumps to Earth from a balloon in the stratosphere.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>