<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_13">
<item>409 – Vandals and Alans cross the Pyrenees and appear in Hispania.</item>
<item>1269 – The present church building at Westminster Abbey is consecrated.</item>
<item>1332 – Rinchinbal Khan becomes the Khagan of the Mongols and Emperor of the Yuan dynasty, reigning for only 53 days.</item>
<item>1644 – A Swedish–Dutch fleet defeats the Danish fleet at Fehmarn and captures about 1,000 prisoners.</item>
<item>1710 – Port Royal, the capital of French Acadia, falls in a siege by British forces.</item>
<item>1775 – The Continental Congress establishes the Continental Navy (predecessor of the United States Navy).</item>
<item>1792 – In Washington, D.C., the cornerstone of the United States Executive Mansion (known as the White House since 1818) is laid.</item>
<item>1821 – The Declaration of Independence of the Mexican Empire is publicly proclaimed.</item>
<item>1843 – In New York City, B\'nai B\'rith, the oldest Jewish service organization in the world, is founded.</item>
<item>1881 – First known conversation in modern Hebrew by Eliezer Ben–Yehuda and friends.</item>
<item>1884 – The International Meridian Conference establishes the meridian of the Greenwich Observatory as the prime meridian.</item>
<item>1885 – The Georgia Institute of Technology is founded in Atlanta, Georgia.</item>
<item>1903 – The Boston Red Sox win the first modern World Series, defeating the Pittsburgh Pirates in the eighth game.</item>
<item>1908 – Margaret Travers Symons bursts into the UK parliament and became the first woman to speak there.</item>
<item>1911 – Prince Arthur, Duke of Connaught and Strathearn, becomes the first Governor General of Canada of royal descent.</item>
<item>1917 – The \"Miracle of the Sun\" is witnessed by an estimated 70,000 people in the Cova da Iria in Portugal]].</item>
<item>1921 – Soviet republics sign the Treaty of Kars to formalize the borders between Turkey and the South Caucasus states.</item>
<item>1923 – Ankara becomes the capital of Turkey.</item>
<item>1946 – France adopts the constitution of the Fourth Republic.</item>
<item>1972 – Uruguayan Air Force Flight 571 crashes in the Andes mountains. 28 survive the crash. All but 16 succumb before rescue on December 23</item>
<item>1976 – The first electron micrograph of an Ebola virus, by Dr. F. A. Murphy, is taken at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention]]</item>
<item>1983 – Ameritech Mobile Communications launches the first US cellular network in Chicago.</item>
<item>2010 – The mining accident in Copiapó, Chile ends as all 33 trapped miners arrive at the surface after a record 69 days underground.</item>
<item>2016 – The Maldives announces its decision to withdraw from the Commonwealth of Nations.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>