<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_29">
<item>539 BC – Cyrus the Great (founder of Persian Empire) entered the capital of Babylon and allowed the Jews to return to their land.</item>
<item>437 – Valentinian III, Western Roman Emperor, marries Licinia Eudoxia, daughter of his cousin Theodosius II, Eastern Roman Emperor in Constantinople unifying the two branches of the House of Theodosius.</item>
<item>969 – Byzantine troops occupy Antioch, Syria.</item>
<item>1591 – Pope Innocent IX is elected.</item>
<item>1611 – Russian homage to the King of Poland, Sigismund III Vasa.</item>
<item>1618 – English adventurer, writer, and courtier Sir Walter Raleigh is beheaded for allegedly conspiring against James I of England.</item>
<item>1665 – Portuguese forces defeat the Kingdom of Kongo and decapitate King António I of Kongo, also known as Nvita a Nkanga.</item>
<item>1675 – Leibniz makes the first use of the long s (∫) as a symbol of the integral in calculus.</item>
<item>1787 – Mozart\'s opera Don Giovanni receives its first performance in Prague.</item>
<item>1792 – Mount Hood (Oregon) is named after Samuel Hood, 1st Viscount Hood by Lt. William E. Broughton who sighted the mountain near the mouth of the Willamette River.</item>
<item>1863 – Eighteen countries meet in Geneva and agree to form the International Red Cross.</item>
<item>1921 – The Link River Dam, a part of the Klamath Reclamation Project, is completed.</item>
<item>1921 – United States: Second trial of Sacco and Vanzetti in Boston, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1921 – The Harvard University football team loses to Centre College, ending a 25–game winning streak. This is considered one of the biggest upsets in college football.</item>
<item>1923 – Turkey becomes a republic following the dissolution of the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1929 – The New York Stock Exchange crashes in what will be called the Crash of \'29 or \"Black Tuesday\", ending the Great Bull Market of the 1920s and beginning the Great Depression.</item>
<item>1941 – The Holocaust: In the Kaunas Ghetto, over 10,000 Jews are shot by German occupiers at the Ninth Fort, a massacre known as the \"Great Action\".</item>
<item>1944 – The Dutch city of Breda is liberated by 1st Polish Armoured Division.</item>
<item>1953 – BCPA Flight 304 DC–6 crashes near San Francisco.</item>
<item>1960 – In Louisville, Kentucky, Cassius Clay (who later takes the name Muhammad Ali) wins his first professional fight.</item>
<item>1960 – An airplane carrying the Cal Poly football team crashes on takeoff in Toledo, Ohio.</item>
<item>1961 – Syria exits from the United Arab Republic.</item>
<item>1964 – The United Republic of Tanganyika and Zanzibar is renamed the United Republic of Tanzania.</item>
<item>1964 – A collection of irreplaceable gems, including the 565 carat (113 g) Star of India, is stolen by a group of thieves (among them is \"Murph the surf\") from the American Museum of Natural History in New York City.</item>
<item>1967 – Montreal\'s World Fair, Expo 67, closes with over 50 million visitors.</item>
<item>1969 – The first–ever computer–to–computer link is established on ARPANET, the precursor to the Internet.</item>
<item>1985 – Major General Samuel K. Doe is announced the winner of the first multi–party election in Liberia.</item>
<item>1986 – British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher opens the last stretch of the M25 motorway.</item>
<item>1991 – The American Galileo spacecraft makes its closest approach to 951 Gaspra, becoming the first probe to visit an asteroid.</item>
<item>1998 – In South Africa, the Truth and Reconciliation Commission presents its report, which condemns both sides for committing atrocities.</item>
<item>1998 – Space Shuttle Discovery blasts off on STS–95 with 77–year–old John Glenn on board, making him the oldest person to go into space.</item>
<item>1998 – ATSC HDTV broadcasting in the United States is inaugurated with the launch of the STS–95 space shuttle mission.</item>
<item>1998 – While en route from Adana to Ankara, a Turkish Airlines flight with a crew of six and 33 passengers is hijacked by a Kurdish militant who orders the pilot to fly to Switzerland. The plane instead lands in Ankara after the pilot tricked the hijacker into thinking that he is landing in the Bulgarian capital of Sofia to refuel.</item>
<item>1999 – A large cyclone devastates Odisha, India.</item>
<item>2008 – Delta Air Lines merges with Northwest Airlines, creating the world\'s largest airline and reducing the number of US legacy carriers to five.</item>
<item>2015 – China announces the end of One–child policy after 35 years.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>