<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_10">
<item>680 – Muhammad\'s grandson Husayn ibn Ali is decapitated by Caliph Yazid I\'s troops.</item>
<item>732 – Charles Martel\'s forces defeat an Umayyad army between near Tours, France.</item>
<item>1575 – Roman Catholic forces under Henry I, Duke of Guise defeat the Protestants, capturing Philippe de Mornay among others.</item>
<item>1580 – Over 600 Papal troops land in Ireland to support the Second Desmond Rebellion.</item>
<item>1760 – In a treaty with the Dutch colonial authorities, the Ndyuka people of Suriname – descended from escaped slaves – gain territorial autonomy.</item>
<item>1845 – In Annapolis, Maryland, the Naval School (later the United States Naval Academy) opens with 50 students.</item>
<item>1846 – Triton, the largest moon of the planet Neptune, is discovered by English astronomer William Lassell.</item>
<item>1903 – The Women\'s Social and Political Union is founded in support of the enfranchisement of British women.</item>
<item>1913 – U.S. President Wilson triggers the explosion of the Gamboa Dike, completing major construction on the Panama Canal.</item>
<item>1920 – The Carinthian plebiscite determines that the larger part of the Duchy of Carinthia should remain part of Austria.</item>
<item>1928 – Chiang Kai–shek becomes Chairman of the Republic of China.</item>
<item>1935 – In Greece, a coup d\'état ends the Second Hellenic Republic.</item>
<item>1938 – Abiding by the Munich Agreement, Czechoslovakia completes its withdrawal from the Sudetenland.</item>
<item>1945 – The Double Tenth Agreement is signed by the Communist Party and the Kuomintang about the future of China.</item>
<item>1957 – The Windscale fire results in Britain\'s worst nuclear accident.</item>
<item>1963 – France cedes control of the Bizerte naval base to Tunisia.</item>
<item>1963 – The Partial Nuclear Test Ban Treaty comes into effect.</item>
<item>1964 – The Tokyo Summer Olympics opening ceremony is the first to be relayed live by satellites.</item>
<item>1967 – The Outer Space Treaty comes into force.</item>
<item>1970 – Fiji becomes independent.</item>
<item>1973 – U.S. Vice President Spiro Agnew resigns after being charged with evasion of federal income tax.</item>
<item>1975 – Papua New Guinea joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1980 – The Farabundo Martí National Liberation Front is founded in El Salvador.</item>
<item>1985 – US Navy aircraft intercept an Egyptian airliner carrying the perpetrators of the Achille Lauro hijacking, and force it to land in Italy.</item>
<item>2009 – Armenia and Turkey sign the Zurich Protocols, intended to normalize relations. However, they are never ratified by either side.</item>
<item>2010 – The Netherlands Antilles are dissolved as a country.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>