<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_15">
<item>1066 – Edgar the Ætheling is proclaimed King of England, but is never crowned. He reigns until 10 December 1066.</item>
<item>1211 – The Latin emperor Henry of Flanders defeats the Nicaean emperor Theodore I Laskaris.</item>
<item>1529 – The Siege of Vienna ends when Austria routs the invading Ottoman forces, ending its European expansion.</item>
<item>1582 – Adoption of the Gregorian calendar begins, eventually leading to near–universal adoption.</item>
<item>1783 – The Montgolfier brothers\' hot air balloon makes the first human ascent, piloted by Jean–François Pilâtre de Rozier.</item>
<item>1809 – The Viceroy the Río de la Plata, Baltasar Hidalgo de Cisneros, opens the port of Buenos Aires to trade with nations other than Spain.</item>
<item>1815 – Napoleon begins his exile on Saint Helena in the South Atlantic Ocean.</item>
<item>1821 – The Cortes of Cádiz decides to create the providence of Logroño.</item>
<item>1874 – The Academia Ecuatoriana de la Lengua is established in Quito, Ecuador.</item>
<item>1878 – The Edison Electric Light Company begins operation.</item>
<item>1880 – In Germany, the inauguration of the Cologne Cathedral is celebrated.</item>
<item>1888 – The \"From Hell\" letter allegedly sent by Jack the Ripper is received by investigators.</item>
<item>1894 – Alfred Dreyfus is arrested for spying.</item>
<item>1910 – Airship America is launched from New Jersey in the first attempt to cross the Atlantic by a powered aircraft.</item>
<item>1923 – The German Rentenmark is introduced in Germany to counter hyperinflation in the Weimar Republic.</item>
<item>1928 – The airship, Graf Zeppelin completes its first trans–Atlantic flight, landing in the United States.</item>
<item>1932 – Tata Airlines (later to become Air India) makes its first flight.</item>
<item>1939 – The New York Municipal Airport (later renamed LaGuardia Airport) is dedicated.</item>
<item>1946 – The United Nations Security Council Resolution 9 concerning the International Court of Justice is unanimously adopted.</item>
<item>1951 – Mexican chemist Luis E. Miramontes completes the synthesis of norethisterone, the basis of an early oral contraceptive.</item>
<item>1956 – FORTRAN, the first modern computer language, is first shared with the coding community.</item>
<item>1962 – The CIA notifies the State Department that Soviet ballistic missiles are in Cuba, leading to the Cuban Missile Crisis.</item>
<item>1964 – Alexei Kosygin becomes the General Secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1966 – The Black Panther Party is founded.</item>
<item>1989 – Wayne Gretzky becomes the all–time leading points scorer in the NHL.</item>
<item>1989 – Eight of those convicted in the Rivonia Trial are released from prison.</item>
<item>1991 – The first ultra–high–energy cosmic ray is detected.</item>
<item>1994 – The Clinton administration returns Haiti\'s first democratically elected president, Jean–Bertrand Aristide, to the island.</item>
<item>1995 – Saddam Hussein is reelected president of Iraq through a referendum.</item>
<item>1997 – Andy Green in ThrustSSC sets the first supersonic land speed record.</item>
<item>1997 – The Cassini probe launches from Cape Canaveral on its way to Saturn.</item>
<item>2001 – NASA\'s Galileo spacecraft passes within 112 miles of Jupiter\'s moon Io.</item>
<item>2003 – China launches Shenzhou 5, its first manned space mission.</item>
<item>2005 – Iraqis vote to ratify the new constitution.</item>
<item>2008 – The Dow Jones Industrial Average closes down 733.08 points, or 7.87%, the second worst percentage drop in the Dow\'s history.</item>
<item>2011 – The 2011 Global Protests occur.</item>
<item>2016 – One hundred ninety–seven nations amend the Montreal Protocol to include a phase–out of hydrofluorocarbons.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>