<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_12">
<item>539 BC – The fall of Babylon to a Persian army.</item>
<item>1279 – The Nichiren Shōshū branch of Buddhism is founded in Japan.</item>
<item>1398 – In the Treaty of Salynas, Lithuania cedes Samogitia to the Teutonic Knights.</item>
<item>1492 – The first of the voyages of Christopher Columbus reaches the Bahamas.</item>
<item>1692 – The Salem witch trials are ended by a letter from the governor of the Massachusetts Bay Province.</item>
<item>1773 – America\'s first insane asylum opens.</item>
<item>1792 – The first celebration of Columbus Day is held in New York City.</item>
<item>1793 – The cornerstone of Old East, the oldest state university building in the United States, is laid at the University of North Carolina.</item>
<item>1799 – Jeanne Geneviève Labrosse becomes the first woman to jump from a balloon with a parachute.</item>
<item>1810 – The citizens of Munich hold the first Oktoberfest.</item>
<item>1822 – Pedro I of Brazil is proclaimed the emperor.</item>
<item>1823 – Charles Macintosh of Scotland sells the first raincoat.</item>
<item>1847 – Werner von Siemens founds Siemens &amp; Halske, which later becomes Siemens AG.</item>
<item>1849 – The city of Manizales, Colombia is founded by \'The Expedition of the 20\'.</item>
<item>1871 – The British in India enact the Criminal Tribes Act, naming many local communities \"Criminal Tribes\".</item>
<item>1890 – Uddevalla Suffrage Association is formed.</item>
<item>1892 – The Pledge of Allegiance is first recited by students in many US public schools.</item>
<item>1901 – President Theodore Roosevelt officially renames the \"Executive Mansion\" to the White House.</item>
<item>1928 – An iron lung respirator is used for the first time at Children\'s Hospital, Boston.</item>
<item>1933 – The military Alcatraz Citadel becomes the civilian Alcatraz Federal Penitentiary.</item>
<item>1960 – Soviet Premier Nikita Khrushchev pounds his shoe on a desk at the United Nations to protest a Philippine assertion.</item>
<item>1963 – After nearly 23 years of imprisonment, Reverend Walter Ciszek, a Jesuit missionary, was released from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1964 – The Soviet Union launches the Voskhod 1 into Earth orbit as the first spacecraft with a multi–person crew, and the first flight without pressure suits.</item>
<item>1968 – Equatorial Guinea becomes independent from Spain.</item>
<item>1971 – The 2,500 year celebration of the Persian Empire begins.</item>
<item>1979 – The lowest recorded non–tornadic atmospheric pressure, 87.0 kPa (870 mbar or 25.69 inHg), occurred in the western Pacific Ocean during Typhoon Tip.</item>
<item>1983 – Japan\'s former Prime Minister Tanaka Kakuei is found guilty of taking a $2 million bribe from the Lockheed Corporation, and is sentenced to four years in jail.</item>
<item>1988 – Two officers of the Victoria Police are gunned down execution–style in the Walsh Street police shootings, Australia.</item>
<item>1999 – Pervez Musharraf takes power in Pakistan from Nawaz Sharif through a bloodless coup.</item>
<item>1999 – The former Autonomous Soviet Republic of Abkhazia declares its independence from Georgia.</item>
<item>2005 – The second Chinese human spaceflight, Shenzhou 6, is launched, carrying two cosmonauts in orbit for five days.</item>
<item>2017 – The United States announces its decision to withdraw from UNESCO. and is immediately followed by Israel.</item>
<item>2018 – Princess Eugenie marries Jack Brooksbank at St. George\'s Chapel, Windsor Castle.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>