<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_5">
<item>816 – King Louis the Pious is crowned emperor of the Holy Roman Empire by the Pope.</item>
<item>869 – The Fourth Council of Constantinople is convened to depose patriarch Photios I.</item>
<item>1143 – King Alfonso VII of León and Castile recognises Portugal as a Kingdom.</item>
<item>1450 – Louis IX, Duke of Bavaria expels Jews from his jurisdiction.</item>
<item>1550 – Foundation of Concepción, Chile.</item>
<item>1665 – The University of Kiel is founded.</item>
<item>1857 – The city of Anaheim, California is founded.</item>
<item>1869 – The Saxby Gale devastates the Bay of Fundy region in Canada.</item>
<item>1905 – The Wright Brothers pilot the Wright Flyer III in a new world record flight of 24 miles in 39 minutes.</item>
<item>1911 – The Kowloon–Canton Railway commences service.</item>
<item>1921 – The World Series is the first to be broadcast on radio.</item>
<item>1930 – British airship R101 crashes in France en route to India on its maiden voyage.</item>
<item>1936 – The Jarrow March sets off for London.</item>
<item>1944 – The Provisional Government of the French Republic enfranchises women.</item>
<item>1947 – President Truman makes the first televised Oval Office address.</item>
<item>1966 – A reactor at the Enrico Fermi Nuclear Generating Station near Detroit suffers a partial meltdown.</item>
<item>1968 – A Northern Ireland Civil Rights Association march in Derry is violently suppressed by police.</item>
<item>1970 – The Public Broadcasting Service (PBS) is founded.</item>
<item>1984 – Marc Garneau becomes the first Canadian in space.</item>
<item>1986 – Mordechai Vanunu\'s story in The Sunday Times reveals Israel\'s secret nuclear weapons.</item>
<item>1988 – A Chilean opposition coalition defeats Augusto Pinochet in his re–election attempt.</item>
<item>1990 – After 150 years The Herald newspaper in Melbourne, Australia, is published for the last time as a separate newspaper.</item>
<item>2000 – Mass demonstrations in Serbia force the resignation of Slobodan Milošević.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>