<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_20">
<item>1548 – The city of La Paz is founded by Alonso de Mendoza.</item>
<item>1568 – The Spanish Duke of Alba defeats a Dutch rebel force under William the Silent.</item>
<item>1720 – Caribbean pirate Calico Jack is captured by the Royal Navy.</item>
<item>1781 – The Patent of Toleration, providing limited freedom of worship, is approved in Austria.</item>
<item>1803 – The United States Senate ratifies the Louisiana Purchase.</item>
<item>1818 – The Convention of 1818 is signed between the United States and the United Kingdom, which settles the Canada–United States border on the 49th parallel for most of its length.</item>
<item>1904 – Chile and Bolivia sign the Treaty of Peace and Friendship, delimiting the border between the two countries.</item>
<item>1910 – The hull of the RMS Olympic, sister–ship to the ill–fated RMS Titanic, is launched from the Harland and Wolff shipyard in Belfast.</item>
<item>1935 – The Long March, a mammoth retreat undertaken by the armed forces of the Chinese Communist Party a year prior, ends.</item>
<item>1944 – American general Douglas MacArthur fulfills his promise to return to the Philippines when he commands an Allied assault on the islands.</item>
<item>1947 – The House Un–American Activities Committee begins its investigation into Communist infiltration of the Hollywood film industry, resulting in a blacklist that prevents some from working in the industry for years.</item>
<item>1951 – The \"Johnny Bright incident\" occurs in Stillwater, Oklahoma.</item>
<item>1952 – The Governor of Kenya declares a state of emergency and begins arresting hundreds of suspected leaders of the Mau Mau Uprising.</item>
<item>1961 – The Soviet Union performs the first armed test of a submarine–launched ballistic missile, launching an R–13 from a Golf–class submarine.</item>
<item>1968 – Former First Lady Jacqueline Kennedy marries Greek shipping tycoon Aristotle Onassis.</item>
<item>1973 – The Sydney Opera House is opened by Elizabeth II after 14 years of construction.</item>
<item>1977 – Rock band Lynyrd Skynyrd\'s airplane crashes. Lead singer Ronnie Van Zant and guitarist Steve Gaines perish in the crash.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>