<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_16">
<item>456 – Ricimer defeats Avitus at Piacenza and becomes master of the Western Roman Empire.</item>
<item>690 – Empress Wu Zetian ascends to the throne of the Tang dynasty and proclaims herself ruler of the Chinese Empire.</item>
<item>912 – Abd ar–Rahman III becomes the 8th Emir of Córdoba</item>
<item>955 – King Otto I defeats a Slavic revolt in what is now Mecklenburg–Vorpommern.</item>
<item>1311 – The Council of Vienne convenes for the first time.</item>
<item>1384 – Jadwiga is crowned King of Poland, although she is a woman.</item>
<item>1736 – Mathematician William Whiston\'s predicted comet fails to strike the Earth.</item>
<item>1841 – Queen\'s University is founded in the Province of Canada.</item>
<item>1843 – William Rowan Hamilton invents quaternions, a three–dimensional system of complex numbers.</item>
<item>1846 – William T. G. Morton administers ether anesthesia during a surgical operation.</item>
<item>1847 – The novel Jane Eyre is published in London.</item>
<item>1869 – The Cardiff Giant, one of the most famous American hoaxes, is \"discovered\".</item>
<item>1869 – Girton College, Cambridge is founded, becoming England\'s first residential college for women.</item>
<item>1875 – Brigham Young University is founded in Provo, Utah.</item>
<item>1882 – The Nickel Plate Railroad opens for business.</item>
<item>1905 – The Partition of Bengal in India takes place.</item>
<item>1916 – Margaret Sanger opens the first family planning clinic in the United States.</item>
<item>1923 – The Walt Disney Company is founded.</item>
<item>1934 – Chinese Communists begin the Long March to escape Nationalist encirclement.</item>
<item>1947 – The Philippines takes over the administration of the Turtle Islands and the Mangsee Islands from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1951 – The first Prime Minister of Pakistan, Liaquat Ali Khan, is assassinated in Rawalpindi.</item>
<item>1964 – China detonates its first nuclear weapon.</item>
<item>1964 – Leonid Brezhnev becomes leader of the Soviet Communist Party, while Alexei Kosygin becomes the head of government.</item>
<item>1968 – Tommie Smith and John Carlos are ejected from the US Olympic team for participating in the Olympics Black Power salute.</item>
<item>1968 – Kingston, Jamaica is rocked by the Rodney riots, inspired by the barring of Walter Rodney from the country.</item>
<item>1975 – Three–year–old Rahima Banu, from Bangladesh, is the last known case of naturally occurring smallpox.</item>
<item>1975 – The Australian Coalition sparks a constitutional crisis when they vote to defer funding for the government\'s annual budget.</item>
<item>1978 – Pope John Paul II becomes the first non–Italian pontiff since 1523.</item>
<item>1995 – The Million Man March takes place in Washington, D.C. About 837,000 attended.</item>
<item>1995 – The Skye Bridge in Scotland is opened.</item>
<item>2002 – The Bibliotheca Alexandrina opens in Egypt, commemorating the ancient library of Alexandria.</item>
<item>2017 – Storm Ophelia strikes the U.K. and Ireland causing major damage and power loss.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>