<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_4">
<item>1511 – Formation of the Holy League of Aragon, the Papal States and Venice against France.</item>
<item>1535 – The Coverdale Bible is printed, with translations into English by William Tyndale and Myles Coverdale.</item>
<item>1582 – The Gregorian Calendar is introduced by Pope Gregory XIII.</item>
<item>1597 – Governor Gonzalo Méndez de Canço begins to suppress a native uprising against his rule in what is now Georgia.</item>
<item>1824 – Mexico adopts a new constitution and becomes a federal republic.</item>
<item>1876 – The Agricultural and Mechanical College of Texas opens as the first public college in Texas.</item>
<item>1883 – First run of the Orient Express.</item>
<item>1883 – First meeting of the Boys\' Brigade in Glasgow, Scotland.</item>
<item>1895 – Horace Rawlins wins the first U.S. Open Men\'s Golf Championship.</item>
<item>1904 – The IFK Göteborg football club is founded in Sweden.</item>
<item>1927 – Gutzon Borglum begins sculpting Mount Rushmore.</item>
<item>1941 – Norman Rockwell\'s Willie Gillis character debuts on the cover of The Saturday Evening Post.</item>
<item>1957 – Sputnik 1 becomes the first artificial satellite to orbit the Earth.</item>
<item>1958 – The current constitution of France is adopted.</item>
<item>1965 – Pope Paul VI begins the first papal visit to the Americas.</item>
<item>1966 – Basutoland becomes independent from the United Kingdom and is renamed Lesotho.</item>
<item>1983 – Richard Noble sets a new land speed record of 633.468 miles per hour (1,019.468 km/h) at the Black Rock Desert in Nevada.</item>
<item>1991 – The Protocol on Environmental Protection to the Antarctic Treaty is opened for signature.</item>
<item>1997 – The second largest cash robbery in U.S. history occurs in North Carolina</item>
<item>2004 – SpaceShipOne wins the Ansari X Prize for private spaceflight.</item>
<item>2006 – WikiLeaks is launched.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>