<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_22">
<item>451 – The Chalcedonian Creed, regarding the divine and human nature of Jesus, is adopted.</item>
<item>794 – Emperor Kanmu relocates the Japanese capital to Heian–kyō (now Kyoto).</item>
<item>1575 – Foundation of Aguascalientes City in New Spain.</item>
<item>1633 – The Ming dynasty defeats the Dutch East India Company.</item>
<item>1707 – Four British naval vessels run aground on the Isles of Scilly because of faulty navigation. In response, the first Longitude Act is enacted in 1714.</item>
<item>1730 – Construction of the Ladoga Canal is completed.</item>
<item>1746 – The College of New Jersey (later renamed Princeton University) receives its charter.</item>
<item>1784 – Russia founds a colony on Kodiak Island, Alaska.</item>
<item>1797 – André–Jacques Garnerin makes the first recorded parachute jump, from one thousand meters (3,200 feet) above Paris.</item>
<item>1836 – Sam Houston is inaugurated as the first President of the Republic of Texas.</item>
<item>1844 – Millerites, followers of anticipate the end of the world in conjunction with the Second Advent of Christ. The following day became known as the Great Disappointment.</item>
<item>1866 – A plebiscite ratifies the annexion of Veneto and Mantua to Italy, which had occurred three days before, on October 19.</item>
<item>1875 – First telegraphic connection in Argentina.</item>
<item>1878 – The Bramall Lane stadium sees the first rugby match played under floodlights.</item>
<item>1883 – The Metropolitan Opera House in New York City opens with a performance of Gounod\'s Faust.</item>
<item>1884 – The Royal Observatory in Britain is adopted as the prime meridian of longitude.</item>
<item>1895 – In Paris an express train derails after overrunning the buffer stop, crossing almost 30 metres (100 ft) of concourse before crashing through a wall and falling 10 metres (33 ft) to the road below.</item>
<item>1907 – A run on the stock of the Knickerbocker Trust Company sets events in motion that will spark the Panic of 1907.</item>
<item>1910 – Hawley Harvey Crippen (the first felon to be arrested with the help of radio) is convicted of poisoning his wife.</item>
<item>1923 – The royalist Leonardopoulos–Gargalidis coup d\'état attempt fails in Greece, discrediting the monarchy and paving the way for the establishment of the Second Hellenic Republic.</item>
<item>1928 – Phi Sigma Alpha fraternity is founded at the University of Puerto Rico.</item>
<item>1947 – The Kashmir conflict between India and Pakistan begins, having started just after the partition of India.</item>
<item>1962 – Cuban Missile Crisis: President Kennedy, after internal counsel from Dwight D. Eisenhower, announces that American reconnaissance planes have discovered Soviet nuclear weapons in Cuba, and that he has ordered a naval \"quarantine\" of the Communist nation.</item>
<item>1963 – A BAC One–Eleven prototype airliner crashes in UK with the loss of all on board.</item>
<item>1964 – An all–party Parliamentary Committee selects the design which will become the new official flag of Canada.</item>
<item>1966 – The Supremes become the first all–female music group to attain a No. 1 selling album (The Supremes A\' Go–Go).</item>
<item>1966 – The Soviet Union launches Luna 12.</item>
<item>1968 – Apollo program: Apollo 7 safely splashes down in the Atlantic Ocean after orbiting the Earth 163 times.</item>
<item>1975 – The Soviet unmanned space mission Venera 9 lands on Venus.</item>
<item>1976 – Red Dye No. 4 is banned by the US Food and Drug Administration after it is discovered that it causes tumors in the bladders of dogs.</item>
<item>1981 – The United States Federal Labor Relations Authority votes to decertify the Professional Air Traffic Controllers Organization (PATCO) for its strike the previous August.</item>
<item>2001 – Grand Theft Auto III is released, popularizing a genre of open–world, action–adventure video games, as well as spurring controversy around violence in video games.</item>
<item>2006 – A Panama Canal expansion proposal is approved by 77.8% of voters in a National referendum.</item>
<item>2008 – India launches its first unmanned lunar mission Chandrayaan–1.</item>
<item>2013 – The Australian Capital Territory becomes the first Australian jurisdiction to legalize same–sex marriage with the Marriage Equality (Same Sex) Act 2013</item>
</string-array>
</resources>