<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_9">
<item>768 – Carloman I and Charlemagne are crowned kings of the Franks.</item>
<item>1238 – James I of Aragon founds the Kingdom of Valencia.</item>
<item>1410 – The first known mention of the Prague astronomical clock.</item>
<item>1446 – The hangul alphabet is published in Korea.</item>
<item>1594 – Troops of the Portuguese Empire are defeated on Sri Lanka, bringing an end to the Campaign of Danture.</item>
<item>1604 – Supernova 1604 is sighted, the most recent supernova to be observed within the Milky Way.</item>
<item>1635 – Roger Williams is banished from the Massachusetts Bay Colony after religious and policy disagreements.</item>
<item>1701 – The Collegiate School of Connecticut (later renamed Yale University) is chartered in Old Saybrook.</item>
<item>1799 – HMS Lutine sinks with the loss of 240 men and a cargo worth £1,200,000.</item>
<item>1804 – Hobart, capital of Tasmania, is founded.</item>
<item>1820 – Guayaquil declares independence from Spain.</item>
<item>1824 – Slavery in Latin America: Slavery is abolished in Costa Rica.</item>
<item>1825 – Restauration arrives in New York Harbor from Norway, the first organized immigration from Norway to the United States.</item>
<item>1831 – Ioannis Kapodistrias, the first head of state of independent Greece, is assassinated.</item>
<item>1834 – Opening of the Dublin and Kingstown Railway, the first public railway on the island of Ireland.</item>
<item>1847 – Slavery in the British and French Caribbean: Slavery is abolished in Saint Barthélemy.</item>
<item>1873 – A meeting at the U.S. Naval Academy establishes the U.S. Naval Institute.</item>
<item>1874 – A international postal union is created by the Treaty of Bern.</item>
<item>1900 – The Cook Islands become a territory of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1907 – Las Cruces, New Mexico is incorporated.</item>
<item>1913 – The steamship SS Volturno catches fire in the mid–Atlantic.</item>
<item>1918 – The Finnish Parliament offers to Prince Frederick Charles of Hesse the throne of a short–lived Kingdom of Finland.</item>
<item>1919 – The Cincinnati Reds win the World Series, resulting in the Black Sox Scandal.</item>
<item>1936 – Boulder Dam (later Hoover Dam) begins to generate electricity and transmit it to Los Angeles.</item>
<item>1941 – A coup in Panama declares Ricardo Adolfo de la Guardia Arango the new president.</item>
<item>1942 – Australia\'s Statute of Westminster Adoption Act 1942 receives royal assent.</item>
<item>1950 – The Goyang Geumjeong Cave massacre in Korea begins.</item>
<item>1962 – Uganda becomes an independent Commonwealth realm.</item>
<item>1969 – In Chicago, the National Guard is called in as demonstrations continue in over the trial of the \"Chicago Eight\".</item>
<item>1970 – The Khmer Republic is proclaimed in Cambodia.</item>
<item>1981 – President Mitterrand abolishes capital punishment in France.</item>
<item>1986 – The Phantom of the Opera, eventually the second longest running musical in London, opens at Her Majesty\'s Theatre.</item>
<item>2003 – Mission: Space opens to the public in Walt Disney World.</item>
<item>2006 – North Korea conducts its first nuclear test.</item>
<item>2009 – First lunar impact of NASA\'s Lunar Precursor Robotic Program.</item>
<item>2012 – Pakistani Taliban attempt to assassinate outspoken schoolgirl Malala Yousafzai.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>