<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a10_1">
<item>366 – Pope Damasus I is elected.</item>
<item>959 – Edgar the Peaceful becomes king of all England.</item>
<item>965 – Pope John XIII is elected.</item>
<item>1553 – Coronation of Queen Mary I of England.</item>
<item>1588 – Coronation of Shah Abbas I of Persia.</item>
<item>1730 – Ahmed III is forced to abdicate as the Ottoman sultan.</item>
<item>1791 – First session of the French Legislative Assembly.</item>
<item>1800 – Via the Third Treaty of San Ildefonso, Spain cedes Louisiana to France, which would sell the land to the United States thirty months later.</item>
<item>1814 – Opening of the Congress of Vienna, intended to redraw Europe\'s political map after the defeat of Napoleon the previous spring.</item>
<item>1829 – South African College is founded in Cape Town, South Africa. It will later separate into the University of Cape Town and the South African College Schools.</item>
<item>1832 – Texian political delegates convene to petition for changes in the governance of Mexican Texas.</item>
<item>1843 – The News of the World tabloid begins publication in London.</item>
<item>1861 – Mrs Beeton\'s Book of Household Management is published, going on to sell 60,000 copies in its first year and remaining in print until the present day</item>
<item>1887 – Balochistan is conquered by the British Empire.</item>
<item>1890 – Yosemite National Park is established by the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1891 – Stanford University opens its doors in California.</item>
<item>1898 – The Vienna University of Economics and Business Administration is founded under the name k.u.k. Exportakademie.</item>
<item>1903 – The Boston Americans play the Pittsburgh Pirates in the first game of the modern World Series.</item>
<item>1908 – Ford Model T automobiles are offered for sale at a price of US$825.</item>
<item>1918 – Sayid Abdullah becomes the last Khan of Khiva.</item>
<item>1928 – The Soviet Union introduces its first five–year plan.</item>
<item>1931 – The George Washington Bridge linking New Jersey and New York opens.</item>
<item>1931 – Clara Campoamor persuades the Constituent Cortes to enfranchise women in Spain\'s new constitution.</item>
<item>1936 – Francisco Franco is named head of the Nationalist government of Spain.</item>
<item>1938 – Germany annexes the Sudetenland.</item>
<item>1940 – The Pennsylvania Turnpike, often considered the first superhighway in the United States, opens to traffic.</item>
<item>1946 – The Daegu October Incident occurs in Allied–occupied Korea.</item>
<item>1946 – Mensa International is founded.</item>
<item>1947 – The North American F–86 Sabre flies for the first time.</item>
<item>1949 – The first National Day of the People\'s Republic of China is held.</item>
<item>1953 – Andhra State is formed, consisting of a Telugu–speaking area carved out of India\'s Madras State.</item>
<item>1953 – A Mutual Defense Treaty Between the United States and the Republic of Korea is concluded in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1955 – The Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region is established.</item>
<item>1957 – First appearance of In God we trust on U.S. paper currency.</item>
<item>1958 – The National Advisory Committee for Aeronautics is replaced by NASA.</item>
<item>1960 – Nigeria gains independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1961 – The United States Defense Intelligence Agency is formed, becoming the country\'s first centralized military intelligence organization.</item>
<item>1961 – East and West Cameroon merge to form the Federal Republic of Cameroon.</item>
<item>1964 – The Free Speech Movement is launched on the campus of the University of California, Berkeley.</item>
<item>1964 – Japanese Shinkansen (\"bullet trains\") begin high–speed rail service from Tokyo to Osaka.</item>
<item>1966 – West Coast Airlines Flight 956 crashes with no survivors in Oregon. This accident marks the first loss of a DC–9.</item>
<item>1968 – Guyana nationalizes the British Guiana Broadcasting Service, which would eventually become part of the National Communications Network, Guyana.</item>
<item>1969 – Concorde breaks the sound barrier for the first time.</item>
<item>1971 – Walt Disney World opens near Orlando, Florida.</item>
<item>1971 – The first practical CT scanner is used to diagnose a patient.</item>
<item>1975 – Muhammad Ali defeats Joe Frazier in a boxing match in Manila, Philippines.</item>
<item>1978 – Tuvalu gains independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1979 – Pope John Paul II begins his first pastoral visit to the United States.</item>
<item>1979 – The MTR, the rapid transit railway system in Hong Kong, opens.</item>
<item>1982 – Helmut Kohl replaces Helmut Schmidt as Chancellor of Germany through a constructive vote of no confidence.</item>
<item>1982 – Epcot opens at Walt Disney World in Florida.</item>
<item>1982 – Sony launches the model CDP–101 compact disk player.</item>
<item>1989 – Denmark introduces the world\'s first legal same–sex registered partnerships.</item>
<item>1992 – Cartoon Network launches.</item>
<item>1994 – Palau enters a Compact of Free Association with the United States.</item>
<item>2009 – The Supreme Court of the United Kingdom takes over the judicial functions of the House of Lords.</item>
<item>2017 – An independence referendum, declared illegal by the Constitutional Court of Spain, takes place in Catalonia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>