<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_14">
<item>1770 – James Bruce discovers what he believes to be the source of the Nile.</item>
<item>1851 – Moby–Dick, a novel by Herman Melville, is published in the USA.</item>
<item>1886 – Friedrich Soennecken first developed the hole puncher, a type of office tool capable of punching small holes in paper.</item>
<item>1889 – Pioneering female journalist Nellie Bly (aka Elizabeth Cochrane) begins a successful attempt to travel around the world in less than 80 days. She completes the trip in 72 days.</item>
<item>1910 – Aviator Eugene Burton Ely performs the first takeoff from a ship in Hampton Roads, Virginia. He took off from a makeshift deck on the USS Birmingham in a Curtiss pusher.</item>
<item>1918 – Czechoslovakia becomes a republic.</item>
<item>1921 – Foundation of the Communist Party of Spain.</item>
<item>1922 – The British Broadcasting Company begins radio service in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1938 – The Lions Gate Bridge, connecting Vancouver to the North Shore region, opens to traffic.</item>
<item>1952 – The first regular UK Singles Chart published by the New Musical Express.</item>
<item>1960 – Ruby Bridges becomes the first black child to attend an all–white elementary school in Louisiana.</item>
<item>1967 – American physicist Theodore Maiman is given a patent for his ruby laser systems, the world\'s first laser.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: NASA launches Apollo 12, the second crewed mission to the surface of the Moon.</item>
<item>1970 – Soviet Union enters ICAO, making Russian the fourth official language of organization.</item>
<item>1971 – Mariner 9 enters orbit around Mars.</item>
<item>1973 – In the United Kingdom, Princess Anne marries Captain Mark Phillips, in Westminster Abbey.</item>
<item>1973 – The Athens Polytechnic uprising, a massive demonstration of popular rejection of the Greek military junta of 1967–74, begins.</item>
<item>1975 – With the signing of the Madrid Accords, Spain abandons Western Sahara.</item>
<item>1977 – During a British House of Commons debate, Labour MP Tam Dalyell poses what would become known as the West Lothian question, referring to issues related to devolution in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1978 – France conducts the Aphrodite nuclear test as 25th in the group of 29, 1975–78 French nuclear tests.</item>
<item>1982 – Lech Wałęsa, the leader of Poland\'s outlawed Solidarity movement, is released after eleven months of internment near the Soviet border.</item>
<item>1984 – Zamboanga City mayor Cesar Climaco, a prominent critic of the government of Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos, is assassinated in his home city.</item>
<item>1990 – After German reunification, the Federal Republic of Germany and Poland sign a treaty confirming the Oder–Neisse line as the border between Germany and Poland.</item>
<item>1991 – American and British authorities announce indictments against two Libyan intelligence officials in connection with the downing of the Pan Am Flight 103.</item>
<item>1991 – Cambodian Prince Norodom Sihanouk returns to Phnom Penh after thirteen years of exile.</item>
<item>1995 – A budget standoff between Democrats and Republicans in the U.S. Congress forces the federal government to temporarily close national parks and museums and to run most government offices with skeleton staffs.</item>
<item>2003 – Astronomers Michael E. Brown, Chad Trujillo, and David L. Rabinowitz discover 90377 Sedna, a Trans–Neptunian object.</item>
<item>2008 – The first G–20 economic summit opens in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>2012 – Israel launches a major military operation in the Gaza Strip, as hostilities with Hamas escalate.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>