<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_19">
<item>461 – Libius Severus is declared emperor of the Western Roman Empire. The real power is in the hands of the magister militum Ricimer.</item>
<item>1493 – Christopher Columbus goes ashore on an island he first saw the day before. He names it San Juan Bautista (later renamed Puerto Rico).</item>
<item>1802 – The Garinagu arrive at British Honduras (Present day Belize)</item>
<item>1847 – The second Canadian railway line, the Montreal and Lachine Railroad, is opened.</item>
<item>1881 – A meteorite lands near the village of Grossliebenthal, southwest of Odessa, Ukraine.</item>
<item>1916 – Samuel Goldwyn and Edgar Selwyn establish Goldwyn Pictures.</item>
<item>1942 – Mutesa II is crowned the 35th and last Kabaka (king) of Buganda, prior to the restoration of the kingdom in 1993.</item>
<item>1946 – Afghanistan, Iceland and Sweden join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1950 – US General Dwight D. Eisenhower becomes Supreme Commander of NATO–Europe.</item>
<item>1952 – Greek Field Marshal Alexander Papagos becomes the 152nd Prime Minister of Greece.</item>
<item>1954 – Télé Monte Carlo, Europe\'s oldest private television channel, is launched by Prince Rainier III.</item>
<item>1955 – National Review publishes its first issue.</item>
<item>1959 – The Ford Motor Company announces the discontinuation of the unpopular Edsel.</item>
<item>1967 – The establishment of TVB, the first wireless commercial television station in Hong Kong.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: Apollo 12 astronauts Pete Conrad and Alan Bean land at Oceanus Procellarum (the \"Ocean of Storms\") and become the third and fourth humans to walk on the Moon.</item>
<item>1969 – Association football player Pelé scores his 1,000th goal.</item>
<item>1985 – Pennzoil wins a US$10.53 billion judgment against Texaco, in the largest civil verdict in the history of the United States, stemming from Texaco executing a contract to buy Getty Oil after Pennzoil had entered into an unsigned, yet still binding, buyout contract with Getty.</item>
<item>1985 – Police in Baling, Malaysia, lay siege to houses occupied by an Islamic sect of about 400 people led by Ibrahim Mahmud.</item>
<item>1994 – In the United Kingdom, the first National Lottery draw is held. A £1 ticket gave a one–in–14–million chance of correctly guessing the winning six out of 49 numbers.</item>
<item>1996 – Lt. Gen. Maurice Baril of Canada arrives in Africa to lead a multi–national policing force in Zaire.</item>
<item>1998 – Lewinsky scandal: The United States House of Representatives Judiciary Committee begins impeachment hearings against U.S. President Bill Clinton.</item>
<item>1998 – Vincent van Gogh\'s Portrait of the Artist Without Beard sells at auction for US$71.5 million.</item>
<item>1999 – Shenzhou 1: The People\'s Republic of China launches its first Shenzhou spacecraft.</item>
<item>2004 – The Malice at the Palace: The worst brawl in NBA history, Ron Artest suspended 86 games (rest of season), Stephen Jackson suspended 30 games.</item>
<item>2006 – Nintendo’s first video game console with motion control, the Wii, is released.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>