<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_22">
<item>1307 – Pope Clement V issues the papal bull Pastoralis Praeeminentiae which instructed all Christian monarchs in Europe to arrest all Templars and seize their assets.</item>
<item>1574 – Spanish navigator Juan Fernández discovers islands now known as the Juan Fernández Islands off Chile.</item>
<item>1635 – Dutch colonial forces on Taiwan launch a pacification campaign against native villages, resulting in Dutch control of the middle and south of the island.</item>
<item>1837 – Canadian journalist and politician William Lyon Mackenzie calls for a rebellion against the United Kingdom in his essay \"To the People of Upper Canada\", published in his newspaper The Constitution.</item>
<item>1869 – In Dumbarton, Scotland, the clipper Cutty Sark is launched and is one of the last clippers ever built, and the only one still surviving today.</item>
<item>1908 – The Congress of Manastir establishes the Albanian alphabet.</item>
<item>1928 – The premier performance of Ravel\'s Boléro takes place in Paris.</item>
<item>1931 – Al–Mina\'a SC is founded in Iraq.</item>
<item>1935 – The China Clipper inaugurates the first commercial transpacific air service, connecting Alameda, California with Manila.</item>
<item>1943 – Lebanon gains independence from France.</item>
<item>1954 – The Humane Society of the United States is founded.</item>
<item>1956 – The Summer Olympics officially known as the games of the XVI Olympiad were opened in Melbourne, Australia.</item>
<item>1963 – William Clay Ford Sr. buys the Detroit Lions for $4.5 million.</item>
<item>1963 – Writers Aldous Huxley and C.S. Lewis pass away.</item>
<item>1963 – The Beatles release With the Beatles.</item>
<item>1967 – UN Security Council Resolution 242 is adopted, establishing a set of the principles aimed at guiding negotiations for an Arab–Israeli peace settlement.</item>
<item>1968 – The Beatles release The Beatles (known popularly as The White Album).</item>
<item>1973 – The Italian Fascist organization Ordine Nuovo is disbanded.</item>
<item>1974 – The United Nations General Assembly grants the Palestine Liberation Organization observer status.</item>
<item>1977 – British Airways inaugurates a regular London to New York City supersonic Concorde service.</item>
<item>1986 – Mike Tyson from Brooklyn, New York becomes the youngest heavyweight champion in boxing history at age 20.</item>
<item>1987 – Two Chicago television stations are hijacked by an unknown pirate dressed as Max Headroom.</item>
<item>1990 – British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher withdraws from the Conservative Party leadership election, confirming the end of her Prime–Ministership.</item>
<item>1995 – Toy Story is released as the first feature–length film created completely using computer–generated imagery.</item>
<item>2003 – Baghdad DHL attempted shootdown incident: Shortly after takeoff, a DHL Express cargo plane is struck on the left wing by a surface–to–air missile and forced to land.</item>
<item>2003 – England defeat Australia in the 2003 Rugby World Cup Final, becoming the first side from the Northern Hemisphere to win the tournament.</item>
<item>2005 – Angela Merkel becomes the first female Chancellor of Germany.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>