<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_10">
<item>937 – Ten Kingdoms: Li Bian usurps the throne and deposes Emperor Yang Pu. The Wu State is replaced by Li (now called \"Xu Zhigao\"), who becomes the first ruler of Southern Tang.</item>
<item>1202 – Fourth Crusade: Despite letters from Pope Innocent III forbidding it and threatening excommunication, Catholic crusaders begin a siege of Zara (now Zadar, Croatia).</item>
<item>1766 – The last colonial governor of New Jersey, William Franklin, signs the charter of Queen\'s College (later renamed Rutgers University).</item>
<item>1775 – The United States Marine Corps is founded at Tun Tavern in Philadelphia by Samuel Nicholas.</item>
<item>1793 – A Goddess of Reason is proclaimed by the French Convention at the suggestion of Pierre Gaspard Chaumette.</item>
<item>1821 – Cry of Independence by Rufina Alfaro at La Villa de Los Santos, Panama setting into motion a revolt which led to Panama\'s independence from Spain and to it immediately becoming part of Colombia.</item>
<item>1871 – Henry Morton Stanley locates missing explorer and missionary, Dr David Livingstone in Ujiji, near Lake Tanganyika, famously greeting him with the words, \"Dr. Livingstone, I presume?\".</item>
<item>1898 – Beginning of the Wilmington insurrection of 1898, the only instance of a municipal government being overthrown in United States history.</item>
<item>1918 – The Western Union Cable Office in North Sydney, Nova Scotia, receives a top–secret coded message from Europe (that would be sent to Ottawa and Washington, D.C.) that said on November 11, 1918, all fighting would cease on land, sea and in the air.</item>
<item>1951 – With the rollout of the North American Numbering Plan, direct–dial coast–to–coast telephone service begins in the United States.</item>
<item>1958 – The Hope Diamond is donated to the Smithsonian Institution by New York diamond merchant Harry Winston.</item>
<item>1969 – National Educational Television (the predecessor to the Public Broadcasting Service) in the United States debuts Sesame Street.</item>
<item>1972 – Southern Airways Flight 49 from Birmingham, Alabama is hijacked and, at one point, is threatened with crashing into the nuclear installation at the Oak Ridge National Laboratory. After two days, the plane lands in Havana, Cuba, where the hijackers are jailed by Fidel Castro.</item>
<item>1975 – Israeli–Palestinian conflict: the United Nations General Assembly passes Resolution 3379, determining that Zionism is a form of racism.</item>
<item>1979 – A 106–car Canadian Pacific freight train carrying explosive and poisonous chemicals from Windsor, Ontario, Canada derails in Mississauga, Ontario, just west of Toronto, causing a massive explosion and the largest peacetime evacuation in Canadian history and one of the largest in North American history.</item>
<item>1983 – Bill Gates introduces Windows 1.0.</item>
<item>1989 – Longtime Bulgarian leader Todor Zhivkov is removed from office and replaced by Petar Mladenov.</item>
<item>1989 – Germans begin to tear down the Berlin Wall.</item>
<item>1995 – In Nigeria, playwright and environmental activist Ken Saro–Wiwa, along with eight others from the Movement for the Survival of the Ogoni People (Mosop), are hanged by government forces.</item>
<item>1997 – WorldCom and MCI Communications announce a $37 billion merger (the largest merger in US history at the time).</item>
<item>2006 – Sri Lankan Tamil politician Nadarajah Raviraj is assassinated in Colombo.</item>
<item>2006 – The National Museum of the Marine Corps in Quantico, Virginia is opened and dedicated by U.S. President George W. Bush, who announces that Marine Corporal Jason Dunham will posthumously receive the Medal of Honor.</item>
<item>2009 – Ships of the South and North Korean navies skirmish off Daecheong Island in the Yellow Sea.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>