<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_12">
<item>954 – The 13–year–old Lothair III is crowned at the Abbey of Saint–Remi as king of the West Frankish Kingdom.</item>
<item>1028 – Future Byzantine empress Zoe takes the throne as empress consort to Romanos III Argyros.</item>
<item>1439 – Plymouth becomes the first town incorporated by the English Parliament.</item>
<item>1555 – The Second Statute of Repeal re–establishes Roman Catholicism in England under Queen Mary I.</item>
<item>1793 – Jean Sylvain Bailly, the first Mayor of Paris, is guillotined.</item>
<item>1892 – William Heffelfinger becomes the first professional American football player on record, participating in his first paid game for the Allegheny Athletic Association.</item>
<item>1893 – Abdur Rahman Khan accepts the Durand Line as the border between Afghanistan and the British Raj.</item>
<item>1905 – Norway holds a referendum resulting in popular approval of the Storting\'s decision to authorise the government to make the offer of the throne of the newly–independent country.</item>
<item>1912 – King George I of Greece makes a triumphal entry into Thessaloniki after its liberation from 482 years of Ottoman rule.</item>
<item>1918 – Austria becomes a republic. After the proclamation, a coup attempt by the communist Red Guard was defeated by the social–democratic Volkswehr.</item>
<item>1920 – Italy and the Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes sign the Treaty of Rapallo.</item>
<item>1936 – In California, the San Francisco–Oakland Bay Bridge opens to traffic.</item>
<item>1954 – Ellis Island ceased operations.</item>
<item>1956 – Morocco, Sudan and Tunisia join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1975 – The Comoros joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1977 – France conducts the Oreste nuclear test as 14th in the group of 29, 1975–78 French nuclear tests series.</item>
<item>1980 – The NASA space probe Voyager I makes its closest approach to Saturn and takes the first images of its rings.</item>
<item>1981 – Space Shuttle program: Mission STS–2, utilizing the Space Shuttle Columbia, marks the first time a manned spacecraft is launched into space twice.</item>
<item>1982 – USSR: Yuri Andropov becomes the General Secretary of the Communist Party\'s Central Committee, succeeding Leonid I. Brezhnev.</item>
<item>1990 – Crown Prince Akihito is formally installed as Emperor Akihito of Japan, becoming the 125th Japanese monarch.</item>
<item>1990 – Tim Berners–Lee publishes a formal proposal for the World Wide Web.</item>
<item>2003 – Shanghai Transrapid sets a new world speed record (501 kilometres per hour (311 mph)) for commercial railway systems, which remains the fastest for unmodified commercial rail vehicles.</item>
<item>2011 – Silvio Berlusconi tenders his resignation as Prime Minister of Italy, effective November 16, due in large part to the European sovereign debt crisis.</item>
<item>2014 – The Philae lander, deployed from the European Space Agency\'s Rosetta probe, reaches the surface of Comet 67P/Churyumov–Gerasimenko.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>