<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_27">
<item>176 – Emperor Marcus Aurelius grants his son Commodus the rank of \"Imperator\" and makes him Supreme Commander of the Roman legions.</item>
<item>1095 – Pope Urban II declares the First Crusade at the Council of Clermont.</item>
<item>1727 – The foundation stone to the Jerusalem Church in Berlin is laid.</item>
<item>1810 – The Berners Street hoax was perpetrated by Theodore Hook in the City of Westminster, London.</item>
<item>1815 – Adoption of Constitution of the Kingdom of Poland.</item>
<item>1830 – Saint Catherine Labouré experiences a Marian apparition.</item>
<item>1839 – In Boston, Massachusetts, the American Statistical Association is founded.</item>
<item>1856 – The Coup of 1856 leads to Luxembourg\'s unilateral adoption of a new, reactionary constitution.</item>
<item>1886 – German judge Emil Hartwich sustains fatal injuries in a duel, which would become the background for Theodor Fontane\'s Effi Briest.</item>
<item>1896 – Also sprach Zarathustra by Richard Strauss is first performed.</item>
<item>1912 – Spain declares a protectorate over the north shore of Morocco.</item>
<item>1924 – In New York City, the first Macy\'s Thanksgiving Day Parade is held.</item>
<item>1940 – In Romania, the ruling Iron Guard fascist party assassinates over 60 of arrested King Carol II of Romania\'s aides and other political dissidents.</item>
<item>1954 – Alger Hiss is released from prison after serving 44 months for perjury.</item>
<item>1968 – Penny Ann Early became the first woman to play major professional basketball, for the Kentucky Colonels in an ABA game against the Los Angeles Stars.</item>
<item>1971 – The Soviet space program\'s Mars 2 orbiter releases a descent module. It malfunctions and crashes, but it is the first man–made object to reach the surface of Mars.</item>
<item>1973 – Twenty–fifth Amendment: The United States Senate votes 92–3 to confirm Gerald Ford as Vice President of the United States. (On December 6, the House will confirm him 387–35).</item>
<item>1978 – In San Francisco, city mayor George Moscone and openly gay city supervisor Harvey Milk are assassinated by former supervisor Dan White.</item>
<item>1978 – The Kurdistan Workers\' Party (PKK) is founded in the city of Riha (Urfa) in Turkey.</item>
<item>1984 – Under the Brussels Agreement signed between the governments of the United Kingdom and Spain, the former agreed to enter into discussions with Spain over Gibraltar, including sovereignty.</item>
<item>1992 – For the second time in a year, military forces try to overthrow president Carlos Andrés Pérez in Venezuela.</item>
<item>1999 – The centre–left Labour Party takes control of the New Zealand government with leader Helen Clark becoming the first elected female Prime Minister in New Zealand\'s history.</item>
<item>2001 – A hydrogen atmosphere is discovered on the extrasolar planet Osiris by the Hubble Space Telescope, the first atmosphere detected on an extrasolar planet.</item>
<item>2004 – Pope John Paul II returns the relics of Saint John Chrysostom to the Eastern Orthodox Church.</item>
<item>2006 – The House of Commons of Canada approves a motion introduced by Prime Minister Stephen Harper recognizing the Québécois as a nation within Canada.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>