<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_4">
<item>1501 – Catherine of Aragon (later Henry VIII\'s first wife) meets Arthur Tudor, Henry VIII\'s older brother – they would later marry.</item>
<item>1677 – The future Mary II of England marries William, Prince of Orange; they later jointly reign as William and Mary.</item>
<item>1737 – The Teatro di San Carlo, the oldest working opera house in Europe, is inaugurated in Naples, Italy.</item>
<item>1780 – The Rebellion of Túpac Amaru II against Spanish rule in the Viceroyalty of Peru begins.</item>
<item>1783 – Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart\'s Symphony No. 36 is performed for the first time in Linz, Austria.</item>
<item>1798 – Beginning of the Russo–Ottoman siege of Corfu.</item>
<item>1839 – Newport Rising: The last large–scale armed rebellion against authority in mainland Britain.</item>
<item>1847 – Sir James Young Simpson, a Scottish physician, discovers the anaesthetic properties of chloroform.</item>
<item>1852 – Camillo Benso, Count of Cavour, becomes the prime minister of Piedmont–Sardinia, which soon expands to become Italy.</item>
<item>1890 – City and South London Railway: London\'s first deep–level tube railway opens between King William Street and Stockwell.</item>
<item>1924 – Nellie Tayloe Ross of Wyoming becomes the first female elected as governor in the United States.</item>
<item>1952 – The United States government establishes the National Security Agency, or NSA.</item>
<item>1960 – At the Kasakela Chimpanzee Community in Tanzania, Dr Jane Goodall observes chimpanzees creating tools, the first–ever observation in non–human animals.</item>
<item>1962 – The United States concludes Operation Fishbowl, its final above–ground nuclear weapons testing series, in anticipation of the 1963 Partial Nuclear Test Ban Treaty.</item>
<item>1970 – Salvador Allende takes office as President of Chile, the first Marxist to become president of a Latin American country through open elections.</item>
<item>1973 – The Netherlands experiences the first Car–Free Sunday caused by the 1973 oil crisis. Highways are used only by cyclists and roller skaters.</item>
<item>1980 – Ronald Reagan is elected the 40th President of The United States, defeating incumbent Jimmy Carter.</item>
<item>1993 – China Airlines Flight 605, a brand–new 747–400, overruns the runway at Kai Tak Airport.</item>
<item>2002 – Chinese authorities arrest cyber–dissident He Depu for signing a pro–democracy letter to the 16th Communist Party Congress.</item>
<item>2008 – Barack Obama becomes the first person of biracial or African–American descent to be elected President of the United States.</item>
<item>2010 – Qantas Flight 32, an Airbus A380, suffers an uncontained engine failure over Indonesia shortly after taking off from Singapore, crippling the jet. The crew manage to safely return to Singapore, saving all 469 passengers and crew.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>