<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_1">
<item>365 – The Alemanni cross the Rhine and invade Gaul. Emperor Valentinian I moves to Paris to command the army and defend the Gallic cities.</item>
<item>996 – Emperor Otto III issues a deed to Gottschalk, Bishop of Freising, which is the oldest known document using the name Ostarrîchi (Austria in Old High German).</item>
<item>1141 – Empress Matilda\'s reign as \'Lady of the English\' ends with Stephen of Blois regaining the title of \'King of England\'.</item>
<item>1179 – Philip II is crowned as \'King of France\'.</item>
<item>1214 – The port city of Sinope surrenders to the Seljuq Turks.</item>
<item>1503 – Pope Julius II is elected.</item>
<item>1512 – The ceiling of the Sistine Chapel, painted by Michelangelo, is exhibited to the public for the first time.</item>
<item>1520 – The Strait of Magellan, the passage immediately south of mainland South America connecting the Pacific and the Atlantic Oceans, is first discovered and navigated by European explorer Ferdinand Magellan during the first recorded circumnavigation voyage.</item>
<item>1555 – French Huguenots establish the France Antarctique colony in present–day Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</item>
<item>1570 – The All Saints\' Flood devastates the Dutch coast.</item>
<item>1604 – William Shakespeare\'s tragedy Othello is performed for the first time, at Whitehall Palace in London.</item>
<item>1611 – Shakespeare\'s play The Tempest is performed for the first time, at Whitehall Palace in London.</item>
<item>1612 – During the Time of Troubles, Polish troops are expelled from Moscow\'s Kitay–gorod by Russian troops under the command of Dmitry Pozharsky (22 October O.S.) .</item>
<item>1683 – The British Crown colony of New York is subdivided into 12 counties.</item>
<item>1765 – The British Parliament enacts the Stamp Act on the Thirteen Colonies in order to help pay for British military operations in North America.</item>
<item>1800 – John Adams becomes the first President of the United States to live in the Executive Mansion (later renamed the White House).</item>
<item>1848 – In Boston, Massachusetts, the first medical school for women, Boston Female Medical School (which later merged with the Boston University School of Medicine), opens.</item>
<item>1870 – In the United States, the Weather Bureau (later renamed the National Weather Service) makes its first official meteorological forecast.</item>
<item>1884 – The Gaelic Athletic Association is set up in Hayes\'s Hotel in Thurles, County Tipperary.</item>
<item>1894 – Buffalo Bill, 15 of his Indians, and Annie Oakley were filmed by Thomas Edison in his Black Maria Studio in West Orange, New Jersey.</item>
<item>1896 – A picture showing the bare breasts of a woman appears in National Geographic magazine for the first time.</item>
<item>1897 – The first Library of Congress building opens its doors to the public; the library had previously been housed in the Congressional Reading Room in the U.S. Capitol.</item>
<item>1901 – Sigma Phi Epsilon, the largest national male collegiate fraternity, is established at Richmond College, in Richmond, Virginia.</item>
<item>1916 – In Russia, Pavel Milyukov delivers in the State Duma the famous \"stupidity or treason\" speech, precipitating the downfall of the government of Boris Stürmer.</item>
<item>1918 – Western Ukraine separates from Austria–Hungary.</item>
<item>1920 – American fishing schooner Esperanto defeats the Canadian fishing schooner Delawana in the First International Fishing Schooner Championship Races in Halifax, Nova Scotia.</item>
<item>1922 – Abolition of the Ottoman sultanate: The last sultan of the Ottoman Empire, Mehmed VI, abdicates.</item>
<item>1928 – The Law on the Adoption and Implementation of the Turkish Alphabet, replaces the Arabic alphabet with the Latin alphabet.</item>
<item>1941 – American photographer Ansel Adams takes a picture of a moonrise over the town of Hernandez, New Mexico that would become one of the most famous images in the history of photography.</item>
<item>1945 – The official North Korean newspaper, Rodong Sinmun, is first published under the name Chongro.</item>
<item>1948 – Athenagoras I, Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople, is enthroned.</item>
<item>1950 – Pope Pius XII claims papal infallibility when he formally defines the dogma of the Assumption of Mary.</item>
<item>1952 – Nuclear weapons testing: The United States successfully detonates Ivy Mike, the first thermonuclear device, at the Eniwetok atoll. The explosion had a yield of ten megatons TNT equivalent.</item>
<item>1956 – The Indian states Kerala, Andhra Pradesh, and Mysore are formally created under the States Reorganisation Act; Kanyakumari district is joined to Tamil Nadu from Kerala.</item>
<item>1957 – The Mackinac Bridge, the world\'s longest suspension bridge between anchorages at the time, opens to traffic connecting Michigan\'s upper and lower peninsulas.</item>
<item>1960 – While campaigning for President of the United States, John F. Kennedy announces his idea of the Peace Corps.</item>
<item>1963 – The Arecibo Observatory in Arecibo, Puerto Rico, with the largest radio telescope ever constructed, officially opens.</item>
<item>1963 – The 1963 South Vietnamese coup begins</item>
<item>1968 – The Motion Picture Association of America\'s film rating system is officially introduced, originating with the ratings G, M, R, and X.</item>
<item>1973 – Watergate scandal: Leon Jaworski is appointed as the new Watergate Special Prosecutor.</item>
<item>1973 – The Indian state of Mysore is renamed as Karnataka to represent all the regions within Karunadu.</item>
<item>1979 – In Bolivia, Colonel Alberto Natusch executes a bloody coup d\'état against the constitutional government of Wálter Guevara.</item>
<item>1981 – Antigua and Barbuda gains independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1982 – Honda becomes the first Asian automobile company to produce cars in the United States with the opening of its factory in Marysville, Ohio; a Honda Accord is the first car produced there.</item>
<item>1987 – British Rail Class 43 (HST) hits the record speed of 238 km/h for rail vehicles with on–board fuel to generate electricity for traction motors.</item>
<item>1993 – The Maastricht Treaty takes effect, formally establishing the European Union.</item>
<item>2000 – The Republic of Serbia and Montenegro joins the United Nations.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>