<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_24">
<item>380 – Theodosius I makes his adventus, or formal entry, into Constantinople.</item>
<item>1190 – Conrad of Montferrat becomes King of Jerusalem upon his marriage to Isabella I of Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1227 – Polish Prince Leszek the White is assassinated at an assembly of Piast dukes at Gąsawa.</item>
<item>1248 – In the middle of the night a mass on the north side of Mont Granier suddenly collapsed, in one of the largest historical rockslope failures known in Europe.</item>
<item>1359 – Peter I of Cyprus ascends to the throne of Cyprus after his father, Hugh IV of Cyprus abdicates.</item>
<item>1750 – Tarabai, regent of the Maratha Empire, imprisons Rajaram II for refusing to remove Balaji Baji Rao from the post of peshwa.</item>
<item>1832 – South Carolina passes the Ordinance of Nullification, declaring that the Tariffs of 1832 and 1838 were null and void in the state, beginning the Nullification Crisis.</item>
<item>1835 – The Texas Provincial Government authorizes the creation of a horse–mounted police force called the Texas Rangers (which is now the Texas Ranger Division of the Texas Department of Public Safety).</item>
<item>1850 – Danish troops defeat a Schleswig–Holstein force in the town of Lottorf, Schleswig–Holstein.</item>
<item>1859 – Charles Darwin publishes On the Origin of Species.</item>
<item>1877 – Anna Sewell\'s animal welfare novel Black Beauty is published.</item>
<item>1906 – A 13–6 victory by the Massillon Tigers over their rivals, the Canton Bulldogs, for the \"Ohio League\" Championship, leads to accusations that the championship series was fixed and results in the first major scandal in professional American football.</item>
<item>1932 – In Washington, D.C., the FBI Scientific Crime Detection Laboratory (better known as the FBI Crime Lab) officially opens.</item>
<item>1935 – The Senegalese Socialist Party holds its second congress.</item>
<item>1962 – The influential British satirical television programme That Was the Week That Was is first broadcast.</item>
<item>1965 – Joseph–Désiré Mobutu seizes power in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and becomes President; he rules the country (which he renames Zaire in 1971) for over 30 years, until being overthrown by rebels in 1997.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: The Apollo 12 command module splashes down safely in the Pacific Ocean, ending the second manned mission to land on the Moon.</item>
<item>1971 – During a severe thunderstorm over Washington state, a hijacker calling himself Dan Cooper (aka D. B. Cooper) parachutes from a Northwest Orient Airlines plane with $200,000 in ransom money. He has never been found.</item>
<item>1973 – A national speed limit is imposed on the Autobahn in Germany because of the 1973 oil crisis. The speed limit lasts only four months.</item>
<item>1974 – Donald Johanson and Tom Gray discover the 40% complete Australopithecus afarensis skeleton, nicknamed \"Lucy\" (after The Beatles song \"Lucy in the Sky with Diamonds\"), in the Awash Valley of Ethiopia\'s Afar Depression.</item>
<item>2013 – Iran signs an interim agreement with the P5+1 countries, limiting its nuclear program in exchange for reduced sanctions.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>