<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_20">
<item>284 – Diocletian is chosen as Roman emperor.</item>
<item>762 – During the An Shi Rebellion, the Tang dynasty, with the help of Huihe tribe, recaptures Luoyang from the rebels.</item>
<item>1194 – Palermo is conquered by Henry VI, Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1789 – New Jersey becomes the first U.S. state to ratify the Bill of Rights.</item>
<item>1805 – Beethoven\'s only opera, Fidelio, premieres in Vienna.</item>
<item>1947 – The Princess Elizabeth marries Lieutenant Philip Mountbatten, who becomes the Duke of Edinburgh, at Westminster Abbey in London.</item>
<item>1959 – The Declaration of the Rights of the Child is adopted by the United Nations.</item>
<item>1962 – Cuban Missile Crisis ends: In response to the Soviet Union agreeing to remove its missiles from Cuba, U.S. President John F. Kennedy ends the quarantine of the Caribbean nation.</item>
<item>1969 – Occupation of Alcatraz: Native American activists seize control of Alcatraz Island until being ousted by the U.S. Government on June 11, 1971.</item>
<item>1974 – The United States Department of Justice files its final anti–trust suit against AT&amp;T Corporation. This suit later leads to the breakup of AT&amp;T and its Bell System.</item>
<item>1980 – Lake Peigneur drains into an underlying salt deposit. A misplaced Texaco oil probe had been drilled into the Diamond Crystal Salt Mine, causing water to flow down into the mine, eroding the edges of the hole.</item>
<item>1985 – Microsoft Windows 1.0 is released.</item>
<item>1991 – An Azerbaijani MI–8 helicopter carrying 19 peacekeeping mission team with officials and journalists from Russia, Kazakhstan and Azerbaijan is shot down by Armenian military forces in Khojavend District of Azerbaijan.</item>
<item>1993 – Savings and loan crisis: The United States Senate Ethics Committee issues a stern censure of California senator Alan Cranston for his \"dealings\" with savings–and–loan executive Charles Keating.</item>
<item>1998 – The first module of the International Space Station, Zarya, is launched.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>