<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_3">
<item>644 – Umar ibn al–Khattab, the second Muslim caliph, is assassinated by a Persian slave in Medina.</item>
<item>1333 – The River Arno flooding causing massive damage in Florence as recorded by the Florentine chronicler Giovanni Villani.</item>
<item>1468 – Liège is sacked by Charles I of Burgundy\'s troops.</item>
<item>1492 – Peace of Etaples between Henry VII of England and Charles VIII of France.</item>
<item>1493 – Christopher Columbus first sights the island of Dominica in the Caribbean Sea.</item>
<item>1534 – English Parliament passes the first Act of Supremacy, making King Henry VIII head of the Anglican Church, supplanting the pope and the Roman Catholic Church.</item>
<item>1592 – The city of San Luis Potosí is founded.</item>
<item>1783 – The American Continental Army is disbanded.</item>
<item>1789 – The first District Court established by the United States Constitution opens in New York City.</item>
<item>1793 – French playwright, journalist and feminist Olympe de Gouges is guillotined.</item>
<item>1817 – The Bank of Montreal, Canada\'s oldest chartered bank, opens in Montreal.</item>
<item>1848 – A greatly revised Dutch constitution, drafted by Johan Rudolph Thorbecke, severely limiting the powers of the Dutch monarchy, and strengthening the powers of parliament and ministers, is proclaimed.</item>
<item>1868 – John Willis Menard (R–Louisiana) was the first African American elected to the United States Congress. Because of an electoral challenge, he was never seated.</item>
<item>1881 – The Mapuche uprising of 1881 begins in Chile.</item>
<item>1883 – American Old West: Self–described \"Black Bart the poet\" gets away with his last stagecoach robbery, but leaves a clue that eventually leads to his capture.</item>
<item>1898 – France withdraws its troops from Fashoda (now in Sudan), ending the Fashoda Incident.</item>
<item>1903 – With the encouragement of the United States, Panama separates from Colombia.</item>
<item>1911 – Chevrolet officially enters the automobile market in competition with the Ford Model T.</item>
<item>1918 – Austria–Hungary enters into the Armistice of Villa Giusti with the Allies, and the Habsburg–ruled empire dissolves.</item>
<item>1930 – Getúlio Vargas becomes Head of the Provisional Government in Brazil after a bloodless coup on October 24.</item>
<item>1932 – Panagis Tsaldaris becomes the 142nd Prime Minister of Greece.</item>
<item>1935 – George II of Greece regains his throne through a popular, though possibly fixed, plebiscite.</item>
<item>1936 – Franklin D. Roosevelt is re–elected President of the United States.</item>
<item>1946 – The Constitution of Japan is adopted through Emperor\'s assent.</item>
<item>1957 – Sputnik program: The Soviet Union launches Sputnik 2. On board is the first animal to enter orbit, a dog named Laika.</item>
<item>1964 – Lyndon B. Johnson is elected to a full term, winning 61% of the vote and 44 states, while Washington D.C. residents are able to vote in a presidential election for the first time, casting the majority of their votes for Lyndon Johnson.</item>
<item>1978 – Dominica gains its independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1986 – The Federated States of Micronesia gain independence from the United States of America.</item>
<item>1988 – Sri Lankan Tamil mercenaries try to overthrow the Maldivian government. At President Maumoon Abdul Gayoom\'s request, the Indian military suppresses the coup attempt within 24 hours.</item>
<item>1997 – The United States of America imposes economic sanctions against Sudan in response to its human rights abuses of its own citizens and its material and political assistance to Islamic extremist groups across the Middle East and Eastern Africa.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>