<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_18">
<item>326 – The old St. Peter\'s Basilica is consecrated.</item>
<item>401 – The Visigoths, led by king Alaric I, cross the Alps and invade northern Italy.</item>
<item>1095 – The Council of Clermont begins: called by Pope Urban II, it led to the First Crusade to the Holy Land.</item>
<item>1105 – Maginulfo is elected the Antipope as Sylvester IV.</item>
<item>1180 – Phillip II becomes king of France.</item>
<item>1210 – Pope Innocent III excommunicates Holy Roman Emperor Otto IV.</item>
<item>1282 – Pope Martin IV excommunicates King Peter III of Aragon.</item>
<item>1302 – Pope Boniface VIII issues the Papal bull Unam sanctam, claiming spiritual supremacy for the papacy.</item>
<item>1493 – Christopher Columbus first sights the island now known as Puerto Rico.</item>
<item>1494 – French King Charles VIII occupies Florence, Italy.</item>
<item>1601 – Tiryaki Hasan Pasha, an Ottoman provincial governor, routs the Habsburg forces commanded by Ferdinand the Archduke of Austria during the Siege of Nagykanizsa.</item>
<item>1626 – The new St Peter\'s Basilica is consecrated.</item>
<item>1730 – The future Frederick II (known as Frederick the Great), King of Prussia, is granted a royal pardon and released from confinement.</item>
<item>1760 – The rebuilt debtors\' prison, at the Castellania in Valletta, receives the first prisoners.</item>
<item>1865 – Mark Twain\'s short story \"The Celebrated Jumping Frog of Calaveras County\" is published in the New York Saturday Press.</item>
<item>1872 – Susan B. Anthony and 14 other women are arrested for illegal voting in the United States presidential election of 1872.</item>
<item>1883 – American and Canadian railroads institute five standard continental time zones, ending the confusion of thousands of local times.</item>
<item>1901 – Britain and the United States sign the Hay–Pauncefote Treaty, which nullifies the Clayton–Bulwer Treaty and withdraws British objections to an American–controlled canal in Panama.</item>
<item>1903 – The Hay–Bunau–Varilla Treaty is signed by the United States and Panama, giving the United States exclusive rights over the Panama Canal Zone.</item>
<item>1905 – Prince Carl of Denmark becomes King Haakon VII of Norway.</item>
<item>1918 – Latvia declares its independence from Russia.</item>
<item>1928 – Release of the animated short Steamboat Willie, the first fully synchronized sound cartoon, directed by Walt Disney and Ub Iwerks, featuring the third appearances of cartoon characters Mickey Mouse and Minnie Mouse. This is considered by the Disney corporation to be Mickey\'s birthday.</item>
<item>1944 – The Popular Socialist Youth is founded in Cuba.</item>
<item>1961 – United States President John F. Kennedy sends 18,000 military advisors to South Vietnam.</item>
<item>1963 – The first push–button telephone goes into service.</item>
<item>1970 – U.S. President Richard Nixon asks the U.S. Congress for $155 million in supplemental aid for the Cambodian government.</item>
<item>1971 – Oman declares its independence from United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1991 – After an 87–day siege, the Croatian city of Vukovar capitulates to the besieging Yugoslav People\'s Army and allied Serb paramilitary forces.</item>
<item>1993 – In the United States, the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) is approved by the House of Representatives.</item>
<item>1993 – In South Africa, 21 political parties approve a new constitution, expanding voting rights and ending white minority rule.</item>
<item>1996 – A fire occurs on a train traveling through the Channel Tunnel from France to England causing several injuries and damaging approximately 500 metres (1,600 ft) of tunnel.</item>
<item>2002 – Iraq disarmament crisis: United Nations weapons inspectors led by Hans Blix arrive in Iraq.</item>
<item>2003 – In the United Kingdom, the Local Government Act 2003, repealing Section 28, becomes effective.</item>
<item>2003 – The Massachusetts Supreme Judicial Court rules 4–3 in Goodridge v. Department of Public Health that the state\'s ban on same–sex marriage is unconstitutional and gives the state legislature 180 days to change the law making Massachusetts the first state in the United States to grant marriage rights to same–sex couples.</item>
<item>2012 – Pope Tawadros II of Alexandria becomes the 118th Pope of the Coptic Orthodox Church of Alexandria.</item>
<item>2013 – NASA launches the MAVEN probe to Mars.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>