<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_29">
<item>1394 – The Korean king Yi Seong–gye, founder of the Joseon dynasty, moves the capital from Kaesŏng to Hanyang, today known as Seoul.</item>
<item>1549 – The papal conclave of 1549–50 begins.</item>
<item>1729 – Natchez Indians massacre 138 Frenchmen, 35 French women, and 56 children at Fort Rosalie, near the site of modern–day Natchez, Mississippi.</item>
<item>1777 – San Jose, California, is founded as Pueblo de San José de Guadalupe by José Joaquín Moraga. It is the first civilian settlement, or pueblo, in Alta California.</item>
<item>1830 – November Uprising: An armed rebellion against Russia\'s rule in Poland begins.</item>
<item>1847 – The Sonderbund is defeated by the joint forces of other Swiss cantons under General Guillaume–Henri Dufour.</item>
<item>1850 – The treaty, Punctation of Olmütz, is signed in Olomouc. Prussia capitulates to Austria, which will take over the leadership of the German Confederation.</item>
<item>1877 – Thomas Edison demonstrates his phonograph for the first time.</item>
<item>1899 – FC Barcelona is founded by Catalan, Spanish and Englishmen. It later develops into one of Spanish football\'s most iconic and strongest teams.</item>
<item>1902 – The Pittsburgh Stars defeated the Philadelphia Athletics, 11–0 to win the first championship associated with an American national professional football league.</item>
<item>1929 – U.S. Admiral Richard E. Byrd leads the first expedition to fly over the South Pole.</item>
<item>1945 – The Federal People\'s Republic of Yugoslavia is declared.</item>
<item>1947 – Partition Plan: The United Nations General Assembly approves a plan for the partition of Palestine.</item>
<item>1961 – Project Mercury: Mercury–Atlas 5 Mission: Enos, a chimpanzee, is launched into space. The spacecraft orbits the Earth twice and splashes down off the coast of Puerto Rico.</item>
<item>1972 – Atari releases Pong, the first commercially successful video game.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>