<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_26">
<item>783 – The Asturian queen Adosinda is held at a monastery to prevent her kin from retaking the throne from Mauregatus.</item>
<item>1476 – Vlad the Impaler defeats Basarab Laiota with the help of Stephen the Great and Stephen V Báthory and becomes the ruler of Wallachia for the third time.</item>
<item>1778 – In the Hawaiian Islands, Captain James Cook becomes the first European to visit Maui.</item>
<item>1789 – A national Thanksgiving Day is observed in the United States as proclaimed by President George Washington at the request of Congress.</item>
<item>1805 – Official opening of Thomas Telford\'s Pontcysyllte Aqueduct.</item>
<item>1825 – At Union College in Schenectady, New York, a group of college students form the Kappa Alpha Society, the first college social fraternity.</item>
<item>1842 – The University of Notre Dame is founded.</item>
<item>1863 – United States President Abraham Lincoln proclaims November 26 as a national Thanksgiving Day, to be celebrated annually on the final Thursday of November. Following the Franksgiving controversy from 1939 to 1941, it has been observed on the fourth Thursday in 1942 and subsequent years.</item>
<item>1917 – The Manchester Guardian publishes the 1916 secret Sykes–Picot Agreement between the United Kingdom and France.</item>
<item>1918 – The Montenegran Podgorica Assembly votes for a \"union of the people\", declaring assimilation into the Kingdom of Serbia.</item>
<item>1922 – The Toll of the Sea debuts as the first general release film to use two–tone Technicolor. (The Gulf Between was the first film to do so, but it was not widely distributed.)</item>
<item>1942 – Casablanca, the movie starring Humphrey Bogart and Ingrid Bergman, premieres in New York City</item>
<item>1949 – The Constituent Assembly of India adopts the constitution presented by Dr. B. R. Ambedkar.</item>
<item>1965 – At the Hammaguir launch facility in the Algerian Sahara, France launches a Diamant–A rocket with its first satellite, Asterix–1, on board.</item>
<item>1970 – In Basse–Terre, Guadeloupe, 1.5 inches (38.1 mm) of rain fall in a minute, the heaviest rainfall ever recorded.</item>
<item>1976 – \"Anarchy in the U.K.\", the debut single of the Sex Pistols, is released, heralding the arrival of punk rock</item>
<item>1977 – An unidentified hijacker named Vrillon, claiming to be the representative of the \"Ashtar Galactic Command\", takes over Britain\'s Southern Television for six minutes, starting at 5:12 pm.</item>
<item>1983 – Brink\'s–Mat robbery: In London, 6,800 gold bars worth nearly £26 million are stolen from the Brink\'s–Mat vault at Heathrow Airport.</item>
<item>1986 – Iran–Contra affair: U.S. President Ronald Reagan announces the members of what will become known as the Tower Commission.</item>
<item>1990 – The Delta II rocket makes its maiden flight.</item>
<item>1991 – National Assembly of Azerbaijan abolishes the autonomous status of Nagorno–Karabakh Autonomous Oblast of Azerbaijan and renames several cities back to their original names.</item>
<item>1998 – Tony Blair becomes the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom to address the Oireachtas, the parliament of the Republic of Ireland.</item>
<item>2000 – George W. Bush is certified the winner of Florida\'s electoral votes by Katherine Harris, going on to win the United States presidential election, despite losing in the national popular vote.</item>
<item>2003 – The Concorde makes its final flight, over Bristol, England.</item>
<item>2011 – The Mars Science Laboratory launches to Mars with the Curiosity Rover.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>