<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_25">
<item>571 BC – Servius Tullius, king of Rome, celebrates a triumph for his victory over the Etruscans.</item>
<item>1120 – The White Ship sinks in the English Channel, drowning William Adelin, son and heir of Henry I of England.</item>
<item>1487 – Elizabeth of York is crowned Queen of England. The new consort of King Henry VII travelled by barge from Greenwich to the Tower of London, whence she processed the day before the ceremony to the royal palace, and on to Westminster Abbey for her coronation, which was conducted by John Morton, Archbishop of Canterbury.</item>
<item>1491 – The siege of Granada, the last Moorish stronghold in Spain, ends with the Treaty of Granada.</item>
<item>1510 – Portuguese conquest of Goa: Portuguese naval forces under the command of Afonso de Albuquerque, and local mercenaries working for privateer Timoji, seize Goa from the Bijapur Sultanate, resulting in 451 years of Portuguese colonial rule.</item>
<item>1678 – Trunajaya rebellion: After a long and logistically challenging march, the allied Mataram and Dutch troops successfully assaulted the rebel stronghold of Kediri.</item>
<item>1755 – King Ferdinand VI of Spain grants royal protection to the Beaterio de la Compañia de Jesus, now known as the Congregation of the Religious of the Virgin Mary.</item>
<item>1795 – Partitions of Poland: Stanisław August Poniatowski, the last king of independent Poland, is forced to abdicate and is exiled to Russia.</item>
<item>1826 – The Greek frigate Hellas arrives in Nafplion to become the first flagship of the Hellenic Navy.</item>
<item>1874 – The United States Greenback Party is established as a political party consisting primarily of farmers affected by the Panic of 1873.</item>
<item>1905 – Prince Carl of Denmark arrives in Norway to become King Haakon VII of Norway.</item>
<item>1915 – Albert Einstein presents the field equations of general relativity to the Prussian Academy of Sciences.</item>
<item>1918 – Vojvodina, formerly Austro–Hungarian crown land, proclaims its secession from Austria–Hungary to join the Kingdom of Serbia.</item>
<item>1947 – Red Scare: The \"Hollywood Ten\" are blacklisted by Hollywood movie studios.</item>
<item>1947 – New Zealand ratifies the Statute of Westminster and thus becomes independent of legislative control by the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1958 – French Sudan gains autonomy as a self–governing member of the French Community.</item>
<item>1960 – The Mirabal sisters of the Dominican Republic are assassinated.</item>
<item>1963 – President John F. Kennedy is buried at Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington County, Virginia, across the Potomac River from Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1963 – Lee Harvey Oswald is buried in Fort Worth, Texas.</item>
<item>1966 – First television link between Australia and the UK.</item>
<item>1970 – In Japan, author Yukio Mishima and one compatriot commit ritualistic seppuku after an unsuccessful coup attempt.</item>
<item>1975 – Suriname gains independence from the Netherlands.</item>
<item>1981 – Pope John Paul II appoints Joseph Cardinal Ratzinger (the future Pope Benedict XVI) Prefect of the Congregation for the Doctrine of the Faith.</item>
<item>1984 – Thirty–six top musicians gather in a Notting Hill studio and record Band Aid\'s \"Do They Know It\'s Christmas?\" in order to raise money for famine relief in Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1986 – Iran–Contra affair: U.S. Attorney General Edwin Meese announces that profits from covert weapons sales to Iran were illegally diverted to the anti–communist Contra rebels in Nicaragua.</item>
<item>1986 – The King Fahd Causeway is officially opened in the Persian Gulf.</item>
<item>1992 – The Federal Assembly of Czechoslovakia votes to split the country into the Czech Republic and Slovakia, with effect from January 1, 1993.</item>
<item>1999 – A 5–year–old Cuban boy, Elian Gonzalez, is rescued by fishermen while floating in an inner tube off the Florida coast.</item>
<item>2009 – Jeddah floods: Freak rains swamp the city of Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, during an ongoing Hajj pilgrimage. Three thousand cars are swept away and 122 people perish in the torrents, with 350 others missing.</item>
<item>2015 – Pope Francis makes his first official visit to Africa.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>