<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_7">
<item>335 – Athanasius is banished to Trier, on charge that he prevented a grain fleet from sailing to Constantinople.</item>
<item>680 – The Sixth Ecumenical Council commences in Constantinople.</item>
<item>921 – Treaty of Bonn: The Frankish kings Charles the Simple and Henry the Fowler sign a peace treaty or \'pact of friendship\' (amicitia), to recognize their borders along the Rhine.</item>
<item>1492 – The Ensisheim meteorite, the oldest meteorite with a known date of impact, strikes the Earth around noon in a wheat field outside the village of Ensisheim, Alsace, France.</item>
<item>1619 – Elizabeth Stuart is crowned Queen of Bohemia.</item>
<item>1665 – The London Gazette, the oldest surviving journal, is first published.</item>
<item>1775 – John Murray, the Royal Governor of the Colony of Virginia, starts the first mass emancipation of slaves in North America by issuing Lord Dunmore\'s Offer of Emancipation, which offers freedom to slaves who abandoned their colonial masters to fight with Murray and the British.</item>
<item>1786 – The oldest musical organization in the United States is founded as the Stoughton Musical Society.</item>
<item>1861 – The first Melbourne Cup horse race is held in Melbourne, Australia.</item>
<item>1874 – A cartoon by Thomas Nast in Harper\'s Weekly, is considered the first important use of an elephant as a symbol for the United States Republican Party.</item>
<item>1885 – The completion of Canada\'s first transcontinental railway is symbolized by the Last Spike ceremony at Craigellachie, British Columbia.</item>
<item>1893 – Women\'s suffrage: Women in the U.S. state of Colorado are granted the right to vote, the second state to do so.</item>
<item>1900 – The People\'s Party is founded in Cuba.</item>
<item>1910 – The first air freight shipment (from Dayton, Ohio, to Columbus, Ohio) is undertaken by the Wright brothers and department store owner Max Moorehouse.</item>
<item>1912 – The Deutsche Opernhaus (now Deutsche Oper Berlin) opens in the Berlin neighborhood of Charlottenburg, with a production of Beethoven\'s Fidelio.</item>
<item>1914 – The first issue of The New Republic is published.</item>
<item>1914 – The German colony of Kiaochow Bay and its centre at Tsingtao are captured by Japanese forces.</item>
<item>1916 – Jeannette Rankin is the first woman elected to the United States Congress.</item>
<item>1918 – Kurt Eisner overthrows the Wittelsbach dynasty in the Kingdom of Bavaria.</item>
<item>1920 – Patriarch Tikhon of Moscow issues a decree that leads to the formation of the Russian Orthodox Church Outside Russia.</item>
<item>1929 – In New York City, the Museum of Modern Art opens to the public.</item>
<item>1933 – Fiorello H. La Guardia is elected the 99th mayor of New York City.</item>
<item>1940 – In Tacoma, Washington, the original Tacoma Narrows Bridge collapses in a windstorm, a mere four months after the bridge\'s completion.</item>
<item>1944 – Franklin D. Roosevelt elected for a record fourth term as President of the United States of America.</item>
<item>1949 – The first oil was taken in Oil Rocks (Neft Daşları), oldest offshore oil platform.</item>
<item>1954 – In the US, Armistice Day becomes Veterans Day.</item>
<item>1956 – Suez Crisis: The United Nations General Assembly adopts a resolution calling for the United Kingdom, France and Israel to immediately withdraw their troops from Egypt.</item>
<item>1967 – Carl B. Stokes is elected as Mayor of Cleveland, Ohio, becoming the first African American mayor of a major American city.</item>
<item>1967 – US President Lyndon B. Johnson signs the Public Broadcasting Act of 1967, establishing the Corporation for Public Broadcasting.</item>
<item>1972 – US President Richard Nixon is re–elected President.</item>
<item>1987 – In Tunisia, president Habib Bourguiba is overthrown and replaced by Prime Minister Zine El Abidine Ben Ali.</item>
<item>1989 – Douglas Wilder wins the governor\'s seat in Virginia, becoming the first elected African American governor in the United States.</item>
<item>1989 – David Dinkins becomes the first African American to be elected Mayor of New York City.</item>
<item>1989 – East German Prime Minister Willi Stoph, along with his entire cabinet, is forced to resign after huge anti–government protests.</item>
<item>1990 – Mary Robinson becomes the first woman to be elected President of the Republic of Ireland.</item>
<item>1991 – Magic Johnson announces that he is infected with HIV and retires from the NBA.</item>
<item>1994 – WXYC, the student radio station of the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, provides the world\'s first internet radio broadcast.</item>
<item>1996 – NASA launches the Mars Global Surveyor.</item>
<item>2000 – Controversial US presidential election that is later resolved in the Bush v. Gore Supreme Court Case, electing George W. Bush the 43rd President of the United States.</item>
<item>2000 – The U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration discovers one of the country\'s largest LSD labs inside a converted military missile silo in Wamego, Kansas.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>