<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_21">
<item>164 BC – Judas Maccabeus, son of Mattathias of the Hasmonean family, restores the Temple in Jerusalem. This event is commemorated each year by the festival of Hanukkah.</item>
<item>235 – Pope Anterus succeeds Pontian as the nineteenth pope. During the persecutions of emperor Maximinus Thrax he is martyred.</item>
<item>1009 – Lý Công Uẩn is enthroned as emperor of Đại Cồ Việt, founding the Lý dynasty.</item>
<item>1386 – Timur of Samarkand captures and sacks the Georgian capital of Tbilisi, taking King Bagrat V of Georgia captive.</item>
<item>1620 – Plymouth Colony settlers sign the Mayflower Compact (November 11, O.S.)</item>
<item>1676 – The Danish astronomer Ole Rømer presents the first quantitative measurements of the speed of light.</item>
<item>1783 – In Paris, Jean–François Pilâtre de Rozier and François Laurent d\'Arlandes, make the first untethered hot air balloon flight.</item>
<item>1789 – North Carolina ratifies the United States Constitution and is admitted as the 12th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1832 – Wabash College is founded in Crawfordsville, Indiana.</item>
<item>1877 – Thomas Edison announces his invention of the phonograph, a machine that can record and play sound.</item>
<item>1902 – The Philadelphia Football Athletics defeated the Kanaweola Athletic Club of Elmira, New York, 39–0, in the first ever professional American football night game.</item>
<item>1905 – Albert Einstein\'s paper that leads to the mass–energy equivalence formula, E = mc², is published in the journal Annalen der Physik.</item>
<item>1918 – The Flag of Estonia, previously used by pro–independence activists, is formally adopted as the national flag of the Republic of Estonia.</item>
<item>1922 – Rebecca Latimer Felton of Georgia takes the oath of office, becoming the first female United States Senator.</item>
<item>1942 – The completion of the Alaska Highway (also known as the Alcan Highway) is celebrated (however, the highway is not usable by standard road vehicles until 1943).</item>
<item>1945 – The United Auto Workers strike 92 General Motors plants in 50 cities to back up worker demands for a 30–percent raise.</item>
<item>1953 – The Natural History Museum, London announces that the \"Piltdown Man\" skull, initially believed to be one of the most important fossilized hominid skulls ever found, is a hoax.</item>
<item>1961 – The \"La Ronde\" opens in Honolulu, first revolving restaurant in the United States.</item>
<item>1964 – The Verrazano–Narrows Bridge opens to traffic. At the time it is the world\'s longest bridge span.</item>
<item>1964 – Second Vatican Council: The third session of the Roman Catholic Church\'s ecumenical council closes.</item>
<item>1969 – U.S. President Richard Nixon and Japanese Premier Eisaku Satō agree on the return of Okinawa to Japanese control in 1972. The U.S. retains rights to bases on the island, but these are to be nuclear–free.</item>
<item>1969 – The first permanent ARPANET link is established between UCLA and SRI.</item>
<item>1972 – Voters in South Korea overwhelmingly approve a new constitution, giving legitimacy to Park Chung–hee and the Fourth Republic.</item>
<item>1977 – Minister of Internal Affairs Allan Highet announces that the national anthems of New Zealand shall be the traditional anthem \"God Save the Queen\" and \"God Defend New Zealand\".</item>
<item>1986 – National Security Council member Oliver North and his secretary start to shred documents allegedly implicating them in the Iran–Contra affair.</item>
<item>2002 – NATO invites Bulgaria, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Romania, Slovakia and Slovenia to become members.</item>
<item>2004 – The second round of the Ukrainian presidential election is held, giving rise to massive protests and controversy over the election\'s integrity.</item>
<item>2004 – The Paris Club agrees to write off 80% (up to $100 billion) of Iraq\'s external debt.</item>
<item>2013 – Massive protests start in Ukraine after President Viktor Yanukovych suspended signing the Ukraine–European Union Association Agreement.</item>
<item>2017 – Robert Mugabe formally resigns as President of Zimbabwe, after some thirty–seven years in office.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>