<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_17">
<item>794 – Japanese Emperor Kanmu changes his residence from Nara to Kyoto.</item>
<item>887 – Emperor Charles the Fat is deposed by the Frankish magnates in an assembly at Frankfurt. His nephew Arnulf of Carinthia is elected as king of the East Frankish Kingdom.</item>
<item>1292 – John Balliol becomes King of Scotland.</item>
<item>1405 – Sharif ul–Hāshim establishes the Sultanate of Sulu.</item>
<item>1511 – Henry VIII of England concludes the Treaty of Westminster, a pledge of mutual aid against the French, with Ferdinand II of Aragon.</item>
<item>1603 – English explorer, writer and courtier Sir Walter Raleigh goes on trial for treason.</item>
<item>1777 – Articles of Confederation (United States) are submitted to the states for ratification.</item>
<item>1800 – The United States Congress holds its first session in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1811 – José Miguel Carrera, Chilean founding father, is sworn in as President of the executive Junta of the government of Chile.</item>
<item>1820 – Captain Nathaniel Palmer becomes the first American to see Antarctica. (The Palmer Peninsula is later named after him.)</item>
<item>1831 – Ecuador and Venezuela are separated from Gran Colombia.</item>
<item>1839 – Oberto, Giuseppe Verdi\'s first opera, opens at the Teatro alla Scala in Milan, Italy.</item>
<item>1856 – American Old West: On the Sonoita River in present–day southern Arizona, the United States Army establishes Fort Buchanan in order to help control new land acquired in the Gadsden Purchase.</item>
<item>1858 – Modified Julian Day zero.</item>
<item>1858 – The city of Denver, Colorado is founded.</item>
<item>1869 – In Egypt, the Suez Canal, linking the Mediterranean Sea with the Red Sea, is inaugurated.</item>
<item>1871 – The National Rifle Association is granted a charter by the state of New York.</item>
<item>1876 – Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky\'s \"Slavonic March\" is given its premiere performance in Moscow, Russia.</item>
<item>1896 – The Western Pennsylvania Hockey League, which later became the first ice hockey league to openly trade and hire players, began play at Pittsburgh\'s Schenley Park Casino.</item>
<item>1903 – The Russian Social Democratic Labour Party splits into two groups: The Bolsheviks (Russian for \"majority\") and Mensheviks (Russian for \"minority\").</item>
<item>1933 – The United States recognizes the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1947 – The Screen Actors Guild implements an anti–Communist loyalty oath.</item>
<item>1950 – Lhamo Dondrub is officially named the 14th Dalai Lama.</item>
<item>1950 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 89 relating to the Palestine Question is adopted.</item>
<item>1953 – The remaining human inhabitants of the Blasket Islands, Kerry, Ireland, are evacuated to the mainland.</item>
<item>1957 – Vickers Viscount G–AOHP of British European Airways crashes at Ballerup after the failure of three engines on approach to Copenhagen Airport. The cause is a malfunction of the anti–icing system on the aircraft.</item>
<item>1962 – President John F. Kennedy dedicates Washington Dulles International Airport, serving the Washington, D.C., region.</item>
<item>1968 – British European Airways introduces the BAC One–Eleven into commercial service.</item>
<item>1970 – Luna programme: The Soviet Union lands Lunokhod 1 on Mare Imbrium (Sea of Rains) on the Moon. This is the first roving remote–controlled robot to land on another world and is released by the orbiting Luna 17 spacecraft.</item>
<item>1973 – Watergate scandal: In Orlando, Florida, U.S. President Richard Nixon tells 400 Associated Press managing editors \"I am not a crook.\"</item>
<item>1973 – The Athens Polytechnic uprising against the military regime ends in a bloodshed in the Greek capital.</item>
<item>1979 – Brisbane Suburban Railway Electrification. The first stage from Ferny Grove to Darra is commissioned.</item>
<item>1983 – The Zapatista Army of National Liberation is founded in Mexico.</item>
<item>1990 – Fugendake, part of the Mount Unzen volcanic complex, Nagasaki Prefecture, Japan, becomes active again and erupts.</item>
<item>1993 – United States House of Representatives passes a resolution to establish the North American Free Trade Agreement.</item>
<item>1993 – In Nigeria, General Sani Abacha ousts the government of Ernest Shonekan in a military coup.</item>
<item>2000 – Alberto Fujimori is removed from office as president of Peru.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>