<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_30">
<item>977 – Emperor Otto II lifts the siege at Paris and withdraws. His rearguard is defeated while crossing the Aisne River by Frankish forces under King Lothair III.</item>
<item>1707 – The second Siege of Pensacola comes to end with the failure of the British to capture Pensacola, Florida.</item>
<item>1803 – The Balmis Expedition starts in Spain with the aim of vaccinating millions against smallpox in Spanish America and Philippines.</item>
<item>1803 – In New Orleans, Spanish representatives officially transfer the Louisiana Territory to a French representative. Just 20 days later, France transfers the same land to the United States as the Louisiana Purchase.</item>
<item>1804 – The Democratic–Republican–controlled United States Senate begins an impeachment trial of Federalist Supreme Court Justice Samuel Chase.</item>
<item>1829 – First Welland Canal opens for a trial run, five years to the day from the ground breaking.</item>
<item>1868 – A statue of King Charles XII of Sweden is inaugurated in Stockholm\'s Kungsträdgården.</item>
<item>1872 – The first–ever international football match takes place at Hamilton Crescent, Glasgow, between Scotland and England.</item>
<item>1886 – The Folies Bergère stages its first revue.</item>
<item>1916 – Costa Rica signs the Buenos Aires Convention, a copyright treaty.</item>
<item>1934 – The LNER Class A3 4472 Flying Scotsman becomes the first steam locomotive to be authenticated as reaching 100 mph.</item>
<item>1954 – In Sylacauga, Alabama, United States, the Hodges meteorite crashes through a roof and hits a woman taking an afternoon nap; this is the only documented case in the Western Hemisphere of a human being hit by a rock from space.</item>
<item>1966 – Barbados becomes independent from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1967 – South Yemen becomes independent from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1967 – The Pakistan Peoples Party is founded by Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, who becomes its first chairman.</item>
<item>1967 – Pro–Soviet communists in the Philippines establish Malayang Pagkakaisa ng Kabataan Pilipino as its new youth wing.</item>
<item>1971 – Iran seizes the Greater and Lesser Tunbs from the United Arab Emirates.</item>
<item>1979 – Pink Floyd\'s rock opera, The Wall is released.</item>
<item>1982 – Michael Jackson\'s sixth solo studio album, Thriller is released worldwide. It will become the best–selling record album in history.</item>
<item>1994 – MS Achille Lauro catches fire off the coast of Somalia.</item>
<item>1995 – Official end of Operation Desert Storm.</item>
<item>1998 – Exxon and Mobil sign a US$73.7 billion agreement to merge, thus creating ExxonMobil, the world\'s largest company.</item>
<item>1999 – In Seattle, United States, demonstrations against a World Trade Organization meeting by anti–globalization protesters catch police unprepared and force the cancellation of opening ceremonies.</item>
<item>1999 – British Aerospace and Marconi Electronic Systems merge to form BAE Systems, Europe\'s largest defense contractor and the fourth largest aerospace firm in the world.</item>
<item>2005 – John Sentamu becomes the first black archbishop in the Church of England with his enthronement as the 97th Archbishop of York.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>