<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_8">
<item>1278 – Trần Thánh Tông, the second emperor of the Trần dynasty, decides to pass the throne to his crown prince Trần Khâm and take up the post of Retired Emperor.</item>
<item>1519 – Hernán Cortés enters Tenochtitlán and Aztec ruler Moctezuma welcomes him with a great celebration.</item>
<item>1520 – Stockholm Bloodbath begins: A successful invasion of Sweden by Danish forces results in the execution of around 100 people.</item>
<item>1602 – The Bodleian Library at the University of Oxford is opened to the public.</item>
<item>1614 – Japanese daimyō Dom Justo Takayama is exiled to the Philippines by shōgun Tokugawa Ieyasu for being Christian.</item>
<item>1644 – The Shunzhi Emperor, the third emperor of the Qing dynasty, is enthroned in Beijing after the collapse of the Ming dynasty as the first Qing emperor to rule over China.</item>
<item>1837 – Mary Lyon founds Mount Holyoke Female Seminary, which later becomes Mount Holyoke College.</item>
<item>1889 – Montana is admitted as the 41st U.S. state.</item>
<item>1892 – The New Orleans general strike begins, uniting black and white American trade unionists in a successful four–day general strike action for the first time.</item>
<item>1895 – While experimenting with electricity, Wilhelm Röntgen discovers the X–ray.</item>
<item>1901 – Gospel riots: Bloody clashes take place in Athens following the translation of the Gospels into demotic Greek.</item>
<item>1933 – Great Depression: New Deal: US President Franklin D. Roosevelt unveils the Civil Works Administration, an organization designed to create jobs for more than 4 million unemployed.</item>
<item>1939 – Venlo Incident: Two British agents of SIS are captured by the Germans.</item>
<item>1965 – The British Indian Ocean Territory is created, consisting of Chagos Archipelago, Aldabra, Farquhar and Des Roches islands.</item>
<item>1966 – U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson signs into law an antitrust exemption allowing the National Football League to merge with the upstart American Football League.</item>
<item>1968 – The Vienna Convention on Road Traffic is signed to facilitate international road traffic and to increase road safety by standardising the uniform traffic rules among the signatories.</item>
<item>1972 – HBO launches its programming, with the broadcast of the 1971 movie Sometimes a Great Notion, starring Paul Newman and Henry Fonda.</item>
<item>1973 – The right ear of John Paul Getty III is delivered to a newspaper together with a ransom note, convincing his father to pay US$2.9 million.</item>
<item>1977 – Manolis Andronikos, a Greek archaeologist and professor at the Aristotle University of Thessaloniki, discovers the tomb of Philip II of Macedon at Vergina.</item>
<item>2002 – Iraq disarmament crisis: UN Security Council Resolution 1441: The United Nations Security Council unanimously approves a resolution on Iraq, forcing Saddam Hussein to disarm or face \"serious consequences\".</item>
<item>2011 – The potentially hazardous asteroid 2005 YU55 passes 0.85 lunar distances from Earth (about 324,600 kilometres or 201,700 miles), the closest known approach by an asteroid of its brightness since 2010 XC15 in 1976.</item>
<item>2016 –Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi of the BJ party led NDA government, publicly announced the withdrawal of ₹500 and ₹1000 denomination banknotes only a few hours before the implementation/imposition of diktat, i.e. from midnight, starting of November 9 (9–11 as per Indian date recordings), from the Indian economy, without popular consent, rendering 86% of Indian currency in circulation invalid.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>