<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_16">
<item>534 – Justinian I, who was an Eastern Roman (Byzantine) emperor in Constantinople, approves and publishes the second and final revision of the Codex Justinianus</item>
<item>951 – Emperor Li Jing sends a Southern Tang expeditionary force of 10,000 men under Bian Hao to conquer Chu. Li Jing removes the ruling family to his own capital in Nanjing, ending the Chu Kingdom.</item>
<item>1491 – An auto–da–fé, held in the Brasero de la Dehesa outside of Ávila, concludes the case of the Holy Child of La Guardia with the public execution of several Jewish and converso suspects.</item>
<item>1797 – The Prussian heir apparent, Frederick William, becomes King of Prussia as Frederick William III.</item>
<item>1822 – American Old West: Missouri trader William Becknell arrives in Santa Fe, New Mexico, over a route that became known as the Santa Fe Trail.</item>
<item>1852 – The English astronomer John Russell Hind discovers the asteroid 22 Kalliope.</item>
<item>1855 – David Livingstone becomes the first European to see the Victoria Falls in what is now Zambia–Zimbabwe.</item>
<item>1871 – The National Rifle Association receives its charter from New York State.</item>
<item>1904 – English engineer John Ambrose Fleming receives a patent for the thermionic valve (vacuum tube).</item>
<item>1907 – Indian Territory and Oklahoma Territory join to form Oklahoma, which is admitted as the 46th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1907 – Cunard Line\'s RMS Mauretania, sister ship of RMS Lusitania, sets sail on her maiden voyage from Liverpool, England, to New York City.</item>
<item>1914 – The Federal Reserve Bank of the United States officially opens.</item>
<item>1920 – Qantas, Australia\'s national airline, is founded as Queensland and Northern Territory Aerial Services Limited.</item>
<item>1933 – The United States and the Soviet Union establish formal diplomatic relations.</item>
<item>1938 – LSD is first synthesized by Albert Hofmann from ergotamine at the Sandoz Laboratories in Basel.</item>
<item>1945 – UNESCO is founded.</item>
<item>1969 – Richard Nixon becomes the first sitting US President to attend a regular season NFL game.</item>
<item>1973 – Skylab program: NASA launches Skylab 4 with a crew of three astronauts from Cape Canaveral, Florida for an 84–day mission.</item>
<item>1973 – U.S. President Richard Nixon signs the Trans–Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act into law, authorizing the construction of the Alaska Pipeline.</item>
<item>1974 – The Arecibo message is broadcast from the Arecibo Radio Telescope in Puerto Rico. It was aimed at the current location of the globular star cluster Messier 13 some 25,000 light years away. The message will reach empty space by the time it finally arrives since the cluster will have changed position.</item>
<item>1979 – The first line of Bucharest Metro (Line M1) is opened from Timpuri Noi to Semănătoarea in Bucharest, Romania.</item>
<item>1988 – The Supreme Soviet of the Estonian Soviet Socialist Republic declares that Estonia is \"sovereign\" but stops short of declaring independence.</item>
<item>1992 – The Hoxne Hoard is discovered by metal detectorist Eric Lawes in Hoxne, Suffolk.</item>
<item>1997 – After nearly 18 years of incarceration, the People\'s Republic of China releases Wei Jingsheng, a pro–democracy dissident, from jail for medical reasons.</item>
<item>2001 – The movie Harry Potter and the Philosopher’s Stone is released, earning $974.8 million in the box office.</item>
<item>2017 – Mauritania officially adopted the new national anthem of Mauritania as the new anthem.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>