<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_28">
<item>587 – Treaty of Andelot: King Guntram of Burgundy recognizes Childebert II as his heir.</item>
<item>936 – Shi Jingtang is enthroned as the first emperor of the Later Jin by Emperor Taizong of Liao, following a revolt against Emperor Fei of Later Tang.</item>
<item>1443 – Skanderbeg and his forces liberate Kruja in central Albania and raise the Albanian flag.</item>
<item>1520 – An expedition under the command of Ferdinand Magellan passes through the Strait of Magellan.</item>
<item>1582 – In Stratford–upon–Avon, William Shakespeare and Anne Hathaway pay a £40 bond for their marriage licence.</item>
<item>1660 – At Gresham College, twelve men, including Christopher Wren, Robert Boyle, John Wilkins, and Sir Robert Moray decide to found what is later known as the Royal Society.</item>
<item>1785 – The first Treaty of Hopewell is signed, by which the United States acknowledges Cherokee lands in what is now East Tennessee.</item>
<item>1811 – Beethoven\'s Piano Concerto No. 5 in E–flat major, Op. 73, premieres at the Gewandhaus in Leipzig.</item>
<item>1814 – The Times of London becomes the first newspaper to be produced on a steam–powered printing press, built by the German team of Koenig &amp; Bauer.</item>
<item>1821 – Panama Independence Day: Panama separates from Spain and joins Gran Colombia.</item>
<item>1843 – Ka Lā Hui (Hawaiian Independence Day): The Kingdom of Hawaii is officially recognized by the United Kingdom and France as an independent nation.</item>
<item>1893 – Women\'s suffrage in New Zealand concludes with the New Zealand general election, 1893.</item>
<item>1895 – The first American automobile race takes place over the 54 miles from Chicago\'s Jackson Park to Evanston, Illinois. Frank Duryea wins in approximately 10 hours.</item>
<item>1905 – Irish nationalist Arthur Griffith founds Sinn Féin as a political party with the main aim of establishing a dual monarchy in Ireland.</item>
<item>1912 – Albania declares its independence from the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1917 – The Estonian Provincial Assembly declares itself the sovereign power of Estonia.</item>
<item>1919 – Lady Astor is elected as a Member of the Parliament of the United Kingdom. She is the first woman to sit in the House of Commons. (Countess Markievicz, the first to be elected, refused to sit.)</item>
<item>1925 – The Grand Ole Opry begins broadcasting in Nashville, Tennessee, as the WSM Barn Dance.</item>
<item>1958 – Chad, the Republic of the Congo, and Gabon become autonomous republics within the French Community.</item>
<item>1960 – Mauritania becomes independent of France.</item>
<item>1966 – Michel Micombero overthrows the monarchy of Burundi and makes himself the first president.</item>
<item>1971 – Wasfi al–Tal, Prime Minister of Jordan, is assassinated by the Black September unit of the Palestine Liberation Organization.</item>
<item>1972 – Last executions in Paris: Claude Buffet and Roger Bontems are guillotined at La Santé Prison.</item>
<item>1975 – East Timor declares its independence from Portugal.</item>
<item>1990 – British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher resigns as leader of the Conservative Party and, therefore, as Prime Minister. She is succeeded in both positions by John Major.</item>
<item>1991 – South Ossetia declares independence from Georgia.</item>
<item>2016 – A chartered Avro RJ85 plane carrying at least 81 people, including the Chapecoense football team, crashes near Medellín, Colombia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>