<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_5">
<item>1138 – Lý Anh Tông is enthroned as emperor of Vietnam at the age of two, beginning a 37–year reign.</item>
<item>1499 – Publication of the Catholicon, written in 1464 by Jehan Lagadeuc in Tréguier; this is the first Breton dictionary as well as the first French dictionary.</item>
<item>1605 – Gunpowder Plot: Guy Fawkes is arrested.</item>
<item>1688 – William III of England lands with a Dutch fleet at Brixham.</item>
<item>1768 – Treaty of Fort Stanwix, the purpose of which is to adjust the boundary line between Indian lands and white settlements set forth in the Royal Proclamation of 1763 in the Thirteen Colonies.</item>
<item>1780 – French–American forces under Colonel LaBalme are defeated by Miami Chief Little Turtle.</item>
<item>1811 – Salvadoran priest José Matías Delgado, rings the bells of La Merced church in San Salvador, calling for insurrection and launching the 1811 Independence Movement.</item>
<item>1872 – Women\'s suffrage in the United States: In defiance of the law, suffragist Susan B. Anthony votes for the first time, and is later fined $100.</item>
<item>1895 – George B. Selden is granted the first U.S. patent for an automobile.</item>
<item>1898 – Filipinos on Negros Island revolt against Spanish rule and establish the short–lived Republic of Negros.</item>
<item>1913 – King Otto of Bavaria is deposed by his cousin, Prince Regent Ludwig, who assumes the title Ludwig III.</item>
<item>1916 – The Kingdom of Poland is proclaimed by the Act of 5th November of the emperors of Germany and Austria–Hungary.</item>
<item>1916 – The Everett massacre takes place in Everett, Washington as political differences lead to a shoot–out between the Industrial Workers of the World organizers and local police.</item>
<item>1917 – Tikhon is elected the Patriarch of Moscow and of the Russian Orthodox Church.</item>
<item>1940 – Franklin D. Roosevelt is the first and only President of the United States to be elected to a third term.</item>
<item>1968 – Richard Nixon is elected as 37th President of the United States.</item>
<item>1986 – USS Rentz, USS Reeves and USS Oldendorf visit Qingdao (Tsing Tao) China – the first US Naval visit to China since 1949.</item>
<item>2007 – China\'s first lunar satellite, Chang\'e 1, goes into orbit around the Moon.</item>
<item>2007 – Android mobile operating system is unveiled by Google.</item>
<item>2013 – India launches the Mars Orbiter Mission, its first interplanetary probe.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>