<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_13">
<item>1160 – Louis VII of France marries Adela of Champagne.</item>
<item>1851 – The Denny Party lands at Alki Point, before moving to the other side of Elliott Bay to what would become Seattle.</item>
<item>1887 – Bloody Sunday clashes in central London.</item>
<item>1927 – The Holland Tunnel opens to traffic as the first Hudson River vehicle tunnel linking New Jersey to New York City.</item>
<item>1940 – Walt Disney\'s animated musical film Fantasia is first released, on the first night of a roadshow at New York\'s Broadway Theatre.</item>
<item>1947 – The Soviet Union completes development of the AK–47, one of the first proper assault rifles.</item>
<item>1954 – Great Britain defeats France to capture the first ever Rugby League World Cup in Paris in front of around 30,000 spectators.</item>
<item>1956 – The Supreme Court of the United States declares Alabama laws requiring segregated buses illegal, thus ending the Montgomery Bus Boycott.</item>
<item>1985 – Xavier Suárez is sworn in as Miami\'s first Cuban–born mayor.</item>
<item>1986 – The Compact of Free Association becomes law, granting the Federated States of Micronesia, the Marshall Islands independence from the United States.</item>
<item>1994 – In a referendum, voters in Sweden decide to join the European Union.</item>
<item>2000 – Philippine House Speaker Manny Villar passes the articles of impeachment against Philippine President Joseph Estrada.</item>
<item>2002 – Iraq disarmament crisis: Iraq agrees to the terms of the UN Security Council Resolution 1441.</item>
<item>2002 – During the Prestige oil spill a storm burst a tank of the oil tanker MV Prestige which was not allowed to dock and sank on November 19, 2002 off the coast of Galicia, spilling 63,000 metric tons of heavy fuel oil, more than the Exxon Valdez Oil Spill.</item>
<item>2011 – Mario Monti accepted to become the 54th Prime Minister of Italy with the ouster of Silvio Berlusconi, who failed to tackle Italy\'s debt crisis.</item>
<item>2012 – A total solar eclipse occurred in parts of Australia and the South Pacific</item>
<item>2013 – Hawaii legalizes same sex marriage.</item>
<item>2013 – 4 World Trade Center officially opens.</item>
<item>2015 – WT1190F, a temporary satellite of Earth, impacts just southeast of Sri Lanka.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>