<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a11_9">
<item>694 – At the Seventeenth Council of Toledo, Egica, a king of the Visigoths of Hispania, accuses Jews of aiding Muslims, sentencing all Jews to slavery.</item>
<item>1456 – Ulrich II, Count of Celje, last ruler of the County of Cilli, is assassinated in Belgrade.</item>
<item>1620 – Pilgrims aboard the Mayflower sight land at Cape Cod, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1697 – Pope Innocent XII founds the city of Cervia.</item>
<item>1729 – Spain, France and Great Britain sign the Treaty of Seville.</item>
<item>1791 – Foundation of the Dublin Society of United Irishmen.</item>
<item>1799 – Napoleon Bonaparte leads the Coup of 18 Brumaire ending the Directory government, and becoming First Consul of the successor (Consulate Government).</item>
<item>1851 – Kentucky marshals abduct abolitionist minister Calvin Fairbank from Jeffersonville, Indiana, and take him to Kentucky to stand trial for helping a slave escape.</item>
<item>1861 – The first documented football match in Canada is played at University College, Toronto.</item>
<item>1867 – Tokugawa shogunate hands power back to the Emperor of Japan, starting the Meiji Restoration.</item>
<item>1872 – The Great Boston Fire of 1872.</item>
<item>1883 – The 90th Winnipeg Battalion of Rifles, (later the Royal Winnipeg Rifles) of the Canadian Armed Forces is founded.</item>
<item>1887 – The United States receives rights to Pearl Harbor, Hawaii.</item>
<item>1888 – The mutilated body of Mary Jane Kelly, believed to be the final victim of Jack the Ripper, is discovered in Spitalfields, London, England.</item>
<item>1906 – Theodore Roosevelt is the first sitting President of the United States to make an official trip outside the country. He did so to inspect progress on the Panama Canal.</item>
<item>1935 – The Congress of Industrial Organizations is founded in Atlantic City, New Jersey, by eight trade unions belonging to the American Federation of Labor.</item>
<item>1953 – Cambodia gains independence from France.</item>
<item>1960 – Robert McNamara is named president of Ford Motor Company, the first non–Ford to serve in that post. A month later, he resigned to join the administration of newly elected John F. Kennedy.</item>
<item>1965 – Several U.S. states and parts of Canada are hit by a series of blackouts lasting up to 13 hours in the Northeast blackout of 1965.</item>
<item>1967 – Apollo program: NASA launches the unmanned Apollo 4 test spacecraft atop the first Saturn V rocket from Cape Kennedy, Florida.</item>
<item>1967 – The first issue of Rolling Stone magazine is published.</item>
<item>1985 – Garry Kasparov, 22, of the Soviet Union becomes the youngest World Chess Champion by beating fellow Soviet Anatoly Karpov.</item>
<item>1994 – The chemical element darmstadtium is discovered.</item>
<item>1998 – A U.S. federal judge, in the largest civil settlement in American history, orders 37 U.S. brokerage houses to pay US$1.03 billion to cheated NASDAQ investors to compensate for price fixing.</item>
<item>2005 – The Venus Express mission of the European Space Agency is launched from the Baikonur Cosmodrome in Kazakhstan.</item>
<item>2007 – The German Bundestag passes the controversial data retention bill mandating storage of citizens\' telecommunications traffic data for six months without probable cause.</item>
<item>2016 – Donald Trump is declared the winner of the US Presidential Election</item>
</string-array>
</resources>