<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_26">
<item>887 – Berengar I is elected as king of Italy by the lords of Lombardy. He is crowned with the Iron Crown of Lombardy at Pavia.</item>
<item>1489 – The forces of the Catholic Monarchs, Ferdinand and Isabella, take control of Almería from the Nasrid ruler of Granada, Muhammad XIII.</item>
<item>1805 – Austria and France sign the Treaty of Pressburg.</item>
<item>1825 – Advocates of liberalism in Russia rise up against Czar Nicholas I but are suppressed in the Decembrist revolt in Saint Petersburg.</item>
<item>1860 – The first ever inter–club English association football match takes place between Hallam and Sheffield football clubs in Sheffield.</item>
<item>1862 – Four nuns serving as volunteer nurses on board USS Red Rover are the first female nurses on a U.S. Navy hospital ship.</item>
<item>1898 – Marie and Pierre Curie announce the isolation of radium.</item>
<item>1919 – Babe Ruth of the Boston Red Sox is sold to the New York Yankees by owner Harry Frazee, allegedly establishing the Curse of the Bambino superstition.</item>
<item>1941 – U.S. President Franklin D. Roosevelt signs a bill establishing the fourth Thursday in November as Thanksgiving Day in the United States.</item>
<item>1948 – Cardinal József Mindszenty is arrested in Hungary and accused of treason and conspiracy.</item>
<item>1948 – The last Soviet troops withdraw from North Korea.</item>
<item>1963 – The Beatles\' \"I Want to Hold Your Hand\" and \"I Saw Her Standing There\" are released in the United States, marking the beginning of Beatlemania on an international level.</item>
<item>1968 – The Communist Party of the Philippines is established by Jose Maria Sison, breaking away from the Partido Komunista ng Pilipinas–1930.</item>
<item>1975 – Tu–144, the world\'s first commercial supersonic aircraft, surpassing Mach 2, went into service.</item>
<item>2006 – Lúrio University is established in Nampula, Mozambique.</item>
<item>2009 – China opens the world\'s longest high–speed rail route, which links Beijing and Guangzhou.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>