<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_15">
<item>687 – Pope Sergius I is elected.</item>
<item>1025 – Constantine VIII becomes sole emperor of the Byzantine Empire, 63 years after being crowned co–emperor.</item>
<item>1167 – Sicilian Chancellor Stephen du Perche moves the royal court to Messina to prevent a rebellion.</item>
<item>1791 – The United States Bill of Rights becomes law when ratified by the Virginia General Assembly.</item>
<item>1851 – Monster Meeting, Australia – approximately, 10,000 to 15,000 diggers took place on 15 December 1851, at the Shepherd\'s Hut, Forest Creek.</item>
<item>1905 – The Pushkin House is established in Saint Petersburg, Russia, to preserve the cultural heritage of Alexander Pushkin.</item>
<item>1906 – The London Underground\'s Great Northern, Piccadilly and Brompton Railway opens.</item>
<item>1933 – The Twenty–first Amendment to the United States Constitution officially becomes effective, repealing the Eighteenth Amendment that prohibited the sale, manufacture, and transportation of alcohol.</item>
<item>1939 – Gone with the Wind (highest inflation adjusted grossing film) receives its premiere at Loew\'s Grand Theatre in Atlanta, Georgia, United States.</item>
<item>1945 – Occupation of Japan/Shinto Directive: General Douglas MacArthur orders that Shinto be abolished as the state religion of Japan.</item>
<item>1960 – Richard Pavlick is arrested for plotting to assassinate U.S. President–Elect John F. Kennedy.</item>
<item>1960 – King Mahendra of Nepal suspends the country\'s constitution, dissolves parliament, dismisses the cabinet, and imposes direct rule.</item>
<item>1965 – Project Gemini: Gemini 6A, crewed by Wally Schirra and Thomas Stafford, is launched from Cape Kennedy, Florida. Four orbits later, it achieves the first space rendezvous, with Gemini 7.</item>
<item>1970 – Soviet spacecraft Venera 7 successfully lands on Venus. It is the first successful soft landing on another planet</item>
<item>1973 – The American Psychiatric Association votes 13–0 to remove homosexuality from its official list of psychiatric disorders, the DSM–II.</item>
<item>1978 – U.S. President Jimmy Carter announces that the United States will recognize the People\'s Republic of China and sever diplomatic relations with Taiwan</item>
<item>1989 – Second Optional Protocol to the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights relating the abolition of capital punishment is adopted.</item>
<item>1993 – The Troubles: The Downing Street Declaration is issued by British Prime Minister John Major and Irish Taoiseach Albert Reynolds.</item>
<item>2000 – The third reactor at the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant is shut down.</item>
<item>2001 – The Leaning Tower of Pisa reopens after 11 years and $27,000,000 spent to stabilize it, without fixing its famous lean.</item>
<item>2005 – Introduction of the Lockheed Martin F–22 Raptor into USAF active service.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>