<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_7">
<item>574 – Byzantine Emperor Justin II retires due to recurring seizures of insanity. He abdicates the throne in favor of his general Tiberius, proclaiming him Caesar.</item>
<item>1724 – Tumult of Thorn: Religious unrest is followed by the execution of nine Protestant citizens and the mayor of Thorn (Toruń) by Polish authorities.</item>
<item>1732 – The Royal Opera House opens at Covent Garden, London, England.</item>
<item>1776 – Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de Lafayette, arranges to enter the American military as a major general.</item>
<item>1842 – First concert of the New York Philharmonic, founded by Ureli Corelli Hill.</item>
<item>1869 – American outlaw Jesse James commits his first confirmed bank robbery in Gallatin, Missouri.</item>
<item>1922 – The Parliament of Northern Ireland votes to remain a part of the United Kingdom and not unify with Southern Ireland.</item>
<item>1930 – W1XAV in Boston, Massachusetts telecasts video from the CBS radio orchestra program, The Fox Trappers. The telecast also includes the first television commercial in the United States, an advertisement for I.J. Fox Furriers, who sponsored the radio show.</item>
<item>1932 – German–born Swiss physicist Albert Einstein is granted an American visa.</item>
<item>1936 – Australian cricketer Jack Fingleton becomes the first player to score centuries in four consecutive Test innings.</item>
<item>1962 – Prince Rainier III of Monaco revises the principality\'s constitution, devolving some of his power to advisory and legislative councils.</item>
<item>1963 – Instant replay makes its debut during the Army–Navy football game in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States.</item>
<item>1965 – Pope Paul VI and Patriarch Athenagoras I simultaneously revoke mutual excommunications that had been in place since 1054.</item>
<item>1971 – Pakistan President Yahya Khan announces the formation of a coalition government with Nurul Amin as Prime Minister and Zulfikar Ali Bhutto as Deputy Prime Minister.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo 17, the last Apollo moon mission, is launched. The crew takes the photograph known as The Blue Marble as they leave the Earth.</item>
<item>1995 – The Galileo spacecraft arrives at Jupiter, a little more than six years after it was launched by Space Shuttle Atlantis during Mission STS–34.</item>
<item>1999 – A&amp;M Records, Inc. v. Napster, Inc.: The Recording Industry Association of America sues the peer–to–peer file–sharing service Napster, alleging copyright infringement.</item>
<item>2003 – The Conservative Party of Canada is officially registered, following the merger of the Canadian Alliance and the Progressive Conservative Party of Canada.</item>
<item>2015 – The JAXA probe Akatsuki successfully enters orbit around Venus five years after the first attempt.</item>
<item>2017 – Marriage Amendment Bill to recognize same–sex marriage passes in Australia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>