<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_14">
<item>1751 – The Theresian Military Academy is founded in Wiener Neustadt, Austria.</item>
<item>1780 – Founding Father Alexander Hamilton marries Elizabeth Schuyler Hamilton at the Schuyler Mansion in Albany, New York</item>
<item>1782 – The Montgolfier brothers first test fly an unmanned hot air balloon in France; it floats nearly 2 km (1.2 mi).</item>
<item>1812 – The French invasion of Russia comes to an end as the remnants of the Grande Armée are expelled from Russia.</item>
<item>1819 – Alabama becomes the 22nd U.S. state.</item>
<item>1896 – The Glasgow Underground Railway is opened by the Glasgow District Subway Company.</item>
<item>1900 – Quantum mechanics: Max Planck presents a theoretical derivation of his black–body radiation law.</item>
<item>1902 – The Commercial Pacific Cable Company lays the first Pacific telegraph cable, from San Francisco to Honolulu.</item>
<item>1903 – The Wright brothers make their first attempt to fly with the Wright Flyer at Kitty Hawk, North Carolina.</item>
<item>1909 – New South Wales Premier Charles Wade signs the Seat of Government Surrender Act 1909, formally completing the transfer of State land to the Commonwealth to create the Australian Capital Territory.</item>
<item>1911 – Roald Amundsen\'s team, comprising himself, Olav Bjaaland, Helmer Hanssen, Sverre Hassel, and Oscar Wisting, becomes the first to reach the South Pole.</item>
<item>1914 – Lisandro de la Torre and others found the Democratic Progressive Party (Partido Demócrata Progresista, PDP) at the Hotel Savoy, Buenos Aires, Argentina.</item>
<item>1918 – Friedrich Karl von Hessen, a German prince elected by the Parliament of Finland to become King Väinö I, renounces the Finnish throne.</item>
<item>1940 – Plutonium (specifically Pu–238) is first isolated at Berkeley, California.</item>
<item>1948 – Thomas T. Goldsmith Jr. and Estle Ray Mann are granted a patent for their cathode–ray tube amusement device, the earliest known interactive electronic game.</item>
<item>1955 – Albania, Austria, Bulgaria, Cambodia, Ceylon, Finland, Hungary, Ireland, Italy, Jordan, Laos, Libya, Nepal, Portugal, Romania and Spain join the United Nations through United Nations Security Council Resolution 109.</item>
<item>1958 – The 3rd Soviet Antarctic Expedition becomes the first to reach the southern pole of inaccessibility.</item>
<item>1960 – Convention against Discrimination in Education of UNESCO is adopted.</item>
<item>1962 – NASA\'s Mariner 2 becomes the first spacecraft to fly by Venus.</item>
<item>1964 – American Civil Rights Movement: Heart of Atlanta Motel v. United States: The Supreme Court of the United States rules that Congress can use the Constitution\'s Commerce Clause to fight discrimination.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo program: Eugene Cernan is the last person to walk on the moon, after he and Harrison Schmitt complete the third and final extravehicular activity (EVA) of the Apollo 17 mission.</item>
<item>1981 – Arab–Israeli conflict: Israel\'s Knesset ratifies the Golan Heights Law, extending Israeli law to the occupied Golan Heights.</item>
<item>1994 – Construction begins on the Three Gorges Dam on the Yangtze river.</item>
<item>2004 – The Millau Viaduct, the tallest bridge in the world, is formally inaugurated near Millau, France.</item>
<item>2008 – Muntadhar al–Zaidi throws his shoes at then–U.S. President George W. Bush during a press conference in Baghdad, Iraq.</item>
<item>2013 – A reported coup attempt in South Sudan leads to continued fighting and hundreds of casualties.</item>
<item>2017 – The Federal Communications Commission voted to repeal net neutrality with a 3–2 majority.</item>
<item>2017 – The Walt Disney Company announces that it would acquire 21st Century Fox, including the 20th Century Fox movie studio, for $52.4 billion.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>