<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_24">
<item>502 – Chinese emperor Xiao Yan names Xiao Tong his heir designate.</item>
<item>640 – Pope John IV is elected.</item>
<item>759 – Tang dynasty poet Du Fu departs for Chengdu, where he is hosted by fellow poet Pei Di.</item>
<item>1144 – The capital of the crusader County of Edessa falls to Imad ad–Din Zengi, the atabeg of Mosul and Aleppo.</item>
<item>1294 – Pope Boniface VIII is elected, replacing St. Celestine V, who had resigned.</item>
<item>1500 – A joint Venetian–Spanish fleet captures the Castle of St. George on the island of Cephalonia.</item>
<item>1777 – Kiritimati, also called Christmas Island, is discovered by James Cook.</item>
<item>1818 – The first performance of \"Silent Night\" takes place in the church of St. Nikolaus in Oberndorf, Austria.</item>
<item>1826 – The Eggnog Riot at the United States Military Academy begins that night, wrapping up the following morning.</item>
<item>1846 – British acquired Labuan from the Sultanate of Brunei for Great Britain.</item>
<item>1865 – Jonathan Shank and Barry Ownby form The Ku Klux Klan.</item>
<item>1871 – The Opera Aida opens in Cairo, Egypt.</item>
<item>1906 – Radio: Reginald Fessenden transmits the first radio broadcast; consisting of a poetry reading, a violin solo, and a speech.</item>
<item>1911 – Lackawanna Cut–Off railway line opens in New Jersey and Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1924 – Albania becomes a republic.</item>
<item>1951 – Libya becomes independent from Italy. Idris I is proclaimed King of Libya.</item>
<item>1968 – Apollo program: The crew of Apollo 8 enters into orbit around the Moon, becoming the first humans to do so. They performed ten lunar orbits and broadcast live TV pictures.</item>
<item>1969 – The oil company Phillips Petroleum made the first oil discovery in the Norwegian sector of North Sea.</item>
<item>1969 – Nigerian troops capture Umuahia, the Biafran capital.</item>
<item>1973 – District of Columbia Home Rule Act is passed, allowing residents of Washington, D.C. to elect their own local government.</item>
<item>1974 – Cyclone Tracy devastates Darwin, Australia.</item>
<item>1980 – Witnesses report the first of several sightings of unexplained lights near RAF Woodbridge, in Rendlesham Forest, Suffolk, England, United Kingdom, an incident called \"Britain\'s Roswell\".</item>
</string-array>
</resources>