<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_29">
<item>875 – Charles the Bald, King of the Franks, is crowned as Holy Roman Emperor Charles II.</item>
<item>1427 – The Ming army begins its withdraw from Hanoi, ending the Chinese domination of Đại Việt.</item>
<item>1835 – The Treaty of New Echota is signed, ceding all the lands of the Cherokee east of the Mississippi River to the United States.</item>
<item>1851 – The first American YMCA opens in Boston, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1874 – The military coup of Gen. Martinez Campos in Sagunto ends the failed First Spanish Republic and the monarchy is restored as Prince Alfonso is proclaimed King of Spain.</item>
<item>1911 – Mongolia gains independence from the Qing dynasty, enthroning 9th Jebtsundamba Khutughtu as Khagan of Mongolia.</item>
<item>1911 – Sun Yat–sen becomes the provisional President of the Republic of China; he formally takes office on January 1, 1912.</item>
<item>1916 – A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man, the first novel by James Joyce, was first published as a book by an American publishing house B. W. Huebschis after it had been serialized in The Egoist (1914–15).</item>
<item>1930 – Sir Muhammad Iqbal\'s presidential address in Allahabad introduces the two–nation theory and outlines a vision for the creation of Pakistan.</item>
<item>1934 – Japan renounces the Washington Naval Treaty of 1922 and the London Naval Treaty of 1930.</item>
<item>1937 – The Irish Free State is replaced by a new state called Ireland with the adoption of a new constitution.</item>
<item>1949 – KC2XAK of Bridgeport, Connecticut becomes the first Ultra high frequency (UHF) television station to operate a daily schedule.</item>
<item>1989 – Czech writer, philosopher and dissident Václav Havel is elected the first post–communist President of Czechoslovakia.</item>
<item>1992 – Fernando Collor de Mello, president of Brazil, tries to resign amidst corruption charges, but is then impeached.</item>
<item>1998 – Leaders of the Khmer Rouge apologize for the 1970s genocide in Cambodia that claimed over one million lives.</item>
<item>2006 – UK settles its Anglo–American loan, post–WWII loan debt.</item>
<item>2011 – Samoa and Tokelau skip straight to December 31 when moving from one side of the International Date Line to another.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>