<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_18">
<item>1271 – Kublai Khan renames his empire \"Yuan\" (元 yuán), officially marking the start of the Yuan dynasty of Mongolia and China.</item>
<item>1499 – Rebellion triggeres in Alpujarras in response to the forced conversions of Muslims in Spain.</item>
<item>1655 – The Whitehall Conference ends with the determination that there was no law preventing Jews from re–entering England after the Edict of Expulsion of 1290.</item>
<item>1777 – The United States celebrates its first Thanksgiving, marking the recent victory by the American rebels over British General John Burgoyne at Saratoga in October.</item>
<item>1787 – New Jersey becomes the third state to ratify the U.S. Constitution.</item>
<item>1793 – Surrender of the frigate La Lutine by French Royalists to Lord Samuel Hood; renamed HMS Lutine, she later becomes a famous treasure wreck.</item>
<item>1833 – The national anthem of the Russian Empire, \"God Save the Tsar!\", is first performed.</item>
<item>1878 – The Al–Thani family become the rulers of the state of Qatar.</item>
<item>1892 – Premiere performance of The Nutcracker by Pyotr Ilyich Tchaikovsky in Saint Petersburg, Russia.</item>
<item>1898 – Gaston de Chasseloup–Laubat sets the first officially recognized land speed record of 39.245 mph (63.159 km/h) in a Jeantaud electric car.</item>
<item>1900 – The Upper Ferntree Gully to Gembrook, Victoria Narrow–gauge (2 ft 6 in or 762 mm) Railway (now the Puffing Billy Railway) in Victoria, Australia is opened for traffic.</item>
<item>1917 – The resolution containing the language of the Eighteenth Amendment to enact Prohibition is passed by the United States Congress.</item>
<item>1932 – The Chicago Bears defeat the Portsmouth Spartans in the first NFL Championship Game.</item>
<item>1935 – The Lanka Sama Samaja Party is founded in Ceylon.</item>
<item>1958 – Project SCORE, the world\'s first communications satellite, is launched.</item>
<item>1966 – Saturn\'s moon Epimetheus is discovered by astronomer Richard Walker.</item>
<item>1973 – Soviet Soyuz Programme: Soyuz 13, crewed by cosmonauts Valentin Lebedev and Pyotr Klimuk, is launched from Baikonur in the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1999 – NASA launches into orbit the Terra platform carrying five Earth Observation instruments, including ASTER, CERES, MISR, MODIS and MOPITT.</item>
<item>2002 – California gubernatorial recall: Then Governor of California Gray Davis announces that the state would face a record budget deficit of $35 billion, roughly double the figure reported during his reelection campaign one month earlier.</item>
<item>2006 – United Arab Emirates holds its first–ever elections.</item>
<item>2015 – Kellingley Colliery, the last deep coal mine in Great Britain, closes.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>