<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_6">
<item>963 – Pope Leo VIII is appointed to the office of Protonotary and begins his papacy as antipope of Rome.</item>
<item>1060 – Béla I is crowned king of Hungary.</item>
<item>1240 – Mongol invasion of Rus\': Kiev under Daniel of Galicia and Voivode Dmytro falls to the Mongols under Batu Khan.</item>
<item>1534 – The city of Quito in Ecuador is founded by Spanish settlers led by Sebastián de Belalcázar.</item>
<item>1648 – Colonel Thomas Pride of the New Model Army purges the Long Parliament of MPs sympathetic to King Charles I of England, in order for the King\'s trial to go ahead; came to be known as \"Pride\'s Purge\".</item>
<item>1768 – The first edition of the Encyclopædia Britannica is published.</item>
<item>1790 – The U.S. Congress moves from New York City to Philadelphia.</item>
<item>1865 – Georgia ratifies 13th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution</item>
<item>1877 – The first edition of The Washington Post is published.</item>
<item>1884 – The Washington Monument in Washington, D.C., is completed.</item>
<item>1897 – London becomes the world\'s first city to host licensed taxicabs.</item>
<item>1904 – Theodore Roosevelt articulated his \"Corollary\" to the Monroe Doctrine, stating that the U.S. would intervene in the Western Hemisphere should Latin American governments prove incapable or unstable.</item>
<item>1912 – The Nefertiti Bust is discovered.</item>
<item>1917 – Finland declares independence from Russia.</item>
<item>1921 – The Anglo–Irish Treaty is signed in London by British and Irish representatives.</item>
<item>1922 – One year to the day after the signing of the Anglo–Irish Treaty, the Irish Free State comes into existence.</item>
<item>1933 – U.S. federal judge John M. Woolsey rules that James Joyce\'s novel Ulysses is not obscene.</item>
<item>1947 – The Everglades National Park in Florida is dedicated.</item>
<item>1953 – Vladimir Nabokov completes his controversial novel Lolita.</item>
<item>1967 – Adrian Kantrowitz performs the first human heart transplant in the United States.</item>
<item>1973 – The Twenty–fifth Amendment: The United States House of Representatives votes 387 to 35 to confirm Gerald Ford as Vice President of the United States. (On November 27, the Senate confirmed him 92 to 3.)</item>
<item>1977 – South Africa grants independence to Bophuthatswana, although it is not recognized by any other country.</item>
<item>1978 – Spain ratifies the Spanish Constitution of 1978 in a referendum.</item>
<item>1998 – in Venezuela, Hugo Chávez is victorious in presidential elections.</item>
<item>2006 – NASA reveals photographs taken by Mars Global Surveyor suggesting the presence of liquid water on Mars.</item>
<item>2015 – Venezuelan elections are held. For the first time in 17 years the United Socialist Party of Venezuela loses its majority in parliament.</item>
<item>2017 – Donald Trump\'s administration officially announces the recognition of Jerusalem as capital of Israel.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>