<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_30">
<item>1066 – Granada massacre: A Muslim mob storms the royal palace in Granada, crucifies Jewish vizier Joseph ibn Naghrela and massacres most of the Jewish population of the city.</item>
<item>1816 – The Treaty of St. Louis between the United States and the united Ottawa, Ojibwa, and Potawatomi Indian tribes is proclaimed.</item>
<item>1825 – The Treaty of St. Louis between the United States and the Shawnee Nation is proclaimed.</item>
<item>1853 – Gadsden Purchase: The United States buys land from Mexico to facilitate railroad building in the Southwest.</item>
<item>1896 – Canadian ice hockey player Ernie McLea scores the first hat–trick in Stanley Cup play, and the Cup–winning goal as the Montreal Victorias defeat the Winnipeg Victorias 6–5.</item>
<item>1897 – The British Colony of Natal annexes Zululand.</item>
<item>1905 – Former Idaho Governor Frank Steunenberg is assassinated at the front gate of his home in Caldwell.</item>
<item>1906 – The All–India Muslim League is founded in Dacca, East Bengal, British India (later Dhaka, Bangladesh).</item>
<item>1916 – The last coronation in Hungary is performed for King Charles IV and Queen Zita.</item>
<item>1919 – Lincoln\'s Inn in London, England, UK admits its first female bar student.</item>
<item>1922 – The Union of Soviet Socialist Republics is formed.</item>
<item>1927 – The Ginza Line, the first subway line in Asia, opens in Tokyo, Japan.</item>
<item>1936 – The United Auto Workers union stages its first sitdown strike.</item>
<item>1943 – Subhas Chandra Bose raises the flag of Indian independence at Port Blair.</item>
<item>1944 – King George II of Greece declares a regency, leaving the throne vacant.</item>
<item>1965 – Ferdinand Marcos becomes President of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1993 – Israel establishes diplomatic relations with Vatican City and also upgrades to full diplomatic relations with Ireland.</item>
<item>1996 – Proposed budget cuts by Benjamin Netanyahu spark protests from 250,000 workers who shut down services across Israel.</item>
<item>2005 – Tropical Storm Zeta forms in the open Atlantic Ocean, tying the record for the latest tropical cyclone ever to form in the North Atlantic basin.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>