<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_23">
<item>558 – Chlothar I is crowned King of the Franks.</item>
<item>583 – Maya queen Yohl Ik\'nal is crowned ruler of Palenque.</item>
<item>1783 – George Washington resigns as commander–in–chief of the Continental Army at the Maryland State House in Annapolis, Maryland.</item>
<item>1815 – The novel Emma by Jane Austen is first published.</item>
<item>1876 – First day of the Constantinople Conference which resulted in agreement for political reforms in the Balkans.</item>
<item>1893 – The opera Hansel and Gretel by Engelbert Humperdinck is first performed.</item>
<item>1913 – The Federal Reserve Act is signed into law by President Woodrow Wilson, creating the Federal Reserve System.</item>
<item>1919 – Sex Disqualification (Removal) Act 1919 becomes law in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1936 – Colombia becomes a signatory to the Buenos Aires copyright treaty.</item>
<item>1947 – The transistor is first demonstrated at Bell Laboratories.</item>
<item>1954 – First successful kidney transplant is performed by J. Hartwell Harrison and Joseph Murray.</item>
<item>1968 – The 82 sailors from the USS Pueblo are released after eleven months of internment in North Korea.</item>
<item>1970 – The North Tower of the World Trade Center in Manhattan, New York, New York is topped out at 1,368 feet (417 m), making it the tallest building in the world.</item>
<item>1970 – The Democratic Republic of the Congo officially becomes a one–party state.</item>
<item>1990 – History of Slovenia: In a referendum, 88.5% of Slovenia\'s overall electorate vote for independence from Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>2002 – A U.S. MQ–1 Predator is shot down by an Iraqi MiG–25 in the first combat engagement between a drone and conventional aircraft.</item>
<item>2007 – An agreement is made for the Kingdom of Nepal to be abolished and the country to become a federal republic with the Prime Minister becoming head of state.</item>
<item>2016 – The United Nations Security Council adopts Resolution 2334 condemning \"Israeli settlements in Palestinian territories occupied since 1967\".</item>
</string-array>
</resources>