<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_2">
<item>1244 – Pope Innocent IV arrives at Lyon for the First Council of Lyon</item>
<item>1409 – The University of Leipzig opens.</item>
<item>1697 – St Paul\'s Cathedral is consecrated in London.</item>
<item>1763 – Dedication of the Touro Synagogue, in Newport, Rhode Island, the first synagogue in what will become the United States.</item>
<item>1804 – At Notre Dame Cathedral in Paris, Napoleon Bonaparte crowns himself Emperor of the French.</item>
<item>1845 – Manifest destiny: In a State of the Union message, U.S. President James K. Polk proposes that the United States should aggressively expand into the West.</item>
<item>1848 – Franz Joseph I becomes Emperor of Austria.</item>
<item>1851 – French President Louis–Napoléon Bonaparte overthrows the Second Republic.</item>
<item>1852 – Louis–Napoléon Bonaparte becomes Emperor of the French as Napoleon III.</item>
<item>1865 – Alabama ratifies 13th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, followed by North Carolina then Georgia, and U.S. slaves were legally free within 2 weeks</item>
<item>1867 – At Tremont Temple in Boston, British author Charles Dickens gives his first public reading in the United States.</item>
<item>1908 – Puyi becomes Emperor of China at the age of two.</item>
<item>1927 – Following 19 years of Ford Model T production, the Ford Motor Company unveils the Ford Model A as its new automobile.</item>
<item>1930 – Great Depression: In a State of the Union message, U.S. President Herbert Hoover proposes a $150 million (equivalent to $2,197,000,000 in 2017) public works program to help generate jobs and stimulate the economy.</item>
<item>1939 – New York City\'s LaGuardia Airport opens.</item>
<item>1947 – Jerusalem Riots of 1947: Riots break out in Jerusalem in response to the United Nations Partition Plan for Palestine.</item>
<item>1949 – Convention for the Suppression of the Traffic in Persons and of the Exploitation of the Prostitution of Others is adopted.</item>
<item>1954 – The Sino–American Mutual Defense Treaty, between the United States and Taiwan, is signed in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1957 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 126 relating to Kashmir conflict is adopted.</item>
<item>1961 – In a nationally broadcast speech, Cuban leader Fidel Castro declares that he is a Marxist–Leninist and that Cuba is going to adopt Communism.</item>
<item>1970 – The United States Environmental Protection Agency begins operations.</item>
<item>1971 – Abu Dhabi, Ajman, Fujairah, Sharjah, Dubai, and Umm al–Quwain form the United Arab Emirates.</item>
<item>1976 – Fidel Castro becomes President of Cuba, replacing Osvaldo Dorticós Torrado.</item>
<item>1982 – At the University of Utah, Barney Clark becomes the first person to receive a permanent artificial heart.</item>
<item>1989 – The Communist insurgency in Malaysia was ended by peace agreement signed and ratified by the Malayan Communist Party (MCP), and the Malaysian – Thailand governments.</item>
<item>1991 – Canada and Poland become the first nations to recognize the independence of Ukraine from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1993 – Space Shuttle program: STS–61: NASA launches the Space Shuttle Endeavour on a mission to repair the Hubble Space Telescope.</item>
<item>1999 – The United Kingdom devolves political power in Northern Ireland to the Northern Ireland Executive following the Good Friday Agreement.</item>
<item>2001 – Enron files for Chapter 11 bankruptcy.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>