<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_13">
<item>1294 – Saint Celestine V resigns the papacy after only five months to return to his previous life as an ascetic hermit.</item>
<item>1545 – Council of Trent begins.</item>
<item>1577 – Sir Francis Drake sets sail from Plymouth, England, on his round–the–world voyage.</item>
<item>1636 – The Massachusetts Bay Colony organizes three militia regiments to defend the colony against the Pequot Indians. This organization is recognized today as the founding of the National Guard of the United States.</item>
<item>1642 – Abel Tasman is the first recorded European to sight New Zealand.</item>
<item>1769 – Dartmouth College is founded by the Reverend Eleazar Wheelock, with a royal charter from King George III, on land donated by Royal governor John Wentworth.</item>
<item>1818 – Cyril VI of Constantinople resigns from his position as Ecumenical Patriarch.</item>
<item>1928 – George Gershwin\'s An American in Paris is first performed.</item>
<item>1938 – The Holocaust: The Neuengamme concentration camp opens in the Bergedorf district of Hamburg, Germany.</item>
<item>1949 – The Knesset votes to move the capital of Israel to Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1951 – WFMT begins broadcasting in Chicago.</item>
<item>1959 – Archbishop Makarios III becomes the first President of Cyprus.</item>
<item>1960 – While Emperor Haile Selassie of Ethiopia visits Brazil, his Imperial Bodyguard seizes the capital and proclaims him deposed and his son, Crown Prince Asfa Wossen, Emperor.</item>
<item>1962 – NASA launches Relay 1, the first active repeater communications satellite in orbit.</item>
<item>1967 – Constantine II of Greece attempts an unsuccessful counter–coup against the Regime of the Colonels.</item>
<item>1968 – Brazilian President Artur da Costa e Silva issues AI–5 (Institutional Act No. 5), enabling government by decree and suspending habeas corpus.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo program: Eugene Cernan and Harrison Schmitt begin the third and final extra–vehicular activity (EVA) or \"Moonwalk\" of Apollo 17. To date they are the last humans to set foot on the Moon.</item>
<item>1974 – Malta becomes a republic within the Commonwealth of Nations.</item>
<item>1981 – General Wojciech Jaruzelski declares martial law in Poland, largely due to the actions by Solidarity.</item>
<item>1988 – PLO Chairman Yasser Arafat gives a speech at a UN General Assembly meeting in Geneva, Switzerland, after United States authorities refused to grant him a visa to visit UN headquarters in New York.</item>
<item>2002 – European Union enlargement: The EU announces that Cyprus, the Czech Republic, Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Poland, Slovakia, and Slovenia will become members from May 1, 2004.</item>
<item>2006 – Convention on the Rights of Persons with Disabilities is adopted by United Nations General Assembly.</item>
<item>2007 – Treaty of Lisbon is signed by members states of European Union.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>