<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_28">
<item>418 – Pope Boniface I is elected.</item>
<item>457 – Majorian is acclaimed emperor of the Western Roman Empire and recognized by Emperor Leo I the Thracian.</item>
<item>484 – Alaric II succeeds his father Euric and becomes king of the Visigoths. He establishes his capital at Aire–sur–l\'Adour (Southern Gaul).</item>
<item>1065 – Westminster Abbey is consecrated in England.</item>
<item>1308 – The reign of Emperor Hanazono of Japan begins.</item>
<item>1768 – King Taksin\'s coronation achieved through conquest as a king of Thailand and established Thonburi as a capital.</item>
<item>1795 – Construction of Yonge Street, formerly recognized as the longest street in the world, begins in York, Upper Canada (present–day Toronto).</item>
<item>1832 – John C. Calhoun becomes the first Vice President of the United States to resign.</item>
<item>1836 – South Australia and Adelaide are founded.</item>
<item>1836 – Spain recognizes the independence of Mexico with the signing of the Santa María–Calatrava Treaty.</item>
<item>1846 – Iowa is admitted as the 29th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1867 – United States claims Midway Atoll, the first territory annexed outside Continental limits.</item>
<item>1895 – Wilhelm Röntgen publishes a paper detailing his discovery of a new type of radiation, which later will be known as x–rays.</item>
<item>1902 – The Syracuse Athletic Club defeated the New York Philadelphians, 5–0, in the first indoor professional football game, which was held at Madison Square Garden.</item>
<item>1912 – The first municipally owned streetcars take to the streets in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1918 – Constance Markievicz, while detained in Holloway prison, became the first woman to be elected MP to the British House of Commons.</item>
<item>1943 – Soviet authorities launch operation Operation Ulussy, beginning the deportation of the Kalmyk nation to Siberia and Central Asia.</item>
<item>1944 – Maurice Richard becomes the first player to score eight points in one game of NHL ice hockey.</item>
<item>1948 – The DC–3 airliner NC16002 disappears 50 miles south of Miami.</item>
<item>1956 – Chin Peng, David Marshall and Tunku Abdul Rahman meet in Baling, Malaya to try and resolve the Malayan Emergency situation.</item>
<item>1973 – The Endangered Species Act is passed in the United States.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>