<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_11">
<item>361 – Julian enters Constantinople as sole Emperor of the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1789 – The University of North Carolina is chartered by the North Carolina General Assembly.</item>
<item>1815 – The U.S. Senate creates a select committee on finance and a uniform national currency, predecessor of the United States Senate Committee on Finance.</item>
<item>1816 – Indiana becomes the 19th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1905 – A workers\' uprising occurs in Kiev, Ukraine (then part of the Russian Empire), and establishes the Shuliavka Republic.</item>
<item>1925 – Roman Catholic papal encyclical Quas primas introduces the Feast of Christ the King.</item>
<item>1927 – Guangzhou Uprising: Communist Red Guards launch an uprising in Guangzhou, China, taking over most of the city and announcing the formation of a Guangzhou Soviet.</item>
<item>1931 – Statute of Westminster 1931: The British Parliament establishes legislative equality between the UK and the Dominions of the Commonwealth—Australia, Canada, Newfoundland, New Zealand, South Africa, and Ireland.</item>
<item>1934 – Bill Wilson, co–founder of Alcoholics Anonymous, takes his last drink and enters treatment for the last time.</item>
<item>1946 – The United Nations International Children\'s Emergency Fund (UNICEF) is established.</item>
<item>1958 – French Upper Volta and French Dahomey gain self–government from France, becoming the Republic of Upper Volta and the Republic of Dahomey (now Benin), respectively, and joining the French Community.</item>
<item>1960 – French forces crack down in a violent clash with protesters in French Algeria during a visit by French President Charles de Gaulle.</item>
<item>1964 – Che Guevara speaks at the United Nations General Assembly in New York City.</item>
<item>1968 – The Rolling Stones Rock and Roll Circus, featuring the Rolling Stones, Jethro Tull, the Who, Taj Mahal, Marianne Faithfull, and the Dirty Mac with Yoko Ono, is filmed in Wembley, London.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo 17 becomes the sixth and last Apollo mission to land on the Moon.</item>
<item>1978 – The Lufthansa heist is committed by a group led by Lucchese family associate Jimmy Burke. It was the largest cash robbery ever committed on American soil, at that time.</item>
<item>1980 – The Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act (Superfund) is enacted by the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1990 – Demonstrations by students and workers across Albania begin, which eventually trigger the fall of communism in Albania.</item>
<item>1997 – The Kyoto Protocol opens for signature.</item>
<item>2001 – The People\'s Republic of China joins the World Trade Organization (WTO).</item>
<item>2006 – The International Conference to Review the Global Vision of the Holocaust is opened in Tehran, Iran, by then–president Mahmoud Ahmadinejad; nations such as Israel and the United States express concern.</item>
<item>2008 – Bernard Madoff is arrested and charged with securities fraud in a $50 billion Ponzi scheme.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>