<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_20">
<item>217 – Callixtus I is elected as the sixteenth pope, although Hippolytus of Rome is soon thereafter elected as a rival pope.</item>
<item>1192 – Richard I of England is captured and imprisoned by Leopold V of Austria on his way home to England after the Third Crusade.</item>
<item>1334 – Pope Benedict XII is elected.</item>
<item>1522 – Siege of Rhodes: Suleiman the Magnificent accepts the surrender of the surviving Knights of Rhodes, who are allowed to evacuate. They eventually settle on Malta and become known as the Knights of Malta.</item>
<item>1606 – The Virginia Company loads three ships with settlers and sets sail to establish Jamestown, Virginia, the first permanent English settlement in the Americas.</item>
<item>1803 – The Louisiana Purchase is completed at a ceremony in New Orleans.</item>
<item>1832 – HMS Clio under the command of Captain Onslow arrives at Port Egmont under orders to take possession of the Falkland Islands</item>
<item>1860 – South Carolina becomes the first state to attempt to secede from the United States.</item>
<item>1917 – Cheka, the first Soviet secret police force, is founded.</item>
<item>1946 – The popular Christmas film It\'s a Wonderful Life is first released in New York City.</item>
<item>1951 – The EBR–1 in Arco, Idaho becomes the first nuclear power plant to generate electricity. The electricity powered four light bulbs.</item>
<item>1955 – Cardiff is proclaimed the capital city of Wales, United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1957 – The initial production version of the Boeing 707 makes its first flight.</item>
<item>1967 – A Pennsylvania Railroad Budd Metroliner exceeds 155 mph on their New York Division, also present day Amtrak\'s Northeast Corridor.</item>
<item>1971 – The international aid organization Doctors Without Borders is founded by Bernard Kouchner and a group of journalists in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1985 – Pope John Paul II announces the institution of World Youth Day.</item>
<item>1989 – The United States invasion of Panama deposes Manuel Noriega.</item>
<item>1995 – NATO begins peacekeeping in Bosnia.</item>
<item>1999 – Macau is handed over to China by Portugal.</item>
<item>2004 – A gang of thieves steal £26.5 million worth of currency from the Donegall Square West headquarters of Northern Bank in Belfast, Northern Ireland, United Kingdom, one of the largest bank robberies in British history.</item>
<item>2007 – Elizabeth II becomes the oldest monarch of the United Kingdom, surpassing Queen Victoria, who lived for 81 years, 7 months and 29 days.</item>
<item>2007 – The Portrait of Suzanne Bloch (1904), by the Spanish artist Pablo Picasso, and O Lavrador de Café by Brazilian modernist painter Cândido Portinari, are stolen from the São Paulo Museum of Art.</item>
<item>2013 – China successfully launches the Bolivian Túpac Katari 1 from the Xichang Satellite Launch Center.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>