<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_5">
<item>63 BC – Cicero gives the fourth and final of the Catiline Orations.</item>
<item>633 – Fourth Council of Toledo takes place.</item>
<item>1082 – Ramon Berenguer II, Count of Barcelona is assassinated.</item>
<item>1408 – Emir Edigu of Golden Horde reaches Moscow.</item>
<item>1484 – Pope Innocent VIII issues the Summis desiderantes affectibus, a papal bull that deputizes Heinrich Kramer and Jacob Sprenger as inquisitors to root out alleged witchcraft in Germany.</item>
<item>1492 – Christopher Columbus becomes the first European to set foot on the island of Hispaniola (now Haiti and the Dominican Republic).</item>
<item>1496 – King Manuel I of Portugal issues a decree ordering the expulsion of \"heretics\" from the country.</item>
<item>1560 – Charles IX becomes king of France.</item>
<item>1766 – In London, auctioneer James Christie holds his first sale.</item>
<item>1775 – At Fort Ticonderoga, Henry Knox begins his historic transport of artillery to Cambridge, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1831 – Former U.S. President John Quincy Adams takes his seat in the House of Representatives.</item>
<item>1847 – Jefferson Davis is elected to the U.S. Senate.</item>
<item>1848 – California Gold Rush: In a message to the United States Congress, U.S. President James K. Polk confirms that large amounts of gold had been discovered in California.</item>
<item>1933 – The Twenty–first Amendment to the United States Constitution is ratified.</item>
<item>1936 – The Soviet Union adopts a new constitution and the Kirghiz Soviet Socialist Republic is established as a full Union Republic of the USSR.</item>
<item>1955 – The American Federation of Labor and the Congress of Industrial Organizations merge and form the AFL–CIO.</item>
<item>1955 – E. D. Nixon and Rosa Parks lead the Montgomery Bus Boycott.</item>
<item>1958 – Subscriber Trunk Dialling (STD) is inaugurated in the United Kingdom by Queen Elizabeth II when she speaks to the Lord Provost in a call from Bristol to Edinburgh.</item>
<item>1958 – The Preston By–pass, the UK\'s first stretch of motorway, opens to traffic for the first time. (It is now part of the M6 and M55 motorways.)</item>
<item>1964 – Lloyd J. Old discovered the first linkage between the major histocompatibility complex (MHC) and disease—mouse leukemia—opening the way for the recognition of the importance of the MHC in the immune response.</item>
<item>1977 – Egypt breaks diplomatic relations with Syria, Libya, Algeria, Iraq and South Yemen. The move is in retaliation for the Declaration of Tripoli against Egypt.</item>
<item>1983 – Dissolution of the Military Junta in Argentina.</item>
<item>1991 – Leonid Kravchuk is elected the first president of Ukraine.</item>
<item>2004 – The Civil Partnership Act comes into effect in the United Kingdom, and the first civil partnership is registered there.</item>
<item>2006 – Commodore Frank Bainimarama overthrows the government in Fiji.</item>
<item>2014 – Exploration Flight Test 1, the first flight test of Orion is launched.</item>
<item>2017 – The International Olympic Committee bans Russia from competing at the 2018 Winter Olympics for doping at the 2014 Winter Olympics.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>