<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_9">
<item>480 – Odoacer, first King of Italy, occupies Dalmatia. He later establishes his political power with the co–operation of the Roman Senate.</item>
<item>1425 – The Catholic University of Leuven is founded.</item>
<item>1793 – New York City\'s first daily newspaper, the American Minerva, is established by Noah Webster.</item>
<item>1851 – The first YMCA in North America is established in Montreal.</item>
<item>1856 – The Iranian city of Bushehr surrenders to occupying British forces.</item>
<item>1872 – In Louisiana, P. B. S. Pinchback becomes the first African–American governor of a U.S. state.</item>
<item>1892 – English soccer club Newcastle United is founded</item>
<item>1897 – Activist Marguerite Durand founds the feminist daily newspaper La Fronde in Paris.</item>
<item>1905 – In France, the law separating church and state is passed.</item>
<item>1922 – Gabriel Narutowicz is elected the first president of Poland.</item>
<item>1931 – The Constituent Cortes approves a constitution which establishes the Second Spanish Republic.</item>
<item>1935 – Student protests in Beiping (now Beijing)\'s Tiananmen Square, dispersed by government.</item>
<item>1946 – The Constituent Assembly of India meets for the first time to write the Constitution of India.</item>
<item>1948 – The Genocide Convention is adopted.</item>
<item>1953 – Red Scare: General Electric announces that all communist employees will be discharged from the company.</item>
<item>1958 – The John Birch Society is founded in the United States.</item>
<item>1960 – The first episode of Coronation Street, the world\'s longest–running television soap opera, is broadcast in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1961 – Tanganyika becomes independent from Britain.</item>
<item>1962 – The Petrified Forest National Park is established in Arizona.</item>
<item>1965 – Kecksburg UFO incident: A fireball is seen from Michigan to Pennsylvania; witnesses report something crashing in the woods near Pittsburgh.</item>
<item>1965 – A Charlie Brown Christmas, first in a series of Peanuts television specials, debuts on CBS.</item>
<item>1968 – Douglas Engelbart gave what became known as \"The Mother of All Demos\", publicly debuting the computer mouse, hypertext, and the bit–mapped graphical user interface using the oN–Line System (NLS).</item>
<item>1973 – British and Irish authorities sign the Sunningdale Agreement in an attempt to establish a power–sharing Northern Ireland Executive and a cross–border Council of Ireland.</item>
<item>1979 – The eradication of the smallpox virus is certified, making smallpox the first of only two diseases that have been driven to extinction (rinderpest in 2011 being the other).</item>
<item>1982 – Explosion in office belonging to the Kuwait Airways in Athens.</item>
<item>1987 – Israeli–Palestinian conflict: The First Intifada begins in the Gaza Strip and West Bank.</item>
<item>1988 – The Michael Hughes Bridge in Sligo, Ireland, is officially opened.</item>
<item>1992 – American troops land in Somalia for Operation Restore Hope.</item>
<item>1996 – Gwen Jacob is acquitted of committing an indecent act, giving women the right to be topfree in Ontario, Canada.</item>
<item>2008 – The Governor of Illinois, Rod Blagojevich, is arrested by federal officials for crimes including attempting to sell the U.S. Senate seat being vacated by President–elect Barack Obama.</item>
<item>2015 – The start of the thirty–sixth GCC summit in Riyadh business.</item>
<item>2016 – President Park Geun–hye of South Korea is impeached by the country\'s National Assembly in response to a major political scandal. Prime Minister Hwang Kyo–ahn becomes Acting President, later declining to run for a full term.</item>
<item>2017 – Australia becomes the 26th country to legalize same–sex marriage.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>