<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_10">
<item>220 – Emperor Xian of Han abdicates the throne to Cao Pi ending the Han dynasty and establish the Kingdom of Wei</item>
<item>1041 – The son of Empress Zoë of Byzantium succeeds to the throne of the Eastern Roman Empire as Michael V.</item>
<item>1508 – The League of Cambrai is formed by Pope Julius II, Louis XII of France, Maximilian I, Holy Roman Emperor and Ferdinand II of Aragon as an alliance against Venice.</item>
<item>1665 – The Royal Netherlands Marine Corps is founded by Michiel de Ruyter</item>
<item>1684 – Isaac Newton\'s derivation of Kepler\'s laws from his theory of gravity, contained in the paper De motu corporum in gyrum, is read to the Royal Society by Edmond Halley.</item>
<item>1799 – France adopts the metre as its official unit of length.</item>
<item>1817 – Mississippi becomes the 20th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1861 – Forces led by Nguyễn Trung Trực, an anti–colonial guerrilla leader in southern Vietnam, sink the French lorcha L\'Esperance.</item>
<item>1868 – The first traffic lights are installed, outside the Palace of Westminster in London. Resembling railway signals, they use semaphore arms and are illuminated at night by red and green gas lamps.</item>
<item>1884 – Mark Twain\'s Adventures of Huckleberry Finn is published.</item>
<item>1896 – Alfred Jarry\'s Ubu Roi premieres in Paris. A riot breaks out at the end of the performance.</item>
<item>1902 – The opening of the reservoir of the Aswan Dam in Egypt.</item>
<item>1907 – The worst night of the Brown Dog riots in London, when 1,000 medical students clash with 400 police officers over the existence of a memorial for animals that have been vivisected.</item>
<item>1909 – Selma Lagerlöf becomes the first female writer to win the Nobel Prize in Literature</item>
<item>1932 – Thailand becomes a constitutional monarchy.</item>
<item>1948 – The Human Rights Convention is signed by the United Nations.</item>
<item>1953 – British Prime Minister Winston Churchill receives the Nobel Prize in literature.</item>
<item>1963 – Zanzibar gains independence from the United Kingdom as a constitutional monarchy, under Sultan Jamshid bin Abdullah.</item>
<item>1968 – Japan\'s biggest heist, the still–unsolved \"300 million yen robbery\", is carried out in Tokyo.</item>
<item>1979 – Kaohsiung Incident: Taiwanese pro–democracy demonstrations are suppressed by the KMT dictatorship, and organizers are arrested.</item>
<item>1983 – Democracy is restored in Argentina with the inauguration of President Raúl Alfonsín.</item>
<item>1993 – The last shift leaves Wearmouth Colliery in Sunderland. The closure of the 156–year–old pit marks the end of the old County Durham coalfield, which had been in operation since the Middle Ages.</item>
<item>1994 – Rwandan genocide: Maurice Baril, military advisor to the U.N. Secretary–General and head of the Military Division of the Department of Peacekeeping Operations, recommends that UNAMIR stand down.</item>
<item>1995 – The Israeli army withdraws from Nablus pursuant to the terms of Oslo Accord.</item>
<item>1996 – The new Constitution of South Africa is promulgated by Nelson Mandela.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>