<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_4">
<item>1110 – The Kingdom of Jerusalem captures Sidon.</item>
<item>1259 – Kings Louis IX of France and Henry III of England agree to the Treaty of Paris, in which Henry renounces his claims to French–controlled territory on continental Europe (including Normandy) in exchange for Louis withdrawing his support for English rebels.</item>
<item>1563 – The final session of the Council of Trent is held. (It had opened on December 13, 1545.)</item>
<item>1619 – Thirty–eight colonists arrive at Berkeley Hundred, Virginia. The group\'s charter proclaims that the day \"be yearly and perpetually kept holy as a day of thanksgiving to Almighty God.\"</item>
<item>1783 – At Fraunces Tavern in New York City, U.S. General George Washington bids farewell to his officers.</item>
<item>1786 – Mission Santa Barbara is dedicated (on the feast day of Saint Barbara).</item>
<item>1791 – The first edition of The Observer, the world\'s first Sunday newspaper, is published.</item>
<item>1829 – In the face of fierce local opposition, British Governor–General Lord William Bentinck issues a regulation declaring that anyone who abets suttee in Bengal is guilty of culpable homicide.</item>
<item>1861 – The 109 Electors of the several states of the Confederate States of America unanimously elect Jefferson Davis as President and Alexander H. Stephens as Vice President.</item>
<item>1865 – North Carolina ratifies 13th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution, followed soon by Georgia, and U.S. slaves were legally free within 2 weeks</item>
<item>1867 – Former Minnesota farmer Oliver Hudson Kelley founds the Order of the Patrons of Husbandry (better known today as the Grange).</item>
<item>1872 – The crewless American ship Mary Celeste is found by the Canadian brig Dei Gratia. The ship had been abandoned for nine days but was only slightly damaged.</item>
<item>1875 – Notorious New York City politician Boss Tweed escapes from prison; he is later recaptured in Spain.</item>
<item>1881 – The first edition of the Los Angeles Times is published.</item>
<item>1906 – Alpha Phi Alpha the first black intercollegiate Greek lettered fraternity was founded at Cornell University in Ithaca, New York.</item>
<item>1909 – In Canadian football, the First Grey Cup game is played. The University of Toronto Varsity Blues defeat the Toronto Parkdale Canoe Club, 26–6.</item>
<item>1945 – By a vote of 65–7, the United States Senate approves United States participation in the United Nations. (The UN had been established on October 24, 1945.)</item>
<item>1954 – The first Burger King is opened in Miami, Florida.</item>
<item>1956 – The Million Dollar Quartet (Elvis Presley, Jerry Lee Lewis, Carl Perkins, and Johnny Cash) get together at Sun Studio for the first and last time.</item>
<item>1977 – Jean–Bédel Bokassa, president of the Central African Republic, crowns himself Emperor Bokassa I of the Central African Empire.</item>
<item>1981 – South Africa grants independence to the Ciskei \"homeland\" (not recognized by any government outside South Africa).</item>
<item>1982 – The People\'s Republic of China adopts its current constitution.</item>
<item>1991 – Pan American World Airways ceases its operations after 64 years.</item>
<item>1998 – The Unity Module, the second module of the International Space Station, is launched.</item>
<item>2005 – Tens of thousands of people in Hong Kong protest for democracy and call on the government to allow universal and equal suffrage.</item>
<item>2006 – Six black youths assault a white teenager in Jena, Louisiana.</item>
<item>2017 – The Lamborghini Urus is the world\'s fastest SUV. Reaching speeds of 190 miles per hour.</item>
<item>2017 – The Pontiac Silverdome in Pontiac, Michigan has been imploded, after a day of failure to be imploded. It is about 30 miles from Detroit, Michigan. It first opened on August 23, 1975.</item>
<item>2017 – The Winklevoss twins are the first Bitcoin billionaires. They are known for suing Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg of stealing their idea from their social website ConnectU during 2004, which is now social media site Facebook.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>