<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_12">
<item>1098 – First Crusade: Siege of Ma\'arrat al–Numan: Crusaders breach the town\'s walls and massacre about 20,000 inhabitants. After finding themselves with insufficient food, they reportedly resort to cannibalism.</item>
<item>1388 – Mary of Enghien sells the lordship of Argos and Nauplia to the Republic of Venice.</item>
<item>1408 – The Order of the Dragon, a monarchical chivalric order, is created by Sigismund of Luxembourg, then king of Hungary.</item>
<item>1870 – Joseph H. Rainey of South Carolina becomes the second black U.S. congressman, the first being Hiram Revels.</item>
<item>1897 – Belo Horizonte, the first planned city in Brazil, is founded.</item>
<item>1901 – Guglielmo Marconi receives the first transatlantic radio signal (the letter \"S\" [***] in Morse Code), at Signal Hill in St John\'s, Newfoundland.</item>
<item>1911 – Delhi replaces Calcutta as the capital of India.</item>
<item>1911 – King George V of the United Kingdom and Mary of Teck are enthroned as Emperor and Empress of India.</item>
<item>1915 – President of the Republic of China, Yuan Shikai, announces his intention to reinstate the monarchy and proclaim himself Emperor of China.</item>
<item>1918 – The Flag of Estonia is raised atop the Pikk Hermann for the first time.</item>
<item>1925 – The Majlis of Iran votes to crown Reza Khan as the new Shah of Iran, starting the Pahlavi dynasty.</item>
<item>1946 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 13 relating to acceptance of Siam to United Nations is adopted.</item>
<item>1950 – Paula Ackerman, the first woman appointed to perform rabbinical functions in the United States, leads the congregation in her first services.</item>
<item>1956 – Beginning of the Irish Republican Army\'s \"Border Campaign\".</item>
<item>1956 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 121 relating to acceptace of Japan to United Nations is adopted.</item>
<item>1963 – Kenya gains its independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1964 – Prime Minister Jomo Kenyatta becomes the first President of the Republic of Kenya.</item>
<item>1979 – President of Pakistan Muhammad Zia–ul–Haq confers Nishan–e–Imtiaz on Nobel laureate Dr Abdus Salam.</item>
<item>1979 – The unrecognised state of Zimbabwe–Rhodesia returns to British control and resumes using the name Southern Rhodesia.</item>
<item>1983 – The Australian Labor government led by Prime Minister Bob Hawke and Treasurer Paul Keating floats the Australian dollar.</item>
<item>1984 – Maaouya Ould Sid\'Ahmed Taya becomes the third president of Mauritania after a coup d\'état against Mohamed Khouna Ould Haidalla while the latter is attending a summit.</item>
<item>1991 – The Russian Federation gains independence from the USSR.</item>
<item>2000 – The United States Supreme Court releases its decision in Bush v. Gore.</item>
<item>2001 – Prime Minister of Vietnam Phan Văn Khải announces the decision on upgrading the Phong Nha–Kẻ Bàng nature reserve to a national park, providing information on projects for the conservation and development of the park and revised maps.</item>
<item>2012 – North Korea successfully launches its first satellite, Kwangmyŏngsŏng–3 Unit 2, using an Unha–3 carrier rocket.</item>
<item>2015 – Paris Agreement relating to United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change is adopted.</item>
<item>2017 – Doug Jones wins the 2017 US Senate special election in Alabama, becoming the first Democrat to win a Senate seat in Alabama since 1992.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>