<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_19">
<item>1154 – Henry II of England is crowned at Westminster Abbey.</item>
<item>1187 – Pope Clement III is elected.</item>
<item>1490 – Anne, Duchess of Brittany, is married to Maximilian I, Holy Roman Emperor by proxy.</item>
<item>1606 – The ships Susan Constant, Godspeed, and Discovery depart England carrying settlers who founded, at Jamestown, Virginia, the first of the thirteen colonies that became the United States.</item>
<item>1776 – Thomas Paine publishes one of a series of pamphlets in The Pennsylvania Journal entitled \"The American Crisis\".</item>
<item>1828 – Nullification Crisis: Vice President of the United States John C. Calhoun pens the South Carolina Exposition and Protest, protesting the Tariff of 1828.</item>
<item>1900 – Hopetoun Blunder: The first Governor–General of Australia John Hope, 7th Earl of Hopetoun, appoints Sir William Lyne premier of the new state of New South Wales, but he is unable to persuade other colonial politicians to join his government and is forced to resign.</item>
<item>1924 – The last Rolls–Royce Silver Ghost is sold in London, England.</item>
<item>1932 – BBC World Service begins broadcasting as the BBC Empire Service.</item>
<item>1961 – India annexes Daman and Diu, part of Portuguese India.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo program: The last manned lunar flight, Apollo 17, crewed by Eugene Cernan, Ronald Evans, and Harrison Schmitt, returns to Earth.</item>
<item>1974 – Nelson Rockefeller is sworn in as Vice President of the United States under President Gerald Ford under the provisions of the 25th Amendment to the United States Constitution.</item>
<item>1983 – The original FIFA World Cup trophy, the Jules Rimet Trophy, is stolen from the headquarters of the Brazilian Football Confederation in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</item>
<item>1984 – The Sino–British Joint Declaration, stating that China would resume the exercise of sovereignty over Hong Kong and the United Kingdom would restore Hong Kong to China with effect from July 1, 1997 is signed in Beijing, China by Deng Xiaoping and Margaret Thatcher.</item>
<item>1986 – Mikhail Gorbachev, leader of the Soviet Union, releases Andrei Sakharov and his wife from exile in Gorky.</item>
<item>1995 – The United States Government restores federal recognition to the Nottawaseppi Huron Band of Potawatomi Native American tribe.</item>
<item>1998 – President Bill Clinton is impeached by the United States House of Representatives, becoming the second President of the United States to be impeached.</item>
<item>2001 – A record high barometric pressure of 1085.6 hPa (32.06 inHg) is recorded at Tosontsengel, Khövsgöl, Mongolia.</item>
<item>2001 – Argentine economic crisis: December riots: Riots erupt in Buenos Aires, Argentina.</item>
<item>2012 – Park Geun–hye is elected the first female president of South Korea.</item>
<item>2013 – Spacecraft Gaia is launched by European Space Agency.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>