<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a12_16">
<item>755 – An Lushan revolts against Chancellor Yang Guozhong at Yanjing, initiating the An Lushan Rebellion during the Tang dynasty of China.</item>
<item>1497 – Vasco da Gama passes the Great Fish River, where Bartolomeu Dias had previously turned back to Portugal.</item>
<item>1653 – English Interregnum: The Protectorate: Oliver Cromwell becomes Lord Protector of the Commonwealth of England, Scotland and Ireland.</item>
<item>1843 – The discovery of octonions by John T. Graves, who denoted them with a boldface O, was announced to his mathematician friend William Hamilton, discoverer of quaternions, in a letter on this date.</item>
<item>1850 – The Charlotte Jane and the Randolph bring the first of the Canterbury Pilgrims to Lyttelton, New Zealand.</item>
<item>1883 – Tonkin Campaign: French forces capture the Sơn Tây citadel.</item>
<item>1907 – The American Great White Fleet begins its circumnavigation of the world.</item>
<item>1918 – Vincas Mickevičius–Kapsukas declares the formation of the Lithuanian Soviet Socialist Republic; it is dissolved in 1919.</item>
<item>1937 – Theodore Cole and Ralph Roe attempt to escape from the American federal prison on Alcatraz Island in San Francisco Bay; neither is ever seen again.</item>
<item>1942 – The Holocaust: Schutzstaffel chief Heinrich Himmler orders that Roma candidates for extermination be deported to Auschwitz.</item>
<item>1947 – William Shockley, John Bardeen and Walter Brattain build the first practical point–contact transistor.</item>
<item>1968 – Second Vatican Council: Official revocation of the Edict of Expulsion of Jews from Spain.</item>
<item>1971 – The United Kingdom recognizes Bahrain\'s independence, which is commemorated annually as Bahrain\'s National Day.</item>
<item>1978 – Cleveland, Ohio becomes the first major American city to default on its financial obligations since the Great Depression.</item>
<item>1979 – Libya joins four other OPEC nations in raising crude oil prices, which has an immediate, dramatic effect on the United States.</item>
<item>1991 – Kazakhstan declares independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>