<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_17">
<item>38 BC – Octavian divorces his wife Scribonia and marries Livia Drusilla, ending the fragile peace between the Second Triumvirate and Sextus Pompey.</item>
<item>1287 – The Treaty of San Agayz is signed. King Alfonso III of Aragon conquers the island of Menorca from the Moors.</item>
<item>1377 – Pope Gregory XI moves the Papacy back to Rome from Avignon.</item>
<item>1562 – France recognizes the Huguenots by the Edict of Saint–Germain.</item>
<item>1773 – Captain James Cook commands the first expedition to sail south of the Antarctic Circle.</item>
<item>1852 – The United Kingdom signs the Sand River Convention with the South African Republic.</item>
<item>1893 – Lorrin A. Thurston, along with the Citizens\' Committee of Public Safety, led the Overthrow of the Kingdom of Hawaii and the government of Queen Liliʻuokalani.</item>
<item>1899 – The United States takes possession of Wake Island in the Pacific Ocean.</item>
<item>1903 – El Yunque National Forest in Puerto Rico becomes part of the United States National Forest System as the Luquillo Forest Reserve.</item>
<item>1904 – Anton Chekhov\'s The Cherry Orchard receives its premiere performance at the Moscow Art Theatre.</item>
<item>1912 – British polar explorer Captain Robert Falcon Scott reaches the South Pole, one month after Roald Amundsen.</item>
<item>1917 – The United States pays Denmark $25 million for the Virgin Islands.</item>
<item>1929 – Popeye the Sailor Man, a cartoon character created by E. C. Segar, first appears in the Thimble Theatre comic strip.</item>
<item>1945 – The SS–Totenkopfverbände begin the evacuation of the Auschwitz concentration camp as Soviet forces close in.</item>
<item>1945 – Swedish diplomat Raoul Wallenberg is taken into Soviet custody while in Hungary; he is never publicly seen again.</item>
<item>1946 – The UN Security Council holds its first session.</item>
<item>1948 – The Renville Agreement between the Netherlands and Indonesia is ratified.</item>
<item>1950 – The Great Brink\'s Robbery: Eleven thieves steal more than $2 million from an armored car company\'s offices in Boston.</item>
<item>1950 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 79 relating to arms control is adopted.</item>
<item>1981 – President of the Philippines Ferdinand Marcos lifts martial law eight years and five months after declaring it.</item>
<item>1996 – The Czech Republic applies for membership of the European Union.</item>
<item>1998 – Lewinsky scandal: Matt Drudge breaks the story of the Bill Clinton–Monica Lewinsky affair on his Drudge Report website.</item>
<item>2002 – Mount Nyiragongo erupts in the Democratic Republic of the Congo, displacing an estimated 400,000 people.</item>
<item>2007 – The Doomsday Clock is set to five minutes to midnight in response to North Korea\'s nuclear testing.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>