<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_16">
<item>27 BC – Gaius Julius Caesar Octavianus is granted the title Augustus by the Roman Senate, marking the beginning of the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>378 – General Siyaj K\'ak\' conquers Tikal, enlarging the domain of King Spearthrower Owl of Teotihuacán.</item>
<item>929 – Emir Abd–ar–Rahman III established the Caliphate of Córdoba.</item>
<item>1120 – The Council of Nablus is held, establishing the earliest surviving written laws of the Crusader Kingdom of Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1412 – The Medici family is appointed official banker of the Papacy.</item>
<item>1492 – The first grammar of the Spanish language (Gramática de la lengua castellana) is presented to Queen Isabella I.</item>
<item>1547 – Grand Duke Ivan IV of Muscovy becomes the first Tsar of Russia, replacing the 264–year–old Grand Duchy of Moscow with the Tsardom of Russia.</item>
<item>1556 – Philip II becomes King of Spain.</item>
<item>1605 – The first edition of El ingenioso hidalgo Don Quijote de la Mancha (Book One of Don Quixote) by Miguel de Cervantes is published in Madrid, Spain.</item>
<item>1707 – The Scottish Parliament ratifies the Act of Union, paving the way for the creation of Great Britain.</item>
<item>1786 – Virginia enacts the Statute for Religious Freedom authored by Thomas Jefferson.</item>
<item>1847 – John C. Frémont is appointed Governor of the new California Territory.</item>
<item>1883 – The Pendleton Civil Service Reform Act, establishing the United States Civil Service, is passed.</item>
<item>1900 – The United States Senate accepts the Anglo–German treaty of 1899 in which the United Kingdom renounces its claims to the Samoan islands.</item>
<item>1909 – Ernest Shackleton\'s expedition finds the magnetic South Pole.</item>
<item>1919 – The United States ratifies the Eighteenth Amendment to the United States Constitution, requiring Prohibition in the United States one year after ratification.</item>
<item>1920 – The League of Nations holds its first council meeting in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1921 – The Marxist Left in Slovakia and the Transcarpathian Ukraine holds its founding congress in Ľubochňa.</item>
<item>1964 – Hello, Dolly! opened on Broadway, beginning a run of 2,844 performances.</item>
<item>1969 – Soviet spacecraft Soyuz 4 and Soyuz 5 perform the first–ever docking of manned spacecraft in orbit, the first–ever transfer of crew from one space vehicle to another, and the only time such a transfer was accomplished with a space walk.</item>
<item>1979 – The last Iranian Shah flees Iran with his family for good and relocates to Egypt.</item>
<item>2002 – The UN Security Council unanimously establishes an arms embargo and the freezing of assets of Osama bin Laden, al–Qaeda, and the remaining members of the Taliban.</item>
<item>2003 – The Space Shuttle Columbia takes off for mission STS–107 which would be its final one. Columbia disintegrated 16 days later on re–entry.</item>
<item>2006 – Ellen Johnson Sirleaf is sworn in as Liberia\'s new president. She becomes Africa\'s first female elected head of state.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>