<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_11">
<item>532 – Nika riots in Constantinople: A quarrel between supporters of different chariot teams—the Blues and the Greens—in the Hippodrome escalates into violence.</item>
<item>630 – Conquest of Mecca: The prophet Muhammad and his followers conquer the city, Quraysh surrender.</item>
<item>947 – Emperor Tai Zong of the Khitan–led Liao Dynasty invades the Later Jin, resulting in the destruction of the Later Jin.</item>
<item>1055 – Theodora is crowned empress of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1158 – Vladislaus II, Duke of Bohemia becomes king of Bohemia.</item>
<item>1569 – First recorded lottery in England.</item>
<item>1571 – Austrian nobility is granted freedom of religion.</item>
<item>1759 – In Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, the first American life insurance company is incorporated.</item>
<item>1779 – Ching–Thang Khomba is crowned King of Manipur.</item>
<item>1787 – William Herschel discovers Titania and Oberon, two moons of Uranus.</item>
<item>1805 – The Michigan Territory is created.</item>
<item>1908 – Grand Canyon National Monument is created.</item>
<item>1912 – Immigrant textile workers in Lawrence, Massachusetts, go on strike when wages are reduced in response to a mandated shortening of the work week.</item>
<item>1922 – First use of insulin to treat diabetes in a human patient.</item>
<item>1927 – Louis B. Mayer, head of film studio Metro–Goldwyn–Mayer (MGM), announces the creation of the Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences, at a banquet in Los Angeles, California.</item>
<item>1935 – Amelia Earhart becomes the first person to fly solo from Hawaii to California.</item>
<item>1943 – The Republic of China agrees to the Sino–British New Equal Treaty and the Sino–American New Equal Treaty.</item>
<item>1946 – Enver Hoxha, Secretary General of the Communist Party of Albania, declares the People\'s Republic of Albania with himself as head of state.</item>
<item>1949 – The first \"networked\" television broadcasts took place as KDKA–TV in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania goes on the air connecting the east coast and mid–west programming.</item>
<item>1957 – The African Convention is founded in Dakar, Senegal.</item>
<item>1961 – Throgs Neck Bridge over the East River, linking New York City\'s boroughs of The Bronx and Queens, opens to road traffic.</item>
<item>1964 – Surgeon General of the United States Dr. Luther Terry, M.D., publishes the landmark report Smoking and Health: Report of the Advisory Committee to the Surgeon General of the United States saying that smoking may be hazardous to health, sparking national and worldwide anti–smoking efforts.</item>
<item>1972 – East Pakistan renames itself Bangladesh.</item>
<item>1973 – Major League Baseball owners vote in approval of the American League adopting the designated hitter position.</item>
<item>1986 – The Gateway Bridge, Brisbane, Queensland, Australia is officially opened.</item>
<item>1994 – The Irish Government announces the end of a 15–year broadcasting ban on the IRA and its political arm Sinn Féin.</item>
<item>1996 – Space Shuttle program: STS–72 launches from the Kennedy Space Center marking the start of the 74th Space Shuttle mission and the 10th flight of Endeavour.</item>
<item>1996 – Ryutaro Hashimoto, leader of the Liberal Democratic Party, becomes Prime Minister of Japan.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>