<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_19">
<item>379 – Emperor Gratian elevates Flavius Theodosius at Sirmium to Augustus, and gives him authority over all the eastern provinces of the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>639 – Clovis II, king of Neustria and Burgundy, is crowned.</item>
<item>649 – Conquest of Kucha: The forces of Kucha surrender after a forty–day siege led by Tang dynasty general Ashina She\'er, establishing Tang control over the northern Tarim Basin in Xinjiang.</item>
<item>1511 – Mirandola surrenders to the French.</item>
<item>1607 – San Agustin Church in Manila is officially completed; it is the oldest church still standing in the Philippines.</item>
<item>1661 – Thomas Venner is hanged, drawn and quartered in London.</item>
<item>1764 – John Wilkes is expelled from the British House of Commons for seditious libel.</item>
<item>1788 – The second group of ships of the First Fleet arrive at Botany Bay.</item>
<item>1795 – The Batavian Republic is proclaimed in the Netherlands, bringing to an end the Republic of the Seven United Netherlands.</item>
<item>1829 – Johann Wolfgang von Goethe\'s Faust: The First Part of the Tragedy receives its premiere performance.</item>
<item>1839 – The British East India Company captures Aden.</item>
<item>1853 – Giuseppe Verdi\'s opera Il trovatore receives its premiere performance in Rome.</item>
<item>1883 – The first electric lighting system employing overhead wires, built by Thomas Edison, begins service at Roselle, New Jersey.</item>
<item>1899 – Anglo–Egyptian Sudan is formed.</item>
<item>1915 – Georges Claude patents the neon discharge tube for use in advertising.</item>
<item>1920 – The United States Senate votes against joining the League of Nations.</item>
<item>1920 – The American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) is founded.</item>
<item>1953 – Almost 72% of all television sets in the United States are tuned into I Love Lucy to watch Lucy give birth.</item>
<item>1960 – Japan and the United States sign the US–Japan Mutual Security Treaty</item>
<item>1974 – China gains control over all the Paracel Islands after a military engagement between the naval forces of China and South Vietnam</item>
<item>1977 – President Gerald Ford pardons Iva Toguri D\'Aquino (a.k.a. \"Tokyo Rose\").</item>
<item>1978 – The last Volkswagen Beetle made in Germany leaves VW\'s plant in Emden. Beetle production in Latin America continues until 2003.</item>
<item>1983 – The Apple Lisa, the first commercial personal computer from Apple Inc. to have a graphical user interface and a computer mouse, is announced.</item>
<item>1993 – Czech Republic and Slovakia join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1995 – After being struck by lightning the crew of Bristow Flight 56C are forced to ditch. All 18 aboard are later rescued.</item>
<item>1997 – Yasser Arafat returns to Hebron after more than 30 years and joins celebrations over the handover of the last Israeli–controlled West Bank city.</item>
<item>1999 – British Aerospace agrees to acquire the defence subsidiary of the General Electric Company plc, forming BAE Systems in November 1999.</item>
<item>2012 – The Hong Kong–based file–sharing website Megaupload is shut down by the FBI.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>