<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_1">
<item>1362 Grand Duchy of Lithuania</item>
<item>1522 Republic of Venice</item>
<item>1544 Holy Roman Empire (Germany)</item>
<item>1556 Spain, Portugal</item>
<item>1559 Prussia, Sweden</item>
<item>1564 France</item>
<item>1576 Southern Netherlands</item>
<item>1579 Duchy of Lorraine</item>
<item>1583 Northern Netherlands</item>
<item>1600 Scotland</item>
<item>1700 Russia</item>
<item>1721 Tuscany</item>
<item>1752 Great Britain (excluding Scotland) and its colonies</item>
<item>153 BC – For the first time, Roman consuls begin their year in office on January 1.</item>
<item>45 BC – The Julian calendar takes effect as the civil calendar of the Roman Empire, establishing January 1 as the new date of the new year.</item>
<item>42 BC – The Roman Senate posthumously deifies Julius Caesar.</item>
<item>193 – The Senate chooses Pertinax against his will to succeed Commodus as Roman emperor.</item>
<item>417 – Emperor Honorius forces Galla Placidia into marriage to Constantius, his famous general (magister militum) (probable).</item>
<item>1001 – Grand Prince Stephen I of Hungary is named the first King of Hungary by Pope Sylvester II (probable).</item>
<item>1068 – Romanos IV Diogenes marries Eudokia Makrembolitissa and is crowned Byzantine Emperor.</item>
<item>1438 – Albert II of Habsburg is crowned King of Hungary.</item>
<item>1502 – The present–day location of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil is first explored by the Portuguese.</item>
<item>1527 – Croatian nobles elect Ferdinand I of Austria as King of Croatia in the Parliament on Cetin.</item>
<item>1600 – Scotland recognises January 1 as the start of the year, instead of March 25.</item>
<item>1651 – Charles II is crowned King of Scotland.</item>
<item>1700 – Russia begins using the Anno Domini era instead of the Anno Mundi era of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1707 – John V is proclaimed King of Portugal and the Algarves in Lisbon.</item>
<item>1739 – Bouvet Island, the world\'s remotest island is discovered by French explorer Jean–Baptiste Charles Bouvet de Lozier.</item>
<item>1772 – The first traveler\'s cheques, which can be used in 90 European cities, is issued by the London Credit Exchange Company.</item>
<item>1773 – The hymn that became known as \"Amazing Grace\", then titled \"1 Chronicles 17:16–17\" is first used to accompany a sermon led by John Newton in the town of Olney, Buckinghamshire, England.</item>
<item>1788 – First edition of The Times of London, previously The Daily Universal Register, is published.</item>
<item>1801 – The legislative union of Kingdom of Great Britain and Kingdom of Ireland is completed, and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland is proclaimed.</item>
<item>1801 – Ceres, the largest and first known object in the Asteroid belt, is discovered by Giuseppe Piazzi.</item>
<item>1804 – French rule ends in Haiti. Haiti becomes the first black republic and second independent country in North America after the United States.</item>
<item>1806 – The French Republican Calendar is abolished.</item>
<item>1808 – The United States bans the importation of slaves.</item>
<item>1810 – Major–General Lachlan Macquarie officially becomes Governor of New South Wales.</item>
<item>1822 – The Greek Constitution of 1822 is adopted by the First National Assembly at Epidaurus. name=\"BlausteinFlanz1976\">Albert P. Blaustein; Gisbert H. Flanz (1976). Constitutions of the Countries of the World. Oceana Publications.</item>
<item>1847 – The world\'s first \"Mercy\" Hospital is founded in Pittsburgh, United States, by a group of Sisters of Mercy from Ireland; the name will go on to grace over 30 major hospitals throughout the world.</item>
<item>1860 – The first Polish stamp is issued, replacing the Russian stamps previously in use.</item>
<item>1861 – Liberal forces supporting Benito Juárez enter Mexico City.</item>
<item>1877 – Queen Victoria of the United Kingdom is proclaimed Empress of India.</item>
<item>1885 – Twenty–five nations adopt Sandford Fleming\'s proposal for standard time (and also, time zones)</item>
<item>1890 – Eritrea is consolidated into a colony by the Italian government.</item>
<item>1892 – Ellis Island begins processing immigrants into the United States.</item>
<item>1898 – New York, New York annexes land from surrounding counties, creating the City of Greater New York. The four initial boroughs, Manhattan, Brooklyn, Queens, and The Bronx, are joined on January 25 by Staten Island to create the modern city of five boroughs.</item>
<item>1899 – Spanish rule ends in Cuba.</item>
<item>1901 – Nigeria becomes a British protectorate.</item>
<item>1901 – The British colonies of New South Wales, Queensland, Victoria, South Australia, Tasmania, and Western Australia federate as the Commonwealth of Australia; Edmund Barton is appointed the first Prime Minister.</item>
<item>1902 – The first American college football bowl game, the Rose Bowl between Michigan and Stanford, is held in Pasadena, California.</item>
<item>1910 – Captain David Beatty is promoted to Rear admiral, and becomes the youngest admiral in the Royal Navy (except for Royal family members), since Horatio Nelson.</item>
<item>1912 – The Republic of China is established.</item>
<item>1914 – The SPT Airboat Line becomes the world\'s first scheduled airline to use a winged aircraft.</item>
<item>1923 – Britain\'s Railways are grouped into the Big Four: LNER, GWR, SR, and LMS.</item>
<item>1929 – The former municipalities of Point Grey, British Columbia and South Vancouver, British Columbia are amalgamated into Vancouver.</item>
<item>1932 – The United States Post Office Department issues a set of 12 stamps commemorating the 200th anniversary of George Washington\'s birth.</item>
<item>1934 – Alcatraz Island in San Francisco Bay becomes a United States federal prison.</item>
<item>1942 – The Declaration by United Nations is signed by twenty–six nations.</item>
<item>1947 – The Canadian Citizenship Act 1946 comes into effect, converting British subjects into Canadian citizens. Prime Minister William Lyon Mackenzie King becomes the first Canadian citizen.</item>
<item>1948 – The British railway network is nationalized to form British Railways.</item>
<item>1956 – Sudan achieves independence from Egypt and the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1957 – George Town, Penang, is made a city by a royal charter of Queen Elizabeth II of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1958 – European Economic Community is established.</item>
<item>1960 – Cameroon achieves independence from France and the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1962 – Western Samoa achieves independence from New Zealand; its name is changed to the Independent State of Western Samoa.</item>
<item>1964 – The Federation of Rhodesia and Nyasaland is divided into the independent republics of Zambia and Malawi, and the British–controlled Rhodesia.</item>
<item>1965 – The People\'s Democratic Party of Afghanistan is founded in Kabul, Afghanistan.</item>
<item>1971 – Cigarette advertisements are banned on American television.</item>
<item>1973 – Denmark, Ireland and the United Kingdom are admitted into the European Economic Community.</item>
<item>1979 – Formal diplomatic relations are established between China and the United States.</item>
<item>1981 – Greece is admitted into the European Community.</item>
<item>1982 – Peruvian Javier Pérez de Cuéllar becomes the first Latin American to hold the title of Secretary–General of the United Nations.</item>
<item>1983 – The ARPANET officially changes to using the Internet Protocol, creating the Internet.</item>
<item>1984 – The original American Telephone &amp; Telegraph Company is divested of its 22 Bell System companies as a result of the settlement of the 1974 United States Department of Justice antitrust suit against AT&amp;T.</item>
<item>1984 – Brunei becomes independent of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1985 – The first British mobile phone call is made by Michael Harrison to his father Sir Ernest Harrison, chairman of Vodafone.</item>
<item>1987 – The Isleta Pueblo tribe elect Verna Williamson to be their first female governor.</item>
<item>1988 – The Evangelical Lutheran Church in America comes into existence, creating the largest Lutheran denomination in the United States.</item>
<item>1989 – The Montreal Protocol comes into force, stopping the use of chemicals contributing to ozone depletion.</item>
<item>1990 – David Dinkins is sworn in as New York City\'s first black mayor.</item>
<item>1993 – Dissolution of Czechoslovakia: Czechoslovakia is divided into the Czech Republic and Slovak Republic.</item>
<item>1994 – The Zapatista Army of National Liberation initiates twelve days of armed conflict in the Mexican state of Chiapas.</item>
<item>1994 – The North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) comes into effect.</item>
<item>1995 – The World Trade Organization comes into being.</item>
<item>1995 – The Draupner wave in the North Sea in Norway is detected, confirming the existence of freak waves.</item>
<item>1995 – Austria, Finland and Sweden join the EU.</item>
<item>1998 – Following a currency reform, Russia begins to circulate new rubles to stem inflation and promote confidence.</item>
<item>1999 – Euro currency is introduced in 11 member nations of the European Union (with the exception of the United Kingdom, Denmark, Greece and Sweden; Greece later adopts the euro).</item>
<item>2002 – Euro currency becomes legal tender in twelve of the European Union\'s member states.</item>
<item>2004 – In a vote of confidence, General Pervez Musharraf wins 658 out of 1,170 votes in the Electoral College of Pakistan, and according to Article 41(8) of the Constitution of Pakistan, is \"deemed to be elected\" to the office of President until October 2007.</item>
<item>2007 – Bulgaria and Romania join the EU.</item>
<item>2007 – Adam Air Flight 574 disappears over Sulawesi Strait, Indonesia with 102 people on board.</item>
<item>2011 – Estonia officially adopts the Euro currency and becomes the 17th Eurozone country.</item>
<item>2015 – The Eurasian Economic Union comes into effect, creating a political and economic union between Russia, Belarus, Armenia, Kazakhstan and Kyrgyzstan.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>