<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_14">
<item>1236 – Marriage of King Henry III of England and Eleanor of Provence.</item>
<item>1343 – Arnošt of Pardubice becomes the last bishop of Prague and, subsequently, the first Archbishop of Prague.</item>
<item>1539 – Spain annexes Cuba.</item>
<item>1639 – The \"Fundamental Orders\", the first written constitution that created a government, is adopted in Connecticut.</item>
<item>1814 – Treaty of Kiel: Frederick VI of Denmark cedes the Kingdom of Norway to Charles XIII of Sweden in return for Pomerania.</item>
<item>1858 – Napoleon III of France escapes an assassination attempt made by Felice Orsini and his accomplices in Paris.</item>
<item>1911 – Roald Amundsen\'s South Pole expedition makes landfall on the eastern edge of the Ross Ice Shelf.</item>
<item>1939 – Norway claims Queen Maud Land in Antarctica.</item>
<item>1950 – The first prototype of the MiG–17 makes its maiden flight.</item>
<item>1952 – NBC\'s long–running morning news program Today debuts, with host Dave Garroway.</item>
<item>1953 – Josip Broz Tito is inaugurated as the first President of Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1954 – The Hudson Motor Car Company merges with Nash–Kelvinator Corporation forming the American Motors Corporation.</item>
<item>1957 – Kripalu Maharaj was named fifth Jagadguru (world teacher) after giving seven days of speeches before 500 Hindu scholars.</item>
<item>1960 – The Reserve Bank of Australia, the country\'s central bank and banknote issuing authority, is established.</item>
<item>1967 – Counterculture of the 1960s: The Human Be–In takes place in San Francisco, California\'s Golden Gate Park, launching the Summer of Love.</item>
<item>1972 – Queen Margrethe II of Denmark ascends the throne, the first Queen of Denmark since 1412 and the first Danish monarch not named Frederick or Christian since 1513.</item>
<item>1973 – Elvis Presley\'s concert Aloha from Hawaii is broadcast live via satellite, and sets the record as the most watched broadcast by an individual entertainer in television history.</item>
<item>2004 – The national flag of the Republic of Georgia, the so–called \"five cross flag\", is restored to official use after a hiatus of some 500 years.</item>
<item>2018 – Russell M. Nelson becomes the 17th President of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter–day Saints.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>