<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_15">
<item>1541 – King Francis I of France gives Jean–François Roberval a commission to settle the province of New France (Canada) and provide for the spread of the \"Holy Catholic faith\".</item>
<item>1559 – Elizabeth I is crowned Queen of England in Westminster Abbey, London, England.</item>
<item>1582 – Truce of Yam–Zapolsky: Russia cedes Livonia to the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth.</item>
<item>1759 – The British Museum opens.</item>
<item>1782 – Superintendent of Finance Robert Morris goes before the U.S. Congress to recommend establishment of a national mint and decimal coinage.</item>
<item>1818 – A paper by David Brewster is read to the Royal Society, belatedly announcing his discovery of what we now call the biaxial class of doubly–refracting crystals. On the same day, Augustin–Jean Fresnel signs a \"supplement\" (submitted four days later) on reflection of polarized light.</item>
<item>1844 – University of Notre Dame receives its charter from the state of Indiana.</item>
<item>1889 – The Coca–Cola Company, then known as the Pemberton Medicine Company, is incorporated in Atlanta.</item>
<item>1892 – James Naismith publishes the rules of basketball.</item>
<item>1908 – The Alpha Kappa Alpha sorority becomes the first Greek–letter organization founded and established by African American college women.</item>
<item>1910 – Construction ends on the Buffalo Bill Dam in Wyoming, United States, which was the highest dam in the world at the time, at 325 ft (99 m).</item>
<item>1936 – The first building to be completely covered in glass, built for the Owens–Illinois Glass Company, is completed in Toledo, Ohio.</item>
<item>1943 – The Pentagon is dedicated in Arlington, Virginia.</item>
<item>1962 – The Derveni papyrus, Europe\'s oldest surviving manuscript dating to 340 BC, is found in northern Greece.</item>
<item>1962 – Netherlands New Guinea Conflict: Indonesian Navy fast patrol boat RI Macan Tutul commanded by Commodore Yos Sudarso sunk in Arafura Sea by the Dutch Navy.</item>
<item>1966 – The First Nigerian Republic, led by Abubakar Tafawa Balewa is overthrown in a military coup d\'état.</item>
<item>1967 – The first Super Bowl is played in Los Angeles. The Green Bay Packers defeat the Kansas City Chiefs 35–10.</item>
<item>1969 – The Soviet Union launches Soyuz 5.</item>
<item>1970 – Muammar Gaddafi is proclaimed premier of Libya.</item>
<item>1981 – Pope John Paul II receives a delegation from Solidarity (Polish trade union) at the Vatican led by Lech Wałęsa.</item>
<item>1991 – Elizabeth II, in her capacity as Queen of Australia, signs letters patent allowing Australia to become the first Commonwealth realm to institute its own Victoria Cross in its honours system.</item>
<item>2001 – Wikipedia, a free wiki content encyclopedia, goes online.</item>
<item>2005 – ESA\'s SMART–1 lunar orbiter discovers elements such as calcium, aluminum, silicon, iron, and other surface elements on the Moon.</item>
<item>2009 – US Airways Flight 1549 ditches safely in the Hudson River after the plane collides with birds several minutes after take–off.</item>
<item>2015 – The Swiss National Bank abandons the cap on the franc\'s value relative to the euro, causing turmoil in international financial markets</item>
</string-array>
</resources>