<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_12">
<item>1528 – Gustav I of Sweden is crowned king of Sweden, having already reigned since his election in June 1523.</item>
<item>1554 – Bayinnaung, who would go on to assemble the largest empire in the history of Southeast Asia, is crowned King of Burma.</item>
<item>1616 – The city of Belém, Brazil is founded on the Amazon River delta, by Portuguese captain Francisco Caldeira Castelo Branco.</item>
<item>1808 – John Rennie\'s scheme to defend St Mary\'s Church, Reculver, founded in 669, from coastal erosion is abandoned in favour of demolition, despite the church being an exemplar of Anglo–Saxon architecture and sculpture.</item>
<item>1808 – The organizational meeting leading to the creation of the Wernerian Natural History Society, a former Scottish learned society, is held in Edinburgh.</item>
<item>1848 – The Palermo rising takes place in Sicily against the Bourbon Kingdom of the Two Sicilies.</item>
<item>1866 – The Royal Aeronautical Society is formed in London.</item>
<item>1872 – Yohannes IV is crowned Emperor of Ethiopia in Axum, the first imperial coronation in that city in over 200 years.</item>
<item>1895 – The National Trust is founded in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1908 – A long–distance radio message is sent from the Eiffel Tower for the first time.</item>
<item>1911 – The University of the Philippines College of Law is formally established; three future Philippine presidents are among the first enrollees.</item>
<item>1915 – The United States House of Representatives rejects a proposal to require states to give women the right to vote.</item>
<item>1921 – Acting to restore confidence in baseball after the Black Sox Scandal, Judge Kenesaw Mountain Landis is elected as Major League Baseball\'s first commissioner.</item>
<item>1932 – Hattie Caraway becomes the first woman elected to the United States Senate.</item>
<item>1966 – Lyndon B. Johnson states that the United States should stay in South Vietnam until Communist aggression there is ended.</item>
<item>1967 – Dr. James Bedford becomes the first person to be cryonically preserved with intent of future resuscitation.</item>
<item>1969 – The New York Jets of the American Football League defeat the Baltimore Colts of the National Football League to win Super Bowl III in what is considered to be one of the greatest upsets in sports history.</item>
<item>1976 – The United Nations Security Council votes 11–1 to allow the Palestine Liberation Organization to participate in a Security Council debate (without voting rights).</item>
<item>1986 – Space Shuttle program: Congressman Bill Nelson lifts off from Kennedy Space Center aboard Columbia on mission STS–61–C as a payload specialist.</item>
<item>1998 – Nineteen European nations agree to forbid human cloning.</item>
<item>2001 – Downtown Disney opens to the public as part of the Disneyland Resort in Anaheim, California.</item>
<item>2004 – The world\'s largest ocean liner, RMS Queen Mary 2, makes its maiden voyage.</item>
<item>2005 – Deep Impact launches from Cape Canaveral on a Delta II rocket.</item>
<item>2012 – Violent protests occur in Bucharest, Romania, as two–day–old demonstrations continue against President Traian Băsescu\'s economic austerity measures. Clashes are reported in numerous Romanian cities between protesters and law enforcement officers.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>