<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_10">
<item>236 – Pope Fabian succeeds Anterus to become the twentieth pope of Rome.</item>
<item>1072 – Robert Guiscard conquers Palermo in Sicily.</item>
<item>1430 – Philip the Good, the Duke of Burgundy, establishes the Order of the Golden Fleece, the most prestigious, exclusive, and expensive order of chivalry in the world.</item>
<item>1645 – Archbishop William Laud is beheaded for treason at the Tower of London.</item>
<item>1812 – The first steamboat on the Ohio River or the Mississippi River arrives in New Orleans, 82 days after departing from Pittsburgh.</item>
<item>1863 – The Metropolitan Railway, the world\'s oldest underground railway, opens between Paddington and Farringdon, marking the beginning of the London Underground.</item>
<item>1870 – John D. Rockefeller incorporates Standard Oil.</item>
<item>1901 – The first great Texas oil gusher is discovered at Spindletop in Beaumont, Texas.</item>
<item>1920 – League of Nations Covenant enters into force. On January 16 the organization holds its first council meeting, in Paris.</item>
<item>1927 – Fritz Lang\'s futuristic film Metropolis is released in Germany.</item>
<item>1946 – The first General Assembly of the United Nations opens in London. Fifty–one nations are represented.</item>
<item>1946 – The United States Army Signal Corps successfully conducts Project Diana, bouncing radio waves off the Moon and receiving the reflected signals.</item>
<item>1962 – Apollo program: NASA announces plans to build the C–5 rocket launch vehicle, which became known as the Saturn V Moon rocket, which launched every Apollo Moon mission.</item>
<item>1972 – Sheikh Mujibur Rahman returns to the newly independent Bangladesh as president after spending over nine months in prison in Pakistan.</item>
<item>1984 – Holy See–United States relations: The United States and Holy See (Vatican City) re–establish full diplomatic relations after almost 117 years, overturning the United States Congress\'s 1867 ban on public funding for such a diplomatic envoy.</item>
<item>1985 – Sandinista Daniel Ortega becomes president of Nicaragua and vows to continue the transformation to socialism and alliance with the Soviet Union and Cuba; American policy continues to support the Contras in their revolt against the Nicaraguan government.</item>
<item>2007 – A general strike begins in Guinea in an attempt to get President Lansana Conté to resign.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>