<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_26">
<item>1500 – Vicente Yáñez Pinzón becomes the first European to set foot on Brazil.</item>
<item>1564 – The Council of Trent establishes an official distinction between Roman Catholicism and Protestantism.</item>
<item>1699 – For the first time, the Ottoman Empire permanently cedes territory to the Christian powers.</item>
<item>1736 – Stanislaus I of Poland abdicates his throne.</item>
<item>1788 – The British First Fleet, led by Arthur Phillip, sails into Port Jackson (Sydney Harbour) to establish Sydney, the first permanent European settlement on Australia. Commemorated as Australia Day.</item>
<item>1808 – The Rum Rebellion is the only successful (albeit short–lived) armed takeover of the government in Australia.</item>
<item>1837 – Michigan is admitted as the 26th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1838 – Tennessee enacts the first prohibition law in the United States</item>
<item>1841 – James Bremer takes formal possession of Hong Kong Island at what is now Possession Point, establishing British Hong Kong.</item>
<item>1855 – Point No Point Treaty is signed in Washington Territory.</item>
<item>1870 – Reconstruction Era: Virginia rejoins the Union.</item>
<item>1905 – The world\'s largest diamond ever, the Cullinan weighing 3,106.75 carats (0.621350 kg), is found at the Premier Mine near Pretoria in South Africa.</item>
<item>1911 – Glenn H. Curtiss flies the first successful American seaplane.</item>
<item>1915 – The Rocky Mountain National Park is established by an act of the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1920 – Former Ford Motor Company executive Henry Leland launches the Lincoln Motor Company which he later sold to his former employer.</item>
<item>1926 – The first demonstration of the television by John Logie Baird.</item>
<item>1934 – The Apollo Theater reopens in Harlem, New York City.</item>
<item>1934 – German–Polish Non–Aggression Pact is signed.</item>
<item>1949 – The Hale telescope at Palomar Observatory sees first light under the direction of Edwin Hubble, becoming the largest aperture optical telescope (until BTA–6 is built in 1976).</item>
<item>1950 – The Constitution of India comes into force, forming a republic. Rajendra Prasad is sworn in as its first President of India. Observed as Republic Day in India.</item>
<item>1956 – Soviet Union cedes Porkkala back to Finland.</item>
<item>1961 – John F. Kennedy appoints Janet G. Travell to be the first woman Physician to the President.</item>
<item>1962 – Ranger 3 is launched to study the Moon. The space probe later misses the moon by 22,000 miles (35,400 km).</item>
<item>1965 – Hindi becomes the official language of India.</item>
<item>1980 – Israel and Egypt establish diplomatic relations.</item>
<item>1986 – The Ugandan government of Tito Okello is overthrown by the National Resistance Army, led by Yoweri Museveni.</item>
<item>1991 – Mohamed Siad Barre is removed from power in Somalia, ending centralized government, and is succeeded by Ali Mahdi.</item>
<item>1992 – Boris Yeltsin announces that Russia will stop targeting United States cities with nuclear weapons.</item>
<item>1998 – Lewinsky scandal: On American television, U.S. President Bill Clinton denies having had \"sexual relations\" with former White House intern Monica Lewinsky.</item>
<item>2009 – Rioting breaks out in Antananarivo, Madagascar, sparking a political crisis that will result in the replacement of President Marc Ravalomanana with Andry Rajoelina.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>