<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_24">
<item>1438 – The Council of Basel suspends Pope Eugene IV.</item>
<item>1458 – Matthias Corvinus becomes king of Hungary.</item>
<item>1624 – Afonso Mendes, appointed by Pope Gregory XV as Prelate of Ethiopia, arrives at Massawa from Goa.</item>
<item>1679 – King Charles II of England dissolves the Cavalier Parliament.</item>
<item>1742 – Charles VII Albert becomes Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1835 – Slaves in Salvador da Bahia, Brazil, stage a revolt, which is instrumental in ending slavery there 50 years later.</item>
<item>1848 – California Gold Rush: James W. Marshall finds gold at Sutter\'s Mill near Sacramento.</item>
<item>1857 – The University of Calcutta is formally founded as the first fully fledged university in South Asia.</item>
<item>1859 – The United Principalities of Moldavia and Wallachia (later named Romania) is formed as a personal union under the rule of Domnitor Alexandru Ioan Cuza.</item>
<item>1862 – Bucharest is proclaimed the capital of Romania.</item>
<item>1908 – The first Boy Scout troop is organized in England by Robert Baden–Powell.</item>
<item>1916 – In Brushaber v. Union Pacific Railroad Co., the Supreme Court of the United States declares the federal income tax constitutional.</item>
<item>1918 – The Gregorian calendar is introduced in Russia by decree of the Council of People\'s Commissars effective February 14(NS)</item>
<item>1933 – The 20th Amendment to the United States Constitution is ratified, changing the beginning and end of terms for all elected federal offices.</item>
<item>1946 – The United Nations General Assembly passes its first resolution to establish the United Nations Atomic Energy Commission.</item>
<item>1977 – Atocha massacre occurs in Madrid during the Spanish transition to democracy.</item>
<item>1984 – Apple Computer places the Macintosh personal computer on sale in the United States.</item>
<item>1990 – Japan launches Hiten, the country\'s first lunar probe, the first robotic lunar probe since the Soviet Union\'s Luna 24 in 1976, and the first lunar probe launched by a country other than Soviet Union or the United States.</item>
<item>2003 – The United States Department of Homeland Security officially begins operation.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>