<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_2">
<item>366 – The Alemanni cross the frozen Rhine in large numbers, invading the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>533 – Mercurius becomes Pope John II, the first pope to adopt a new name upon elevation to the papacy.</item>
<item>1492 – Reconquista: the Emirate of Granada, the last Moorish stronghold in Spain, surrenders.</item>
<item>1788 – Georgia becomes the fourth state to ratify the United States Constitution.</item>
<item>1818 – The British Institution of Civil Engineers is founded.</item>
<item>1833 – Reassertion of British sovereignty over the Falkland Islands.</item>
<item>1860 – The discovery of the planet Vulcan is announced at a meeting of the French Academy of Sciences in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1900 – American statesman and diplomat John Hay announces the Open Door Policy to promote trade with China.</item>
<item>1942 – The Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) obtains the conviction of 33 members of a German spy ring headed by Fritz Joubert Duquesne in the largest espionage case in United States history—the Duquesne Spy Ring.</item>
<item>1949 – Luis Muñoz Marín becomes the first democratically elected Governor of Puerto Rico.</item>
<item>1955 – Panamanian president José Antonio Remón Cantera is assassinated.</item>
<item>1959 – Luna 1, the first spacecraft to reach the vicinity of the Moon and to orbit the Sun, is launched by the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1967 – Ronald Reagan, past movie actor and future President of the United States, is sworn in as Governor of California.</item>
<item>1974 – United States President Richard Nixon signs a bill lowering the maximum U.S. speed limit to 55 MPH in order to conserve gasoline during an OPEC embargo.</item>
<item>1975 – The Federal Rules of Evidence are approved by the United States Congress.</item>
<item>1978 – On the orders of Muhammad Zia–ul–Haq, paramilitary forces opened fire on peaceful protesting workers in Multan, Pakistan, its known as 1978 massacre at Multan Colony Textile Mills.</item>
<item>1991 – Sharon Pratt Kelly becomes the first African American woman mayor of a major city and first woman Mayor of the District of Columbia.</item>
<item>1992 – Leaders of armed opposition declare the President Zviad Gamsakhurdia deposed during a military coup in Georgia.</item>
<item>2004 – Stardust successfully flies past Comet Wild 2, collecting samples that are returned to Earth.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>