<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_27">
<item>945 – The co–emperors Stephen and Constantine are overthrown. Constantine VII becomes sole emperor of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1186 – Henry VI, the son and heir of the Holy Roman Emperor Frederick I, marries Constance of Sicily.</item>
<item>1302 – Dante Alighieri is exiled from Florence.</item>
<item>1343 – Pope Clement VI issues the papal bull Unigenitus to justify the power of the pope and the use of indulgences. Nearly 200 years later, Martin Luther would protest this.</item>
<item>1606 – Gunpowder Plot: The trial of Guy Fawkes and other conspirators begins, ending with their execution on January 31.</item>
<item>1785 – The University of Georgia is founded, the first public university in the United States.</item>
<item>1820 – A Russian expedition led by Fabian Gottlieb von Bellingshausen and Mikhail Petrovich Lazarev discovers the Antarctic continent, approaching the Antarctic coast.</item>
<item>1825 – The U.S. Congress approves Indian Territory (in what is present–day Oklahoma), clearing the way for forced relocation of the Eastern Indians on the \"Trail of Tears\".</item>
<item>1880 – Thomas Edison receives the patent on the incandescent lamp.</item>
<item>1927 – Ibn Saud takes the title of King of Nejd.</item>
<item>1939 – First flight of the Lockheed P–38 Lightning.</item>
<item>1951 – Nuclear testing at the Nevada Test Site begins with Operation Ranger.</item>
<item>1961 – The Soviet submarine S–80 sinks when its snorkel malfunctions, flooding the boat.</item>
<item>1980 – Through cooperation between the U.S. and Canadian governments, six American diplomats secretly escape hostilities in Iran in the culmination of the Canadian Caper.</item>
<item>1983 – The pilot shaft of the Seikan Tunnel, the world\'s longest sub–aqueous tunnel (53.85 km) between the Japanese islands of Honshū and Hokkaidō, breaks through.</item>
<item>1996 – In a military coup, Colonel Ibrahim Baré Maïnassara deposes the first democratically elected president of Niger, Mahamane Ousmane.</item>
<item>1996 – Germany first observes the International Holocaust Remembrance Day.</item>
<item>2003 – The first selections for the National Recording Registry are announced by the Library of Congress.</item>
<item>2010 – The 2009 Honduran constitutional crisis ends when Porfirio Lobo Sosa becomes the new President of Honduras.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>