<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_20">
<item>250 – Emperor Decius begins a widespread persecution of Christians. Pope Fabian is martyred.</item>
<item>649 – King Chindasuinth, at the urging of bishop Braulio of Zaragoza, crowns his son Recceswinth as co–ruler of the Visigothic Kingdom.</item>
<item>1265 – The first English parliament to include not only Lords but also representatives of the major towns holds its first meeting in the Palace of Westminster, now commonly known as the \"Houses of Parliament\".</item>
<item>1320 – Duke Wladyslaw Lokietek becomes king of Poland.</item>
<item>1523 – Christian II is forced to abdicate as King of Denmark and Norway.</item>
<item>1576 – The Mexican city of León is founded by order of the viceroy Don Martín Enríquez de Almanza.</item>
<item>1649 – Charles I of England goes on trial for treason and other \"high crimes\".</item>
<item>1788 – The third and main part of First Fleet arrives at Botany Bay. Arthur Phillip decides that Port Jackson is a more suitable location for a colony.</item>
<item>1841 – Hong Kong Island is occupied by the British.</item>
<item>1877 – The last day of the Constantinople Conference results in agreement for political reforms in the Balkans.</item>
<item>1887 – The United States Senate allows the Navy to lease Pearl Harbor as a naval base.</item>
<item>1921 – The first Constitution of Turkey is adopted, making fundamental changes in the source and exercise of sovereignty by consecrating the principle of national sovereignty.</item>
<item>1929 – In Old Arizona, the first full–length talking motion picture filmed outdoors, is released.</item>
<item>1937 – Franklin Delano Roosevelt and John Nance Garner are sworn in for their second terms as U.S. President and U.S. Vice President, the first occasion a Presidential Inauguration to take place on January 20 following the ratification of the 20th Amendment</item>
<item>1948 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 39 relating to India and Pakistan is adopted.</item>
<item>1949 – Point Four Program a program for economic aid to poor countries announced by United States President Harry S. Truman in his inaugural address for a full term as President.</item>
<item>1953 – Dwight D. Eisenhower is inaugurated as the 34th President of the United States of America, becoming the first President to begin his presidency on January 20 following the ratification of the 20th Amendment.</item>
<item>1954 – In the United States, the National Negro Network is established with 40 charter member radio stations.</item>
<item>1961 – John F. Kennedy is inaugurated the 35th President of the United States of America, becoming the second youngest man to take the office, and the first Catholic.</item>
<item>1969 – Richard Nixon is inaugurated the 37th President of the United States of America.</item>
<item>1977 – Jimmy Carter is inaugurated the 39th President of the United States of America.</item>
<item>1986 – In the United States, Martin Luther King, Jr. Day is celebrated as a federal holiday for the first time.</item>
<item>1989 – George H. W. Bush is inaugurated the 41st President of the United States of America.</item>
<item>1990 – Protests in Azerbaijan, part of the Dissolution of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1993 – Bill Clinton is inaugurated the 42nd President of the United States of America.</item>
<item>2001 – George W. Bush is inaugurated the 43rd President of the United States of America.</item>
<item>2007 – Four–man Team N2i, using only skis and kites, completes a 1,093–mile (1,759 km) trek to reach the Antarctic pole of inaccessibility for the first time since 1965 and for the first time ever without mechanical assistance.</item>
<item>2009 – Barack Obama is inaugurated as the 44th President of the United States of America, becoming the first African–American President of the United States.</item>
<item>2009 – A protest movement in Iceland culminates as the 2009 Icelandic financial crisis protests start.</item>
<item>2017 – Donald Trump is inaugurated as the 45th President of the United States of America, becoming the oldest person to assume the office.</item>
<item>2018 – The United States federal government shuts down after the Senate fails to pass a temporary funding bill.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>