<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_21">
<item>1525 – The Swiss Anabaptist Movement is founded when Conrad Grebel, Felix Manz, George Blaurock, and about a dozen others baptize each other in the home of Manz\'s mother in Zürich, breaking a thousand–year tradition of church–state union.</item>
<item>1720 – Sweden and Prussia sign the Treaty of Stockholm.</item>
<item>1774 – Abdul Hamid I became Sultan of the Ottoman Empire and Caliph of Islam.</item>
<item>1789 – The first American novel, The Power of Sympathy or the Triumph of Nature Founded in Truth by William Hill Brown, is printed in Boston.</item>
<item>1893 – The Tati Concessions Land, formerly part of Matabeleland, is formally annexed to the Bechuanaland Protectorate, now Botswana.</item>
<item>1908 – New York City passes the Sullivan Ordinance, making it illegal for women to smoke in public, only to have the measure vetoed by the mayor.</item>
<item>1911 – The first Monte Carlo Rally takes place.</item>
<item>1915 – Kiwanis International is founded in Detroit.</item>
<item>1925 – Albania declares itself a republic.</item>
<item>1931 – Sir Isaac Isaacs is sworn in as the first Australian–born Governor–General of Australia.</item>
<item>1948 – The Flag of Quebec is adopted and flown for the first time over the National Assembly of Quebec. The day is marked annually as Québec Flag Day.</item>
<item>1950 – American lawyer and government official Alger Hiss is convicted of perjury.</item>
<item>1954 – The first nuclear–powered submarine, the USS Nautilus, is launched in Groton, Connecticut by Mamie Eisenhower, the First Lady of the United States.</item>
<item>1960 – Little Joe 1B, a Mercury spacecraft, lifts off from Wallops Island, Virginia with Miss Sam, a female rhesus monkey on board.</item>
<item>1971 – The current Emley Moor transmitting station, the tallest free–standing structure in the United Kingdom, begins transmitting UHF broadcasts.</item>
<item>1976 – Commercial service of Concorde begins with the London–Bahrain and Paris–Rio routes.</item>
<item>1981 – Production of the iconic DeLorean DMC–12 sports car begins in Dunmurry, Northern Ireland, United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1997 – The U.S. House of Representatives votes 395–28 to reprimand Newt Gingrich for ethics violations, making him the first Speaker of the House to be so disciplined.</item>
<item>2000 – Ecuador: After the Ecuadorian Congress is seized by indigenous organizations, Col. Lucio Gutiérrez, Carlos Solorzano and Antonio Vargas depose President Jamil Mahuad. Gutierrez is later replaced by Gen. Carlos Mendoza, who resigns and allows Vice–President Gustavo Noboa to succeed Mahuad.</item>
<item>2004 – NASA\'s MER–A (the Mars Rover Spirit) ceases communication with mission control. The problem lies in the management of its flash memory and is fixed remotely from Earth on February 6.</item>
<item>2005 – In Belmopan, Belize, the unrest over the government\'s new taxes erupts into riots.</item>
<item>2017 – Over 400 cities across America and 160+ countries worldwide participate in a large–scale women\'s march, on Donald Trump\'s first full day as president of the United States.</item>
<item>2018 – Rocket Lab\'s Electron becomes the first rocket to reach orbit using an electric pump–fed engine and deploys three CubeSats..</item>
</string-array>
</resources>