<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_23">
<item>393 – Roman Emperor Theodosius I proclaims his eight–year–old son Honorius co–emperor.</item>
<item>1368 – In a coronation ceremony, Zhu Yuanzhang ascends the throne of China as the Hongwu Emperor, initiating Ming dynasty rule over China that would last for three centuries.</item>
<item>1546 – Having published nothing for eleven years, François Rabelais publishes the Tiers Livre, his sequel to Gargantua and Pantagruel.</item>
<item>1571 – The Royal Exchange opens in London.</item>
<item>1579 – The Union of Utrecht forms a Protestant republic in the Netherlands.</item>
<item>1656 – Blaise Pascal publishes the first of his Lettres provinciales.</item>
<item>1719 – The Principality of Liechtenstein is created within the Holy Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1789 – Georgetown College, the first Catholic university in the United States, is founded in Georgetown, Maryland (now a part of Washington, D.C.)</item>
<item>1793 – Second Partition of Poland.</item>
<item>1846 – Slavery in Tunisia is abolished.</item>
<item>1899 – The Malolos Constitution is inaugurated, establishing the First Philippine Republic. Emilio Aguinaldo is sworn in as its first President.</item>
<item>1912 – The International Opium Convention is signed at The Hague.</item>
<item>1920 – The Netherlands refuses to surrender the exiled Kaiser Wilhelm II of Germany to the Allies.</item>
<item>1950 – The Knesset resolves that Jerusalem is the capital of Israel.</item>
<item>1957 – American inventor Walter Frederick Morrison sells the rights to his flying disc to the Wham–O toy company, which later renames it the \"Frisbee\".</item>
<item>1958 – After a general uprising and rioting in the streets, President Marcos Pérez Jiménez leaves Venezuela.</item>
<item>1960 – The bathyscaphe USS Trieste breaks a depth record by descending to 10,911 metres (35,797 ft) in the Pacific Ocean.</item>
<item>1964 – The 24th Amendment to the United States Constitution, prohibiting the use of poll taxes in national elections, is ratified.</item>
<item>1967 – Diplomatic relations between the Soviet Union and Ivory Coast are established.</item>
<item>1967 – Milton Keynes (England) is founded as a new town by Order in Council, with a planning brief to become a city of 250,000 people. Its initial designated area enclosed three existing towns and twenty one villages. The area to be developed was largely farmland, with evidence of continuous settlement dating back to the Bronze Age.</item>
<item>1973 – United States President Richard Nixon announces that a peace accord has been reached in Vietnam.</item>
<item>1986 – The Rock and Roll Hall of Fame inducts its first members: Little Richard, Chuck Berry, James Brown, Ray Charles, Sam Cooke, Fats Domino, The Everly Brothers, Buddy Holly, Jerry Lee Lewis and Elvis Presley.</item>
<item>1997 – Madeleine Albright becomes the first woman to serve as United States Secretary of State.</item>
<item>1998 – Netscape announced Mozilla, with the intention to release Communicator code as open source.</item>
<item>2003 – A very weak signal from Pioneer 10 is detected for the last time, but no usable data can be extracted.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>