<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_29">
<item>904 – Sergius III comes out of retirement to take over the papacy from the deposed antipope Christopher.</item>
<item>1790 – The first boat specializing as a lifeboat is tested on the River Tyne.</item>
<item>1819 – Stamford Raffles lands on the island of Singapore.</item>
<item>1845 – \"The Raven\" is published in The Evening Mirror in New York, the first publication with the name of the author, Edgar Allan Poe</item>
<item>1850 – Henry Clay introduces the Compromise of 1850 to the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1861 – Kansas is admitted as the 34th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1886 – Karl Benz patents the first successful gasoline–driven automobile.</item>
<item>1891 – Liliuokalani is proclaimed the last monarch and only queen regnant of the Kingdom of Hawaii.</item>
<item>1907 – Charles Curtis of Kansas becomes the first Native American U.S. Senator.</item>
<item>1936 – The first inductees into the Baseball Hall of Fame are announced.</item>
<item>1959 – The first Melodifestivalen is held in Stockholm, Sweden.</item>
<item>1963 – The first inductees into the Pro Football Hall of Fame are announced.</item>
<item>1980 – The Rubik\'s Cube makes its international debut at the Ideal Toy Corp. in Earl\'s Court, London.</item>
<item>1996 – President Jacques Chirac announces a \"definitive end\" to French nuclear weapons testing.</item>
<item>2001 – Thousands of student protesters in Indonesia storm parliament and demand that President Abdurrahman Wahid resign due to alleged involvement in corruption scandals.</item>
<item>2002 – In his State of the Union address, President George W. Bush describes \"regimes that sponsor terror\" as an Axis of evil, in which he includes Iraq, Iran and North Korea.</item>
<item>2009 – The Supreme Constitutional Court of Egypt rules that people who do not adhere to one of the three government–recognised religions, while not allowed to list any belief outside of those three, are still eligible to receive government identity documents.</item>
<item>2009 – Governor of Illinois Rod Blagojevich is removed from office following his conviction of several corruption charges, including the alleged solicitation of personal benefit in exchange for an appointment to the United States Senate as a replacement for then–U.S. president–elect Barack Obama.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>