<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_28">
<item>946 – Caliph Al–Mustakfi is blinded and deposed by Emir Mu\'izz al–Dawla, ruler of the Buyid Empire. He is succeeded by Al–Muti as caliph of the Abbasid Caliphate.</item>
<item>1077 – Walk to Canossa: The excommunication of Henry IV, Holy Roman Emperor is lifted.</item>
<item>1568 – The Edict of Torda prohibited the persecution of individuals on religious ground in John Sigismund Zápolya\'s Eastern Hungarian Kingdom.</item>
<item>1724 – The Russian Academy of Sciences is founded in St. Petersburg by Peter the Great, and implemented by Senate decree. It is called the St. Petersburg Academy of Sciences until 1917.</item>
<item>1754 – Sir Horace Walpole coins the word serendipity in a letter to a friend.</item>
<item>1813 – Jane Austen\'s Pride and Prejudice is first published in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1851 – Northwestern University becomes the first chartered university in Illinois.</item>
<item>1855 – A locomotive on the Panama Canal Railway runs from the Atlantic Ocean to the Pacific Ocean for the first time.</item>
<item>1878 – Yale Daily News becomes the first daily college newspaper in the United States.</item>
<item>1896 – Walter Arnold of East Peckham, Kent, becomes the first person to be convicted of speeding. He was fined one shilling, plus costs, for speeding at 8 mph (13 km/h), thereby exceeding the contemporary speed limit of 2 mph (3.2 km/h).</item>
<item>1902 – The Carnegie Institution of Washington is founded in Washington, D.C. with a $10 million gift from Andrew Carnegie.</item>
<item>1908 – Members of the Portuguese Republican Party fail in their attempted coup d\'état against the administrative dictatorship of Prime Minister João Franco.</item>
<item>1915 – An act of the U.S. Congress creates the United States Coast Guard as a branch of the United States Armed Forces.</item>
<item>1920 – Foundation of the Spanish Legion.</item>
<item>1922 – Knickerbocker Storm, Washington D.C.\'s biggest snowfall, causes the city\'s greatest loss of life when the roof of the Knickerbocker Theatre collapses.</item>
<item>1933 – The name Pakistan is coined by Choudhry Rahmat Ali Khan and is accepted by Indian Muslims who then thereby adopted it further for the Pakistan Movement seeking independence.</item>
<item>1935 – Iceland becomes the first Western country to legalize therapeutic abortion.</item>
<item>1938 – The World Land Speed Record on a public road is broken by Rudolf Caracciola in the Mercedes–Benz W195 at a speed of 432.7 kilometres per hour (268.9 mph).</item>
<item>1956 – Elvis Presley makes his first national television appearance.</item>
<item>1958 – The Lego company patents the design of its Lego bricks, still compatible with bricks produced today.</item>
<item>1960 – The National Football League announced expansion teams for Dallas to start in the 1960 NFL season and Minneapolis–St. Paul for 1961 NFL season.</item>
<item>1964 – An unarmed United States Air Force T–39 Sabreliner on a training mission is shot down over Erfurt, East Germany, by a Soviet MiG–19.</item>
<item>1965 – The current design of the Flag of Canada is chosen by an act of Parliament.</item>
<item>1977 – The first day of the Great Lakes Blizzard of 1977 which dumps 10 feet (3.0 m) of snow in one day in Upstate New York, with Buffalo, Syracuse, Watertown, and surrounding areas are most affected.</item>
<item>1981 – Ronald Reagan lifts remaining domestic petroleum price and allocation controls in the United States helping to end the 1979 energy crisis and begin the 1980s oil glut.</item>
<item>1985 – Supergroup USA for Africa (United Support of Artists for Africa) records the hit single We Are the World, to help raise funds for Ethiopian famine relief.</item>
<item>1988 – In R v Morgentaler the Supreme Court of Canada strikes down all anti–abortion laws.</item>
<item>2016 – The World Health Organization announces an outbreak of the Zika virus.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>