<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_22">
<item>613 – Eight–month–old Constantine is crowned as co–emperor (Caesar) by his father Heraclius at Constantinople.</item>
<item>1506 – The first contingent of 150 Swiss Guards arrives at the Vatican.</item>
<item>1555 – The Ava Kingdom falls to the Taungoo Dynasty in what is now Myanmar.</item>
<item>1689 – The Convention Parliament convenes to determine whether James II and VII, the last Roman Catholic monarch of England, Ireland and Scotland, had vacated the thrones of England and Ireland when he fled to France in 1688.</item>
<item>1808 – The Portuguese royal family arrives in Brazil after fleeing the French army\'s invasion of Portugal two months earlier.</item>
<item>1824 – The Ashantis defeat British forces in the Gold Coast.</item>
<item>1863 – The January Uprising breaks out in Poland, Lithuania and Belarus. The aim of the national movement is to regain Polish–Lithuanian–Ruthenian Commonwealth from occupation by Russia.</item>
<item>1889 – Columbia Phonograph is formed in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1890 – The United Mine Workers of America is founded in Columbus, Ohio.</item>
<item>1919 – Act Zluky is signed, unifying the Ukrainian People\'s Republic and the West Ukrainian National Republic.</item>
<item>1924 – Ramsay MacDonald becomes the first Labour Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1927 – Teddy Wakelam gives the first live radio commentary of a football match anywhere in the world, between Arsenal F.C. and Sheffield United at Highbury.</item>
<item>1946 – In Iran, Qazi Muhammad declares the independent people\'s Republic of Mahabad at Chahar Cheragh Square in the Kurdish city of Mahabad; he becomes the new president and Haji Baba Sheikh becomes the prime minister.</item>
<item>1946 – Creation of the Central Intelligence Group, forerunner of the Central Intelligence Agency.</item>
<item>1947 – KTLA, the first commercial television station west of the Mississippi River, begins operation in Hollywood.</item>
<item>1957 – Israel withdraws from the Sinai Peninsula.</item>
<item>1963 – The Élysée Treaty of cooperation between France and Germany is signed by Charles de Gaulle and Konrad Adenauer.</item>
<item>1968 – Apollo 5 lifts off carrying the first Lunar module into space.</item>
<item>1968 – Operation Igloo White, a US electronic surveillance system to stop communist infiltration into South Vietnam begins installation.</item>
<item>1970 – The Boeing 747, the world\'s first \"jumbo jet\", enters commercial service for launch customer Pan American Airways with its maiden voyage from John F. Kennedy International Airport to London Heathrow Airport.</item>
<item>1971 – The Singapore Declaration, one of the two most important documents to the uncodified constitution of the Commonwealth of Nations, is issued.</item>
<item>1973 – The Supreme Court of the United States delivers its decisions in Roe v. Wade and Doe v. Bolton, legalizing elective abortion in all fifty states.</item>
<item>1973 – The crew of Apollo 17 addresses a joint session of Congress after the completion of the final Apollo moon landing mission.</item>
<item>1973 – In a bout for the world heavyweight boxing championship in Kingston, Jamaica, challenger George Foreman knocks down champion Joe Frazier six times in the first two rounds before the fight is stopped by referee Arthur Mercante.</item>
<item>1984 – The Apple Macintosh, the first consumer computer to popularize the computer mouse and the graphical user interface, is introduced during a Super Bowl XVIII television commercial.</item>
<item>1992 – Rebel forces occupy Zaire\'s national radio station in Kinshasa and broadcast a demand for the government\'s resignation.</item>
<item>1992 – Space Shuttle program: Dr. Roberta Bondar becomes the first Canadian woman and the first neurologist in space.</item>
<item>2002 – Kmart becomes the largest retailer in United States history to file for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection.</item>
<item>2006 – Evo Morales is inaugurated as President of Bolivia, becoming the country\'s first indigenous president.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>