<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_25">
<item>1494 – Alfonso II becomes king of Naples.</item>
<item>1515 – Coronation of Francis I of France.</item>
<item>1533 – Henry VIII of England secretly marries his second wife Anne Boleyn.</item>
<item>1554 – Founding of São Paulo city, Brazil.</item>
<item>1575 – Luanda, the capital of Angola, is founded by the Portuguese navigator Paulo Dias de Novais.</item>
<item>1755 – Moscow University is established on Tatiana Day.</item>
<item>1765 – Port Egmont, the first British settlement in the Falkland Islands at the southern tip of South America, is founded.</item>
<item>1791 – The British Parliament passes the Constitutional Act of 1791 and splits the old Province of Quebec into Upper Canada and Lower Canada.</item>
<item>1792 – The London Corresponding Society is founded.</item>
<item>1858 – The Wedding March by Felix Mendelssohn is played at the marriage of Queen Victoria\'s daughter, Victoria, and Friedrich of Prussia, and becomes a popular wedding processional.</item>
<item>1879 – The Bulgarian National Bank is founded.</item>
<item>1881 – Thomas Edison and Alexander Graham Bell form the Oriental Telephone Company.</item>
<item>1890 – Nellie Bly completes her round–the–world journey in 72 days.</item>
<item>1909 – Richard Strauss\'s opera Elektra receives its debut performance at the Dresden State Opera.</item>
<item>1915 – Alexander Graham Bell inaugurates U.S. transcontinental telephone service, speaking from New York to Thomas Watson in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1918 – The Ukrainian People\'s Republic declares independence from Bolshevik Russia.</item>
<item>1924 – The 1924 Winter Olympics opens in Chamonix, in the French Alps, inaugurating the Winter Olympic Games.</item>
<item>1937 – The Guiding Light debuts on NBC radio from Chicago. In 1952 it moves to CBS television, where it remains until September 18, 2009.</item>
<item>1941 – Pope Pius XII elevates the Apostolic Vicariate of the Hawaiian Islands to the dignity of a diocese. It becomes the Roman Catholic Diocese of Honolulu.</item>
<item>1946 – The United Mine Workers rejoins the American Federation of Labor.</item>
<item>1946 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 1 relating to Military Staff Committee is adopted.</item>
<item>1947 – Thomas Goldsmith Jr. files a patent for a \"Cathode Ray Tube Amusement Device\", the first ever electronic game.</item>
<item>1960 – The National Association of Broadcasters reacts to the \"payola\" scandal by threatening fines for any disc jockeys who accept money for playing particular records.</item>
<item>1961 – In Washington, D.C., President John F. Kennedy delivers the first live presidential television news conference.</item>
<item>1961 – 101 Dalmatians premiered from Walt Disney Productions.</item>
<item>1964 – Blue Ribbon Sports is founded by University of Oregon track and field athletes, which would later become Nike.</item>
<item>1969 – Brazilian Army captain Carlos Lamarca deserts in order to fight against the military dictatorship, taking with him ten machine guns and 63 rifles.</item>
<item>1971 – Idi Amin leads a coup deposing Milton Obote and becomes Uganda\'s president.</item>
<item>1979 – Pope John Paul II starts his first official papal visits outside Italy to The Bahamas, Dominican Republic, and Mexico.</item>
<item>1986 – The National Resistance Movement topples the government of Tito Okello in Uganda.</item>
<item>1994 – The spacecraft Clementine by BMDO and NASA is launched.</item>
<item>1996 – Billy Bailey becomes the last person to be hanged in the U.S.A.</item>
<item>1998 – During a historic visit to Cuba, Pope John Paul II demands political reforms and the release of political prisoners while condemning US attempts to isolate the country.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>