<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_30">
<item>516 BCE – The Second Temple of Jerusalem finishes construction.</item>
<item>1018 – Poland and the Holy Roman Empire conclude the Peace of Bautzen.</item>
<item>1649 – King Charles I of England is beheaded.</item>
<item>1789 – Tây Sơn forces emerge victorious against Qing armies and liberate the capital Thăng Long.</item>
<item>1826 – The Menai Suspension Bridge, considered the world\'s first modern suspension bridge, connecting the Isle of Anglesey to the north West coast of Wales, is opened.</item>
<item>1847 – Yerba Buena, California is renamed San Francisco, California.</item>
<item>1858 – The first Hallé concert is given in Manchester, England, marking the official founding of The Hallé orchestra as a full–time, professional orchestra.</item>
<item>1902 – The first Anglo–Japanese Alliance is signed in London.</item>
<item>1925 – The Government of Turkey expels Patriarch Constantine VI from Istanbul.</item>
<item>1930 – The Politburo of the Soviet Union orders the extermination of the Kulaks.</item>
<item>1948 – British South American Airways\' Tudor IV Star Tiger disappears over the Bermuda Triangle.</item>
<item>1960 – The African National Party is founded in Chad, through the merger of traditionalist parties.</item>
<item>1964 – In a bloodless coup, General Nguyễn Khánh overthrows General Dương Văn Minh\'s military junta in South Vietnam.</item>
<item>1969 – The Beatles\' last public performance, on the roof of Apple Records in London. The impromptu concert is broken up by the police.</item>
<item>1972 – Pakistan leaves the Commonwealth of Nations in protest of its recognition of breakaway Bangladesh.</item>
<item>1975 – The Monitor National Marine Sanctuary is established as the first United States National Marine Sanctuary.</item>
<item>1979 – A Varig Boeing 707–323C freighter, flown by the same commander as Flight 820, disappears over the Pacific Ocean 30 minutes after taking off from Tokyo.</item>
<item>1982 – Richard Skrenta writes the first PC virus code, which is 400 lines long and disguised as an Apple boot program called \"Elk Cloner\".</item>
<item>1989 – Closure of the American embassy in Kabul, Democratic Republic of Afghanistan.</item>
<item>1995 – Workers from the National Institutes of Health announce the success of clinical trials testing the first preventive treatment for sickle–cell disease.</item>
<item>2013 – Naro–1 becomes the first carrier rocket launched by South Korea.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>