<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_3">
<item>1521 – Pope Leo X excommunicates Martin Luther in the papal bull Decet Romanum Pontificem.</item>
<item>1653 – By the Coonan Cross Oath, the Eastern Church in India cuts itself off from colonial Portuguese tutelage.</item>
<item>1749 – Benning Wentworth issues the first of the New Hampshire Grants, leading to the establishment of Vermont.</item>
<item>1749 – The first issue of Berlingske, Denmark\'s oldest continually operating newspaper, is published.</item>
<item>1815 – Austria, the United Kingdom, and France form a secret defensive alliance against Prussia and Russia.</item>
<item>1823 – Stephen F. Austin receives a grant of land in Texas from the government of Mexico.</item>
<item>1833 – The United Kingdom claims sovereignty over the Falkland Islands.</item>
<item>1848 – Joseph Jenkins Roberts is sworn in as the first president of Liberia.</item>
<item>1868 – Meiji Restoration in Japan: The Tokugawa shogunate is abolished; agents of Satsuma and Chōshū seize power.</item>
<item>1870 – Construction of the Brooklyn Bridge begins.</item>
<item>1888 – The James Lick telescope at the Lick Observatory, measuring 91 cm in diameter, is used for the first time. It was the largest refracting telescope in the world at the time.</item>
<item>1913 – An Atlantic coast storm sets the lowest confirmed barometric pressure reading for a non–tropical system in the continental United States.</item>
<item>1919 – At the Paris Peace Conference, Emir Faisal I of Iraq signs an agreement with Zionist leader Chaim Weizmann on the development of a Jewish homeland in Palestine.</item>
<item>1932 – Martial law is declared in Honduras to stop a revolt by banana workers fired by the United Fruit Company.</item>
<item>1933 – Minnie D. Craig becomes the first woman elected as Speaker of the North Dakota House of Representatives, the first woman to hold a Speaker position anywhere in the United States.</item>
<item>1938 – The March of Dimes is established as a foundation to combat infant polio by President Franklin D. Roosevelt.</item>
<item>1947 – Proceedings of the U.S. Congress are televised for the first time.</item>
<item>1949 – The Bangko Sentral ng Pilipinas, the central bank of the Philippines, is established.</item>
<item>1953 – Frances P. Bolton and her son, Oliver from Ohio, become the first mother and son to serve simultaneously in the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1956 – A fire damages the top part of the Eiffel Tower.</item>
<item>1957 – The Hamilton Watch Company introduces the first electric watch.</item>
<item>1959 – Alaska is admitted as the 49th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1962 – Pope John XXIII excommunicates Fidel Castro.</item>
<item>1976 – International Covenant on Economic, Social and Cultural Rights entered into force.</item>
<item>1977 – Apple Computer is incorporated.</item>
<item>1990 – United States invasion of Panama: Manuel Noriega, former leader of Panama, surrenders to American forces.</item>
<item>1993 – In Moscow, Russia, George H. W. Bush and Boris Yeltsin sign the second Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty (START).</item>
<item>1994 – More than seven million people from the former apartheid Homelands receive South African citizenship.</item>
<item>1999 – The Mars Polar Lander is launched by NASA.</item>
<item>2000 – Final daily edition of the Peanuts comic strip.</item>
<item>2002 – Israeli–Palestinian conflict: Israeli forces seize the Palestinian freighter Karine A in the Red Sea, finding 50 tons of weapons.</item>
<item>2009 – The first block of the blockchain of the decentralized payment system Bitcoin, called the Genesis block, was established by the creator of the system, Satoshi Nakamoto.</item>
<item>2016 – Following the fallout caused by the execution of Nimr al–Nimr, Iran ends its diplomatic relations with Saudi Arabia.</item>
<item>2018 – Computer analysts report two major security vulnerabilities, named \"Meltdown\" and \"Spectre,\" affecting the microprocessors of almost all computers in the world.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>