<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_5">
<item>1500 – Duke Ludovico Sforza conquers Milan.</item>
<item>1846 – The United States House of Representatives votes to stop sharing the Oregon Territory with the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1875 – The Palais Garnier, one of the most famous opera houses in the world, is inaugurated in Paris.</item>
<item>1911 – Kappa Alpha Psi, the world\'s third oldest and largest black fraternity, is founded at Indiana University.</item>
<item>1912 – The Prague Party Conference takes place.</item>
<item>1914 – The Ford Motor Company announces an eight–hour workday and minimum daily wage of $5 in salary plus bonuses subject to restrictions and imposed \"character standards.\"</item>
<item>1925 – Nellie Tayloe Ross of Wyoming becomes the first female governor in the United States.</item>
<item>1933 – Construction of the Golden Gate Bridge begins in San Francisco Bay.</item>
<item>1944 – The Daily Mail becomes the first transoceanic newspaper.</item>
<item>1945 – The Soviet Union recognizes the new pro–Soviet government of Poland.</item>
<item>1949 – United States President Harry S. Truman unveils his Fair Deal program.</item>
<item>1953 – The play Waiting for Godot by Samuel Beckett is first performed.</item>
<item>1957 – In a speech given to the United States Congress, United States President Dwight D. Eisenhower announces the establishment of what will later be called the Eisenhower Doctrine.</item>
<item>1968 – Alexander Dubček comes to power; \"Prague Spring\" begins in Czechoslovakia.</item>
<item>1972 – United States President Richard Nixon orders the development of a Space Shuttle program.</item>
<item>1976 – The Khmer Rouge proclaim the Constitution of Democratic Kampuchea.</item>
<item>1993 – The oil tanker MV Braer runs aground on the coast of the Shetland Islands, spilling 84,700 tons of crude oil.</item>
<item>2014 – A launch of the communication satellite GSAT–14 aboard the GSLV MK.II D5 marks the first successful flight of an Indian cryogenic engine.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>