<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_6">
<item>1017 – Cnut the Great is crowned King of England.</item>
<item>1066 – Harold Godwinson (or Harold II) is crowned King of England.</item>
<item>1205 – Philip of Swabia becomes King of the Romans.</item>
<item>1355 – Charles I of Bohemia is crowned with the Iron Crown of Lombardy as King of Italy in Milan.</item>
<item>1449 – Constantine XI is crowned Byzantine Emperor at Mystras.</item>
<item>1492 – The Catholic Monarchs Ferdinand and Isabella enter Granada, completing the Reconquista.</item>
<item>1540 – King Henry VIII of England marries Anne of Cleves.</item>
<item>1579 – The Union of Arras unites the southern Netherlands under the Duke of Parma, governor in the name of king Philip II of Spain.</item>
<item>1661 – English Restoration: The Fifth Monarchists unsuccessfully attempt to seize control of London, England.</item>
<item>1690 – Joseph, son of Emperor Leopold I, becomes King of the Romans.</item>
<item>1721 – The Committee of Inquiry on the South Sea Bubble publishes its findings.</item>
<item>1838 – Alfred Vail demonstrates a telegraph system using dots and dashes (this is the forerunner of Morse code).</item>
<item>1870 – The inauguration of the Musikverein in Vienna, Austria.</item>
<item>1893 – The Washington National Cathedral is chartered by Congress. The charter is signed by President Benjamin Harrison.</item>
<item>1907 – Maria Montessori opens her first school and daycare center for working class children in Rome, Italy.</item>
<item>1912 – New Mexico is admitted to the Union as the 47th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1912 – German geophysicist Alfred Wegener first presents his theory of continental drift.</item>
<item>1929 – King Alexander of the Serbs, Croats and Slovenes suspends his country\'s constitution (the January 6th Dictatorship).</item>
<item>1929 – Mother Teresa arrives in Calcutta, India, to begin her work among India\'s poorest and sick people.</item>
<item>1931 – Thomas Edison signs his last patent application.</item>
<item>1941 – United States President Franklin D. Roosevelt delivers his Four Freedoms speech in the State of the Union address.</item>
<item>1946 – The first general election ever in Vietnam is held.</item>
<item>1947 – Pan American Airlines becomes the first commercial airline to offer a round–the–world ticket.</item>
<item>1950 – The United Kingdom recognizes the People\'s Republic of China. The Republic of China severs diplomatic relations with the UK in response.</item>
<item>1960 – The Associations Law comes into force in Iraq, allowing registration of political parties.</item>
<item>1974 – In response to the 1973 oil crisis, daylight saving time commences nearly four months early in the United States.</item>
<item>1992 – President of Georgia Zviad Gamsakhurdia flees the country as a result of the military coup.</item>
<item>2001 – The US Congress certifies George W. Bush winner of 2000 presidential election.</item>
<item>2005 – A train collision in Graniteville, South Carolina, releases about 60 tons of chlorine gas.</item>
<item>2017 – The US Congress certifies Donald Trump winner of 2016 presidential election.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>