<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_7">
<item>1325 – Alfonso IV becomes King of Portugal.</item>
<item>1558 – French troops, led by Francis, Duke of Guise, take Calais, the last continental possession of England.</item>
<item>1566 – Pope Pius V is elected.</item>
<item>1610 – Galileo Galilei makes his first observation of the four Galilean moons: Ganymede, Callisto, Io and Europa, although he is not able to distinguish the last two until the following day.</item>
<item>1782 – The first American commercial bank, the Bank of North America, opens.</item>
<item>1785 – Frenchman Jean–Pierre Blanchard and American John Jeffries travel from Dover, England, to Calais, France, in a gas balloon.</item>
<item>1835 – HMS Beagle drops anchor off the Chonos Archipelago.</item>
<item>1894 – William Kennedy Dickson receives a patent for motion picture film.</item>
<item>1904 – The distress signal \"CQD\" is established only to be replaced two years later by \"SOS\".</item>
<item>1919 – Montenegrin guerrilla fighters rebel against the planned annexation of Montenegro by Serbia, but fail.</item>
<item>1920 – The New York State Assembly refuses to seat five duly elected Socialist assemblymen.</item>
<item>1922 – Dáil Éireann ratifies the Anglo–Irish Treaty by a 64–57 vote.</item>
<item>1927 – The first transatlantic telephone service is established from New York City to London.</item>
<item>1931 – Guy Menzies flies the first solo non–stop trans–Tasman flight (from Australia to New Zealand) in 11 hours and 45 minutes, crash–landing on New Zealand\'s west coast.</item>
<item>1948 – Kentucky Air National Guard pilot Thomas Mantell crashes while in pursuit of a supposed UFO.</item>
<item>1954 – Georgetown–IBM experiment: The first public demonstration of a machine translation system, is held in New York at the head office of IBM.</item>
<item>1955 – Contralto Marian Anderson becomes the first person of color to perform at the Metropolitan Opera in Giuseppe Verdi\'s Un ballo in maschera.</item>
<item>1959 – The United States recognizes the new Cuban government of Fidel Castro.</item>
<item>1968 – Surveyor Program: Surveyor 7, the last spacecraft in the Surveyor series, lifts off from launch complex 36A, Cape Canaveral.</item>
<item>1980 – U.S. President Jimmy Carter authorizes legislation giving $1.5 billion in loans to bail out the Chrysler Corporation.</item>
<item>1984 – Brunei becomes the sixth member of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN).</item>
<item>1985 – Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency launches Sakigake, Japan\'s first interplanetary spacecraft and the first deep space probe to be launched by any country other than the United States or the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1991 – Roger Lafontant, former leader of the Tonton Macoute in Haiti under François Duvalier, attempts a coup d\'état, which ends in his arrest.</item>
<item>1993 – The Fourth Republic of Ghana is inaugurated with Jerry Rawlings as President.</item>
<item>1999 – The Senate trial in the impeachment of U.S. President Bill Clinton begins.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>