<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a1_9">
<item>475 – Byzantine Emperor Zeno is forced to flee his capital at Constantinople, and his general, Basiliscus gains control of the empire.</item>
<item>681 – Twelfth Council of Toledo: King Erwig of the Visigoths initiates a council in which he implements diverse measures against the Jews in Spain.</item>
<item>1431 – Judges\' investigations for the trial of Joan of Arc begin in Rouen.</item>
<item>1788 – Connecticut becomes the fifth state to ratify the Constitution.</item>
<item>1792 – Treaty of Jassy between Russian and Ottoman Empire is signed.</item>
<item>1793 – Jean–Pierre Blanchard becomes the first person to fly in a balloon in the United States.</item>
<item>1806 – Admiral Horatio Lord Nelson receives a state funeral and is interred in St Paul\'s Cathedral.</item>
<item>1822 – The Portuguese prince Pedro I of Brazil decides to stay in Brazil against the orders of the Portuguese King João VI, beginning the Brazilian independence process.</item>
<item>1839 – The French Academy of Sciences announces the Daguerreotype photography process.</item>
<item>1858 – Anson Jones, the last President of the Republic of Texas, commits suicide.</item>
<item>1878 – Umberto I becomes King of Italy.</item>
<item>1894 – New England Telephone and Telegraph installs the first battery–operated telephone switchboard in Lexington, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1903 – Hallam Tennyson, 2nd Baron Tennyson, son of the poet Alfred Tennyson, becomes the second Governor–General of Australia.</item>
<item>1909 – Ernest Shackleton, leading the Nimrod Expedition to the South Pole, plants the British flag 97 nautical miles (180 km; 112 mi) from the South Pole, the farthest anyone had ever reached at that time.</item>
<item>1923</item>
<item>1957 – British Prime Minister Sir Anthony Eden resigns from office following his failure to retake the Suez Canal from Egyptian sovereignty.</item>
<item>1960 – President of Egypt Gamal Abdel Nasser opens construction on the Aswan Dam by detonating ten tons of dynamite to demolish twenty tons of granite on the east bank of the Nile.</item>
<item>1961 – British authorities announce they have uncovered the Soviet Portland Spy Ring in London.</item>
<item>1964 – Martyrs\' Day: Several Panamanian youths try to raise the Panamanian flag in the U.S.–controlled Panama Canal Zone, leading to fighting between U.S. military and Panamanian civilians.</item>
<item>1965 – The Mirzapur Cadet College formally opens for academic activities in East Pakistan (now Bangladesh).</item>
<item>1991 – Representatives from the United States and Iraq meet at the Geneva Peace Conference to try to find a peaceful resolution to the Iraqi invasion of Kuwait.</item>
<item>1992 – The Assembly of the Serb People in Bosnia and Herzegovina proclaims the creation of Republika Srpska, a new state within Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1992 – The first discoveries of extrasolar planets are announced by astronomers Aleksander Wolszczan and Dale Frail. They discovered two planets orbiting the pulsar PSR 1257+12.</item>
<item>2005 – Mahmoud Abbas wins the election to succeed Yasser Arafat as President of the Palestinian National Authority, replacing interim president Rawhi Fattouh.</item>
<item>2007 – Apple CEO Steve Jobs introduces the original iPhone at a Macworld keynote in San Francisco.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>