<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_16">
<item>116 – Emperor Trajan sends laureatae to the Roman Senate at Rome on account of his victories and conquest of Parthia.</item>
<item>1249 – Andrew of Longjumeau is dispatched by Louis IX of France as his ambassador to meet with the Khagan of the Mongol Empire.</item>
<item>1630 – Dutch forces led by Hendrick Lonck capture Olinda in what was to become part of Dutch Brazil.</item>
<item>1699 – First Leopoldine Diploma is issued by the Holy Roman Emperor, recognizing the Greek Catholic clergy enjoyed the same privileges as Roman Catholic priests in the Principality of Transylvania.</item>
<item>1742 – Spencer Compton, Earl of Wilmington, becomes British Prime Minister.</item>
<item>1796 – Colombo in Ceylon (now Sri Lanka) falls to the British, completing their invasion of Ceylon.</item>
<item>1881 – The Canadian Pacific Railway is incorporated by Act of Parliament at Ottawa (44th Vic., c.1).</item>
<item>1899 – Iceland\'s first football club, Knattspyrnufélag Reykjavíkur, is founded.</item>
<item>1918 – The Council of Lithuania unanimously adopts the Act of Independence, declaring Lithuania an independent state.</item>
<item>1930 – The Romanian Football Federation joins FIFA.</item>
<item>1933 – The Blaine Act ends Prohibition in the United States.</item>
<item>1936 – Elections bring the Popular Front to power in Spain.</item>
<item>1937 – Wallace H. Carothers receives a United States patent for nylon.</item>
<item>1959 – Fidel Castro becomes Premier of Cuba after dictator Fulgencio Batista was overthrown on January 1.</item>
<item>1960 – The U.S. Navy submarine USS Triton begins Operation Sandblast, setting sail from New London, Connecticut, to begin the first submerged circumnavigation of the globe.</item>
<item>1961 – Explorer program: Explorer 9 (S–56a) is launched.</item>
<item>1968 – In Haleyville, Alabama, the first 9–1–1 emergency telephone system goes into service.</item>
<item>1978 – The first computer bulletin board system is created (CBBS in Chicago).</item>
<item>1985 – Hezbollah is founded.</item>
<item>1986 – The Soviet liner MS Mikhail Lermontov runs aground in the Marlborough Sounds, New Zealand.</item>
<item>2005 – The Kyoto Protocol comes into force, following its ratification by Russia.</item>
<item>2005 – The National Hockey League cancels the entire 2004–05 regular season and playoffs.</item>
<item>2006 – The last Mobile army surgical hospital (MASH) is decommissioned by the United States Army.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>