<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_17">
<item>1411 – Following the successful campaigns during the Ottoman Interregnum, Musa Çelebi, one of the sons of Bayezid I, becomes Sultan with the support of Mircea I of Wallachia.</item>
<item>1621 – Myles Standish is appointed as first military commander of the English Plymouth Colony in North America.</item>
<item>1753 – In Sweden February 17 is followed by March 1 as the country moves from the Julian calendar to the Gregorian calendar.</item>
<item>1801 – An electoral tie between Thomas Jefferson and Aaron Burr is resolved when Jefferson is elected President of the United States and Burr, Vice President by the United States House of Representatives.</item>
<item>1819 – The United States House of Representatives passes the Missouri Compromise for the first time.</item>
<item>1854 – The United Kingdom recognizes the independence of the Orange Free State.</item>
<item>1867 – The first ship passes through the Suez Canal.</item>
<item>1904 – Madama Butterfly receives its première at La Scala in Milan.</item>
<item>1913 – The Armory Show opens in New York City, displaying works of artists who are to become some of the most influential painters of the early 20th century.</item>
<item>1919 – The Ukrainian People\'s Republic asks Entente and the US for help fighting the Bolsheviks.</item>
<item>1933 – Newsweek magazine is first published.</item>
<item>1949 – Chaim Weizmann begins his term as the first President of Israel.</item>
<item>1959 – Project Vanguard: Vanguard 2: The first weather satellite is launched to measure cloud–cover distribution.</item>
<item>1964 – In Wesberry v. Sanders the Supreme Court of the United States rules that congressional districts have to be approximately equal in population.</item>
<item>1964 – Gabonese president Léon M\'ba is toppled by a coup and his rival, Jean–Hilaire Aubame, is installed in his place.</item>
<item>1965 – Project Ranger: The Ranger 8 probe launches on its mission to photograph the Mare Tranquillitatis region of the Moon in preparation for the manned Apollo missions. Mare Tranquillitatis or the \"Sea of Tranquility\" would become the site chosen for the Apollo 11 lunar landing.</item>
<item>1968 – In Springfield, Massachusetts, the Naismith Memorial Basketball Hall of Fame opens.</item>
<item>1972 – Cumulative sales of the Volkswagen Beetle exceed those of the Ford Model T.</item>
<item>1974 – Robert K. Preston, a disgruntled U.S. Army private, buzzes the White House in a stolen helicopter.</item>
<item>1980 – First winter ascent of Mount Everest by Krzysztof Wielicki and Leszek Cichy.</item>
<item>1996 – In Philadelphia, world champion Garry Kasparov beats the Deep Blue supercomputer in a chess match.</item>
<item>1996 – NASA\'s Discovery Program begins as the NEAR Shoemaker spacecraft lifts off on the first mission ever to orbit and land on an asteroid, 433 Eros.</item>
<item>2008 – Kosovo declares independence from Serbia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>