<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_11">
<item>660 BC – Traditional date for the foundation of Japan by Emperor Jimmu.</item>
<item>1177 – John de Courcy\'s army defeats the native Dunleavey Clan in Ulster. The English establish themselves in Ulster.</item>
<item>1534 – Henry VIII of England is recognized as supreme head of the Church of England.</item>
<item>1626 – Emperor Susenyos I of Ethiopia and Patriarch Afonso Mendes declare the primacy of the Roman See over the Ethiopian Church, and Catholicism to be the state religion of Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1659 – The assault on Copenhagen by Swedish forces is beaten back with heavy losses.</item>
<item>1790 – The Religious Society of Friends, also known as Quakers, petitions U.S. Congress for the abolition of slavery.</item>
<item>1794 – First session of United States Senate opens to the public.</item>
<item>1812 – Massachusetts governor Elbridge Gerry is accused of \"gerrymandering\" for the first time.</item>
<item>1826 – University College London is founded as University of London.</item>
<item>1840 – Gaetano Donizetti\'s opera La fille du régiment receives its first performance in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1843 – Giuseppe Verdi\'s opera I Lombardi alla prima crociata receives its first performance in Milan, Italy.</item>
<item>1855 – Kassa Hailu is crowned Tewodros II, Emperor of Ethiopia, by Abuna Salama III in a ceremony at the church of Derasge Maryam</item>
<item>1856 – The Kingdom of Awadh is annexed by the British East India Company and Wajid Ali Shah, the king of Awadh, is imprisoned and later exiled to Calcutta.</item>
<item>1858 – Bernadette Soubirous\'s first vision of the Blessed Virgin Mary in Lourdes, France.</item>
<item>1873 – King Amadeo I of Spain abdicates.</item>
<item>1903 – Anton Bruckner\'s 9th Symphony receives its first performance in Vienna, Austria.</item>
<item>1906 – Pope Pius X publishes the encyclical Vehementer Nos.</item>
<item>1919 – Friedrich Ebert (SPD), is elected President of Germany.</item>
<item>1929 – Kingdom of Italy and the Vatican sign the Lateran Treaty.</item>
<item>1937 – The Flint sit–down strike ends when General Motors recognizes the United Auto Workers trade union.</item>
<item>1938 – BBC Television produces the world\'s first ever science fiction television program, an adaptation of a section of the Karel Čapek play R.U.R., that coined the term \"robot\".</item>
<item>1939 – A Lockheed P–38 Lightning flies from California to New York in seven hours two minutes.</item>
<item>1953 – The Soviet Union breaks off diplomatic relations with Israel.</item>
<item>1959 – The Federation of Arab Emirates of the South, which will later become South Yemen, is created as a protectorate of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1964 – Greeks and Turks begin fighting in Limassol, Cyprus.</item>
<item>1978 – Censorship: China lifts a ban on works by Aristotle, William Shakespeare and Charles Dickens.</item>
<item>1981 – Around 100,000 US gallons (380 m3) of radioactive coolant leak into the containment building of TVA Sequoyah 1 nuclear plant in Tennessee, contaminating eight workers.</item>
<item>1990 – Nelson Mandela is released from Victor Verster Prison outside Cape Town, South Africa after 27 years as a political prisoner.</item>
<item>1990 – Buster Douglas, a 42:1 underdog, knocks out Mike Tyson in ten rounds at Tokyo to win boxing\'s world Heavyweight title.</item>
<item>1997 – Space Shuttle Discovery is launched on a mission to service the Hubble Space Telescope.</item>
<item>1999 – Pluto crosses Neptune\'s orbit, ending a nearly 20–year period (since 1979) when it was closer to the Sun than the gas giant; Pluto is not expected to interact with Neptune\'s orbit for another 228 years.</item>
<item>2001 – A Dutch programmer launched the Anna Kournikova virus infecting millions of emails via a trick photo of the tennis star.</item>
<item>2006 – U.S. Vice President Dick Cheney shot Harry Whittington, a 78–year–old Texas attorney, while participating in a quail hunt on a ranch in Riviera, Texas.</item>
<item>2013 – The Vatican confirmed that Pope Benedict XVI would resign the papacy on 28 February 2013, as a result of his advanced age.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>