<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_18">
<item>1229 – The Sixth Crusade: Frederick II, Holy Roman Emperor signs a ten–year truce with al–Kamil, regaining Jerusalem, Nazareth, and Bethlehem with neither military engagements nor support from the papacy.</item>
<item>1332 – Amda Seyon I, Emperor of Ethiopia begins his campaigns in the southern Muslim provinces.</item>
<item>1745 – The city of Surakarta, Central Java is founded on the banks of Bengawan Solo River, and becomes the capital of the Sunanate of Surakarta Hadiningrat.</item>
<item>1766 – A mutiny by captive Malagasy begins at sea on the slave ship Meermin, leading to the ship\'s destruction on Cape Agulhas in present–day South Africa and the recapture of the instigators.</item>
<item>1791 – Congress passes a law admitting the state of Vermont to the Union, effective 4 March, after that state had existed for 14 years as a de facto independent largely unrecognized state.</item>
<item>1861 – In Montgomery, Alabama, Jefferson Davis is inaugurated as the provisional President of the Confederate States of America.</item>
<item>1861 – With Italian unification almost complete, Victor Emmanuel II of Piedmont, Savoy and Sardinia assumes the title of King of Italy.</item>
<item>1885 – Adventures of Huckleberry Finn by Mark Twain is published in the United States.</item>
<item>1906 – Édouard de Laveleye forms the Belgian Olympic Committee in Brussels.</item>
<item>1911 – The first official flight with airmail takes place from Allahabad, United Provinces, British India (now India), when Henri Pequet, a 23–year–old pilot, delivers 6,500 letters to Naini, about 10 kilometres (6.2 mi) away.</item>
<item>1930 – While studying photographs taken in January, Clyde Tombaugh discovers Pluto.</item>
<item>1930 – Elm Farm Ollie becomes the first cow to fly in a fixed–wing aircraft and also the first cow to be milked in an aircraft.</item>
<item>1932 – The Empire of Japan declares a puppet state of Manzhouguo (the obsolete Chinese name for Manchuria) independent from the Republic of China and installed former Chinese Emperor Aisin Gioro Puyi as Chief Executive of the State.</item>
<item>1954 – The first Church of Scientology is established in Los Angeles.</item>
<item>1955 – Operation Teapot: Teapot test shot \"Wasp\" is successfully detonated at the Nevada Test Site with a yield of 1.2 kilotons. Wasp is the first of fourteen shots in the Teapot series.</item>
<item>1965 – The Gambia becomes independent from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1970 – The Chicago Seven are found not guilty of conspiring to incite riots at the 1968 Democratic National Convention.</item>
<item>1977 – The Space Shuttle Enterprise test vehicle is carried on its maiden \"flight\" on top of a Boeing 747.</item>
<item>1979 – Richard Petty wins a then–record sixth Daytona 500 after leaders Donnie Allison and Cale Yarborough crash on the final lap of the first NASCAR race televised live flag–to–flag.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>