<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_10">
<item>1258 – Mongol invasions: Baghdad falls to the Mongols, bringing the Islamic Golden Age to an end.</item>
<item>1840 – Queen Victoria of the United Kingdom marries Prince Albert of Saxe–Coburg–Gotha.</item>
<item>1861 – Jefferson Davis is notified by telegraph that he has been chosen as provisional President of the Confederate States of America.</item>
<item>1870 – The YWCA is founded in New York City.</item>
<item>1920 – Józef Haller de Hallenburg performs symbolic wedding of Poland to the sea, celebrating restitution of Polish access to open sea.</item>
<item>1923 – Texas Tech University is founded as Texas Technological College in Lubbock, Texas</item>
<item>1930 – The Việt Nam Quốc Dân Đảng launches the failed Yên Bái mutiny in hope to overthrow French protectorate over Vietnam.</item>
<item>1940 – The Soviet Union begins mass deportations of Polish citizens from occupied eastern Poland to Siberia.</item>
<item>1940 – Tom and Jerry make their debut with Puss Gets the Boot.</item>
<item>1947 – Crowds gathered at shop windows in Paris to see Christian Dior\'s New Look fashion—longer skirts, nipped–in waists and padded shoulders.</item>
<item>1962 – Roy Lichtenstein\'s first solo exhibition opened, and it included Look Mickey, which featured his first employment of Ben–Day dots, speech balloons and comic imagery sourcing, all of which he is now known for.</item>
<item>1967 – The 25th Amendment to the United States Constitution is ratified.</item>
<item>1972 – Ras Al Khaimah joins the United Arab Emirates, now making up seven emirates.</item>
<item>1989 – Ron Brown is elected chairman of the Democratic National Committee becoming the first African American to lead a major American political party.</item>
<item>1996 – IBM supercomputer Deep Blue defeats Garry Kasparov in chess for the first time.</item>
<item>2007 – Then Illinois senator Barack Obama announces his candidacy for president in the 2008 elections, which he later goes on to win.</item>
<item>2016 – South Korea decides to stop the operation of the Kaesong joint industrial complex with North Korea in response to the launch of Kwangmyŏngsŏng–4.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>