<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_14">
<item>842 – Charles the Bald and Louis the German swear the Oaths of Strasbourg in the French and German languages.</item>
<item>1014 – Pope Benedict VIII crowns Henry of Bavaria, King of Germany and of Italy, as Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1076 – Pope Gregory VII excommunicates Henry IV, Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1130 – Pope Innocent II is elected.</item>
<item>1530 – Spanish conquistadores, led by Nuño de Guzmán, overthrow and execute Tangaxuan II, the last independent monarch of the Tarascan state in present–day central Mexico.</item>
<item>1556 – Thomas Cranmer is declared a heretic.</item>
<item>1556 – Coronation of Akbar.</item>
<item>1778 – The United States flag is formally recognized by a foreign naval vessel for the first time, when French Admiral Toussaint–Guillaume Picquet de la Motte renders a nine gun salute to USS Ranger, commanded by John Paul Jones.</item>
<item>1804 – Karađorđe leads the First Serbian Uprising against the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1835 – The original Quorum of the Twelve Apostles, in the Latter Day Saint movement, is formed in Kirtland, Ohio.</item>
<item>1849 – In New York City, James Knox Polk becomes the first serving President of the United States to have his photograph taken.</item>
<item>1852 – Great Ormond St Hospital for Sick Children, the first hospital in England to provide in–patient beds specifically for children, is founded in London.</item>
<item>1855 – Texas is linked by telegraph to the rest of the United States, with the completion of a connection between New Orleans and Marshall, Texas.</item>
<item>1859 – Oregon is admitted as the 33rd U.S. state.</item>
<item>1876 – Alexander Graham Bell applies for a patent for the telephone, as does Elisha Gray.</item>
<item>1899 – Voting machines are approved by the U.S. Congress for use in federal elections.</item>
<item>1903 – The United States Department of Commerce and Labor is established (later split into the Department of Commerce and the Department of Labor).</item>
<item>1912 – Arizona is admitted as the 48th and the last contiguous U.S. state.</item>
<item>1918 – The Soviet Union adopts the Gregorian calendar (on 1 February according to the Julian calendar).</item>
<item>1920 – The League of Women Voters is founded in Chicago.</item>
<item>1924 – The Computing–Tabulating–Recording Company changes its name to International Business Machines Corporation (IBM).</item>
<item>1945 – President Franklin D. Roosevelt meets with King Ibn Saud of Saudi Arabia aboard the USS Quincy, officially beginning U.S.–Saudi diplomatic relations.</item>
<item>1946 – The Bank of England is nationalized.</item>
<item>1949 – The Knesset (Israeli parliament) convenes for the first time.</item>
<item>1950 – The Sino–Soviet Treaty of Friendship, Alliance and Mutual Assistance is signed.</item>
<item>1961 – Discovery of the chemical elements: Element 103, Lawrencium, is first synthesized at the University of California.</item>
<item>1966 – Australian currency is decimalized.</item>
<item>1983 – United American Bank of Knoxville, Tennessee collapses. Its president, Jake Butcher, is later convicted of fraud.</item>
<item>1990 – The Voyager 1 spacecraft takes the photograph of planet Earth that later become famous as Pale Blue Dot.</item>
<item>2000 – The spacecraft NEAR Shoemaker enters orbit around asteroid 433 Eros, the first spacecraft to orbit an asteroid.</item>
<item>2005 – YouTube is launched by a group of college students, eventually becoming the largest video sharing website in the world and a main source for viral videos.</item>
<item>2011 – As a part of Arab Spring, the Bahraini uprising begins with a \'Day of Rage\'.</item>
<item>2018 – Jacob Zuma resigns as President of South Africa.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>