<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_1">
<item>481 – Vandal king Huneric organises a conference between Catholic and Arian bishops at Carthage.</item>
<item>1329 – King John of Bohemia captures Medvėgalis, an important fortress of the pagan Grand Duchy of Lithuania, and baptizes 6,000 of its defenders</item>
<item>1411 – The First Peace of Thorn is signed in Thorn (Toruń), Monastic State of the Teutonic Knights (Prussia).</item>
<item>1662 – The Chinese general Koxinga seizes the island of Taiwan after a nine–month siege.</item>
<item>1713 – The Kalabalik or Tumult in Bendery results from the Ottoman sultan\'s order that his unwelcome guest, King Charles XII of Sweden, be seized.</item>
<item>1835 – Slavery is abolished in Mauritius.</item>
<item>1865 – President Abraham Lincoln signs the Thirteenth Amendment to the United States Constitution.</item>
<item>1884 – The first volume (A to Ant) of the Oxford English Dictionary is published.</item>
<item>1893 – Thomas A. Edison finishes construction of the first motion picture studio, the Black Maria in West Orange, New Jersey.</item>
<item>1895 – Fountains Valley, Pretoria, the oldest nature reserve in Africa, is proclaimed by President Paul Kruger.</item>
<item>1896 – La bohème premieres in Turin at the Teatro Regio (Turin), conducted by the young Arturo Toscanini.</item>
<item>1897 – Shinhan Bank, the oldest bank in South Korea, opens in Seoul.</item>
<item>1918 – Russia adopts the Gregorian calendar.</item>
<item>1924 – The United Kingdom recognizes the USSR.</item>
<item>1942 – Voice of America, the official external radio and television service of the United States government, begins broadcasting with programs aimed at areas controlled by the Axis powers.</item>
<item>1942 – Mao Zedong makes a speech on \"Reform in Learning, the Party and Literature\", which puts into motion the Yan\'an Rectification Movement.</item>
<item>1946 – Trygve Lie of Norway is picked to be the first United Nations Secretary–General.</item>
<item>1946 – The Parliament of Hungary abolishes the monarchy after nine centuries, and proclaims the Hungarian Republic.</item>
<item>1953 – North Sea flood of 1953 is caused by a heavy storm which occurred overnight, 31 January–1 February 1953; floods strike the Netherlands, Belgium and the U.K.</item>
<item>1960 – Four black students stage the first of the Greensboro sit–ins at a lunch counter in Greensboro, North Carolina.</item>
<item>1964 – The Beatles have their first number one hit in the United States with \"I Want to Hold Your Hand\".</item>
<item>1965 – The Hamilton River in Labrador, Canada is renamed the Churchill River in honour of Winston Churchill.</item>
<item>1968 – Canada\'s three military services, the Royal Canadian Navy, the Canadian Army and the Royal Canadian Air Force, are unified into the Canadian Forces.</item>
<item>1968 – The New York Central Railroad and the Pennsylvania Railroad are merged to form Penn Central Transportation.</item>
<item>1972 – Kuala Lumpur becomes a city by a royal charter granted by the Yang di–Pertuan Agong of Malaysia.</item>
<item>1979 – Iranian Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini returns to Tehran after nearly 15 years of exile.</item>
<item>1989 – The Western Australian towns of Kalgoorlie and Boulder amalgamate to form the City of Kalgoorlie–Boulder.</item>
<item>1996 – The Communications Decency Act is passed by the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>2005 – King Gyanendra of Nepal carries out a coup d\'état to capture the democracy, becoming Chairman of the Councils of ministers.</item>
<item>2009 – The first cabinet of Jóhanna Sigurðardóttir was formed in Iceland, making her the country\'s first female prime minister and the world\'s first openly gay head of government.</item>
<item>2013 – The Shard, the tallest building in the European Union, is opened to the public.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>