<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_19">
<item>356 – Emperor Constantius II issues a decree closing all pagan temples in the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1594 – Having already been elected to the throne of the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth in 1587, Sigismund III of the House of Vasa is crowned King of Sweden, having succeeded his father John III of Sweden in 1592.</item>
<item>1600 – The Peruvian stratovolcano Huaynaputina explodes in the most violent eruption in the recorded history of South America.</item>
<item>1726 – The Supreme Privy Council is established in Russia.</item>
<item>1807 – Former Vice President of the United States Aaron Burr is arrested for treason in Wakefield, Alabama and confined to Fort Stoddert.</item>
<item>1819 – British explorer William Smith discovers the South Shetland Islands and claims them in the name of King George III.</item>
<item>1846 – In Austin, Texas the newly formed Texas state government is officially installed. The Republic of Texas government officially transfers power to the State of Texas government following the annexation of Texas by the United States.</item>
<item>1847 – The first group of rescuers reaches the Donner Party.</item>
<item>1878 – Thomas Edison patents the phonograph.</item>
<item>1913 – Pedro Lascuráin becomes President of Mexico for 45 minutes; this is the shortest term to date of any person as president of any country.</item>
<item>1948 – The Conference of Youth and Students of Southeast Asia Fighting for Freedom and Independence convenes in Calcutta.</item>
<item>1953 – Censorship: Georgia approves the first literature censorship board in the United States.</item>
<item>1954 – Transfer of Crimea: The Soviet Politburo of the Soviet Union orders the transfer of the Crimean Oblast from the Russian SFSR to the Ukrainian SSR.</item>
<item>1959 – The United Kingdom grants Cyprus independence, which is formally proclaimed on August 16, 1960.</item>
<item>1960 – China successfully launches the T–7, its first sounding rocket.</item>
<item>1963 – The publication of Betty Friedan\'s The Feminine Mystique reawakens the feminist movement in the United States as women\'s organizations and consciousness raising groups spread.</item>
<item>1965 – Colonel Phạm Ngọc Thảo of the Army of the Republic of Vietnam, and a communist spy of the North Vietnamese Viet Minh, along with Generals Lâm Văn Phát and Trần Thiện Khiêm, all Catholics, attempt a coup against the military junta of the Buddhist Nguyễn Khánh.</item>
<item>1976 – Executive Order 9066, which led to the relocation of Japanese Americans to internment camps, is rescinded by President Gerald Ford\'s Proclamation 4417.</item>
<item>1985 – William J. Schroeder becomes the first recipient of an artificial heart to leave hospital.</item>
<item>1986 – Akkaraipattu massacre: the Sri Lankan Army massacres 80 Tamil farm workers in eastern Sri Lanka.</item>
<item>2002 – NASA\'s Mars Odyssey space probe begins to map the surface of Mars using its thermal emission imaging system.</item>
<item>2011 – The debut exhibition of the Belitung shipwreck, containing the largest collection of Tang dynasty artifacts found in one location, begins in Singapore.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>