<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_23">
<item>303 – Roman emperor Diocletian orders the destruction of the Christian church in Nicomedia, beginning eight years of Diocletianic Persecution.</item>
<item>532 – Byzantine emperor Justinian I orders the building of a new Orthodox Christian basilica in Constantinople – the Hagia Sophia.</item>
<item>1455 – Traditional date for the publication of the Gutenberg Bible, the first Western book printed with movable type.</item>
<item>1739 – At York Castle, the outlaw Dick Turpin is identified by his former schoolteacher. Turpin had been using the name Richard Palmer.</item>
<item>1854 – The official independence of the Orange Free State is declared.</item>
<item>1883 – Alabama becomes the first U.S. state to enact an anti–trust law.</item>
<item>1886 – Charles Martin Hall produced the first samples of man–made aluminium, after several years of intensive work. He was assisted in this project by his older sister, Julia Brainerd Hall.</item>
<item>1898 – Émile Zola is imprisoned in France after writing J\'Accuse…!, a letter accusing the French government of antisemitism and wrongfully imprisoning Captain Alfred Dreyfus.</item>
<item>1903 – Cuba leases Guantánamo Bay to the United States \"in perpetuity\".</item>
<item>1905 – Chicago attorney Paul Harris and three other businessmen meet for lunch to form the Rotary Club, the world\'s first service club.</item>
<item>1909 – The AEA Silver Dart makes the first powered flight in Canada and the British Empire.</item>
<item>1927 – U.S. President Calvin Coolidge signs a bill by Congress establishing the Federal Radio Commission (later replaced by the Federal Communications Commission) which was to regulate the use of radio frequencies in the United States.</item>
<item>1927 – German theoretical physicist Werner Heisenberg writes a letter to fellow physicist Wolfgang Pauli, in which he describes his uncertainty principle for the first time.</item>
<item>1934 – Leopold III becomes King of Belgium.</item>
<item>1941 – Plutonium is first produced and isolated by Dr. Glenn T. Seaborg.</item>
<item>1943 – Greek Resistance: The United Panhellenic Organization of Youth is founded in Greece.</item>
<item>1944 – The Soviet Union begins the forced deportation of the Chechen and Ingush people from the North Caucasus to Central Asia.</item>
<item>1947 – International Organization for Standardization is founded.</item>
<item>1954 – The first mass inoculation of children against polio with the Salk vaccine begins in Pittsburgh.</item>
<item>1966 – In Syria, Ba\'ath Party member Salah Jadid leads an intra–party military coup that replaces the previous government of General Amin al–Hafiz, also a Baathist.</item>
<item>1981 – In Spain, Antonio Tejero attempts a coup d\'état by capturing the Spanish Congress of Deputies.</item>
<item>1983 – The United States Environmental Protection Agency announces its intent to buy out and evacuate the dioxin–contaminated community of Times Beach, Missouri.</item>
<item>1987 – Supernova 1987a is seen in the Large Magellanic Cloud.</item>
<item>1991 – In Thailand, General Sunthorn Kongsompong leads a bloodless coup d\'état, deposing Prime Minister Chatichai Choonhavan.</item>
<item>1999 – Kurdish rebel leader Abdullah Öcalan is charged with treason in Ankara, Turkey.</item>
<item>2017 – The Turkish–backed Free Syrian Army captures Al–Bab from ISIL.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>