<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_2">
<item>506 – Alaric II, eighth king of the Visigoths promulgates the Breviary of Alaric (Breviarium Alaricianum or Lex Romana Visigothorum), a collection of \"Roman law\".</item>
<item>962 – Translatio imperii: Pope John XII crowns Otto I, Holy Roman Emperor, the first Holy Roman Emperor in nearly 40 years.</item>
<item>1032 – Conrad II, Holy Roman Emperor becomes king of Burgundy.</item>
<item>1207 – Terra Mariana, eventually comprising present–day Latvia and Estonia, is established.</item>
<item>1536 – Spaniard Pedro de Mendoza founds Buenos Aires, Argentina.</item>
<item>1653 – New Amsterdam (later renamed The City of New York) is incorporated.</item>
<item>1709 – Alexander Selkirk is rescued after being shipwrecked on a desert island, inspiring Daniel Defoe\'s adventure book Robinson Crusoe.</item>
<item>1876 – The National League of Professional Baseball Clubs of Major League Baseball is formed.</item>
<item>1887 – In Punxsutawney, Pennsylvania the first Groundhog Day is observed.</item>
<item>1899 – The Australian Premiers\' Conference held in Melbourne decides to locate Australia\'s capital city, Canberra, between Sydney and Melbourne.</item>
<item>1901 – Funeral of Queen Victoria.</item>
<item>1913 – Grand Central Terminal is opened in New York City.</item>
<item>1920 – The Tartu Peace Treaty is signed between Estonia and Russia.</item>
<item>1920 – France occupies Memel.</item>
<item>1922 – Ulysses by James Joyce is published.</item>
<item>1925 – Serum run to Nome: Dog sleds reach Nome, Alaska with diphtheria serum, inspiring the Iditarod race.</item>
<item>1934 – The Export–Import Bank of the United States is incorporated.</item>
<item>1971 – Idi Amin replaces President Milton Obote as leader of Uganda.</item>
<item>1971 – The international Ramsar Convention for the conservation and sustainable utilization of wetlands is signed in Ramsar, Mazandaran, Iran.</item>
<item>1980 – Reports surface that the FBI is targeting allegedly corrupt Congressmen in the Abscam operation.</item>
<item>1990 – Apartheid: F. W. de Klerk announces the unbanning of the African National Congress and promises to release Nelson Mandela.</item>
<item>2000 – First digital cinema projection in Europe (Paris) realized by Philippe Binant with the DLP CINEMA technology developed by Texas Instruments.</item>
<item>2004 – Swiss tennis player Roger Federer becomes the No. 1 ranked men\'s singles player, a position he will hold for a record 237 weeks.</item>
<item>2005 – The Government of Canada introduces the Civil Marriage Act. This legislation would become law on July 20, 2005, legalizing same–sex marriage.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>