<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_28">
<item>202 BC – Liu Bang is enthroned as the Emperor of China, beginning four centuries of rule by the Han dynasty.</item>
<item>870 – The Fourth Council of Constantinople closes.</item>
<item>1246 – The siege of Jaén ends in the context of the Spanish Reconquista resulting in the Castilian takeover of the city from the Taifa of Jaen.</item>
<item>1638 – The Scottish National Covenant is signed in Edinburgh.</item>
<item>1700 – Today is followed by March 1 in Sweden, thus creating the Swedish calendar.</item>
<item>1784 – John Wesley charters the Methodist Church.</item>
<item>1827 – The Baltimore and Ohio Railroad is incorporated, becoming the first railroad in America offering commercial transportation of both people and freight.</item>
<item>1838 – Robert Nelson, leader of the Patriotes, proclaims the independence of Lower Canada (today Quebec).</item>
<item>1849 – Regular steamship service from the east to the west coast of the United States begins with the arrival of the SS California in San Francisco Bay, four months 22 days after leaving New York Harbor.</item>
<item>1867 – Seventy years of Holy See–United States relations are ended by a Congressional ban on federal funding of diplomatic envoys to the Vatican and are not restored until January 10, 1984.</item>
<item>1870 – The Bulgarian Exarchate is established by decree of Sultan Abdülaziz of the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1874 – One of the longest cases ever heard in an English court ends when the defendant is convicted of perjury for attempting to assume the identity of the heir to the Tichborne baronetcy.</item>
<item>1897 – Queen Ranavalona III, the last monarch of Madagascar, is deposed by a French military force.</item>
<item>1904 – S.L. Benfica is founded in Portugal.</item>
<item>1922 – The United Kingdom ends its protectorate over Egypt through a Unilateral Declaration of Independence.</item>
<item>1935 – DuPont scientist Wallace Carothers invents nylon.</item>
<item>1939 – The erroneous word \"dord\" is discovered in the Webster\'s New International Dictionary, Second Edition, prompting an investigation.</item>
<item>1940 – Basketball is televised for the first time (Fordham University vs. the University of Pittsburgh in Madison Square Garden).</item>
<item>1947 – February 28 Incident: In Taiwan, civil disorder is put down with the loss of an estimated 30,000 civilians.</item>
<item>1953 – James Watson and Francis Crick announce to friends that they have determined the chemical structure of DNA; the formal announcement takes place on April 25 following publication in April\'s Nature (pub. April 2).</item>
<item>1954 – The first color television sets using the NTSC standard are offered for sale to the general public.</item>
<item>1959 – Discoverer 1, an American spy satellite that is the first object intended to achieve a polar orbit, is launched but fails to achieve orbit.</item>
<item>1972 – China–United States relations: The United States and China sign the Shanghai Communiqué.</item>
<item>1980 – Andalusia approves its statute of autonomy through a referendum.</item>
<item>1983 – The final episode of M*A*S*H airs, with almost 106 million viewers. It still holds the record for the highest viewership of a season finale.</item>
<item>1995 – Former Australian Liberal party leader John Hewson resigns from the Australian parliament almost two years after losing the Australian federal election, 1993.</item>
<item>1997 – GRB 970228, a highly luminous flash of gamma rays, strikes the Earth for 80 seconds, providing early evidence that gamma–ray bursts occur well beyond the Milky Way.</item>
<item>1998 – First flight of RQ–4 Global Hawk, the first unmanned aerial vehicle certified to file its own flight plans and fly regularly in U.S. civilian airspace.</item>
<item>2004 – Over one million Taiwanese participate in the 228 Hand–in–Hand rally form a 500–kilometre (310 mi) long human chain to commemorate the February 28 Incident in 1947</item>
<item>2013 – Pope Benedict XVI resigns as the pope of the Catholic Church, becoming the first pope to do so since Pope Gregory XII, in 1415.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>