<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_24">
<item>303 – Galerius publishes his edict that begins the persecution of Christians in his portion of the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1538 – Treaty of Nagyvárad between Ferdinand I and John Zápolya.</item>
<item>1582 – With the papal bull Inter gravissimas, Pope Gregory XIII announces the Gregorian calendar.</item>
<item>1607 – L\'Orfeo by Claudio Monteverdi, one of the first works recognized as an opera, receives its première performance.</item>
<item>1711 – The London première of Rinaldo by George Frideric Handel, the first Italian opera written for the London stage.</item>
<item>1803 – In Marbury v. Madison, the Supreme Court of the United States establishes the principle of judicial review.</item>
<item>1822 – The first Swaminarayan temple in the world, Shri Swaminarayan Mandir, Ahmedabad, is inaugurated.</item>
<item>1831 – The Treaty of Dancing Rabbit Creek, the first removal treaty in accordance with the Indian Removal Act, is proclaimed. The Choctaws in Mississippi cede land east of the river in exchange for payment and land in the West.</item>
<item>1848 – King Louis–Philippe of France abdicates the throne.</item>
<item>1854 – A Penny Red with perforations was the first perforated postage stamp to be officially issued for distribution.</item>
<item>1863 – Arizona is organized as a United States territory.</item>
<item>1868 – Andrew Johnson becomes the first President of the United States to be impeached by the United States House of Representatives. He is later acquitted in the Senate.</item>
<item>1881 – China and Russia sign the Sino–Russian Ili Treaty.</item>
<item>1916 – The Governor–General of Korea establishes a clinic called Jahyewon in Sorokdo to segregate Hansen\'s disease patients.</item>
<item>1918 – Estonian Declaration of Independence.</item>
<item>1920 – Nancy Astor became the first woman to speak in the House of Commons of the United Kingdom following her election as a Member of Parliament (MP) three months earlier.</item>
<item>1944 – Merrill\'s Marauders: The Marauders begin their 1,000–mile journey through Japanese occupied Burma.</item>
<item>1946 – Colonel Juan Perón, founder of the political movement that became known as Peronism, is elected to his first term as President of Argentina.</item>
<item>1976 – The current constitution of Cuba is formally proclaimed.</item>
<item>1980 – The United States Olympic hockey team completes its Miracle on Ice by defeating Finland 4–2 to win the gold medal.</item>
<item>1989 – United Airlines Flight 811, bound for New Zealand from Honolulu, rips open during flight, blowing nine passengers out of the business–class section.</item>
<item>1996 – Two civilian airplanes operated by the Miami–based group Brothers to the Rescue are shot down in international waters by the Cuban Air Force.</item>
<item>2006 – Philippine President Gloria Macapagal Arroyo declares Proclamation 1017 placing the country in a state of emergency in attempt to subdue a possible military coup.</item>
<item>2007 – Japan launches its fourth spy satellite, stepping up its ability to monitor potential threats such as North Korea.</item>
<item>2008 – Fidel Castro retires as the President of Cuba and the Council of Ministers after 32 years. He remains as head of the Communist Party for another three years.</item>
<item>2016 – Tara Air Flight 193, a de Havilland Canada DHC–6 Twin Otter aircraft, crashed, with 23 fatalities, in Solighopte, Myagdi District, Dhaulagiri Zone, while en route from Pokhara Airport to Jomsom Airport.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>