<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_26">
<item>747 BC – Epoch (origin) of Ptolemy\'s Nabonassar Era.</item>
<item>364 – Valentinian I is proclaimed Roman emperor.</item>
<item>1606 – The Janszoon voyage of 1605–06 becomes the first European expedition to sight Australia, although it is mistaken as a part of New Guinea.</item>
<item>1616 – Galileo Galilei is formally banned by the Roman Catholic Church from teaching or defending the view that the earth orbits the sun.</item>
<item>1815 – Napoleon Bonaparte escapes from Elba.</item>
<item>1876 – Japan and Korea sign a treaty granting Japanese citizens extraterritoriality rights, opening three ports to Japanese trade, and ending Korea\'s status as a tributary state of Qing dynasty China.</item>
<item>1909 – Kinemacolor, the first successful color motion picture process, is first shown to the general public at the Palace Theatre in London.</item>
<item>1914 – HMHS Britannic, sister to the RMS Titanic, is launched at Harland and Wolff shipyard in Belfast.</item>
<item>1919 – President Woodrow Wilson signs an act of Congress establishing the Grand Canyon National Park.</item>
<item>1929 – President Calvin Coolidge signs an executive order establishing the 96,000 acre Grand Teton National Park in Wyoming.</item>
<item>1935 – Robert Watson–Watt carries out a demonstration near Daventry which leads directly to the development of radar in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1936 – In the February 26 Incident, young Japanese military officers attempt to stage a coup against the government.</item>
<item>1952 – Vincent Massey is sworn in as the first Canadian–born Governor General of Canada.</item>
<item>1966 – Apollo program: Launch of AS–201, the first flight of the Saturn IB rocket</item>
<item>1971 – U.N. Secretary–General U Thant signs United Nations proclamation of the vernal equinox as Earth Day.</item>
<item>1979 – The Superliner railcar enters revenue service with Amtrak.</item>
<item>1980 – Egypt and Israel establish full diplomatic relations.</item>
<item>1987 – Iran–Contra affair: The Tower Commission rebukes President Ronald Reagan for not controlling his national security staff.</item>
<item>1995 – The UK\'s oldest investment banking institute, Barings Bank, collapses after a rogue securities broker Nick Leeson loses $1.4 billion by speculating on the Singapore International Monetary Exchange using futures contracts.</item>
<item>2008 – The New York Philharmonic performs in Pyongyang, North Korea; this is the first event of its kind to take place in North Korea.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>