<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_25">
<item>138 – The Roman emperor Hadrian adopts Antoninus Pius, effectively making him his successor.</item>
<item>493 – Odoacer surrenders Ravenna after a 3–year siege and agrees to a mediated peace with Theoderic the Great.</item>
<item>628 – Khosrow II, the last great king of the Sasanian Empire, is overthrown by his son Kavadh II.</item>
<item>1336 – Four thousand defenders of Pilėnai commit mass suicide rather than be taken captive by the Teutonic Knights.</item>
<item>1631 – François de Bassompierre, a French courtier, is arrested on Richelieu\'s orders.</item>
<item>1836 – Samuel Colt is granted a United States patent for the Colt revolver.</item>
<item>1843 – Lord George Paulet occupies the Kingdom of Hawaii in the name of Great Britain in the Paulet Affair (1843).</item>
<item>1847 – State University of Iowa is founded in Iowa City, Iowa.</item>
<item>1866 – Miners in Calaveras County, California, discover what is now called the Calaveras Skull – human remains that supposedly indicated that man, mastodons, and elephants had co–existed.</item>
<item>1870 – Hiram Rhodes Revels, a Republican from Mississippi, is sworn into the United States Senate, becoming the first African American ever to sit in the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1875 – Guangxu Emperor of Qing dynasty China begins his reign, under Empress Dowager Cixi\'s regency.</item>
<item>1901 – J. P. Morgan incorporates the United States Steel Corporation.</item>
<item>1912 – Marie–Adélaïde, the eldest of six daughters of Guillaume IV, becomes the first reigning Grand Duchess of Luxembourg.</item>
<item>1919 – Oregon places a one cent per U.S. gallon tax on gasoline, becoming the first U.S. state to levy a gasoline tax.</item>
<item>1921 – Tbilisi, capital of the Democratic Republic of Georgia, is occupied by Bolshevist Russia.</item>
<item>1928 – Charles Jenkins Laboratories of Washington, D.C. becomes the first holder of a broadcast license for television from the Federal Radio Commission.</item>
<item>1933 – The USS Ranger is launched. It is the first US Navy ship to be designed from the start of construction as an aircraft carrier.</item>
<item>1947 – The formal abolition of Prussia is proclaimed by the Allied Control Council. The Prussian government had already been abolished by the Preußenschlag of 1932.</item>
<item>1951 – The first Pan American Games were officially opened in Buenos Aires, Argentina by President Juan Perón.</item>
<item>1954 – Gamal Abdel Nasser is made premier of Egypt.</item>
<item>1964 – North Korean Prime Minister Kim Il–sung calls for the removal of feudalistic land ownership aimed at turning all cooperative farms into state–run ones.</item>
<item>1980 – The government of Suriname is overthrown by a military coup led by Dési Bouterse.</item>
<item>1987 – Southern Methodist University\'s football program is the first college football program to be banned from competition by the NCAA\'s Committee on Infractions.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>