<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_4">
<item>960 – The coronation of Zhao Kuangyin as Emperor Taizu of Song, initiating the Song dynasty period of China that would last more than three centuries.</item>
<item>1488 – Bartolomeu Dias commands the first European expedition to reach South Africa and the Indian Ocean.</item>
<item>1758 – Macapá, Brazil is founded.</item>
<item>1789 – George Washington is unanimously elected as the first President of the United States by the U.S. Electoral College.</item>
<item>1801 – John Marshall is sworn in as Chief Justice of the United States.</item>
<item>1810 – The Royal Navy seizes Guadeloupe.</item>
<item>1820 – The Chilean Navy under the command of Lord Cochrane completes the 2–day long Capture of Valdivia with just 300 men and 2 ships.</item>
<item>1825 – The Ohio Legislature authorizes the construction of the Ohio and Erie Canal and the Miami and Erie Canal.</item>
<item>1859 – The Codex Sinaiticus is discovered in Egypt.</item>
<item>1941 – The United Service Organization (USO) is created to entertain American troops.</item>
<item>1948 – Ceylon (later renamed Sri Lanka) becomes independent within the British Commonwealth.</item>
<item>1967 – Lunar Orbiter program: Lunar Orbiter 3 lifts off from Cape Canaveral\'s Launch Complex 13 on its mission to identify possible landing sites for the Surveyor and Apollo spacecraft.</item>
<item>1969 – Yasser Arafat takes over as chairman of the Palestine Liberation Organization.</item>
<item>1992 – A coup d\'état is led by Hugo Chávez against Venezuelan President Carlos Andrés Pérez.</item>
<item>1999 – Unarmed West African immigrant Amadou Diallo is shot 41 times by four plainclothes New York City police officers on an unrelated stake–out, inflaming race relations in the city.</item>
<item>2003 – The Federal Republic of Yugoslavia adopts a new constitution, becoming a loose confederacy between Montenegro and Serbia.</item>
<item>2004 – Facebook, a mainstream online social networking site, is founded by Mark Zuckerberg.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>