<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_5">
<item>756 – An Lushan, leader of a revolt against the Tang Dynasty, declares himself emperor and establishes the state of Yan.</item>
<item>789 – Idris I reaches Volubilis and founds the Idrisid dynasty, ceding Morocco from the Abbasid caliphate and founding the first Moroccan state.</item>
<item>1649 – Charles Stuart, the son of King Charles I, is declared King Charles II of England and Scotland by the Scottish Parliament.</item>
<item>1778 – South Carolina becomes the second state to ratify the Articles of Confederation.</item>
<item>1782 – Spanish defeat British forces and capture Menorca.</item>
<item>1807 – HMS Blenheim (1761) and HMS Java disappear off the coast of Rodrigues.</item>
<item>1818 – Jean–Baptiste Bernadotte ascends to the thrones of Sweden and Norway.</item>
<item>1849 – University of Wisconsin–Madison\'s first class meets at Madison Female Academy.</item>
<item>1852 – The New Hermitage Museum in Saint Petersburg, Russia, one of the largest and oldest museums in the world, opens to the public.</item>
<item>1859 – Wallachia and Moldavia are united under Alexandru Ioan Cuza as the United Principalities, an autonomous region within the Ottoman Empire, which ushered the birth of the modern Romanian state.</item>
<item>1869 – The largest alluvial gold nugget in history, called the \"Welcome Stranger\", is found in Moliagul, Victoria, Australia.</item>
<item>1885 – King Leopold II of Belgium establishes the Congo as a personal possession.</item>
<item>1905 – In Mexico, the General Hospital of Mexico is inaugurated, started with four basic specialties.</item>
<item>1909 – Belgian chemist Leo Baekeland announces the creation of Bakelite, the world\'s first synthetic plastic.</item>
<item>1913 – Greek military aviators, Michael Moutoussis and Aristeidis Moraitinis perform the first naval air mission in history, with a Farman MF.7 hydroplane.</item>
<item>1917 – The current constitution of Mexico is adopted, establishing a federal republic with powers separated into independent executive, legislative, and judicial branches.</item>
<item>1917 – The Congress of the United States passes the Immigration Act of 1917 over President Woodrow Wilson\'s veto.</item>
<item>1918 – Stephen W. Thompson shoots down a German airplane; this is the first aerial victory by the U.S. military.</item>
<item>1918 – SS Tuscania is torpedoed off the coast of Ireland; it is the first ship carrying American troops to Europe to be torpedoed and sunk.</item>
<item>1919 – Charlie Chaplin, Mary Pickford, Douglas Fairbanks, and D. W. Griffith launch United Artists.</item>
<item>1924 – The Royal Greenwich Observatory begins broadcasting the hourly time signals known as the Greenwich Time Signal.</item>
<item>1939 – Generalísimo Francisco Franco becomes the 68th \"Caudillo de España\", or Leader of Spain.</item>
<item>1958 – Gamal Abdel Nasser is nominated to be the first president of the United Arab Republic.</item>
<item>1962 – French President Charles de Gaulle calls for Algeria to be granted independence.</item>
<item>1963 – The European Court of Justice\'s ruling in Van Gend en Loos v Nederlandse Administratie der Belastingen establishes the principle of direct effect, one of the most important, if not the most important, decisions in the development of European Union law.</item>
<item>1971 – Astronauts land on the moon in the Apollo 14 mission.</item>
<item>1975 – Riots break in Lima, Peru after the police forces go on strike the day before. The uprising (locally known as the Limazo) is bloodily suppressed by the military dictatorship.</item>
<item>1988 – Manuel Noriega is indicted on drug smuggling and money laundering charges.</item>
<item>1997 – The so–called Big Three banks in Switzerland announce the creation of a $71 million fund to aid Holocaust survivors and their families.</item>
<item>2000 – Russian forces massacre at least 60 civilians in the Novye Aldi suburb of Grozny, Chechnya.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>