<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_8">
<item>421 – Constantius III becomes co–Emperor of the Western Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1575 – Leiden University is founded, and given the motto Praesidium Libertatis.</item>
<item>1693 – The College of William &amp; Mary in Williamsburg, Virginia, is granted a charter by King William III and Queen Mary II.</item>
<item>1817 – Las Heras crosses the Andes with an army to join San Martín and liberate Chile from Spain.</item>
<item>1837 – Richard Johnson becomes the first Vice President of the United States chosen by the United States Senate.</item>
<item>1879 – Sandford Fleming first proposes adoption of Universal Standard Time at a meeting of the Royal Canadian Institute.</item>
<item>1885 – The first government–approved Japanese immigrants arrived in Hawaii.</item>
<item>1887 – The Dawes Act authorizes the President of the United States to survey Native American tribal land and divide it into individual allotments.</item>
<item>1910 – The Boy Scouts of America is incorporated by William D. Boyce.</item>
<item>1915 – D. W. Griffith\'s controversial film The Birth of a Nation premieres in Los Angeles.</item>
<item>1924 – Capital punishment: The first state execution in the United States by gas chamber takes place in Nevada.</item>
<item>1946 – The first portion of the Revised Standard Version of the Bible, the first serious challenge to the popularity of the Authorized King James Version, is published.</item>
<item>1952 – Elizabeth II is proclaimed Queen of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1955 – The Government of Sindh, Pakistan, abolishes the Jagirdari system in the province. One million acres (4000 km2) of land thus acquired is to be distributed among the landless peasants.</item>
<item>1960 – Queen Elizabeth II of the United Kingdom issues an Order–in–Council, stating that she and her family would be known as the House of Windsor, and that her descendants will take the name Mountbatten–Windsor.</item>
<item>1963 – Travel, financial and commercial transactions by United States citizens to Cuba are made illegal by the John F. Kennedy administration.</item>
<item>1971 – The NASDAQ stock market index opens for the first time.</item>
<item>1971 – South Vietnamese ground troops launch an incursion into Laos to try to cut off the Ho Chi Minh trail and stop communist infiltration.</item>
<item>1974 – After 84 days in space, the crew of Skylab 4, the last crew to visit American space station Skylab, returns to Earth.</item>
<item>1978 – Proceedings of the United States Senate are broadcast on radio for the first time.</item>
<item>1983 – The Melbourne dust storm hits Australia\'s second largest city. The result of the worst drought on record and a day of severe weather conditions, a 320 metres (1,050 ft) deep dust cloud envelops the city, turning day to night.</item>
<item>1996 – The U.S. Congress passes the Communications Decency Act.</item>
<item>2013 – A blizzard disrupts transportation and leaves hundreds of thousands of people without electricity in the Northeastern United States and parts of Canada.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>