<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a2_9">
<item>474 – Zeno is crowned as co–emperor of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1003 – Boleslaus III is restored to authority with armed support from Bolesław I the Brave of Poland.</item>
<item>1621 – Gregory XV becomes Pope, the last Pope elected by acclamation.</item>
<item>1825 – After no candidate receives a majority of electoral votes in the US presidential election of 1824, the United States House of Representatives elects John Quincy Adams as President of the United States.</item>
<item>1849 – The new Roman Republic is declared.</item>
<item>1870 – US president Ulysses S. Grant signs a joint resolution of Congress establishing the U.S. Weather Bureau.</item>
<item>1889 – US president Grover Cleveland signs a bill elevating the United States Department of Agriculture to a Cabinet–level agency.</item>
<item>1895 – William G. Morgan creates a game called Mintonette, which soon comes to be referred to as volleyball.</item>
<item>1900 – The Davis Cup competition is established.</item>
<item>1907 – The Mud March is the first large procession organised by the National Union of Women\'s Suffrage Societies (NUWSS).</item>
<item>1913 – A group of meteors is visible across much of the eastern seaboard of North and South America, leading astronomers to conclude the source had been a small, short–lived natural satellite of the Earth.</item>
<item>1920 – Under the terms of the Svalbard Treaty, international diplomacy recognizes Norwegian sovereignty over Arctic archipelago Svalbard, and designates it as demilitarized.</item>
<item>1922 – Brazil becomes a member of the Berne Convention copyright treaty.</item>
<item>1934 – The Balkan Entente is formed.</item>
<item>1950 – Second Red Scare: US Senator Joseph McCarthy accuses the United States Department of State of being filled with Communists.</item>
<item>1959 – The R–7 Semyorka, the first intercontinental ballistic missile, becomes operational at Plesetsk, USSR.</item>
<item>1965 – The United States Marine Corps sends a MIM–23 Hawk missile battalion to South Vietnam, the first American troops in–country without an official advisory or training mission.</item>
<item>1971 – Satchel Paige becomes the first Negro League player to be voted into the USA\'s Baseball Hall of Fame.</item>
<item>1971 – Apollo program: Apollo 14 returns to Earth after the third manned Moon landing.</item>
<item>1975 – The Soyuz 17 Soviet spacecraft returns to Earth.</item>
<item>1978 – The Budd Company unveils its first SPV–2000 self–propelled railcar in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1986 – Halley\'s Comet last appeared in the inner Solar System.</item>
<item>1991 – Voters in Lithuania vote for independence.</item>
<item>1996 – Copernicium is first discovered.</item>
<item>2018 – 2018 Winter Olympics : opening ceremony is performed in Pyeongchang County in South Korea.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>