<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_11">
<item>1649 – The Frondeurs and the French sign the Peace of Rueil.</item>
<item>1702 – The Daily Courant, England\'s first national daily newspaper is published for the first time.</item>
<item>1708 – Queen Anne withholds Royal Assent from the Scottish Militia Bill, the last time a British monarch vetoes legislation.</item>
<item>1811 – During André Masséna\'s retreat from the Lines of Torres Vedras, a division led by French Marshal Michel Ney fights off a combined Anglo–Portuguese force to give Masséna time to escape.</item>
<item>1848 – Louis–Hippolyte Lafontaine and Robert Baldwin become the first Prime Ministers of the Province of Canada to be democratically elected under a system of responsible government.</item>
<item>1851 – The first performance of Rigoletto by Giuseppe Verdi takes place in Venice.</item>
<item>1872 – Construction of the Seven Sisters Colliery, South Wales, begins; located on one of the richest coal sources in Britain.</item>
<item>1879 – Shō Tai formally abdicated his position of King of Ryūkyū, under orders from Tokyo, ending the Ryukyu Kingdom.</item>
<item>1927 – In New York City, Samuel Roxy Rothafel opens the Roxy Theatre.</item>
<item>1931 – Ready for Labour and Defence of the USSR, abbreviated as GTO, is introduced in the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1946 – Rudolf Höss, the first commandant of Auschwitz concentration camp, is captured by British troops.</item>
<item>1981 – Hundreds of students protest in the University of Pristina in Kosovo, then part of Yugoslavia, to give their republic more political rights. The protests then became a nationwide movement.</item>
<item>1983 – Pakistan successfully conducts a cold test of a nuclear weapon.</item>
<item>1983 – Bob Hawke is appointed Prime Minister of Australia.</item>
<item>1990 – Lithuania declares itself independent from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1990 – Patricio Aylwin is sworn in as the first democratically elected President of Chile since 1970.</item>
<item>1993 – Janet Reno is confirmed by the United States Senate and sworn in the next day, becoming the first female Attorney General of the United States.</item>
<item>1999 – Infosys becomes the first Indian company listed on the NASDAQ stock exchange.</item>
<item>2006 – Michelle Bachelet is inaugurated as first female president of Chile.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>