<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_10">
<item>298 – Roman Emperor Maximian concludes his campaign in North Africa against the Berbers, and makes a triumphal entry into Carthage.</item>
<item>947 – The Later Han is founded by Liu Zhiyuan. He declares himself emperor and establishes the capital in Bian, present–day Kaifeng.</item>
<item>1629 – Charles I of England dissolves Parliament, beginning the eleven–year period known as the Personal Rule.</item>
<item>1735 – An agreement between Nader Shah and Russia is signed near Ganja, Azerbaijan and Russian troops are withdrawn from Baku.</item>
<item>1804 – Louisiana Purchase: In St. Louis, Missouri, a formal ceremony is conducted to transfer ownership of the Louisiana Territory from France to the United States.</item>
<item>1816 – Crossing of the Andes: A group of royalist scouts are captured during the Action of Juncalito.</item>
<item>1876 – The first successful test of a telephone is made by Alexander Graham Bell.</item>
<item>1891 – Almon Strowger, an undertaker in Topeka, Kansas, patents the Strowger switch, a device which led to the automation of telephone circuit switching.</item>
<item>1909 – By signing the Anglo–Siamese Treaty of 1909, Thailand relinquishes its sovereignty over the Malay states of Kedah, Kelantan, Perlis and Terengganu, which become British protectorates.</item>
<item>1916 – The McMahon–Hussein Correspondence between Hussein bin Ali, Sharif of Mecca and the British official Henry McMahon concerning the Arab revolt against the Ottoman Empire ends.</item>
<item>1917 – Some provinces and cities in the Philippines are incorporated due to the ratification of Act No. 2711 or the Administrative Code of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1949 – Mildred Gillars (\"Axis Sally\") is convicted of treason.</item>
<item>1952 – Fulgencio Batista leads a successful coup in Cuba and appoints himself as the \"provisional president\".</item>
<item>1966 – Military Prime Minister of South Vietnam Nguyễn Cao Kỳ sacked rival General Nguyễn Chánh Thi, precipitating large–scale civil and military dissension in parts of the nation.</item>
<item>1977 – Astronomers discover the rings of Uranus.</item>
<item>1990 – In Haiti, Prosper Avril is ousted 18 months after seizing power in a coup.</item>
<item>2000 – The Nasdaq Composite stock market index peaks at 5132.52, signaling the beginning of the end of the dot–com boom.</item>
<item>2006 – The Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter arrives at Mars.</item>
<item>2017 – The impeachment of President Park Geun–hye of South Korea in response to a major political scandal is unanimously upheld by the country\'s Constitutional Court, ending her presidency.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>