<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_15">
<item>280 – Sun Hao of Eastern Wu surrenders to Sima Yan which began the Jin dynasty.</item>
<item>351 – Constantius II elevates his cousin Gallus to Caesar, and puts him in charge of the Eastern part of the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>493 – Odoacer, the first barbarian King of Italy after the fall of the Western Roman Empire, is slain by Theoderic the Great, king of the Ostrogoths, while the two kings were feasting together.</item>
<item>856 – Michael III, emperor of the Byzantine Empire, overthrows the regency of his mother, empress Theodora (wife of Theophilos) with support of the Byzantine nobility.</item>
<item>1147 – Conquest of Santarém: The forces of Afonso I of Portugal capture Santarém.</item>
<item>1493 – Christopher Columbus returns to Spain after his first trip to the Americas.</item>
<item>1564 – Mughal Emperor Akbar abolishes \"jizya\" (per capita tax).</item>
<item>1672 – Charles II of England issues the Royal Declaration of Indulgence.</item>
<item>1783 – In an emotional speech in Newburgh, New York, George Washington asks his officers not to support the Newburgh Conspiracy. The plea is successful and the threatened coup d\'état never takes place.</item>
<item>1819 – French physicist Augustin–Jean Fresnel wins a contest at the Académie des Sciences in Paris by proving that light behaves like a wave. The Fresnel integrals, still used to calculate wave patterns, silence skeptics who had backed the particle theory of Isaac Newton.</item>
<item>1820 – Maine becomes the 23rd U.S. state.</item>
<item>1827 – University of Toronto is founded.</item>
<item>1874 – France and Vietnam sign the Second Treaty of Saigon, further recognizing the full sovereignty of France over Cochinchina.</item>
<item>1875 – Archbishop of New York John McCloskey is named the first cardinal in the United States.</item>
<item>1877 – First ever official cricket test match is played: Australia vs England at the MCG Stadium, in Melbourne, Australia.</item>
<item>1878 – Restoration of the Scottish Catholic hierarchy, broken off back in 1603.</item>
<item>1895 – Heian Shrine is founded.</item>
<item>1906 – Rolls–Royce Limited is incorporated.</item>
<item>1916 – United States President Woodrow Wilson sends 4,800 United States troops over the U.S.–Mexico border to pursue Pancho Villa.</item>
<item>1917 – Tsar Nicholas II of Russia abdicates the Russian throne ending the 304–year Romanov dynasty.</item>
<item>1922 – After Egypt gains nominal independence from the United Kingdom, Fuad I becomes King of Egypt.</item>
<item>1926 – The dictator Theodoros Pangalos is elected President of Greece without opposition.</item>
<item>1927 – The first Women\'s Boat Race between the University of Oxford and the University of Cambridge takes place on The Isis in Oxford.</item>
<item>1933 – Austrian Chancellor Engelbert Dollfuss keeps members of the National Council from convening, starting the Austrofascist dictatorship.</item>
<item>1939 – Carpatho–Ukraine declares itself an independent republic, but is annexed by Hungary the next day.</item>
<item>1941 – Philippine Airlines, the flag carrier of the Philippines takes its first flight between Manila (from Nielson Field) to Baguio City with a Beechcraft Model 18 making the airline the first and oldest commercial airline in Asia operating under its original name.</item>
<item>1951 – Iranian oil industry is nationalized.</item>
<item>1952 – In Cilaos, Réunion, 1870 mm (73 inches) of rain falls in a 24–hour period, setting a new world record (March 15 through March 16).</item>
<item>1961 – At the 1961 Commonwealth Prime Ministers\' Conference, South Africa announces that it will withdraw from the Commonwealth when the South African Constitution of 1961 comes into effect.</item>
<item>1965 – President Lyndon B. Johnson, responding to the Selma crisis, tells U.S. Congress \"We shall overcome\" while advocating the Voting Rights Act.</item>
<item>1985 – José Sarney becomes the first civilian President of Brazil after 21 years of military rule, he took office after President–elect Tancredo Neves became seriously ill the day before.</item>
<item>1985 – The first Internet domain name is registered (symbolics.com).</item>
<item>1990 – Mikhail Gorbachev is elected as the first President of the Soviet Union.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>