<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_19">
<item>1649 – The House of Commons of England passes an act abolishing the House of Lords, declaring it \"useless and dangerous to the people of England\".</item>
<item>1812 – The Cádiz Cortes promulgates the Spanish Constitution of 1812.</item>
<item>1853 – The Taiping reform movement occupies and makes Nanjing its capital until 1864.</item>
<item>1885 – Louis Riel declares a provisional government in Saskatchewan, beginning the North–West Rebellion.</item>
<item>1895 – Auguste and Louis Lumière record their first footage using their newly patented cinematograph.</item>
<item>1918 – The U.S. Congress establishes time zones and approves daylight saving time.</item>
<item>1920 – The United States Senate rejects the Treaty of Versailles for the second time (the first time was on November 19, 1919).</item>
<item>1931 – Gambling is legalized in Nevada.</item>
<item>1932 – The Sydney Harbour Bridge is opened.</item>
<item>1943 – Frank Nitti, the Chicago Outfit Boss after Al Capone, commits suicide at the Chicago Central Railyard.</item>
<item>1946 – French Guiana, Guadeloupe, Martinique and Réunion become overseas départements of France.</item>
<item>1954 – Joey Giardello knocks out Willie Tory in round seven at Madison Square Garden in the first televised prize boxing fight shown in colour.</item>
<item>1954 – Willie Mosconi sets a world record by running 526 consecutive balls without a miss during a straight pool exhibition at East High Billiard Club in Springfield, Ohio, setting a record which remains unbroken.</item>
<item>1962 – Highly influential artist Bob Dylan releases his first album, Bob Dylan, for Columbia Records.</item>
<item>1964 – Over 500,000 Brazilians attend the March of the Family with God for Liberty, in protest against the government of João Goulart and against Communism.</item>
<item>1965 – The wreck of the SS Georgiana, valued at over $50,000,000 and said to have been the most powerful Confederate cruiser, is discovered by teenage diver and pioneer underwater archaeologist E. Lee Spence, exactly 102 years after its destruction.</item>
<item>1966 – Texas Western becomes the first college basketball team to win the Final four with an all–black starting lineup.</item>
<item>1969 – The 385 metres (1,263 ft) tall TV–mast at Emley Moor transmitting station, United Kingdom, collapses due to ice build–up.</item>
<item>1979 – The United States House of Representatives begins broadcasting its day–to–day business via the cable television network C–SPAN.</item>
<item>1987 – Televangelist Jim Bakker resigns as head of the PTL Club due to a brewing sex scandal; he hands over control to Jerry Falwell.</item>
<item>2002 – Zimbabwe is suspended from the Commonwealth on charges of human rights abuses and of electoral fraud, following a turbulent presidential election.</item>
<item>2004 – Catalina affair: A Swedish DC–3 shot down by a Soviet MiG–15 in 1952 over the Baltic Sea is finally recovered after years of work.</item>
<item>2004 – March 19 Shooting Incident: the Republic of China(Taiwan) president Chen Shui–bian was shot just before the country\'s presidential election on March 20.</item>
<item>2008 – GRB 080319B: A cosmic burst that is the farthest object visible to the naked eye is briefly observed.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>