<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_17">
<item>455 – Petronius Maximus becomes, with support of the Roman Senate, emperor of the Western Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1001 – The Raja of Butuan in what is now the Philippines sends a tributary mission to the Song dynasty.</item>
<item>1805 – The Italian Republic, with Napoleon as president, becomes the Kingdom of Italy, with Napoleon as King.</item>
<item>1824 – The Anglo–Dutch Treaty is signed in London, dividing the Malay archipelago. As a result, the Malay Peninsula is dominated by the British, while Sumatra and Java and surrounding areas are dominated by the Dutch.</item>
<item>1842 – The Relief Society of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter–day Saints is formed.</item>
<item>1852 – Annibale De Gasparis discovers in Naples the asteroid Psyche from the north dome of the Astronomical Observatory of Capodimonte</item>
<item>1861 – The Kingdom of Italy is proclaimed.</item>
<item>1921 – The Second Polish Republic adopts the March Constitution.</item>
<item>1941 – In Washington, D.C., the National Gallery of Art is officially opened by President Franklin D. Roosevelt.</item>
<item>1945 – The Ludendorff Bridge in Remagen, Germany, collapses, ten days after its capture.</item>
<item>1948 – Belgium, France, Luxembourg, the Netherlands and the United Kingdom sign the Treaty of Brussels, a precursor to the North Atlantic Treaty establishing NATO.</item>
<item>1950 – Researchers at the University of California, Berkeley announce the creation of element 98, which they name \"californium\".</item>
<item>1958 – The United States launches the Vanguard 1 satellite.</item>
<item>1959 – Tenzin Gyatso, the 14th Dalai Lama, flees Tibet for India.</item>
<item>1960 – U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower signs the National Security Council directive on the anti–Cuban covert action program that will ultimately lead to the Bay of Pigs Invasion.</item>
<item>1969 – Golda Meir becomes the first female Prime Minister of Israel.</item>
<item>1992 – A referendum to end apartheid in South Africa is passed 68.7% to 31.2%.</item>
<item>2003 – Secretary of State for Foreign and Commonwealth Affairs Robin Cook, resigns from the British Cabinet in disagreement with government plans for the 2003 invasion of Iraq.</item>
<item>2011 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 1972 relating to Somalia is adopted.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>