<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_20">
<item>235 – Maximinus Thrax is proclaimed emperor.</item>
<item>673 – Emperor Tenmu of Japan assumes the Chrysanthemum Throne at the Palace of Kiyomihara in Asuka.</item>
<item>1206 – Michael IV Autoreianos is appointed Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople.</item>
<item>1600 – The Linköping Bloodbath takes place on Maundy Thursday in Linköping, Sweden.</item>
<item>1602 – The Dutch East India Company is established.</item>
<item>1616 – Sir Walter Raleigh is freed from the Tower of London after 13 years of imprisonment.</item>
<item>1815 – After escaping from Elba, Napoleon enters Paris with a regular army of 140,000 and a volunteer force of around 200,000, beginning his \"Hundred Days\" rule.</item>
<item>1852 – Harriet Beecher Stowe\'s Uncle Tom\'s Cabin is published.</item>
<item>1854 – The Republican Party of the United States is organized in Ripon, Wisconsin.</item>
<item>1883 – The Paris Convention for the Protection of Industrial Property is signed.</item>
<item>1888 – The premiere of the very first Romani language operetta is staged in Moscow, Russia.</item>
<item>1890 – Prime minister Otto von Bismarck of German Empire is dismissed by Emperor Wilhelm II.</item>
<item>1896 – With the approval of Emperor Guangxu, Qing dynasty post office is opened,which marked Chinese Post was beginning.</item>
<item>1915 – Albert Einstein publishes his general theory of relativity.</item>
<item>1921 – The Upper Silesia plebiscite was a plebiscite mandated by the Versailles Treaty to determine a section of the border between Weimar Germany and Poland.</item>
<item>1922 – The USS Langley is commissioned as the first United States Navy aircraft carrier.</item>
<item>1923 – The Arts Club of Chicago hosts the opening of Pablo Picasso\'s first United States showing, entitled Original Drawings by Pablo Picasso, becoming an early proponent of modern art in the United States.</item>
<item>1933 – Reichsführer–SS Heinrich Himmler ordered the creation of Dachau concentration camp as Chief of Police of Munich and appointed Theodor Eicke as the camp commandant.</item>
<item>1948 – With a Musicians Union ban lifted, the first telecasts of classical music in the United States, under Eugene Ormandy and Arturo Toscanini, are given on CBS and NBC.</item>
<item>1951 – Fujiyoshida, a city located in Yamanashi Prefecture, Japan, in the center of the Japanese main island of Honshū is founded.</item>
<item>1952 – The US Senate ratifies the Security Treaty Between the United States and Japan.</item>
<item>1956 – Tunisia gains independence from France.</item>
<item>1964 – The precursor of the European Space Agency, ESRO (European Space Research Organisation) is established per an agreement signed on June 14, 1962.</item>
<item>1985 – Libby Riddles becomes the first woman to win the 1,135–mile Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race.</item>
<item>1985 – Canadian paraplegic athlete and humanitarian Rick Hansen begins his circumnavigation of the globe in a wheelchair in the name of spinal cord injury medical research.</item>
<item>1987 – The Food and Drug Administration approves the anti–AIDS drug, AZT.</item>
<item>1990 – Ferdinand Marcos\'s widow, Imelda Marcos, goes on trial for bribery, embezzlement, and racketeering.</item>
<item>1999 – Legoland California, the first Legoland outside of Europe, opens in Carlsbad, California.</item>
<item>2003 – Invasion of Iraq: In the early hours of the morning, the United States and three other countries (the UK, Australia and Poland) begin military operations in Iraq.</item>
<item>2015 – A Solar eclipse, equinox, and a Supermoon all occur on the same day.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>