<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_23">
<item>1400 – The Trần dynasty of Vietnam is deposed, after one hundred and seventy–five years of rule, by Hồ Quý Ly, a court official.</item>
<item>1540 – Waltham Abbey is surrendered to King Henry VIII of England; the last religious community to be closed during the Dissolution of the Monasteries.</item>
<item>1806 – After traveling through the Louisiana Purchase and reaching the Pacific Ocean, explorers Lewis and Clark and their \"Corps of Discovery\" begin their arduous journey home.</item>
<item>1848 – The ship John Wickliffe arrives at Port Chalmers carrying the first Scottish settlers for Dunedin, New Zealand. Otago province is founded.</item>
<item>1857 – Elisha Otis\'s first elevator is installed at 488 Broadway New York City.</item>
<item>1868 – The University of California is founded in Oakland, California when the Organic Act is signed into law.</item>
<item>1888 – In England, The Football League, the world\'s oldest professional association football league, meets for the first time.</item>
<item>1889 – The Ahmadiyya Muslim Community is established by Mirza Ghulam Ahmad in Qadian, British India.</item>
<item>1901 – Emilio Aguinaldo, only President of the First Philippine Republic, was captured at Palanan, Isabela by the forces of General Frederick Funston.</item>
<item>1905 – Eleftherios Venizelos calls for Crete\'s union with Greece, and begins what is to be known as the Theriso revolt.</item>
<item>1909 – Theodore Roosevelt leaves New York for a post–presidency safari in Africa. The trip is sponsored by the Smithsonian Institution and National Geographic Society.</item>
<item>1935 – Signing of the Constitution of the Commonwealth of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1956 – Pakistan becomes the first Islamic republic in the world. (Republic Day in Pakistan)</item>
<item>1965 – NASA launches Gemini 3, the United States\' first two–man space flight (crew: Gus Grissom and John Young).</item>
<item>1977 – The first of The Nixon Interviews (12 will be recorded over four weeks) is videotaped with British journalist David Frost interviewing former United States President Richard Nixon about the Watergate scandal and the Nixon tapes.</item>
<item>1978 – The first UNIFIL troops arrived in Lebanon for peacekeeping mission along the Blue Line.</item>
<item>1982 – Guatemala\'s government, headed by Fernando Romeo Lucas García is overthrown in a military coup by right–wing General Efraín Ríos Montt.</item>
<item>1983 – Strategic Defense Initiative: President Ronald Reagan makes his initial proposal to develop technology to intercept enemy missiles.</item>
<item>1996 – Taiwan holds its first direct elections and chooses Lee Teng–hui as President.</item>
<item>2001 – The Russian Mir space station is disposed of, breaking up in the atmosphere before falling into the southern Pacific Ocean near Fiji.</item>
<item>2008 – Official opening of Rajiv Gandhi International Airport in Hyderabad, India</item>
</string-array>
</resources>