<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_21">
<item>537 – Siege of Rome: King Vitiges attempts to assault the northern and eastern city walls, but is repulsed at the Praenestine Gate, known as the Vivarium, by the defenders under the Byzantine generals Bessas and Peranius.</item>
<item>630 – Emperor Heraclius returns the True Cross, one of the holiest Christian relics, to Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1152 – Annulment of the marriage of King Louis VII of France and Queen Eleanor of Aquitaine.</item>
<item>1188 – Emperor Antoku accedes to the throne of Japan.</item>
<item>1788 – A fire in New Orleans leaves most of the town in ruins.</item>
<item>1800 – With the church leadership driven out of Rome during an armed conflict, Pius VII is crowned Pope in Venice with a temporary papal tiara made of papier–mâché.</item>
<item>1804 – Code Napoléon is adopted as French civil law.</item>
<item>1844 – The Bahá\'í calendar begins. This is the first day of the first year of the Bahá\'í calendar. It is annually celebrated by members of the Bahá\'í Faith as the Bahá\'í New Year or Náw–Rúz.</item>
<item>1861 – Alexander Stephens gives the Cornerstone Speech.</item>
<item>1871 – Otto von Bismarck is appointed as the first Chancellor of the German Empire.</item>
<item>1871 – Journalist Henry Morton Stanley begins his trek to find the missionary and explorer David Livingstone.</item>
<item>1925 – The Butler Act prohibits the teaching of human evolution in Tennessee.</item>
<item>1925 – Syngman Rhee is removed from office after being impeached as the President of the Provisional Government of the Republic of Korea.</item>
<item>1928 – Charles Lindbergh is presented with the Medal of Honor for the first solo trans–Atlantic flight.</item>
<item>1935 – Shah of Iran Reza Shah Pahlavi formally asks the international community to call Persia by its native name, Iran.</item>
<item>1937 – Ponce massacre: Nineteen people in Ponce, Puerto Rico are gunned down by police acting on orders of the US–appointed Governor, Blanton C. Winship.</item>
<item>1946 – The Los Angeles Rams sign Kenny Washington, making him the first African American player in the American football since 1933.</item>
<item>1952 – Alan Freed presents the Moondog Coronation Ball, the first rock and roll concert, in Cleveland, Ohio.</item>
<item>1963 – Alcatraz Federal Penitentiary (in California) closes.</item>
<item>1965 – Ranger program: NASA launches Ranger 9, the last in a series of unmanned lunar space probes.</item>
<item>1965 – Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. leads 3,200 people on the start of the third and finally successful civil rights march from Selma to Montgomery, Alabama.</item>
<item>1970 – The first Earth Day proclamation is issued by Joseph Alioto, Mayor of San Francisco.</item>
<item>1986 – Debi Thomas became the first African American to win the World Figure Skating Championships</item>
<item>1990 – Namibia becomes independent after 75 years of South African rule.</item>
<item>1994 – The United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change enters into force.</item>
<item>1999 – Bertrand Piccard and Brian Jones become the first to circumnavigate the Earth in a hot air balloon.</item>
<item>2000 – Pope John Paul II makes his first ever pontifical visit to Israel.</item>
<item>2006 – The social media site Twitter is founded.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>