<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_25">
<item>708 – Pope Constantine succeeds Pope Sisinnius as the 88th pope.</item>
<item>717 – Theodosius III resigns the throne to the Byzantine Empire to enter the clergy.</item>
<item>919 – Romanos Lekapenos seizes the Boukoleon Palace in Constantinople and becomes regent of the Byzantine emperor Constantine VII.</item>
<item>1000 – Fatimid caliph al–Hakim bi–Amr Allah assassinates the eunuch chief minister Barjawan and assumes control of the government.</item>
<item>1306 – Robert the Bruce becomes King of Scots (Scotland).</item>
<item>1409 – The Council of Pisa opens.</item>
<item>1555 – The city of Valencia is founded in present–day Venezuela.</item>
<item>1576 – Jerome Savage takes out a sub–lease to start the Newington Butts Theatre outside London.</item>
<item>1584 – Sir Walter Raleigh is granted a patent to colonize Virginia.</item>
<item>1655 – Saturn\'s largest moon, Titan, is discovered by Christiaan Huygens.</item>
<item>1802 – The Treaty of Amiens is signed as a \"Definitive Treaty of Peace\" between France and the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1807 – The Slave Trade Act becomes law, abolishing the slave trade in the British Empire.</item>
<item>1807 – The Swansea and Mumbles Railway, then known as the Oystermouth Railway, becomes the first passenger–carrying railway in the world.</item>
<item>1811 – Percy Bysshe Shelley is expelled from the University of Oxford for publishing the pamphlet The Necessity of Atheism.</item>
<item>1845 – New Zealand Legislative Council pass the first Militia Act constituting the New Zealand Army.</item>
<item>1894 – Coxey\'s Army, the first significant American protest march, departs Massillon, Ohio for Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1917 – The Georgian Orthodox Church restores its autocephaly abolished by Imperial Russia in 1811.</item>
<item>1918 – The Belarusian People\'s Republic is established.</item>
<item>1924 – On the anniversary of Greek Independence, Alexandros Papanastasiou proclaims the Second Hellenic Republic.</item>
<item>1931 – The Scottsboro Boys are arrested in Alabama and charged with rape.</item>
<item>1941 – The Kingdom of Yugoslavia joins the Axis powers with the signing of the Tripartite Pact.</item>
<item>1949 – More than 92,000 kulaks are suddenly deported from the Baltic states to Siberia.</item>
<item>1957 – United States Customs seizes copies of Allen Ginsberg\'s poem \"Howl\" on obscenity grounds.</item>
<item>1957 – The European Economic Community is established with West Germany, France, Italy, Belgium, Netherlands and Luxembourg as the first members.</item>
<item>1965 – Civil rights activists led by Martin Luther King Jr. successfully complete their 4–day 50–mile march from Selma to the capitol in Montgomery, Alabama.</item>
<item>1969 – During their honeymoon, John Lennon and Yoko Ono hold their first Bed–In for Peace at the Amsterdam Hilton Hotel (until March 31).</item>
<item>1971 – The Army of the Republic of Vietnam abandon an attempt to cut off the Ho Chi Minh trail in Laos.</item>
<item>1979 – The first fully functional Space Shuttle orbiter, Columbia, is delivered to the John F. Kennedy Space Center to be prepared for its first launch.</item>
<item>1988 – The Candle demonstration in Bratislava is the first mass demonstration of the 1980s against the communist regime in Czechoslovakia.</item>
<item>1996 – The European Union\'s Veterinarian Committee bans the export of British beef and its by–products as a result of mad cow disease (Bovine spongiform encephalopathy).</item>
<item>2006 – Protesters demanding a new election in Belarus, following the rigged Belarusian presidential election, 2006, clash with riot police. Opposition leader Aleksander Kozulin is among several protesters arrested.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>