<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_2">
<item>537 – Siege of Rome: The Ostrogoth army under king Vitiges begins the siege of the capital. Belisarius conducts a delaying action outside the Flaminian Gate; he and a detachment of his bucellarii are almost cut off.</item>
<item>986 – Louis V becomes King of the Franks.</item>
<item>1127 – Assassination of Charles the Good, Count of Flanders.</item>
<item>1444 – Skanderbeg organizes a group of Albanian nobles to form the League of Lezhë.</item>
<item>1458 – George of Poděbrady is chosen as the king of Bohemia.</item>
<item>1484 – The College of Arms is formally incorporated by Royal Charter signed by King Richard III of England.</item>
<item>1498 – Vasco da Gama\'s fleet visits the Island of Mozambique.</item>
<item>1561 – Mendoza, Argentina is founded by Spanish conquistador Pedro del Castillo.</item>
<item>1717 – The Loves of Mars and Venus is the first ballet performed in England.</item>
<item>1791 – Long–distance communication speeds up with the unveiling of a semaphore machine in Paris.</item>
<item>1797 – The Bank of England issues the first one–pound and two–pound banknotes.</item>
<item>1807 – The U.S. Congress passes the Act Prohibiting Importation of Slaves, disallowing the importation of new slaves into the country.</item>
<item>1808 – The inaugural meeting of the Wernerian Natural History Society, a former Scottish learned society, is held in Edinburgh.</item>
<item>1815 – Signing of the Kandyan Convention treaty by British invaders and the leaders of the Kingdom of Kandy.</item>
<item>1825 – Roberto Cofresí, one of the last successful Caribbean pirates, is defeated in combat and captured by authorities.</item>
<item>1855 – Alexander II becomes Tsar of Russia.</item>
<item>1859 – The two–day Great Slave Auction, the largest such auction in United States history, begins.</item>
<item>1867 – The U.S. Congress passes the first Reconstruction Act.</item>
<item>1877 – U.S. presidential election, 1876: Just two days before inauguration, the U.S. Congress declares Rutherford B. Hayes the winner of the election even though Samuel J. Tilden had won the popular vote on November 7, 1876.</item>
<item>1882 – Queen Victoria narrowly escapes an assassination attempt by Roderick McLean in Windsor.</item>
<item>1901 – United States Steel Corporation is founded as a result of a merger between Carnegie Steel Company and Federal Steel Company which became the first corporation in the world with a market capital over $1 billion.</item>
<item>1901 – The U.S. Congress passes the Platt Amendment limiting the autonomy of Cuba, as a condition of the withdrawal of American troops.</item>
<item>1903 – In New York City the Martha Washington Hotel opens, becoming the first hotel exclusively for women.</item>
<item>1917 – The enactment of the Jones–Shafroth Act grants Puerto Ricans United States citizenship.</item>
<item>1919 – The first Communist International meets in Moscow.</item>
<item>1933 – The film King Kong opens at New York\'s Radio City Music Hall.</item>
<item>1937 – The Steel Workers Organizing Committee signs a collective bargaining agreement with U.S. Steel, leading to unionization of the United States steel industry.</item>
<item>1939 – Cardinal Eugenio Pacelli is elected Pope and takes the name Pius XII.</item>
<item>1946 – Ho Chi Minh is elected the President of North Vietnam.</item>
<item>1949 – Captain James Gallagher lands his B–50 Superfortress Lucky Lady II in Fort Worth, Texas after completing the first non–stop around–the–world airplane flight in 94 hours and one minute.</item>
<item>1955 – Norodom Sihanouk, king of Cambodia, abdicates the throne in favor of his father, Norodom Suramarit.</item>
<item>1961 – John F. Kennedy announces the creation of the Peace Corps in a nationally televised broadcast.</item>
<item>1962 – In Burma, the army led by General Ne Win seizes power in a coup d\'état.</item>
<item>1962 – Wilt Chamberlain sets the single–game scoring record in the National Basketball Association by scoring 100 points.</item>
<item>1968 – Baggeridge Colliery closes marking the end of over 300 years of coal mining in the Black Country.</item>
<item>1969 – In Toulouse, France, the first test flight of the Anglo–French Concorde is conducted.</item>
<item>1970 – Rhodesia declares itself a republic, breaking its last links with the British crown.</item>
<item>1972 – The Pioneer 10 space probe is launched from Cape Canaveral, Florida with a mission to explore the outer planets.</item>
<item>1977 – Libya becomes the Socialist People\'s Libyan Arab Jamahiriya as the General People\'s Congress adopted the \"Declaration on the Establishment of the Authority of the People\".</item>
<item>1978 – Czech Vladimír Remek becomes the first non–Russian or non–American to go into space, when he is launched aboard Soyuz 28.</item>
<item>1983 – Compact discs and players are released for the first time in the United States and other markets. They had previously been available only in Japan.</item>
<item>1989 – Twelve European Community nations agree to ban the production of all chlorofluorocarbons (CFCs) by the end of the century.</item>
<item>1990 – Nelson Mandela is elected deputy President of the African National Congress.</item>
<item>1992 – Armenia, Azerbaijan, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, San Marino, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan and Uzbekistan join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1995 – Researchers at Fermilab announce the discovery of the top quark.</item>
<item>1995 – Yahoo! is incorporated.</item>
<item>1998 – Data sent from the Galileo spacecraft indicates that Jupiter\'s moon Europa has a liquid ocean under a thick crust of ice.</item>
<item>2017 – The elements Moscovium, Tennessine, and Oganesson were officially added to the periodic table at a conference in Moscow, Russia</item>
</string-array>
</resources>