<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_22">
<item>238 – Gordian I and his son Gordian II are proclaimed Roman emperors.</item>
<item>1508 – Ferdinand II of Aragon commissions Amerigo Vespucci chief navigator of the Spanish Empire.</item>
<item>1621 – The Pilgrims of Plymouth Colony sign a peace treaty with Massasoit of the Wampanoags.</item>
<item>1630 – The Massachusetts Bay Colony outlaws the possession of cards, dice, and gaming tables.</item>
<item>1638 – Anne Hutchinson is expelled from Massachusetts Bay Colony for religious dissent.</item>
<item>1739 – Nader Shah occupies Delhi in India and sacks the city, stealing the jewels of the Peacock Throne.</item>
<item>1765 – The British Parliament passes the Stamp Act that introduces a tax to be levied directly on its American colonies.</item>
<item>1784 – The Emerald Buddha is moved with great ceremony to its current location in Wat Phra Kaew, Thailand.</item>
<item>1829 – In the London Protocol, the three protecting powers (United Kingdom, France and Russia) establish the borders of Greece.</item>
<item>1871 – In North Carolina, William Woods Holden becomes the first governor of a U.S. state to be removed from office by impeachment.</item>
<item>1872 – Illinois becomes the first state to require gender equality in employment.</item>
<item>1873 – The Spanish National Assembly abolishes slavery in Puerto Rico.</item>
<item>1894 – The first playoff game for the Stanley Cup starts.</item>
<item>1906 – The first England vs France rugby union match is played at Parc des Princes in Paris</item>
<item>1916 – The last Emperor of China, Yuan Shikai, abdicates the throne and the Republic of China is restored.</item>
<item>1933 – Cullen–Harrison Act: President Franklin Roosevelt signs an amendment to the Volstead Act, legalizing the manufacture and sale of \"3.2 beer\" (3.2% alcohol by weight, approximately 4% alcohol by volume) and light wines.</item>
<item>1939 – Germany takes Memel from Lithuania.</item>
<item>1945 – The Arab League is founded when a charter is adopted in Cairo, Egypt.</item>
<item>1960 – Arthur Leonard Schawlow and Charles Hard Townes receive the first patent for a laser.</item>
<item>1972 – The United States Congress sends the Equal Rights Amendment to the states for ratification.</item>
<item>1972 – In Eisenstadt v. Baird, the United States Supreme Court decides that unmarried persons have the right to possess contraceptives.</item>
<item>1982 – NASA\'s Space Shuttle Columbia is launched from the Kennedy Space Center on its third mission, STS–3.</item>
<item>1992 – Fall of communism in Albania: The Democratic Party of Albania wins a decisive majority in the parliamentary election.</item>
<item>1993 – The Intel Corporation ships the first Pentium chips (80586), featuring a 60 MHz clock speed, 100+ MIPS, and a 64 bit data path.</item>
<item>1995 – Cosmonaut Valeri Polyakov returns to earth after setting a record of 438 days in space.</item>
<item>1997 – Tara Lipinski, aged 14 years and 9 months, becomes the youngest women\'s World Figure Skating Champion.</item>
<item>2013 – My Chemical Romance breakup.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>