<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_27">
<item>1309 – Pope Clement V imposes excommunication and interdiction on Venice, and a general prohibition of all commercial intercourse with Venice, which had seized on Ferrara, a papal fiefdom.</item>
<item>1329 – Pope John XXII issues his In Agro Dominico condemning some writings of Meister Eckhart as heretical.</item>
<item>1513 – Spanish explorer Juan Ponce de León reaches the northern end of The Bahamas on his first voyage to Florida.</item>
<item>1625 – Charles I becomes King of England, Scotland and Ireland as well as claiming the title King of France.</item>
<item>1782 – Charles Watson–Wentworth, 2nd Marquess of Rockingham becomes Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1794 – The United States Government establishes a permanent navy and authorizes the building of six frigates.</item>
<item>1794 – Denmark and Sweden form a neutrality compact.</item>
<item>1866 – President Andrew Johnson vetoes the Civil Rights Act of 1866. His veto is overridden by Congress and the bill passes into law on April 9.</item>
<item>1915 – Typhoid Mary, the first healthy carrier of disease ever identified in the United States, is put in quarantine, where she would remain for the rest of her life.</item>
<item>1918 – The National Council of Bessarabia proclaims union with the Kingdom of Romania.</item>
<item>1958 – Nikita Khrushchev becomes Chairman of the Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1975 – Construction of the Trans–Alaska Pipeline System begins.</item>
<item>1980 – Silver Thursday: A steep fall in silver prices, resulting from the Hunt Brothers attempting to corner the market in silver, leads to panic on commodity and futures exchanges.</item>
<item>1990 – The United States begins broadcasting anti–Castro propaganda to Cuba on TV Martí.</item>
<item>1993 – Jiang Zemin is appointed President of the People\'s Republic of China.</item>
<item>1993 – Italian former minister and Christian Democracy leader Giulio Andreotti is accused of mafia allegiance by the tribunal of Palermo.</item>
<item>1998 – The Food and Drug Administration approves Viagra for use as a treatment for male impotence, the first pill to be approved for this condition in the United States.</item>
<item>2000 – Syrian Children\'s channel Spacetoon launches.</item>
<item>2004 – HMS Scylla, a decommissioned Leander–class frigate, is sunk as an artificial reef off Cornwall, the first of its kind in Europe.</item>
<item>2014 – Philippines signs a peace accord with the largest Muslim rebel group, the Moro Islamic Liberation Front, ending decades of conflict.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>