<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_28">
<item>364 – Roman Emperor Valentinian I appoints his brother Flavius Valens co–emperor.</item>
<item>1566 – The foundation stone of Valletta, Malta\'s capital city, is laid by Jean Parisot de Valette, Grand Master of the Sovereign Military Order of Malta.</item>
<item>1776 – Juan Bautista de Anza finds the site for the Presidio of San Francisco.</item>
<item>1794 – Allies under Prince Josias of Saxe–Coburg–Saalfeld defeat French forces at Le Cateau.</item>
<item>1795 – Partitions of Poland: The Duchy of Courland and Semigallia, a northern fief of the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth, ceases to exist and becomes part of Imperial Russia.</item>
<item>1801 – Treaty of Florence is signed.</item>
<item>1802 – Heinrich Wilhelm Matthäus Olbers discovers 2 Pallas, the second asteroid ever to be discovered.</item>
<item>1842 – First concert of the Vienna Philharmonic Orchestra, conducted by Otto Nicolai.</item>
<item>1871 – The Paris Commune is formally established in Paris.</item>
<item>1910 – Henri Fabre becomes the first person to fly a seaplane, the Fabre Hydravion, after taking off from a water runway near Martigues, France.</item>
<item>1959 – The State Council of the People\'s Republic of China dissolves the government of Tibet.</item>
<item>1969 – Greek poet and Nobel Prize laureate Giorgos Seferis makes a famous statement on the BBC World Service opposing the junta in Greece.</item>
<item>1978 – The US Supreme Court hands down 5–3 decision in Stump v. Sparkman, a controversial case involving involuntary sterilization and judicial immunity.</item>
<item>1979 – A coolant leak at the Three Mile Island\'s Unit 2 nuclear reactor outside Harrisburg, Pennsylvania leads to the core overheating and a partial meltdown.</item>
<item>1979 – The British House of Commons passes a vote of no confidence against James Callaghan\'s government by 1 vote, precipitating a general election.</item>
<item>1988 – Atlantic Airways, Faroe Islands\' national airline, carries out their first commercial flight between Vágar Airport and Copenhagen Airport.</item>
<item>2006 – Massive protests are mounted against France\'s First Employment Contract law, meant to reduce youth unemployment.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>