<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_30">
<item>598 – Balkan Campaign: The Avars lift the siege at the Byzantine stronghold of Tomis. Their leader Bayan I retreats north of the Danube River after the Avaro–Slavic hordes are decimated by the plague.</item>
<item>1282 – The people of Sicily rebel against the Angevin king Charles I, in what becomes known as the Sicilian Vespers.</item>
<item>1699 – Guru Gobind Singh establishes the Khalsa in Anandpur Sahib, Punjab.</item>
<item>1815 – Joachim Murat issues the Rimini Proclamation which would later inspire Italian unification.</item>
<item>1818 – Physicist Augustin Fresnel reads a memoir on optical rotation to the French Academy of Sciences, reporting that when polarized light is \"depolarized\" by a Fresnel rhomb, its properties are preserved in any subsequent passage through an optically–rotating crystal or liquid.</item>
<item>1822 – The Florida Territory is created in the United States.</item>
<item>1841 – The National Bank of Greece is founded in Athens.</item>
<item>1842 – Ether anesthesia is used for the first time, in an operation by the American surgeon Dr. Crawford Long.</item>
<item>1861 – Discovery of the chemical elements: Sir William Crookes announces his discovery of thallium.</item>
<item>1863 – Danish prince Wilhelm Georg is chosen as King George of Greece.</item>
<item>1870 – Texas is readmitted to the Union following Reconstruction.</item>
<item>1899 – German Society of Chemistry issues an invitation to other national scientific organizations to appoint delegates to the International Committee on Atomic Weights.</item>
<item>1912 – Sultan Abd al–Hafid signs the Treaty of Fez, making Morocco a French protectorate.</item>
<item>1918 – Outburst of bloody March Events in Baku and other locations of Baku Governorate.</item>
<item>1939 – The Heinkel He 100 fighter sets a world airspeed record of 463 mph (745 km/h).</item>
<item>1961 – The Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs is signed in New York City.</item>
<item>1976 – Israeli–Palestinian conflict: in the first organized response against Israeli policies by a Palestinian collective since 1948, Palestinians create the first Land Day.</item>
<item>1982 – Space Shuttle program: STS–3 Mission is completed with the landing of Columbia at White Sands Missile Range, New Mexico.</item>
<item>2017 – SpaceX conducts the world’s first reflight of an orbital class rocket.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>