<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_4">
<item>306 – Martyrdom of Saint Adrian of Nicomedia.</item>
<item>852 – Croatian Knez Trpimir I issues a statute, a document with the first known written mention of the Croats name in Croatian sources.</item>
<item>932 – Translation of the relics of martyr Wenceslaus I, Duke of Bohemia, Prince of the Czechs.</item>
<item>1152 – Frederick I Barbarossa is elected King of Germany.</item>
<item>1351 – Ramathibodi becomes King of Siam.</item>
<item>1386 – Władysław II Jagiełło (Jogaila) is crowned King of Poland.</item>
<item>1493 – Explorer Christopher Columbus arrives back in Lisbon, Portugal, aboard his ship Niña from his voyage to what are now The Bahamas and other islands in the Caribbean.</item>
<item>1519 – Hernán Cortés arrives in Mexico in search of the Aztec civilization and its wealth.</item>
<item>1628 – The Massachusetts Bay Colony is granted a Royal charter.</item>
<item>1675 – John Flamsteed is appointed the first Astronomer Royal of England.</item>
<item>1681 – Charles II grants a land charter to William Penn for the area that will later become Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1789 – In New York City, the first Congress of the United States meets, putting the United States Constitution into effect. The United States Bill of Rights is written and proposed to Congress.</item>
<item>1790 – France is divided into 83 départements, cutting across the former provinces in an attempt to dislodge regional loyalties based on ownership of land by the nobility.</item>
<item>1791 – The Constitutional Act of 1791 is introduced by the British House of Commons in London which envisages the separation of Canada into Lower Canada (Quebec) and Upper Canada (Ontario).</item>
<item>1791 – Vermont is admitted to the United States as the fourteenth state.</item>
<item>1794 – The 11th Amendment to the U.S. Constitution is passed by the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1797 – John Adams is inaugurated as the 2nd President of the United States of America, becoming the first President to begin his presidency on March 4.</item>
<item>1804 – Castle Hill Rebellion: Irish convicts rebel against British colonial authority in the Colony of New South Wales.</item>
<item>1813 – Cyril VI of Constantinople is elected Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople.</item>
<item>1837 – The city of Chicago is incorporated.</item>
<item>1848 – Carlo Alberto di Savoia signs the Statuto Albertino that will later represent the first constitution of the Regno d\'Italia.</item>
<item>1861 – The first national flag of the Confederate States of America (the \"Stars and Bars\") is adopted.</item>
<item>1865 – The third and final national flag of the Confederate States of America is adopted by the Confederate Congress.</item>
<item>1882 – Britain\'s first electric trams run in east London.</item>
<item>1909 – U.S. President William Taft used what became known as a Saxbe fix, a mechanism to avoid the restriction of the U.S. Constitution\'s Ineligibility Clause, to appoint Philander C. Knox as U.S. Secretary of State</item>
<item>1913 – The United States Department of Labor is formed.</item>
<item>1917 – Jeannette Rankin of Montana becomes the first female member of the United States House of Representatives.</item>
<item>1933 – Frances Perkins becomes United States Secretary of Labor, the first female member of the United States Cabinet.</item>
<item>1933 – The Parliament of Austria is suspended because of a quibble over procedure – Chancellor Engelbert Dollfuss initiates an authoritarian rule by decree.</item>
<item>1957 – The S&amp;P 500 stock market index is introduced, replacing the S&amp;P 90.</item>
<item>1966 – In an interview in the London Evening Standard, The Beatles\' John Lennon declares that the band is \"more popular than Jesus now\".</item>
<item>1970 – French submarine Eurydice explodes underwater, resulting in the loss of the entire 57–man crew.</item>
<item>1974 – People magazine is published for the first time in the United States as People Weekly.</item>
<item>1976 – The Northern Ireland Constitutional Convention is formally dissolved in Northern Ireland resulting in direct rule of Northern Ireland from London by the British parliament.</item>
<item>1980 – Nationalist leader Robert Mugabe wins a sweeping election victory to become Zimbabwe\'s first black prime minister.</item>
<item>1985 – The Food and Drug Administration approves a blood test for AIDS infection, used since then for screening all blood donations in the United States.</item>
<item>1986 – The Soviet Vega 1 begins returning images of Halley\'s Comet and the first images of its nucleus.</item>
<item>1998 – Gay rights: Oncale v. Sundowner Offshore Services, Inc.: The Supreme Court of the United States rules that federal laws banning on–the–job sexual harassment also apply when both parties are the same sex.</item>
<item>2018 – Former MI6 spy Sergei Skripal and his daughter are poisoned with a Novichok nerve agent in Salisbury, England, causing a diplomatic uproar that results in mass–expulsions of diplomats from all countries involved.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>