<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_5">
<item>1046 – Nasir Khusraw begins the seven–year Middle Eastern journey which he will later describe in his book Safarnama.</item>
<item>1496 – King Henry VII of England issues letters patent to John Cabot and his sons, authorising them to explore unknown lands.</item>
<item>1766 – Antonio de Ulloa, the first Spanish governor of Louisiana, arrives in New Orleans.</item>
<item>1836 – Samuel Colt patents the first production–model revolver, the .34–caliber.</item>
<item>1850 – The Britannia Bridge across the Menai Strait between the island of Anglesey and the mainland of Wales is opened.</item>
<item>1860 – Parma, Tuscany, Modena and Romagna vote in referendums to join the Kingdom of Sardinia.</item>
<item>1868 – Mefistofele, an opera by Arrigo Boito, receives its premiere performance at La Scala.</item>
<item>1872 – George Westinghouse patents the air brake.</item>
<item>1931 – The British Raj: Gandhi–Irwin Pact is signed.</item>
<item>1933 – Great Depression: President Franklin D. Roosevelt declares a \"bank holiday\", closing all U.S. banks and freezing all financial transactions.</item>
<item>1936 – First flight of K5054, the first prototype Supermarine Spitfire advanced monoplane fighter aircraft in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1960 – Indonesian President Soekarno dismissed the Dewan Perwakilan Rakyat (DPR), 1955 democratically elected parliament, and replaced with DPR–GR, the parliament of his own selected members.</item>
<item>1965 – March Intifada: A Leftist uprising erupts in Bahrain against British colonial presence.</item>
<item>1970 – The Treaty on the Non–Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons goes into effect after ratification by 43 nations.</item>
<item>1978 – The Landsat 3 is launched from Vandenberg Air Force Base in California.</item>
<item>1979 – Soviet probes Venera 11, Venera 12 and the German–American solar satellite Helios II all are hit by \"off the scale\" gamma rays leading to the discovery of soft gamma repeaters.</item>
<item>1981 – The ZX81, a pioneering British home computer, is launched by Sinclair Research and would go on to sell over 1.5 million units around the world.</item>
<item>1982 – Soviet probe Venera 14 lands on Venus.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>