<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_6">
<item>12 BC – The Roman Emperor Augustus is named Pontifex Maximus, incorporating the position into that of the emperor.</item>
<item>632 – The Farewell Sermon (Khutbah, Khutbatul Wada\') of the Islamic prophet Muhammad.</item>
<item>845 – Execution of the 42 Martyrs of Amorium at Samarra.</item>
<item>961 – Byzantine conquest of Chandax by Nikephoros Phokas, end of the Emirate of Crete.</item>
<item>1204 – The Siege of Château Gaillard ends in a French victory over King John of England, who loses control of Normandy to King Philip II Augustus.</item>
<item>1323 – Treaty of Paris of 1323 is signed.</item>
<item>1521 – Ferdinand Magellan arrives at Guam.</item>
<item>1665 – The first joint Secretary of the Royal Society, Henry Oldenburg, publishes the first issue of Philosophical Transactions of the Royal Society, the world\'s longest–running scientific journal.</item>
<item>1788 – The First Fleet arrives at Norfolk Island in order to found a convict settlement.</item>
<item>1820 – The Missouri Compromise is signed into law by President James Monroe. The compromise allows Missouri to enter the Union as a slave state, brings Maine into the Union as a free state, and makes the rest of the northern part of the Louisiana Purchase territory slavery–free.</item>
<item>1834 – York, Upper Canada, is incorporated as Toronto.</item>
<item>1857 – The Supreme Court of the United States rules in the Dred Scott v. Sandford case.</item>
<item>1869 – Dmitri Mendeleev presents the first periodic table to the Russian Chemical Society.</item>
<item>1882 – The Serbian kingdom is re–founded.</item>
<item>1899 – Bayer registers \"Aspirin\" as a trademark.</item>
<item>1902 – Real Madrid C.F. is founded.</item>
<item>1921 – Portuguese Communist Party is founded as the Portuguese Section of the Communist International.</item>
<item>1930 – International Unemployment Day demonstrations globally initiated by the Comintern</item>
<item>1943 – Norman Rockwell published Freedom from Want in The Saturday Evening Post with a matching essay by Carlos Bulosan as part of the Four Freedoms series.</item>
<item>1946 – Ho Chi Minh signs an agreement with France which recognizes Vietnam as an autonomous state in the Indochinese Federation and the French Union.</item>
<item>1957 – Ghana becomes the first Sub–Saharan country to gain independence from the British.</item>
<item>1964 – Nation of Islam leader Elijah Muhammad officially gives boxing champion Cassius Clay the name Muhammad Ali.</item>
<item>1964 – Constantine II becomes King of Greece.</item>
<item>1965 – Premier Tom Playford of South Australia loses power after 27 years in office.</item>
<item>1975 – Algiers Accord: Iran and Iraq announce a settlement of their border dispute.</item>
<item>1983 – The first United States Football League games are played.</item>
<item>1984 – In the United Kingdom, a walkout at Cortonwood Colliery in Brampton Bierlow signals the start of a strike that lasted almost a year and involved the majority [but never all] of the country\'s miners.</item>
<item>1992 – The Michelangelo computer virus begins to affect computers.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>