<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_8">
<item>1010 – Ferdowsi completes his epic poem Shahnameh.</item>
<item>1618 – Johannes Kepler discovers the third law of planetary motion.</item>
<item>1655 – John Casor becomes the first legally–recognized slave in England\'s North American colonies where a crime was not committed.</item>
<item>1702 – Queen Anne, the younger sister of Mary II, becomes Queen regnant of England, Scotland, and Ireland.</item>
<item>1736 – Nader Shah, founder of the Afsharid dynasty, is crowned Shah of Iran.</item>
<item>1775 – An anonymous writer, thought by some to be Thomas Paine, publishes \"African Slavery in America\", the first article in the American colonies calling for the emancipation of slaves and the abolition of slavery.</item>
<item>1817 – The New York Stock Exchange is founded.</item>
<item>1844 – King Oscar I ascends to the thrones of Sweden and Norway.</item>
<item>1910 – French aviator Raymonde de Laroche becomes the first woman to receive a pilot\'s license.</item>
<item>1914 – First flights (for the Royal Thai Air Force) at Don Mueang International Airport in Bangkok.</item>
<item>1917 – The United States Senate votes to limit filibusters by adopting the cloture rule.</item>
<item>1920 – The Arab Kingdom of Syria, the first modern Arab state to come into existence, is established.</item>
<item>1936 – Daytona Beach and Road Course holds its first oval stock car race.</item>
<item>1944 – The NKVD begins the forced deportation of the entire Balkar nation.</item>
<item>1949 – President of France Vincent Auriol and ex–emperor of Annam Bảo Đại sign the Élysée Accords, giving Vietnam greater independence from France and creating the State of Vietnam to oppose Viet Minh–led Democratic Republic of Vietnam.</item>
<item>1957 – Egypt re–opens the Suez Canal after the Suez Crisis.</item>
<item>1957 – The 1957 Georgia Memorial to Congress, which petitions the U.S. Congress to declare the ratification of the 14th and 15th Amendments to the U.S. Constitution null and void, is adopted by the U.S. state of Georgia.</item>
<item>1971 – The Fight of the Century between Joe Frazier and Muhammad Ali commences. Frazier wins in 15 rounds via unanimous decision.</item>
<item>1974 – Charles de Gaulle Airport opens in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1979 – Philips demonstrates the compact disc publicly for the first time.</item>
<item>2004 – A new constitution is signed by Iraq\'s Governing Council.</item>
<item>2014 – Malaysia Airlines Flight 370, carrying a total of 239 people, disappears en route from Kuala Lumpur to Beijing.</item>
<item>2017 – The Azure Window, a natural arch on the Maltese island of Gozo, collapsed in stormy weather.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>