<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a3_9">
<item>141 BC – Liu Che, posthumously known as Emperor Wu of Han, assumes the throne over the Han dynasty of China.</item>
<item>1009 – First known mention of Lithuania, in the annals of the monastery of Quedlinburg.</item>
<item>1276 – Augsburg becomes a Free imperial city.</item>
<item>1776 – The Wealth of Nations by Scottish economist and philosopher Adam Smith is published.</item>
<item>1796 – Napoléon Bonaparte marries his first wife, Joséphine de Beauharnais.</item>
<item>1815 – Francis Ronalds describes the first battery–operated clock in the Philosophical Magazine.</item>
<item>1841 – The U.S. Supreme Court rules in the United States v. The Amistad case that captive Africans who had seized control of the ship carrying them had been taken into slavery illegally.</item>
<item>1842 – Giuseppe Verdi\'s third opera, Nabucco, receives its première performance in Milan; its success establishes Verdi as one of Italy\'s foremost opera composers.</item>
<item>1842 – The first documented discovery of gold in California occurs at Rancho San Francisco, six years before the California Gold Rush.</item>
<item>1910 – The Westmoreland County coal strike, involving 15,000 coal miners represented by the United Mine Workers, begins.</item>
<item>1933 – Great Depression: President Franklin D. Roosevelt submits the Emergency Banking Act to Congress, the first of his New Deal policies.</item>
<item>1954 – McCarthyism: CBS television broadcasts the See It Now episode, \"A Report on Senator Joseph McCarthy\", produced by Fred Friendly.</item>
<item>1959 – The Barbie doll makes its debut at the American International Toy Fair in New York.</item>
<item>1960 – Dr. Belding Hibbard Scribner implants for the first time a shunt he invented into a patient, which allows the patient to receive hemodialysis on a regular basis.</item>
<item>1961 – Sputnik 9 successfully launches, carrying a human dummy nicknamed Ivan Ivanovich, and demonstrating that the Soviet Union was ready to begin human spaceflight.</item>
<item>1974 – The Mars 7 Flyby bus releases the descent module too early, missing Mars.</item>
<item>1978 – President Soeharto inaugurated Jagorawi Toll Road, the first toll highway in Indonesia, connecting Jakarta, Bogor and Ciawi, West Java.</item>
<item>1982 – \"Krononauts\" hosted an event in Baltimore, Maryland asking time–travelers to meet and demonstrate future science methods of Time travel.</item>
<item>1997 – Comet Hale–Bopp: Observers in China, Mongolia and eastern Siberia are treated to a rare double feature as an eclipse permits Hale–Bopp to be seen during the day.</item>
<item>2011 – Space Shuttle Discovery makes its final landing after 39 flights.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>