<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_1">
<item>286 – Emperor Diocletian elevates his general Maximian to co–emperor with the rank of Augustus and gives him control over the Western regions of the Roman Empire.</item>
<item>325 – Crown Prince Jin Chengdi, age 4, succeeds his father Jin Mingdi as emperor of the Eastern Jin dynasty.</item>
<item>457 – Majorian is acclaimed emperor by the Roman army after defeating 900 Alemanni near Lake Maggiore (Italy).</item>
<item>527 – Byzantine Emperor Justin I names his nephew Justinian I as co–ruler and successor to the throne.</item>
<item>528 – The daughter of Emperor Xiaoming of Northern Wei was made the \"Emperor\" as a male heir of the late emperor by Empress Dowager Hu. Deposed and replaced by Yuan Zhao the next day, she was the first female monarch in the History of China, but is not widely recognised.</item>
<item>988 – Robert II of France is married to Rozala of Italy. The marriage is arranged by his father, King Hugh Capet.</item>
<item>1293 – Robert Winchelsey leaves England for Rome, to be consecrated as Archbishop of Canterbury.</item>
<item>1318 – Berwick–upon–Tweed is captured by Scotland from England.</item>
<item>1545 – Potosí is founded after the discovery of huge silver deposits in the area.</item>
<item>1789 – In New York City, the United States House of Representatives holds its first quorum and elects Frederick Muhlenberg of Pennsylvania as its first Speaker.</item>
<item>1826 – Samuel Morey received a patent for a compressionless \"Gas or Vapor Engine\".</item>
<item>1833 – The Convention of 1833, a political gathering of settlers in Mexican Texas to help draft a series of petitions to the Mexican government, begins in San Felipe de Austin</item>
<item>1854 – Charles Dickens\' novel Hard Times begins serialisation in his magazine Household Words.</item>
<item>1867 – Singapore becomes a British crown colony.</item>
<item>1871 – The 3rd Duke of Buckingham opened the Brill Tramway, a short railway line to transport goods between his lands and the national rail network.</item>
<item>1889 – The University of Northern Colorado was established, as the Colorado State Normal School.</item>
<item>1891 – The Wrigley Company is founded in Chicago, Illinois.</item>
<item>1893 – The rank of Chief Petty Officer in the United States Navy is established.</item>
<item>1908 – The Territorial Force (renamed Territorial Army in 1920) is formed as a volunteer reserve component of the British Army.</item>
<item>1918 – The Royal Air Force is created by the merger of the Royal Flying Corps and the Royal Naval Air Service.</item>
<item>1924 – The Royal Canadian Air Force is formed.</item>
<item>1933 – English cricketer Wally Hammond set a record for the highest individual Test innings of 336 not out, during a Test match against New Zealand.</item>
<item>1935 – India\'s central banking institution, The Reserve Bank of India is formed.</item>
<item>1937 – Aden becomes a British crown colony.</item>
<item>1937 – The Royal New Zealand Air Force is formed as an independent service.</item>
<item>1941 – A military coup in Iraq overthrows the regime of \'Abd al–Ilah and installs Rashid Ali al–Gaylani as Prime Minister.</item>
<item>1947 – The only mutiny in the history of the Royal New Zealand Navy begins.</item>
<item>1948 – Faroe Islands gain autonomy from Denmark.</item>
<item>1949 – The Government of Canada repeals Japanese–Canadian internment after seven years.</item>
<item>1954 – United States President Dwight D. Eisenhower authorizes the creation of the United States Air Force Academy in Colorado.</item>
<item>1955 – The EOKA rebellion against the British Empire begins in Cyprus, with the goal of unifying with Greece.</item>
<item>1960 – The TIROS–1 satellite transmits the first television picture from space.</item>
<item>1969 – The Hawker Siddeley Harrier, the first operational fighter aircraft with Vertical/Short Takeoff and Landing capabilities, entered service with the Royal Air Force.</item>
<item>1970 – The first of over 670,000 AMC Gremlins were released into North America to compete with foreign imported cars.</item>
<item>1973 – Project Tiger, a tiger conservation project, is launched in the Jim Corbett National Park, India.</item>
<item>1974 – The Local Government Act 1972 of England and Wales comes into effect.</item>
<item>1976 – Apple Inc. is formed by Steve Jobs, Steve Wozniak, and Ronald Wayne in Cupertino, California, USA.</item>
<item>1978 – The Philippine College of Commerce, through a presidential decree, becomes the Polytechnic University of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1979 – Iran becomes an Islamic republic by a 99% vote, officially overthrowing the Shah.</item>
<item>1989 – Margaret Thatcher\'s new local government tax, the Community Charge (commonly known as the \"poll tax\"), is introduced in Scotland.</item>
<item>1996 – The government of Nova Scotia amalgamated the City of Halifax and the over 200 communities around the area to create the Halifax Regional Municipality.</item>
<item>1997 – Comet Hale–Bopp is seen passing at perihelion.</item>
<item>1999 – Nunavut is established as a Canadian territory carved out of the eastern part of the Northwest Territories.</item>
<item>2001 – An EP–3E United States Navy surveillance aircraft collides with a Chinese People\'s Liberation Army Shenyang J–8 fighter jet. The Navy crew makes an emergency landing in Hainan, China and is detained.</item>
<item>2001 – Same–sex marriage becomes legal in the Netherlands, the first contemporary country to allow it.</item>
<item>2004 – Google announces Gmail to the public.</item>
<item>2006 – Serious Organised Crime Agency (SOCA) of the Government of the United Kingdom is enforced, but later merged into National Crime Agency on 7 October 2013.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>