<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_16">
<item>1346 – Dušan the Mighty is proclaimed Emperor, with the Serbian Empire occupying much of the Balkans.</item>
<item>1520 – The Revolt of the Comuneros begins in Spain against the rule of Charles V.</item>
<item>1582 – Spanish conquistador Hernando de Lerma founds the settlement of Salta, Argentina.</item>
<item>1780 – Franz Friedrich Wilhelm von Fürstenberg founds the University of Münster.</item>
<item>1818 – The United States Senate ratifies the Rush–Bagot Treaty, establishing the border with Canada.</item>
<item>1853 – The Great Indian Peninsula Railway opens the first passenger rail in India, from Bori Bunder to Thane.</item>
<item>1858 – The Wernerian Natural History Society, a former Scottish learned society, is wound up.</item>
<item>1908 – Natural Bridges National Monument is established in Utah.</item>
<item>1910 – The oldest existing indoor ice hockey arena still used for the sport in the 21st century, Boston Arena, opens for the first time.</item>
<item>1912 – Harriet Quimby becomes the first woman to fly an airplane across the English Channel.</item>
<item>1917 – Vladimir Lenin returns to Petrograd, Russia, from exile in Switzerland.</item>
<item>1922 – The Treaty of Rapallo, pursuant to which Germany and the Soviet Union re–establish diplomatic relations, is signed.</item>
<item>1943 – Albert Hofmann accidentally discovers the hallucinogenic effects of the research drug LSD. He intentionally takes the drug three days later on April 19.</item>
<item>1961 – In a nationally broadcast speech, Cuban leader Fidel Castro declares that he is a Marxist–Leninist and that Cuba is going to adopt Communism.</item>
<item>1963 – Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. pens his Letter from Birmingham Jail while incarcerated in Birmingham, Alabama for protesting against segregation.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo program: The launch of Apollo 16 from Cape Canaveral, Florida.</item>
<item>1992 – The Katina P runs aground off of Maputo, Mozambique and 60,000 tons of crude oil spill into the ocean.</item>
<item>2001 – India and Bangladesh begin a five–day border conflict, but are unable to resolve the disputes about their border.</item>
<item>2003 – The Treaty of Accession is signed in Athens admitting ten new member states to the European Union.</item>
<item>2007 – Virginia Tech shooting: Seung–Hui Cho guns down 32 people and injures 17 before committing suicide.</item>
<item>2012 – The Pulitzer Prize winners were announced, it was the first time since 1977 that no book won the Fiction Prize.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>