<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_11">
<item>491 – Flavius Anastasius becomes Byzantine emperor, with the name of Anastasius I.</item>
<item>1034 – Emperor Romanos III Argyros is drowned in his bath on Empress Zoë orders.</item>
<item>1689 – William III and Mary II are crowned as joint sovereigns of Great Britain.</item>
<item>1727 – Premiere of Johann Sebastian Bach\'s St Matthew Passion BWV 244b at the St. Thomas Church, Leipzig</item>
<item>1868 – Former shōgun Tokugawa Yoshinobu surrenders Edo Castle to Imperial forces, marking the end of the Tokugawa shogunate.</item>
<item>1876 – The Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks is organized.</item>
<item>1881 – Spelman College is founded in Atlanta, Georgia as the Atlanta Baptist Female Seminary, an institute of higher education for African–American women.</item>
<item>1908 – SMS Blücher, the last armored cruiser to be built by the Imperial German Navy, launches.</item>
<item>1909 – The city of Tel Aviv is founded.</item>
<item>1921 – Emir Abdullah establishes the first centralised government in the newly created British protectorate of Transjordan.</item>
<item>1951 – The Stone of Scone, the stone upon which Scottish monarchs were traditionally crowned, is found on the site of the altar of Arbroath Abbey. It had been taken by Scottish nationalist students from its place in Westminster Abbey.</item>
<item>1954 – The Belgian general election occurred, replacing the Christian Social Party\'s majority government with a Socialist–Liberal coalition.</item>
<item>1957 – United Kingdom agrees to Singaporean self–rule.</item>
<item>1961 – The trial of Adolf Eichmann begins in Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1963 – Pope John XXIII issues Pacem in terris, the first encyclical addressed to all Christians instead of only Catholics.</item>
<item>1964 – Brazilian Marshal Humberto de Alencar Castelo Branco is elected President by the National Congress.</item>
<item>1968 – President Lyndon B. Johnson signs the Civil Rights Act of 1968, prohibiting discrimination in the sale, rental, and financing of housing.</item>
<item>1968 – Assassination attempt on Rudi Dutschke, leader of the German student movement.</item>
<item>1970 – Apollo 13 is launched.</item>
<item>1976 – The Apple I is created.</item>
<item>1977 – London Transport\'s Silver Jubilee AEC Routemaster buses are launched.</item>
<item>1979 – Ugandan dictator Idi Amin is deposed.</item>
<item>1981 – A massive riot in Brixton, south London results in almost 300 police injuries and 65 serious civilian injuries.</item>
<item>1987 – The London Agreement is secretly signed between Israeli Foreign Affairs Minister Shimon Peres and King Hussein of Jordan.</item>
<item>1990 – Customs officers in Middlesbrough, England, seize what they believe to be the barrel of a massive gun on a ship bound for Iraq.</item>
<item>1993 – Four hundred fifty prisoners rioted at the Southern Ohio Correctional Facility in Lucasville, Ohio, and continued to do so for ten days, citing grievances related to prison conditions, as well as the forced vaccination of Nation of Islam prisoners (for tuberculosis) against their religious beliefs.</item>
<item>2001 – The detained crew of a United States EP–3E aircraft that landed in Hainan, China after a collision with a J–8 fighter, is released.</item>
<item>2006 – Iranian president Mahmoud Ahmadinejad announces Iran\'s claim to have successfully enriched uranium.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>