<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_14">
<item>193 – Septimius Severus is proclaimed Roman emperor by the army in Illyricum (in the Balkans).</item>
<item>966 – After his marriage to the Christian Doubravka of Bohemia, the pagan ruler of the Polans, Mieszko I, converts to Christianity, an event considered to be the founding of the Polish state.</item>
<item>972 – Co–Emperor Otto II, a son of Otto I (the Great), marries the Byzantine princess Theophanu. She is crowned empress by Pope John XIII at Rome.</item>
<item>1028 – Henry III, son of Conrad, is elected King of Germany.</item>
<item>1294 – Temür, grandson of Kublai, is elected Khagan of the Mongols and Emperor of the Yuan dynasty with the reigning titles Oljeitu and Chengzong.</item>
<item>1341 – Sack of Saluzzo (Italy) by Italian–Angevine troops under Manfred V, Marquess of Saluzzo.</item>
<item>1434 – The foundation stone of Nantes Cathedral, France is laid.</item>
<item>1775 – The first abolition society in North America is established. The Society for the Relief of Free Negroes Unlawfully Held in Bondage is organized in Philadelphia by Benjamin Franklin and Benjamin Rush.</item>
<item>1828 – Noah Webster copyrights the first edition of his dictionary.</item>
<item>1849 – Hungary declares itself independent of Austria with Lajos Kossuth as its leader.</item>
<item>1890 – The Pan–American Union is founded by the First International Conference of American States in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1894 – The first ever commercial motion picture house opened in New York City using ten Kinetoscopes, a device for peep–show viewing of films.</item>
<item>1900 – The Exposition Universelle begins.</item>
<item>1902 – James Cash Penney opens his first store in Kemmerer, Wyoming.</item>
<item>1906 – The Azusa Street Revival opens and will launch Pentecostalism as a worldwide movement.</item>
<item>1908 – Hauser Dam, a steel dam on the Missouri River in Montana, U.S., fails, sending a surge of water 25 to 30 feet (7.6 to 9.1 m) high downstream.</item>
<item>1909 – A massacre is organized by the Ottoman Empire against the Armenian population of Cilicia.</item>
<item>1912 – The British passenger liner RMS Titanic hits an iceberg in the North Atlantic at 23:40 (sinks morning of April 15th).</item>
<item>1927 – The first Volvo car premieres in Gothenburg, Sweden.</item>
<item>1928 – The Bremen, a German Junkers W 33 type aircraft, reaches Greenly Island, Canada – the first successful transatlantic aeroplane flight from east to west.</item>
<item>1931 – The Spanish Cortes deposes King Alfonso XIII and proclaims the Second Spanish Republic.</item>
<item>1935 – The Black Sunday dust storm, considered one of the worst storms of the Dust Bowl, swept across the Oklahoma and Texas panhandles and neighboring areas.</item>
<item>1939 – The Grapes of Wrath, by American author John Steinbeck is first published by the Viking Press.</item>
<item>1942 – Malta receives the George Cross for its gallantry. The George Cross was given by King George VI himself and is now an emblem on the Maltese national flag.</item>
<item>1958 – The Soviet satellite Sputnik 2 falls from orbit after a mission duration of 162 days. This was the first spacecraft to carry a living animal, a female dog named Laika, who likely lived only a few hours.</item>
<item>1967 – Gnassingbé Eyadéma overthrows President of Togo Nicolas Grunitzky and installs himself as the new president, a title he would hold for the next 38 years.</item>
<item>1978 – Tbilisi Demonstrations: Thousands of Georgians demonstrate against Soviet attempts to change the constitutional status of the Georgian language.</item>
<item>1981 – STS–1: The first operational Space Shuttle, Columbia completes its first test flight.</item>
<item>1988 – The USS Samuel B. Roberts strikes a mine in the Persian Gulf during Operation Earnest Will.</item>
<item>1988 – In a United Nations ceremony in Geneva, Switzerland, the Soviet Union signs an agreement pledging to withdraw its troops from Afghanistan.</item>
<item>1991 – The Republic of Georgia introduces the post of President after its declaration of independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>2002 – Venezuelan President Hugo Chávez returns to office two days after being ousted and arrested by the country\'s military.</item>
<item>2003 – The Human Genome Project is completed with 99% of the human genome sequenced to an accuracy of 99.99%.</item>
<item>2005 – The Oregon Supreme Court nullifies marriage licenses issued to same–sex couples a year earlier by Multnomah County.</item>
<item>2012 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 2042 relating to Syrian uprising is adopted.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>