<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_15">
<item>769 – The Lateran Council condemned the Council of Hieria and anathematized its iconoclastic rulings.</item>
<item>1071 – Bari, the last Byzantine possession in southern Italy, is surrendered to Robert Guiscard.</item>
<item>1736 – Foundation of the Kingdom of Corsica</item>
<item>1738 – Serse, an Italian opera by George Frideric Handel receives its premiere performance in London, England.</item>
<item>1755 – Samuel Johnson\'s A Dictionary of the English Language is published in London.</item>
<item>1817 – Thomas Hopkins Gallaudet and Laurent Clerc founded the American School for the Deaf, the first American school for deaf students, in Hartford, Connecticut.</item>
<item>1892 – The General Electric Company is formed.</item>
<item>1896 – Closing ceremony of the Games of the I Olympiad in Athens, Greece.</item>
<item>1907 – Triangle Fraternity is founded at the University of Illinois at Urbana–Champaign</item>
<item>1922 – U.S. Senator John B. Kendrick of Wyoming introduces a resolution calling for an investigation of a secret land deal, which leads to the discovery of the Teapot Dome scandal.</item>
<item>1923 – Insulin becomes generally available for use by people with diabetes.</item>
<item>1924 – Rand McNally publishes its first road atlas.</item>
<item>1936 – First day of the Arab revolt in Mandatory Palestine.</item>
<item>1945 – Bergen–Belsen concentration camp is liberated.</item>
<item>1947 – Jackie Robinson debuts for the Brooklyn Dodgers, breaking baseball\'s color line.</item>
<item>1955 – McDonald\'s restaurant dates its founding to the opening of a franchised restaurant by Ray Kroc, in Des Plaines, Illinois</item>
<item>1960 – At Shaw University in Raleigh, North Carolina, Ella Baker leads a conference that results in the creation of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, one of the principal organizations of the civil rights movement in the 1960s.</item>
<item>1994 – Marrakesh Agreement relating to foundation of World Trade Organization is adopted.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>