<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_18">
<item>1025 – Bolesław Chrobry is crowned in Gniezno, becoming the first King of Poland.</item>
<item>1506 – The cornerstone of the current St. Peter\'s Basilica is laid.</item>
<item>1518 – Bona Sforza is crowned as queen consort of Poland.</item>
<item>1689 – Bostonians rise up in rebellion against Sir Edmund Andros.</item>
<item>1738 – Real Academia de la Historia (\"Royal Academy of History\") is founded in Madrid.</item>
<item>1831 – The University of Alabama is founded in Tuscaloosa, Alabama.</item>
<item>1857 – \"The Spirits Book\" by Allan Kardec is published, marking the birth of Spiritualism in France.</item>
<item>1899 – The St. Andrew\'s Ambulance Association is granted a royal charter by Queen Victoria.</item>
<item>1909 – Joan of Arc is beatified in Rome.</item>
<item>1912 – The Cunard liner RMS Carpathia brings 705 survivors from the RMS Titanic to New York City.</item>
<item>1923 – Yankee Stadium: \"The House that Ruth Built\" opens.</item>
<item>1925 – The International Amateur Radio Union is formed in Paris.</item>
<item>1930 – The British Broadcasting Corporation announced that \"there is no news\" in their evening report.</item>
<item>1942 – Pierre Laval becomes Prime Minister of Vichy France.</item>
<item>1946 – The International Court of Justice holds its inaugural meeting in The Hague, Netherlands.</item>
<item>1949 – The Republic of Ireland Act comes into effect.</item>
<item>1949 – The keel for the aircraft carrier USS United States is laid down at Newport News Drydock and Shipbuilding. However, construction is canceled five days later, resulting in the Revolt of the Admirals.</item>
<item>1954 – Gamal Abdel Nasser seizes power in Egypt.</item>
<item>1955 – Twenty–nine nations meet at Bandung, Indonesia, for the first Asian–African Conference.</item>
<item>1980 – The Republic of Zimbabwe (formerly Rhodesia) comes into being, with Canaan Banana as the country\'s first President. The Zimbabwean dollar replaces the Rhodesian dollar as the official currency.</item>
<item>1992 – General Abdul Rashid Dostum revolts against President Mohammad Najibullah of the Democratic Republic of Afghanistan and allies with Ahmad Shah Massoud to capture Kabul.</item>
<item>2018 – King Mswati III of Swaziland announced to change his country\'s name to Eswatini.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>