<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_19">
<item>1012 – Martyrdom of Ælfheah in Greenwich, England.</item>
<item>1506 – The Lisbon Massacre begins, in which accused Jews are being slaughtered by Portuguese Catholics.</item>
<item>1539 – Treaty of Frankfurt signed.</item>
<item>1677 – The French army captures the town of Cambrai held by Spanish troops.</item>
<item>1713 – With no living male heirs, Charles VI, Holy Roman Emperor, issues the Pragmatic Sanction of 1713 to ensure that Habsburg lands and the Austrian throne would be inherited by his daughter, Maria Theresa (not actually born until 1717).</item>
<item>1770 – Captain James Cook, still holding the rank of lieutenant, sights the eastern coast of what is now Australia.</item>
<item>1770 – Marie Antoinette marries Louis XVI of France in a proxy wedding.</item>
<item>1782 – John Adams secures the Dutch Republic\'s recognition of the United States as an independent government. The house which he had purchased in The Hague, Netherlands becomes the first American embassy.</item>
<item>1810 – Venezuela achieves home rule: Vicente Emparán, Governor of the Captaincy General is removed by the people of Caracas and a junta is installed.</item>
<item>1818 – French physicist Augustin Fresnel signs his preliminary \"Note on the Theory of Diffraction\" (deposited on the following day). The document ends with what we now call the Fresnel integrals.</item>
<item>1839 – The Treaty of London establishes Belgium as a kingdom and guarantees its neutrality.</item>
<item>1903 – The Kishinev pogrom in Kishinev (Bessarabia) begins, forcing tens of thousands of Jews to later seek refuge in Palestine and the Western world.</item>
<item>1943 – Albert Hofmann deliberately doses himself with LSD for the first time, three days after having discovered its effects on April 16.</item>
<item>1956 – Actress Grace Kelly marries Prince Rainier of Monaco.</item>
<item>1960 – Students in South Korea hold a nationwide pro–democracy protest against president Syngman Rhee, eventually forcing him to resign.</item>
<item>1971 – Sierra Leone becomes a republic, and Siaka Stevens the president.</item>
<item>1971 – Launch of Salyut 1, the first space station.</item>
<item>1973 – The Portuguese Socialist Party is founded in the German town of Bad Münstereifel.</item>
<item>1975 – India\'s first satellite Aryabhata launched in orbit from Kapustin Yar, Russia.</item>
<item>1984 – Advance Australia Fair is proclaimed as Australia\'s national anthem, and green and gold as the national colours.</item>
<item>1985 – Two hundred ATF and FBI agents lay siege to the compound of the white supremacist survivalist group The Covenant, The Sword, and the Arm of the Lord in Arkansas; the CSA surrenders two days later.</item>
<item>1987 – The Simpsons first appear as a series of shorts on The Tracey Ullman Show, first starting with Good Night.</item>
<item>1999 – The German Bundestag returns to Berlin.</item>
<item>2005 – Cardinal Joseph Ratzinger is elected to the papacy and becomes Pope Benedict XVI.</item>
<item>2011 – Fidel Castro resigns as First Secretary of the Communist Party of Cuba after holding the title since July 1961.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>