<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_10">
<item>428 – Nestorius becomes the Patriarch of Constantinople.</item>
<item>837 – Halley\'s Comet makes its closest approach to Earth at a distance equal to 0.0342 AU (5.1 million kilometres/3.2 million miles).</item>
<item>1500 – Ludovico Sforza is captured by Swiss troops at Novara and is handed over to the French.</item>
<item>1606 – The Virginia Company of London is established by royal charter by James I of England with the purpose of establishing colonial settlements in North America.</item>
<item>1710 – The Statute of Anne, the first law regulating copyright, comes into force in Great Britain.</item>
<item>1816 – The Federal government of the United States approves the creation of the Second Bank of the United States.</item>
<item>1821 – Patriarch Gregory V of Constantinople is hanged by the Ottoman government from the main gate of the Patriarchate and his body is thrown into the Bosphorus.</item>
<item>1826 – The 10,500 inhabitants of the Greek town of Missolonghi begin leaving the town after a year\'s siege by Turkish forces. Very few of them survive.</item>
<item>1858 – After the original Big Ben, a 14.5 tonnes (32,000 lb) bell for the Palace of Westminster, had cracked during testing, it is recast into the current 13.76 tonnes (30,300 lb) bell by Whitechapel Bell Foundry.</item>
<item>1864 – Archduke Maximilian of Habsburg is proclaimed emperor of Mexico during the French intervention in Mexico.</item>
<item>1866 – The American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals (ASPCA) is founded in New York City by Henry Bergh.</item>
<item>1872 – The first Arbor Day is celebrated in Nebraska.</item>
<item>1887 – On Easter Sunday, Pope Leo XIII authorizes the establishment of the Catholic University of America.</item>
<item>1912 – RMS Titanic sets sail from Southampton, England on her maiden and only voyage.</item>
<item>1916 – The Professional Golfers\' Association of America (PGA) is created in New York City.</item>
<item>1925 – The Great Gatsby by F. Scott Fitzgerald is first published in New York City, by Charles Scribner\'s Sons.</item>
<item>1957 – The Suez Canal is reopened for all shipping after being closed for three months.</item>
<item>1970 – Paul McCartney announces that he is leaving The Beatles for personal and professional reasons.</item>
<item>1971 – Ping–pong diplomacy: In an attempt to thaw relations with the United States, China hosts the U.S. table tennis team for a week–long visit.</item>
<item>1991 – A rare tropical storm develops in the South Atlantic Ocean near Angola; the first to be documented by satellites.</item>
<item>1998 – The Good Friday Agreement is signed in Northern Ireland.</item>
<item>2009 – President of Fiji Ratu Josefa Iloilo announces the abrogation of the constitution and assumes all governance in the country, creating a constitutional crisis.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>