<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_24">
<item>1479 BC – Thutmose III ascends to the throne of Egypt, although power effectively shifts to Hatshepsut (according to the Low Chronology of the 18th dynasty).</item>
<item>1184 BC – Traditional date of the fall of Troy.</item>
<item>1558 – Mary, Queen of Scots, marries the Dauphin of France, François, at Notre Dame de Paris.</item>
<item>1704 – The first regular newspaper in British Colonial America, The Boston News–Letter, is published.</item>
<item>1800 – The United States Library of Congress is established when President John Adams signs legislation to appropriate $5,000 to purchase \"such books as may be necessary for the use of Congress\".</item>
<item>1885 – American sharpshooter Annie Oakley is hired by Nate Salsbury to be a part of Buffalo Bill\'s Wild West.</item>
<item>1895 – Joshua Slocum, the first person to sail single–handedly around the world, sets sail from Boston, Massachusetts aboard the sloop \"Spray\".</item>
<item>1913 – The Woolworth Building, a skyscraper in New York City, is opened.</item>
<item>1914 – The Franck–Hertz experiment, a pillar of quantum mechanics, is presented to the German Physical Society.</item>
<item>1915 – The arrest of 250 Armenian intellectuals and community leaders in Istanbul marks the beginning of the Armenian Genocide.</item>
<item>1916 – Easter Rising: Irish rebels, led by Patrick Pearse and James Connolly, launch an uprising in Dublin against British rule and proclaim an Irish Republic.</item>
<item>1916 – Ernest Shackleton and five men of the Imperial Trans–Antarctic Expedition launch a lifeboat from uninhabited Elephant Island in the Southern Ocean to organise a rescue for the crew of the sunken Endurance.</item>
<item>1922 – The first segment of the Imperial Wireless Chain providing wireless telegraphy between Leafield in Oxfordshire, England, and Cairo, Egypt, comes into operation.</item>
<item>1923 – In Vienna, the paper Das Ich und das Es (The Ego and the Id) by Sigmund Freud is published, which outlines Freud\'s theories of the id, ego, and super–ego.</item>
<item>1932 – Benny Rothman leads the mass trespass of Kinder Scout, leading to substantial legal reforms in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1953 – Winston Churchill is knighted by Queen Elizabeth II.</item>
<item>1957 – Suez Crisis: The Suez Canal is reopened following the introduction of UNEF peacekeepers to the region.</item>
<item>1963 – Marriage of HRH Princess Alexandra of Kent to the Hon Angus Ogilvy at Westminster Abbey in London.</item>
<item>1990 – STS–31: The Hubble Space Telescope is launched from the Space Shuttle Discovery.</item>
<item>1990 – Gruinard Island, Scotland, is officially declared free of the anthrax disease after 48 years of quarantine.</item>
<item>2005 – Cardinal Joseph Ratzinger is inaugurated as the 265th Pope of the Catholic Church taking the name Pope Benedict XVI.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>