<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_28">
<item>357 – Emperor Constantius II enters Rome for the first time to celebrate his victory over Magnus Magnentius.</item>
<item>1253 – Nichiren, a Japanese Buddhist monk, propounds Namu Myōhō Renge Kyō for the very first time and declares it to be the essence of Buddhism, in effect founding Nichiren Buddhism.</item>
<item>1611 – Establishment of the Pontifical and Royal University of Santo Tomas, The Catholic University of the Philippines, the largest Catholic university in the world.</item>
<item>1788 – Maryland becomes the seventh state to ratify the United States Constitution.</item>
<item>1789 – Mutiny on the Bounty: Lieutenant William Bligh and 18 sailors are set adrift and the rebel crew returns to Tahiti briefly and then sets sail for Pitcairn Island.</item>
<item>1796 – The Armistice of Cherasco is signed by Napoleon Bonaparte and Vittorio Amedeo III, King of Sardinia, expanding French territory along the Mediterranean coast.</item>
<item>1869 – Chinese and Irish laborers for the Central Pacific Railroad working on the First Transcontinental Railroad lay ten miles of track in one day, a feat which has never been matched.</item>
<item>1881 – Billy the Kid escapes from the Lincoln County jail in Mesilla, New Mexico.</item>
<item>1910 – Frenchman Louis Paulhan wins the 1910 London to Manchester air race, the first long–distance aeroplane race in England.</item>
<item>1920 – Azerbaijan is added to the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1923 – Wembley Stadium is opened, named initially as the Empire Stadium.</item>
<item>1930 – The Independence Producers hosted the first night game in the history of Organized Baseball in Independence, Kansas.</item>
<item>1941 – The Ustaše massacre nearly 200 Serbs in the village of Gudovac, the first massacre of their genocidal campaign against Serbs of the Independent State of Croatia.</item>
<item>1947 – Thor Heyerdahl and five crew mates set out from Peru on the Kon–Tiki to demonstrate that Peruvian natives could have settled Polynesia.</item>
<item>1948 – Igor Stravinsky conducted the premiere of his American ballet, Orpheus at the New York City Center.</item>
<item>1952 – Dwight D. Eisenhower resigns as Supreme Allied Commander of NATO.</item>
<item>1965 – United States occupation of the Dominican Republic: American troops land in the Dominican Republic to \"forestall establishment of a Communist dictatorship\" and to evacuate U.S. Army troops.</item>
<item>1969 – Charles de Gaulle resigns as President of France.</item>
<item>1973 – The Dark Side of the Moon by Pink Floyd, recorded in Abbey Road Studios goes to number one on the US charts, beginning a record–breaking 741–week chart run.</item>
<item>1975 – General Cao Văn Viên, chief of the South Vietnamese military, departs for the US as the North Vietnamese Army closed in on victory.</item>
<item>1978 – President of Afghanistan, Mohammed Daoud Khan, is overthrown and assassinated in a coup led by pro–communist rebels.</item>
<item>1986 – The United States Navy aircraft carrier USS Enterprise becomes the first nuclear–powered aircraft carrier to transit the Suez Canal, navigating from the Red Sea to the Mediterranean Sea to relieve the USS Coral Sea.</item>
<item>1994 – Former Central Intelligence Agency counterintelligence officer and analyst Aldrich Ames pleads guilty to giving U.S. secrets to the Soviet Union and later Russia.</item>
<item>1996 – Whitewater controversy: President Bill Clinton gives a 4½ hour videotaped testimony for the defense.</item>
<item>2011 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 1980 relating to Ivorian crisis is adopted.</item>
<item>2015 – The National Football League announces it is giving up its tax–exempt status.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>