<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_26">
<item>1336 – Francesco Petrarca (Petrarch) ascends Mont Ventoux.</item>
<item>1607 – English colonists make landfall at Cape Henry, Virginia.</item>
<item>1777 – Sybil Ludington, aged 16, rode 40 miles to alert American colonial forces to the approach of the British regular forces</item>
<item>1803 – Thousands of meteor fragments fall from the skies of L\'Aigle, France; the event convinces European scientists that meteors exist.</item>
<item>1903 – Atlético Madrid Association football club is founded</item>
<item>1923 – The Duke of York weds Lady Elizabeth Bowes–Lyon at Westminster Abbey.</item>
<item>1925 – Paul von Hindenburg defeats Wilhelm Marx in the second round of the German presidential election to become the first directly elected head of state of the Weimar Republic.</item>
<item>1943 – The Easter Riots break out in Uppsala, Sweden.</item>
<item>1944 – Georgios Papandreou becomes head of the Greek government–in–exile based in Egypt.</item>
<item>1944 – Heinrich Kreipe is captured by Allied commandos in occupied Crete.</item>
<item>1954 – The Geneva Conference, an effort to restore peace in Indochina and Korea, begins.</item>
<item>1958 – Final run of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad\'s Royal Blue from Washington, D.C., to New York City after 68 years, the first U.S. passenger train to use electric locomotives.</item>
<item>1962 – NASA\'s Ranger 4 spacecraft crashes into the Moon.</item>
<item>1963 – In Libya, amendments to the constitution transform Libya (United Kingdom of Libya) into one national unity (Kingdom of Libya) and allows for female participation in elections.</item>
<item>1964 – Tanganyika and Zanzibar merge to form Tanzania.</item>
<item>1966 – A new government is formed in the Republic of the Congo, led by Ambroise Noumazalaye.</item>
<item>1970 – The Convention Establishing the World Intellectual Property Organization enters into force.</item>
<item>1981 – Dr. Michael R. Harrison of the University of California, San Francisco Medical Center performs the world\'s first human open fetal surgery.</item>
<item>1989 – People\'s Daily publishes the April 26 Editorial which inflames the nascent Tiananmen Square protests</item>
<item>2005 – Under international pressure, Syria withdraws the last of its 14,000 troop military garrison in Lebanon, ending its 29–year military domination of that country (Syrian occupation of Lebanon).</item>
<item>2018 – American comedian Bill Cosby is found guilty of sexual assault.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>