<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_29">
<item>1429 – Joan of Arc arrives to relieve the Siege of Orléans.</item>
<item>1483 – Gran Canaria, the main island of the Canary Islands, is conquered by the Kingdom of Castile.</item>
<item>1770 – James Cook arrives in Australia at Botany Bay, which he names.</item>
<item>1834 – Charles Darwin during the second survey voyage of HMS Beagle, ascended the Bell mountain, Cerro La Campana on 17 August 1834, his visit being commemorated by a memorial plaque.</item>
<item>1910 – The Parliament of the United Kingdom passes the People\'s Budget, the first budget in British history with the expressed intent of redistributing wealth among the British public.</item>
<item>1911 – Tsinghua University, one of mainland China\'s leading universities, is founded.</item>
<item>1916 – Easter Rising: After six days of fighting, Irish rebel leaders surrender to British forces in Dublin, bringing the Easter Rising to an end.</item>
<item>1945 – Dachau concentration camp is liberated by United States troops.</item>
<item>1945 – The Italian commune of Fornovo di Taro is liberated from German forces by Brazilian forces.</item>
<item>1951 – Tibetan delegates to the Central People\'s Government arrive in Beijing and draft a Seventeen Point Agreement for Chinese sovereignty and Tibetan autonomy.</item>
<item>1953 – The first U.S. experimental 3D television broadcast showed an episode of Space Patrol on Los Angeles ABC affiliate KECA–TV.</item>
<item>1965 – Pakistan\'s Space and Upper Atmosphere Research Commission (SUPARCO) successfully launches its seventh rocket in its Rehber series.</item>
<item>1967 – After refusing induction into the United States Army the previous day, Muhammad Ali is stripped of his boxing title.</item>
<item>1974 – Watergate scandal: United States President Richard Nixon announces the release of edited transcripts of White House tape recordings relating to the scandal.</item>
<item>1997 – The Chemical Weapons Convention of 1993 enters into force, outlawing the production, stockpiling and use of chemical weapons by its signatories.</item>
<item>2011 – The Wedding of Prince William and Catherine Middleton takes place at Westminster Abbey in London.</item>
<item>2013 – A powerful explosion occurs in an office building in Prague, believed to have been caused by natural gas, injures 43 people.</item>
<item>2015 – A baseball game between the Baltimore Orioles and the Chicago White Sox sets the all–time low attendance mark for Major League Baseball. Zero fans were in attendance for the game, as the stadium was officially closed to the public due to the 2015 Baltimore protests.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>