<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_23">
<item>215 BC – A temple is built on the Capitoline Hill dedicated to Venus Erycina to commemorate the Roman defeat at Lake Trasimene.</item>
<item>711 – Dagobert III succeeds his father King Childebert III as King of the Franks.</item>
<item>1016 – Edmund Ironside succeeds his father Æthelred the Unready as King of England.</item>
<item>1343 – St. George\'s Night Uprising commences in the Duchy of Estonia.</item>
<item>1635 – The first public school in the United States, Boston Latin School, is founded in Boston.</item>
<item>1660 – Treaty of Oliva is established between Sweden and Poland.</item>
<item>1661 – King Charles II of England, Scotland and Ireland is crowned in Westminster Abbey.</item>
<item>1914 – First baseball game at Wrigley Field, then known as Weeghman Park, in Chicago.</item>
<item>1920 – The Grand National Assembly of Turkey (TBMM) is founded in Ankara. The assembly denounces the government of Sultan Mehmed VI and announces the preparation of a temporary constitution.</item>
<item>1927 – Cardiff City defeat Arsenal in the FA Cup Final, the only time it has been won by a team not based in England.</item>
<item>1935 – The Polish Constitution of 1935 is adopted.</item>
<item>1946 – Manuel Roxas is elected the last President of the Commonwealth of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1961 – Algiers putsch by French generals.</item>
<item>1967 – Soviet space program: Soyuz 1 (Russian: Союз 1, Union 1) a manned spaceflight carrying cosmonaut Colonel Vladimir Komarov is launched into orbit.</item>
<item>1985 – Coca–Cola changes its formula and releases New Coke. The response is overwhelmingly negative, and the original formula is back on the market in less than three months.</item>
<item>1990 – Namibia becomes the 160th member of the United Nations and the 50th member of the Commonwealth of Nations.</item>
<item>1993 – Eritreans vote overwhelmingly for independence from Ethiopia in a United Nations–monitored referendum.</item>
<item>2005 – The first ever YouTube video, titled \"Me at the zoo\", was published by user \"jawed\".</item>
</string-array>
</resources>