<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_20">
<item>1303 – The Sapienza University of Rome is instituted by Pope Boniface VIII.</item>
<item>1453 – Three Genoese galleys and a Byzantine blockade runner fight their way through an Ottoman blockading fleet a few weeks before the fall of Constantinople.</item>
<item>1534 – Jacques Cartier begins his first voyage to what is today the east coast of Canada, Newfoundland and Labrador.</item>
<item>1535 – The sun dog phenomenon observed over Stockholm and depicted in the famous painting Vädersolstavlan.</item>
<item>1653 – Oliver Cromwell dissolves the Rump Parliament.</item>
<item>1657 – Freedom of religion is granted to the Jews of New Amsterdam (later New York City).</item>
<item>1689 – Deposed monarch James II of England lays siege to Derry.</item>
<item>1770 – The Georgian king, Erekle II, abandoned by his Russian ally Count Totleben, wins a victory over Ottoman forces at Aspindza.</item>
<item>1789 – George Washington arrives at Grays Ferry, Philadelphia while en route to Manhattan for his inauguration.</item>
<item>1800 – The Septinsular Republic is established.</item>
<item>1810 – The Governor of Caracas, Venezuela declares independence from Spain.</item>
<item>1828 – René Caillié becomes the second non–Muslim to enter (and the first to return from) Timbuktu, following Major Gordon Laing.</item>
<item>1836 – U.S. Congress passes an act creating the Wisconsin Territory.</item>
<item>1862 – Louis Pasteur and Claude Bernard complete the experiment disproving the theory of spontaneous generation.</item>
<item>1865 – Astronomer Angelo Secchi demonstrates the Secchi disk, which measures water clarity, aboard Pope Pius IX\'s yacht, the L\'Immaculata Concezion.</item>
<item>1884 – Pope Leo XIII publishes the encyclical Humanum genus.</item>
<item>1902 – Pierre and Marie Curie refine radium chloride.</item>
<item>1908 – Opening day of competition in the New South Wales Rugby League.</item>
<item>1912 – Opening day for baseball\'s Tiger Stadium in Detroit, and Fenway Park in Boston.</item>
<item>1916 – The Chicago Cubs play their first game at Weeghman Park (currently Wrigley Field), defeating the Cincinnati Reds 7–6 in 11 innings.</item>
<item>1922 – The Soviet government creates South Ossetian Autonomous Oblast within Georgian SSR.</item>
<item>1946 – The League of Nations officially dissolves, giving most of its power to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1968 – English politician Enoch Powell makes his controversial \"Rivers of Blood\" speech.</item>
<item>1972 – Apollo program: Apollo 16 lunar module, commanded by John Young and piloted by Charles Duke, lands on the moon.</item>
<item>2008 – Danica Patrick wins the Indy Japan 300 becoming the first female driver in history to win an Indy car race.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>