<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_2">
<item>1513 – Spanish explorer Juan Ponce de León first sights land in what is now the United States state of Florida.</item>
<item>1755 – Commodore William James captures the Maratha fortress of Suvarnadurg on west coast of India.</item>
<item>1792 – The Coinage Act is passed establishing the United States Mint.</item>
<item>1800 – Ludwig van Beethoven leads the premiere of his First Symphony in Vienna.</item>
<item>1800 – The Treaty of Constantinople establishes the Septinsular Republic, the first autonomous Greek state since the Fall of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1851 – Rama IV is crowned King of Thailand.</item>
<item>1900 – The United States Congress passes the Foraker Act, giving Puerto Rico limited self–rule.</item>
<item>1902 – Dmitry Sipyagin, Minister of Interior of the Russian Empire, is assassinated in the Marie Palace, Saint Petersburg.</item>
<item>1902 – \"Electric Theatre\", the first full–time movie theater in the United States, opens in Los Angeles.</item>
<item>1911 – The Australian Bureau of Statistics conducts the country\'s first national census.</item>
<item>1912 – The ill–fated RMS Titanic begins sea trials.</item>
<item>1921 – The Autonomous Government of Khorasan, a military government encompassing the modern state of Iran, is established.</item>
<item>1956 – As the World Turns and The Edge of Night premiere on CBS. The two soaps become the first daytime dramas to debut in the 30–minute format.</item>
<item>1964 – The National Congress of Brazil declares the Presidency to be vacant and replaces President João Goulart with the President of the Chamber of the Deputies Ranieri Mazzilli.</item>
<item>1972 – Actor Charlie Chaplin returns to the United States for the first time since being labeled a communist during the Red Scare in the early 1950s.</item>
<item>1973 – Launch of the LexisNexis computerized legal research service.</item>
<item>1976 – Prince Norodom Sihanouk resigns as leader of Cambodia and is placed under house arrest.</item>
<item>1980 – United States President Jimmy Carter signs the Crude Oil Windfall Profits Tax Act.</item>
<item>1986 – Alabama governor George Wallace, a former segregationist, best known for the \"Stand in the Schoolhouse Door\", announces that he will not seek a fifth four–year term and will retire from public life upon the end of his term in January 1987.</item>
<item>1989 – Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev arrives in Havana, Cuba, to meet with Fidel Castro in an attempt to mend strained relations.</item>
<item>1991 – Rita Johnston becomes the first female Premier of a Canadian province when she succeeds William Vander Zalm (who had resigned) as Premier of British Columbia.</item>
<item>1992 – Forty–two civilians were massacred in the town of Bijeljina.</item>
<item>2002 – Israeli forces surround the Church of the Nativity in Bethlehem into which armed Palestinians had retreated.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>