<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_3">
<item>686 – Maya king Yuknoom Yich\'aak K\'ahk\' assumes the crown of Calakmul.</item>
<item>801 – King Louis the Pious captures Barcelona from the Moors after a siege of several months.</item>
<item>1077 – The first Parliament of Friuli is created.</item>
<item>1860 – The first successful United States Pony Express run from St. Joseph, Missouri, to Sacramento, California, begins.</item>
<item>1885 – Gottlieb Daimler is granted a German patent for his engine design.</item>
<item>1895 – The trial in the libel case brought by Oscar Wilde begins, eventually resulting in his imprisonment on charges of homosexuality.</item>
<item>1933 – First flight over Mount Everest, a British expedition, led by the Marquis of Clydesdale, and funded by Lucy, Lady Houston.</item>
<item>1955 – The American Civil Liberties Union announces it will defend Allen Ginsberg\'s book Howl against obscenity charges.</item>
<item>1968 – Martin Luther King Jr. delivers his \"I\'ve Been to the Mountaintop\" speech. He was assassinated the next day.</item>
<item>1973 – Martin Cooper of Motorola makes the first handheld mobile phone call to Joel S. Engel of Bell Labs.</item>
<item>1975 – Bobby Fischer refuses to play in a chess match against Anatoly Karpov, giving Karpov the title of World Champion by default.</item>
<item>1980 – US Congress restores a federal trust relationship with the 501 members of the Shvwits, Kanosh, Koosharem, and the Indian Peaks and Cedar City bands of the Paiute people of Utah.</item>
<item>1981 – The Osborne 1, the first successful portable computer, is unveiled at the West Coast Computer Faire in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1989 – The US Supreme Court upholds the jurisdictional rights of tribal courts under the Indian Child Welfare Act of 1978 in Mississippi Choctaw Band v. Holyfield.</item>
<item>2000 – United States v. Microsoft Corp.: Microsoft is ruled to have violated United States antitrust law by keeping \"an oppressive thumb\" on its competitors.</item>
<item>2007 – Conventional–Train World Speed Record: A French TGV train on the LGV Est high speed line sets an official new world speed record.</item>
<item>2008 – ATA Airlines, once one of the ten largest U.S. passenger airlines and largest charter airline, files for bankruptcy for the second time in five years and ceases all operations.</item>
<item>2008 – Texas law enforcement cordons off the FLDS\'s YFZ Ranch. Eventually 533 women and children will be taken into state custody.</item>
<item>2010 – Apple Inc. released the first generation iPad, a tablet computer.</item>
<item>2016 – The Panama Papers, a leak of legal documents, reveals information on 214,488 offshore companies.</item>
<item>2018 – YouTube headquarters shooting.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>