<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_30">
<item>311 – The Diocletianic Persecution of Christians in the Roman Empire ends.</item>
<item>642 – Chindasuinth is proclaimed king by the Visigothic nobility and bishops.</item>
<item>1315 – Enguerrand de Marigny is hanged at the instigation of Charles, Count of Valois.</item>
<item>1492 – Spain gives Christopher Columbus his commission of exploration.</item>
<item>1598 – Juan de Oñate begins the conquest of Santa Fe de Nuevo México.</item>
<item>1598 – Henry IV of France issues the Edict of Nantes, allowing freedom of religion to the Huguenots.</item>
<item>1789 – On the balcony of Federal Hall on Wall Street in New York City, George Washington takes the oath of office to become the first elected President of the United States.</item>
<item>1803 – Louisiana Purchase: The United States purchases the Louisiana Territory from France for $15 million, more than doubling the size of the young nation.</item>
<item>1812 – The Territory of Orleans becomes the 18th U.S. state under the name Louisiana.</item>
<item>1838 – Nicaragua declares independence from the Central American Federation.</item>
<item>1871 – The Camp Grant massacre takes place in Arizona Territory.</item>
<item>1885 – Governor of New York David B. Hill signs legislation creating the Niagara Reservation, New York\'s first state park, ensuring that Niagara Falls will not be devoted solely to industrial and commercial use.</item>
<item>1897 – J. J. Thomson of the Cavendish Laboratory announces his discovery of the electron as a subatomic particle, over 1,800 times smaller than a proton (in the atomic nucleus), at a lecture at the Royal Institution in London.</item>
<item>1900 – Hawaii becomes a territory of the United States, with Sanford B. Dole as governor.</item>
<item>1904 – The Louisiana Purchase Exposition World\'s Fair opens in St. Louis, Missouri.</item>
<item>1905 – Albert Einstein completes his doctoral thesis at the University of Zurich.</item>
<item>1925 – Automaker Dodge Brothers, Inc is sold to Dillon, Read &amp; Co. for US$146 million plus $50 million for charity.</item>
<item>1927 – The Federal Industrial Institute for Women opens in Alderson, West Virginia, as the first women\'s federal prison in the United States.</item>
<item>1927 – Douglas Fairbanks and Mary Pickford become the first celebrities to leave their footprints in concrete at Grauman\'s Chinese Theater in Hollywood.</item>
<item>1937 – The Commonwealth of the Philippines holds a plebiscite for Filipino women on whether they should be extended the right to suffrage; over 90% would vote in the affirmative.</item>
<item>1938 – The animated cartoon short Porky\'s Hare Hunt debuts in movie theaters, introducing Happy Rabbit (a prototype of Bugs Bunny).</item>
<item>1939 – The 1939–40 New York World\'s Fair opens.</item>
<item>1939 – NBC inaugurates its regularly scheduled television service in New York City, broadcasting President Franklin D. Roosevelt\'s N.Y. World\'s Fair opening day ceremonial address.</item>
<item>1947 – In Nevada, Boulder Dam is renamed Hoover Dam.</item>
<item>1948 – In Bogotá, Colombia, the Organization of American States is established.</item>
<item>1957 – Supplementary Convention on the Abolition of Slavery entered into force.</item>
<item>1961 – K–19, the first Soviet nuclear submarine equipped with nuclear missiles, is commissioned.</item>
<item>1963 – The Bristol Bus Boycott is held in Bristol to protest the Bristol Omnibus Company\'s refusal to employ Black or Asian bus crews, drawing national attention to racial discrimination in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1966 – The Church of Satan is formed in The Black House, San Francisco</item>
<item>1980 – Beatrix is inaugurated as Queen of the Netherlands following the abdication of Juliana.</item>
<item>1980 – The Iranian Embassy siege begins in London.</item>
<item>1982 – The Bijon Setu massacre occurs in Calcutta, India.</item>
<item>1993 – CERN announces World Wide Web protocols will be free.</item>
<item>1997 – Ellen DeGeneres came out as gay. Her sitcom, Ellen, became one of first major television shows featuring an openly gay main character.</item>
<item>1998 – Daniel V. Jones, an American maintenance worker, commits suicide on live television in Los Angeles, California.</item>
<item>2000 – Canonization of Faustina Kowalska in the presence of 200,000 people and the first Divine Mercy Sunday celebrated worldwide.</item>
<item>2009 – Chrysler files for Chapter 11 bankruptcy.</item>
<item>2013 – Willem–Alexander is inaugurated as King of the Netherlands following the abdication of Beatrix.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>