<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_5">
<item>823 – Lothair I is crowned King of Italy by Pope Paschal I.</item>
<item>1081 – Alexios I Komnenos is crowned Byzantine emperor at Constantinople, bringing the Komnenian dynasty to full power.</item>
<item>1536 – Royal Entry of Charles V into Rome: The last Roman triumph.</item>
<item>1566 – Two–hundred Dutch noblemen, led by Hendrick van Brederode, force themselves into the presence of Margaret of Parma and present the Petition of Compromise, denouncing the Spanish Inquisition in the Seventeen Provinces.</item>
<item>1609 – Daimyo (Lord) Shimazu Tadatsune of the Satsuma Domain in southern Kyūshū, Japan, completes his successful invasion of the Ryūkyū Kingdom in Okinawa.</item>
<item>1614 – In Virginia, Native American Pocahontas marries English colonist John Rolfe.</item>
<item>1621 – The Mayflower sets sail from Plymouth, Massachusetts on a return trip to England.</item>
<item>1710 – The Statute of Anne receives the royal assent establishing the Copyright law of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1722 – The Dutch explorer Jacob Roggeveen discovers Easter Island.</item>
<item>1792 – United States President George Washington exercises his authority to veto a bill, the first time this power is used in the United States.</item>
<item>1795 – Peace of Basel between France and Prussia is made.</item>
<item>1900 – Archaeologists in Knossos, Crete, discover a large cache of clay tablets with hieroglyphic writing in a script they call Linear B.</item>
<item>1904 – The first international rugby league match is played between England and an Other Nationalities team (Welsh &amp; Scottish players) in Central Park, Wigan, England.</item>
<item>1915 – Boxing challenger Jess Willard knocks out Jack Johnson in Havana, Cuba to become the Heavyweight Champion of the World.</item>
<item>1922 – The American Birth Control League, forerunner of Planned Parenthood, is incorporated.</item>
<item>1932 – Dominion of Newfoundland: Ten thousand rioters seize the Colonial Building leading to the end of self–government.</item>
<item>1933 – U.S. President Franklin D. Roosevelt signs two executive orders: 6101 to establish the Civilian Conservation Corps, and 6102 \"forbidding the Hoarding of Gold Coin, Gold Bullion, and Gold Certificates\" by U.S. citizens.</item>
<item>1946 – Soviet troops end their year–long occupation of the Danish island of Bornholm.</item>
<item>1956 – In Sri Lanka, the Mahajana Eksath Peramuna win the general elections in a landslide and S. W. R. D. Bandaranaike is sworn in as the Prime Minister of Ceylon.</item>
<item>1957 – In India, Communists win the first elections in united Kerala and E. M. S. Namboodiripad is sworn in as the first Chief Minister.</item>
<item>1971 – In Sri Lanka, Janatha Vimukthi Peramuna launches a revolt against the United Front government of Sirimavo Bandaranaike.</item>
<item>1976 – In China, the April Fifth Movement leads to the Tiananmen Incident.</item>
<item>1992 – Alberto Fujimori, president of Peru, dissolves the Peruvian congress by military force.</item>
<item>1998 – In Japan, the Akashi Kaikyō Bridge opens to traffic, becoming the longest bridge span in the world.</item>
<item>1999 – Two Libyans suspected of bringing down Pan Am Flight 103 in 1988 are handed over for eventual trial in the Netherlands.</item>
<item>2009 – North Korea launches its controversial Kwangmyŏngsŏng–2 rocket. The satellite passed over mainland Japan, which prompted an immediate reaction from the United Nations Security Council, as well as participating states of Six–party talks.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>