<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_6">
<item>1320 – The Scots reaffirm their independence by signing the Declaration of Arbroath.</item>
<item>1327 – The poet Petrarch first sees his idealized love, Laura, in the church of Saint Clare in Avignon.</item>
<item>1385 – John, Master of the Order of Aviz, is made king John I of Portugal.</item>
<item>1453 – Mehmed II begins his siege of Constantinople (Istanbul), which falls on May 29.</item>
<item>1652 – At the Cape of Good Hope, Dutch sailor Jan van Riebeeck establishes a resupply camp that eventually becomes Cape Town.</item>
<item>1712 – The New York Slave Revolt of 1712 begins near Broadway.</item>
<item>1782 – King Buddha Yodfa Chulaloke (Rama I) of Siam (modern day Thailand) establishes the Chakri dynasty.</item>
<item>1808 – John Jacob Astor incorporates the American Fur Company, that would eventually make him America\'s first millionaire.</item>
<item>1814 – Nominal beginning of the Bourbon Restoration; anniversary date that Napoleon abdicates and is exiled to Elba.</item>
<item>1830 – Church of Christ, the original church of the Latter Day Saint movement, is organized by Joseph Smith and others at either Fayette or Manchester, New York.</item>
<item>1860 – The Reorganized Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints, later renamed Community of Christ, is organized by Joseph Smith III and others at Amboy, Illinois.</item>
<item>1861 – First performance of Arthur Sullivan\'s debut success, his suite of incidental music for The Tempest, leading to a career that included the famous Gilbert and Sullivan operas.</item>
<item>1869 – Celluloid is patented.</item>
<item>1893 – Salt Lake Temple of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter–day Saints is dedicated by Wilford Woodruff.</item>
<item>1895 – Oscar Wilde is arrested in the Cadogan Hotel, London, after losing a libel case against the Marquess of Queensberry.</item>
<item>1896 – In Athens, the opening of the first modern Olympic Games is celebrated, 1,500 years after the original games are banned by Roman emperor Theodosius I.</item>
<item>1909 – Robert Peary and Matthew Henson reach the North Pole.</item>
<item>1926 – Varney Airlines makes its first commercial flight (Varney is the root company of United Airlines).</item>
<item>1929 – Huey P. Long, Governor of Louisiana, is impeached by the Louisiana House of Representatives.</item>
<item>1930 – At the end of the Salt March, Gandhi raises a lump of mud and salt and declares, \"With this, I am shaking the foundations of the British Empire.\"</item>
<item>1957 – Greek shipping tycoon Aristotle Onassis buys the Hellenic National Airlines (TAE) and founds Olympic Airlines.</item>
<item>1965 – Launch of Early Bird, the first commercial communications satellite to be placed in geosynchronous orbit.</item>
<item>1968 – Pierre Elliott Trudeau wins the Liberal Leadership Election, and becomes Prime Minister of Canada soon after.</item>
<item>1973 – Launch of Pioneer 11 spacecraft.</item>
<item>1973 – The American League of Major League Baseball begins using the designated hitter.</item>
<item>1974 – The Swedish pop band ABBA wins the Eurovision Song Contest with the song \"Waterloo\", launching their international career.</item>
<item>1979 – Student protests break out in Nepal.</item>
<item>1984 – Members of Cameroon\'s Republican Guard unsuccessfully attempt to overthrow the government headed by Paul Biya.</item>
<item>1994 – The Rwandan genocide begins when the aircraft carrying Rwandan president Juvénal Habyarimana and Burundian president Cyprien Ntaryamira is shot down.</item>
<item>1998 – Nuclear weapons testing: Pakistan tests medium–range missiles capable of reaching India.</item>
<item>1998 – Travelers Group announces an agreement to undertake the $76 billion merger between Travelers and Citicorp, and the merger is completed on October 8, of that year, forming Citibank.</item>
<item>2004 – Rolandas Paksas becomes the first president of Lithuania to be peacefully removed from office by impeachment.</item>
<item>2005 – Kurdish leader Jalal Talabani becomes Iraqi president; Shiite Arab Ibrahim al–Jaafari is named premier the next day.</item>
<item>2008 – The 2008 Egyptian general strike starts led by Egyptian workers later to be adopted by April 6 Youth Movement and Egyptian activists.</item>
<item>2011 – In San Fernando, Tamaulipas, Mexico, over 193 victims of Los Zetas were exhumed from several mass graves.</item>
<item>2012 – Azawad declares itself independent from the Republic of Mali.</item>
<item>2017 – U.S. military launches 59 Tomahawk cruise missiles at an air base in Syria. Russia describes the strikes as an \"aggression\", adding they significantly damage US–Russia ties.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>