<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_7">
<item>529 – First draft of the Corpus Juris Civilis (a fundamental work in jurisprudence) is issued by Eastern Roman Emperor Justinian I.</item>
<item>611 – Maya king Uneh Chan of Calakmul sacks rival city–state Palenque in southern Mexico.</item>
<item>1141 – Empress Matilda became the first female ruler of England, adopting the title \'Lady of the English\'.</item>
<item>1348 – Charles University is founded in Prague.</item>
<item>1521 – Ferdinand Magellan arrives at Cebu.</item>
<item>1724 – Premiere performance of Johann Sebastian Bach\'s St John Passion BWV 245 at St. Nicholas Church, Leipzig.</item>
<item>1788 – American pioneers to the Northwest Territory establish Marietta, Ohio as the first permanent American settlement in the Northwest Territory.</item>
<item>1789 – Selim III became Sultan of the Ottoman Empire and Caliph of Islam.</item>
<item>1798 – The Mississippi Territory is organized from disputed territory claimed by both the United States and Spain. It is expanded in 1804 and again in 1812.</item>
<item>1805 – Lewis and Clark Expedition: The Corps of Discovery breaks camp among the Mandan tribe and resumes its journey West along the Missouri River.</item>
<item>1805 – German composer Ludwig van Beethoven premiered his Third Symphony, at the Theater an der Wien in Vienna.</item>
<item>1827 – John Walker, an English chemist, sells the first friction match that he had invented the previous year.</item>
<item>1829 – Joseph Smith, founder of the Latter Day Saint movement, commences translation of the Book of Mormon, with Oliver Cowdery as his scribe.</item>
<item>1831 – Emperor Pedro I of Brazil resigns. He goes to his native Portugal to become King Pedro IV.</item>
<item>1890 – Completion of the first Lake Biwa Canal.</item>
<item>1906 – Mount Vesuvius erupts and devastates Naples.</item>
<item>1906 – The Algeciras Conference gives France and Spain control over Morocco.</item>
<item>1908 – H. H. Asquith of the Liberal Party takes office as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom, succeeding Sir Henry Campbell–Bannerman.</item>
<item>1922 – The United States Secretary of the Interior leases federal petroleum reserves to private oil companies on excessively generous terms.</item>
<item>1927 – The first long–distance public television broadcast (from Washington, D.C., to New York City, displaying the image of Commerce Secretary Herbert Hoover).</item>
<item>1933 – Prohibition in the United States is repealed for beer of no more than 3.2% alcohol by weight, eight months before the ratification of the XXI amendment. (Now celebrated as National Beer Day in the United States.)</item>
<item>1940 – Booker T. Washington becomes the first African American to be depicted on a United States postage stamp.</item>
<item>1943 – The Holocaust in Ukraine: In Terebovlia, Germans order 1,100 Jews to undress and march through the city to the nearby village of Plebanivka, where they are shot and buried in ditches.</item>
<item>1943 – Ioannis Rallis becomes collaborationist Prime Minister of Greece during the Axis Occupation.</item>
<item>1946 – Syria\'s independence from France is officially recognised.</item>
<item>1948 – The World Health Organization is established by the United Nations.</item>
<item>1954 – United States President Dwight D. Eisenhower gives his \"domino theory\" speech during a news conference.</item>
<item>1955 – Winston Churchill resigns as Prime Minister of the United Kingdom amid indications of failing health.</item>
<item>1964 – IBM announces the System/360.</item>
<item>1965 – Representatives of the National Congress of American Indians testify before members of the US Senate against the termination of the Colville tribe in Washington DC.</item>
<item>1969 – The Internet\'s symbolic birth date: Publication of RFC 1.</item>
<item>1971 – President Richard Nixon announces his decision to quicken the pace of Vietnamization.</item>
<item>1977 – German Federal prosecutor Siegfried Buback and his driver are shot by two Red Army Faction members while waiting at a red light.</item>
<item>1983 – During STS–6, astronauts Story Musgrave and Don Peterson perform the first Space Shuttle spacewalk.</item>
<item>1990 – Iran–Contra affair: John Poindexter is found guilty of five charges for his part in the scandal (the conviction is later reversed on appeal).</item>
<item>1994 – Rwandan genocide: Massacres of Tutsis begin in Kigali, Rwanda.</item>
<item>1999 – The World Trade Organization rules in favor of the United States in its long–running trade dispute with the European Union over bananas.</item>
<item>2001 – Mars Odyssey is launched.</item>
<item>2003 – U.S. troops capture Baghdad; Saddam Hussein\'s regime falls two days later.</item>
<item>2009 – Mass protests begin across Moldova under the belief that results from the parliamentary election are fraudulent.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>