<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_8">
<item>1093 – The new Winchester Cathedral is dedicated by Walkelin.</item>
<item>1139 – Roger II of Sicily is excommunicated.</item>
<item>1149 – Pope Eugene III takes refuge in the castle of Ptolemy II of Tusculum.</item>
<item>1271 – In Syria, sultan Baibars conquers the Krak des Chevaliers.</item>
<item>1277 – Fall of Welsh Dolforwyn Castle to the English led by Henry de Lacy, 3rd Earl of Lincoln and Otto de Grandson.</item>
<item>1665 – English colonial patents are granted for the establishment of the Monmouth Tract, for what would eventually become Monmouth County in northeastern New Jersey.</item>
<item>1730 – Shearith Israel, the first synagogue in New York City, is dedicated.</item>
<item>1808 – The Roman Catholic Diocese of Baltimore is promoted to an archdiocese, with the founding of the dioceses of New York, Philadelphia, Boston, and Bardstown (now Louisville) by Pope Pius VII.</item>
<item>1820 – The Venus de Milo is discovered on the Aegean island of Milos.</item>
<item>1866 – Italy and Prussia ally against the Austrian Empire.</item>
<item>1895 – In Pollock v. Farmers\' Loan &amp; Trust Co. the Supreme Court of the United States declares unapportioned income tax to be unconstitutional.</item>
<item>1904 – The French Third Republic and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland sign the Entente cordiale.</item>
<item>1904 – Longacre Square in Midtown Manhattan is renamed Times Square after The New York Times.</item>
<item>1908 – Harvard University votes to establish the Harvard Business School.</item>
<item>1911 – Dutch physicist Heike Kamerlingh Onnes discovers superconductivity.</item>
<item>1913 – The 17th Amendment to the United States Constitution, requiring direct election of Senators, becomes law.</item>
<item>1924 – Sharia courts are abolished in Turkey, as part of Atatürk\'s Reforms.</item>
<item>1935 – The Works Progress Administration is formed when the Emergency Relief Appropriation Act of 1935 becomes law.</item>
<item>1946 – Électricité de France, the world\'s largest utility company, is formed as a result of the nationalisation of a number of electricity producers, transporters and distributors.</item>
<item>1950 – India and Pakistan sign the Liaquat–Nehru Pact.</item>
<item>1952 – U.S. President Harry Truman calls for the seizure of all domestic steel mills in an attempt to prevent the 1952 steel strike.</item>
<item>1953 – Mau Mau leader Jomo Kenyatta is convicted by British Kenya\'s rulers.</item>
<item>1959 – A team of computer manufacturers, users, and university people led by Grace Hopper meets to discuss the creation of a new programming language that would be called COBOL.</item>
<item>1959 – The Organization of American States drafts an agreement to create the Inter–American Development Bank.</item>
<item>1960 – The Netherlands and West Germany sign an agreement to negotiate the return of German land annexed by the Dutch in return for 280 million German marks as Wiedergutmachung.</item>
<item>1964 – The Gemini 1 test flight is conducted.</item>
<item>1974 – At Atlanta–Fulton County Stadium, Hank Aaron hits his 715th career home run to surpass Babe Ruth\'s 39–year–old record.</item>
<item>1975 – Frank Robinson manages the Cleveland Indians in his first game as major league baseball\'s first African American manager.</item>
<item>1987 – Los Angeles Dodgers executive Al Campanis resigns amid controversy over racially charged remarks he had made while on Nightline.</item>
<item>1992 – Retired tennis great Arthur Ashe announces that he has AIDS, acquired from blood transfusions during one of his two heart surgeries.</item>
<item>1993 – The Republic of Macedonia joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1999 – Haryana Gana Parishad, a political party in the Indian state of Haryana, merges with the Indian National Congress.</item>
<item>2008 – The construction of the world\'s first skyscraper to integrate wind turbines is completed in Bahrain.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>