<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a4_9">
<item>475 – Byzantine Emperor Basiliscus issues a circular letter (Enkyklikon) to the bishops of his empire, supporting the Monophysite christological position.</item>
<item>1413 – Henry V is crowned King of England.</item>
<item>1440 – Christopher of Bavaria is appointed King of Denmark.</item>
<item>1454 – The Treaty of Lodi is signed, establishing a balance of power among northern Italian city–states for almost 50 years.</item>
<item>1511 – St John\'s College, Cambridge, England, founded by Lady Margaret Beaufort, receives its charter.</item>
<item>1585 – The expedition organised by Sir Walter Raleigh departs England for Roanoke Island (now in North Carolina) to establish the Roanoke Colony.</item>
<item>1609 – Philip III of Spain issues the decree of the \"Expulsion of the Moriscos\".</item>
<item>1682 – Robert Cavelier de La Salle discovers the mouth of the Mississippi River, claims it for France and names it Louisiana.</item>
<item>1860 – On his phonautograph machine, Édouard–Léon Scott de Martinville makes the oldest known recording of an audible human voice.</item>
<item>1909 – The U.S. Congress passes the Payne–Aldrich Tariff Act.</item>
<item>1937 – The Kamikaze arrives at Croydon Airport in London. It is the first Japanese–built aircraft to fly to Europe.</item>
<item>1940 – Vidkun Quisling seizes power in Norway.</item>
<item>1945 – The United States Atomic Energy Commission is formed.</item>
<item>1947 – The Journey of Reconciliation, the first interracial Freedom Ride begins through the upper South in violation of Jim Crow laws. The riders wanted enforcement of the United States Supreme Court\'s 1946 Irene Morgan decision that banned racial segregation in interstate travel.</item>
<item>1947 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 22 relating to Corfu Channel incident is adopted.</item>
<item>1957 – The Suez Canal in Egypt is cleared and opens to shipping.</item>
<item>1959 – Project Mercury: NASA announces the selection of the United States\' first seven astronauts, whom the news media quickly dub the \"Mercury Seven\".</item>
<item>1961 – The Pacific Electric Railway in Los Angeles, once the largest electric railway in the world, ends operations.</item>
<item>1965 – Astrodome opens. First indoor baseball game is played.</item>
<item>1967 – The first Boeing 737 (a 100 series) makes its maiden flight.</item>
<item>1969 – The first British–built Concorde 002 makes its maiden flight from Filton to RAF Fairford.</item>
<item>1975 – The first game of the Philippine Basketball Association, the second oldest professional basketball league in the world.</item>
<item>1990 – 13,000 members of the Dene and Métis tribes sign a land claim agreement for 180,000 square kilometres (69,000 sq mi) in the Mackenzie Valley of the western Arctic.</item>
<item>1991 – Georgia declares independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>2005 – Charles, Prince of Wales marries Camilla Parker Bowles in a civil ceremony at Windsor\'s Guildhall.</item>
<item>2009 – In Tbilisi, Georgia, up to 60,000 people protest against the government of Mikheil Saakashvili.</item>
<item>2014 – A student stabs 20 people at Franklin Regional High School in Murrysville, Pennsylvania.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>