<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_14">
<item>1607 – Jamestown, Virginia is settled as an English colony.</item>
<item>1608 – The Protestant Union is founded.</item>
<item>1787 – In Philadelphia, delegates convene a Constitutional Convention to write a new Constitution for the United States; George Washington presides.</item>
<item>1800 – The process of the U.S. Government moving the United States capital city from Philadelphia to Washington, D.C. begins.</item>
<item>1804 – The Lewis and Clark Expedition departs from Camp Dubois and begins its historic journey by traveling up the Missouri River.</item>
<item>1811 – Paraguay: Pedro Juan Caballero, Fulgencio Yegros and José Gaspar Rodríguez de Francia start actions to depose the Spanish governor</item>
<item>1836 – The Treaties of Velasco are signed in Velasco, Texas.</item>
<item>1870 – The first game of rugby in New Zealand is played in Nelson between Nelson College and the Nelson Rugby Football Club.</item>
<item>1878 – The last witchcraft trial held in the United States begins in Salem, Massachusetts, after Lucretia Brown, an adherent of Christian Science, accused Daniel Spofford of attempting to harm her through his mental powers.</item>
<item>1879 – The first group of 463 Indian indentured laborers arrives in Fiji aboard the Leonidas.</item>
<item>1913 – Governor of New York William Sulzer approves the charter for the Rockefeller Foundation, which begins operations with a $100 million donation from John D. Rockefeller.</item>
<item>1925 – Virginia Woolf\'s novel Mrs Dalloway is published.</item>
<item>1935 – The 1935 Constitution of the Philippines is ratified by a popular vote.</item>
<item>1939 – Lina Medina becomes the youngest confirmed mother in medical history at the age of five.</item>
<item>1951 – Trains run on the Talyllyn Railway in Wales for the first time since preservation, making it the first railway in the world to be operated by volunteers.</item>
<item>1970 – Andreas Baader is freed from custody by Ulrike Meinhof, Gudrun Ensslin and others, a pivotal moment in the formation of the Red Army Faction.</item>
<item>1973 – Skylab, the United States\' first space station, is launched.</item>
<item>2004 – The Constitutional Court of South Korea overturns the impeachment of President Roh Moo–hyun.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>