<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_15">
<item>589 – King Authari marries Theodelinda, daughter of the Bavarian duke Garibald I. A Catholic, she has great influence among the Lombard nobility.</item>
<item>908 – The three–year–old Constantine VII, the son of Emperor Leo VI the Wise, is crowned as co–emperor of the Byzantine Empire by Patriarch Euthymius I at Constantinople.</item>
<item>1618 – Johannes Kepler confirms his previously rejected discovery of the third law of planetary motion (he first discovered it on March 8 but soon rejected the idea after some initial calculations were made).</item>
<item>1648 – The Treaty of Westphalia is signed.</item>
<item>1718 – James Puckle, a London lawyer, patents the world\'s first machine gun.</item>
<item>1730 – Robert Walpole effectively became the first Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1817 – Opening of the first private mental health hospital in the United States, the Asylum for the Relief of Persons Deprived of the Use of Their Reason (now Friends Hospital, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania).</item>
<item>1836 – Francis Baily observes \"Baily\'s beads\" during an annular eclipse.</item>
<item>1850 – The Bloody Island massacre takes place in Lake County, California, in which a large number of Pomo Indians are slaughtered by a regiment of the United States Cavalry.</item>
<item>1850 – The Arana–Southern Treaty is ratified, ending \"the existing differences\" between Great Britain and Argentina.</item>
<item>1851 – The first Australian gold rush is proclaimed, although the discovery had been made three months earlier.</item>
<item>1858 – Opening of the present Royal Opera House in Covent Garden, London.</item>
<item>1862 – President Abraham Lincoln signs a bill into law creating the United States Bureau of Agriculture. It is later renamed the United States Department of Agriculture.</item>
<item>1867 – Canadian Bank of Commerce opens for business in Toronto, Ontario. The bank would later merge with Imperial Bank of Canada to become what is CIBC in 1961.</item>
<item>1869 – Women\'s suffrage: In New York, Susan B. Anthony and Elizabeth Cady Stanton form the National Woman Suffrage Association.</item>
<item>1891 – Pope Leo XIII defends workers\' rights and property rights in the encyclical Rerum novarum, the beginning of modern Catholic social teaching.</item>
<item>1905 – Las Vegas is founded when 110 acres (0.45 km2), in what later would become downtown, are auctioned off.</item>
<item>1911 – In Standard Oil Co. of New Jersey v. United States, the United States Supreme Court declares Standard Oil to be an \"unreasonable\" monopoly under the Sherman Antitrust Act and orders the company to be broken up.</item>
<item>1919 – The Winnipeg general strike begins. By 11:00, almost the whole working population of Winnipeg had walked off the job.</item>
<item>1925 – Al–Insaniyyah, the first Arabic communist newspaper, is founded.</item>
<item>1928 – Walt Disney character Mickey Mouse premieres in his first cartoon, \"Plane Crazy\".</item>
<item>1933 – All military aviation organizations within, or under the control of, the RLM of Germany were officially merged in a covert manner, to form its Wehrmacht military\'s air arm, the Luftwaffe.</item>
<item>1934 – Kārlis Ulmanis establishes an authoritarian government in Latvia.</item>
<item>1940 – USS Sailfish is recommissioned. It was originally the USS Squalus.</item>
<item>1940 – McDonald\'s opens its first restaurant in San Bernardino, California.</item>
<item>1941 – Joe DiMaggio begins a 56–game hitting streak.</item>
<item>1958 – The Soviet Union launches Sputnik 3.</item>
<item>1960 – The Soviet Union launches Sputnik 4.</item>
<item>1963 – Project Mercury: The launch of the final Mercury mission, Mercury–Atlas 9 with astronaut Gordon Cooper on board. He becomes the first American to spend more than a day in space, and the last American to go into space alone.</item>
<item>1970 – President Richard Nixon appoints Anna Mae Hays and Elizabeth P. Hoisington the first female United States Army generals.</item>
<item>1972 – Ryukyu Islands, under U.S. military governance since its conquest in 1945, hand over to Japanese control.</item>
<item>1972 – In Laurel, Maryland, Arthur Bremer shoots and paralyzes Alabama Governor George Wallace while he is campaigning to become President.</item>
<item>1987 – The Soviet Union launches the Polyus prototype orbital weapons platform. It fails to reach orbit.</item>
<item>1991 – Édith Cresson becomes France\'s first female premier.</item>
<item>2004 – Arsenal F.C. go an entire league campaign unbeaten in the English Premier League, joining Preston North End F.C with the right to claim the title The Invincibles</item>
<item>2008 – California becomes the second U.S. state after Massachusetts in 2004 to legalize same–sex marriage after the state\'s own Supreme Court rules a previous ban unconstitutional.</item>
<item>2010 – Jessica Watson becomes the youngest person to sail, non–stop and unassisted around the world solo.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>