<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_18">
<item>332 – Constantine the Great announced free distributions of food to the citizens in Constantinople.</item>
<item>872 – Louis II of Italy is crowned for the second time as Roman Emperor at Rome, at the age of 47. His first coronation was 28 years earlier, in 844, during the reign of his father Lothair I.</item>
<item>1096 – First Crusade: Around 800 Jews are massacred in Worms, Germany.</item>
<item>1268 – The Principality of Antioch, a crusader state, falls to the Mamluk Sultan Baibars in the Siege of Antioch.</item>
<item>1291 – Fall of Acre, the end of Crusader presence in the Holy Land.</item>
<item>1302 – Bruges Matins, the nocturnal massacre of the French garrison in Bruges by members of the local Flemish militia.</item>
<item>1499 – Alonso de Ojeda sets sail from Cádiz on his voyage to what is now Venezuela.</item>
<item>1565 – The Great Siege of Malta begins, in which Ottoman forces attempt and fail to conquer Malta.</item>
<item>1631 – In Dorchester, Massachusetts, John Winthrop takes the oath of office and becomes the first Governor of Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1652 – Rhode Island passes the first law in English–speaking North America making slavery illegal.</item>
<item>1783 – First United Empire Loyalists reach Parrtown (later called Saint John, New Brunswick), Canada, after leaving the United States.</item>
<item>1804 – Napoleon Bonaparte is proclaimed Emperor of the French by the French Senate.</item>
<item>1843 – The Disruption in Edinburgh of the Free Church of Scotland from the Church of Scotland.</item>
<item>1848 – Opening of the first German National Assembly (Nationalversammlung) in Frankfurt, Germany.</item>
<item>1896 – The United States Supreme Court rules in Plessy v. Ferguson that the \"separate but equal\" doctrine is constitutional.</item>
<item>1900 – The United Kingdom proclaims a protectorate over Tonga.</item>
<item>1912 – The first Indian film, Shree Pundalik by Dadasaheb Torne, is released in Mumbai.</item>
<item>1926 – Evangelist Aimee Semple McPherson disappears in Venice, California.</item>
<item>1927 – After being founded for 20 years, the Government of the Republic of China approves Tongji University to be among the first national universities of the Republic of China.</item>
<item>1933 – New Deal: President Franklin D. Roosevelt signs an act creating the Tennessee Valley Authority.</item>
<item>1944 – Deportation of Crimean Tatars by the Soviet Union government.</item>
<item>1948 – The First Legislative Yuan of the Republic of China officially convenes in Nanking.</item>
<item>1953 – Jackie Cochran becomes the first woman to break the sound barrier.</item>
<item>1965 – Israeli spy Eli Cohen is hanged in Damascus, Syria.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: Apollo 10 is launched.</item>
<item>1974 – Nuclear weapons testing: Under project Smiling Buddha, India successfully detonates its first nuclear weapon becoming the sixth nation to do so.</item>
<item>1980 – Students in Gwangju, South Korea begin demonstrations calling for democratic reforms.</item>
<item>1990 – In France, a modified TGV train achieves a new rail world speed record of 515.3 km/h (320.2 mph).</item>
<item>1991 – Northern Somalia declares independence from the rest of Somalia as the Republic of Somaliland but is not recognized by the international community.</item>
<item>1994 – Israeli troops finish retreating from the Gaza Strip after occupying it, giving the area to the Palestinians to govern.</item>
<item>2005 – A second photo from the Hubble Space Telescope confirms that Pluto has two additional moons, Nix and Hydra.</item>
<item>2006 – The post Loktantra Andolan government passes a landmark bill curtailing the power of the monarchy and making Nepal a secular country.</item>
<item>2009 – The LTTE are defeated by the Sri Lankan government, ending almost 26 years of fighting between the two sides.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>