<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_11">
<item>330 – Byzantium is renamed Nova Roma during a dedication ceremony, but it is more popularly referred to as Constantinople.</item>
<item>868 – A copy of the Diamond Sutra is printed in China, making it the oldest known dated printed book.</item>
<item>912 – Alexander becomes Emperor of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1502 – Christopher Columbus departs Cádiz on his fourth and final voyage to the Americas.</item>
<item>1647 – Peter Stuyvesant arrives in New Amsterdam to replace Willem Kieft as Director–General of New Netherland, the Dutch colonial settlement in present–day New York City.</item>
<item>1792 – Robert Gray commands the first expedition to sail into the Columbia River.</item>
<item>1813 – William Lawson, Gregory Blaxland and William Wentworth discover a route across the Blue Mountains, opening up inland Australia to settlement.</item>
<item>1857 – Indian Rebellion of 1857: Indian rebels seize Delhi from the British.</item>
<item>1858 – Minnesota is admitted as the 32nd U.S. State.</item>
<item>1867 – Luxembourg gains its independence.</item>
<item>1894 – Four thousand Pullman Palace Car Company workers go on a wildcat strike.</item>
<item>1910 – An act of the U.S. Congress establishes Glacier National Park in Montana.</item>
<item>1918 – The Mountainous Republic of the Northern Caucasus is officially established.</item>
<item>1927 – The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences is founded.</item>
<item>1942 – William Faulkner\'s collections of short stories, Go Down, Moses, is published.</item>
<item>1949 – Siam officially changes its name to Thailand for the second time. The name had been in use since 1939 but was reverted in 1945.</item>
<item>1972 – The United States performs a nuclear test at the Nevada Test Site, which was part of Operation Grommet.</item>
<item>1973 – Citing government misconduct, Daniel Ellsberg\'s charges for his involvement in releasing the Pentagon Papers to The New York Times are dismissed.</item>
<item>1995 – More than 170 countries extend the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty indefinitely and without conditions.</item>
<item>1997 – Deep Blue, a chess–playing supercomputer, defeats Garry Kasparov in the last game of the rematch, becoming the first computer to beat a world–champion chess player in a classic match format.</item>
<item>1998 – India conducts three underground atomic tests in Pokhran.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>