<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_10">
<item>28 BC – A sunspot is observed by Han dynasty astronomers during the reign of Emperor Cheng of Han, one of the earliest dated sunspot observations in China.</item>
<item>1497 – Amerigo Vespucci allegedly leaves Cádiz for his first voyage to the New World.</item>
<item>1503 – Christopher Columbus visits the Cayman Islands and names them Las Tortugas after the numerous turtles there.</item>
<item>1534 – Jacques Cartier visits Newfoundland.</item>
<item>1655 – England, with troops under the command of Admiral William Penn and General Robert Venables, annexes Jamaica from Spain.</item>
<item>1768 – John Wilkes is imprisoned for writing an article for The North Briton severely criticizing King George III. This action provokes rioting in London.</item>
<item>1773 – The Parliament of Great Britain passes the Tea Act, designed to save the British East India Company by granting it a monopoly on the North American tea trade.</item>
<item>1774 – Louis XVI and Marie Antoinette become King and Queen of France.</item>
<item>1824 – The National Gallery in London opens to the public.</item>
<item>1833 – The desecration of the grave of the viceroy of southern Vietnam Lê Văn Duyệt by Emperor Minh Mạng provokes his adopted son to start a revolt.</item>
<item>1837 – Panic of 1837: New York City banks fail, and unemployment reaches record levels.</item>
<item>1869 – The First Transcontinental Railroad, linking the eastern and western United States, is completed at Promontory Summit, Utah with the golden spike.</item>
<item>1872 – Victoria Woodhull becomes the first woman nominated for President of the United States.</item>
<item>1876 – The Centennial Exposition is opened in Philadelphia by U.S. President Ulysses S. Grant and Brazilian Emperor Dom Pedro II.</item>
<item>1877 – The lower chamber of the Romanian Parliament sanctions the Declaration of Independence from the Ottoman Empire, proclaimed the previous day in the Senate by Mihail Kogălniceanu.</item>
<item>1881 – Carol I is crowned the King of the Romanian Kingdom.</item>
<item>1904 – The Horch &amp; Cir. Motorwagenwerke AG is founded. It would eventually become the Audi company.</item>
<item>1908 – Mother\'s Day is observed for the first time in the United States, in Grafton, West Virginia.</item>
<item>1916 – Sailing in the lifeboat James Caird, Ernest Shackleton arrives at South Georgia after a journey of 800 nautical miles from Elephant Island.</item>
<item>1922 – The United States annexes the Kingman Reef.</item>
<item>1946 – First successful launch of an American V–2 rocket at White Sands Proving Ground.</item>
<item>1948 – The Republic of China implements \"temporary provisions\" granting President Chiang Kai–shek extended powers to deal with the Communist uprising; they will remain in effect until 1991.</item>
<item>1954 – Bill Haley &amp; His Comets release \"Rock Around the Clock\", the first rock and roll record to reach number one on the Billboard charts.</item>
<item>1960 – The nuclear submarine USS Triton completes Operation Sandblast, the first underwater circumnavigation of the earth.</item>
<item>1962 – Marvel Comics publishes the first issue of The Incredible Hulk.</item>
<item>1967 – The Northrop M2–F2 crashes on landing, becoming the inspiration for the novel Cyborg and TV series The Six Million Dollar Man.</item>
<item>1970 – Bobby Orr scores \"The Goal\" to win the 1970 Stanley Cup Finals, for the Boston Bruins\' fourth NHL championship in their history.</item>
<item>1975 – Sony introduces the Betamax videocassette recorder in Japan.</item>
<item>1981 – François Mitterrand wins the presidential election and becomes the first Socialist President of France in the French Fifth Republic.</item>
<item>1994 – Nelson Mandela is inaugurated as South Africa\'s first black president.</item>
<item>2002 – FBI agent Robert Hanssen is sentenced to life imprisonment without the possibility of parole for selling United States secrets to Russia for $1.4 million in cash and diamonds.</item>
<item>2005 – A hand grenade thrown by Vladimir Arutyunian lands about 65 feet (20 meters) from U.S. President George W. Bush while he is giving a speech to a crowd in Tbilisi, Georgia, but it malfunctions and does not detonate.</item>
<item>2013 – One World Trade Center becomes the tallest building in the Western Hemisphere.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>