<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_17">
<item>1536 – Henry VIII and Anne Boleyn\'s marriage is annulled.</item>
<item>1590 – Anne of Denmark is crowned Queen of Scotland.</item>
<item>1642 – Paul de Chomedey, Sieur de Maisonneuve (1612–1676) founds the Ville Marie de Montréal.</item>
<item>1673 – Louis Jolliet and Jacques Marquette begin exploring the Mississippi River.</item>
<item>1792 – The New York Stock Exchange is formed under the Buttonwood Agreement.</item>
<item>1805 – Muhammad Ali becomes Wāli of Egypt.</item>
<item>1809 – Emperor Napoleon I orders the annexation of the Papal States to the French Empire.</item>
<item>1814 – Occupation of Monaco changes from French to Austrian.</item>
<item>1814 – The Constitution of Norway is signed and Crown Prince Christian Frederick of Denmark is elected King of Norway by the Norwegian Constituent Assembly.</item>
<item>1859 – Members of the Melbourne Football Club codified the first rules of Australian rules football.</item>
<item>1863 – Rosalía de Castro publishes Cantares Gallegos, the first book in the Galician language.</item>
<item>1865 – The International Telegraph Union (later the International Telecommunication Union) is established in Paris.</item>
<item>1875 – Aristides wins the first Kentucky Derby.</item>
<item>1902 – Greek archaeologist Valerios Stais discovers the Antikythera mechanism, an ancient mechanical analog computer.</item>
<item>1914 – The Protocol of Corfu is signed, recognising full autonomy to Northern Epirus under nominal Albanian sovereignty.</item>
<item>1915 – The last British Liberal Party government (led by Herbert Henry Asquith) falls.</item>
<item>1933 – Vidkun Quisling and Johan Bernhard Hjort form Nasjonal Samling — the national–socialist party of Norway.</item>
<item>1939 – The Columbia Lions and the Princeton Tigers play in the United States\' first televised sporting event, a collegiate baseball game in New York City.</item>
<item>1954 – The United States Supreme Court hands down a unanimous decision in Brown v. Board of Education of Topeka, Kansas.</item>
<item>1973 – Watergate scandal: Televised hearings begin in the United States Senate.</item>
<item>1977 – Nolan Bushnell opened the first Chuck E. Cheese\'s in San Jose, California.</item>
<item>1980 – General Chun Doo–hwan of South Korea seizes control of the government and declares martial law in order to suppress student demonstrations.</item>
<item>1983 – The U.S. Department of Energy declassifies documents showing world\'s largest mercury pollution event in Oak Ridge, Tennessee (ultimately found to be 4.2 million pounds), in response to the Appalachian Observer\'s Freedom of Information Act request.</item>
<item>1983 – Lebanon, Israel, and the United States sign an agreement on Israeli withdrawal from Lebanon.</item>
<item>1984 – Prince Charles calls a proposed addition to the National Gallery, London, a \"monstrous carbuncle on the face of a much–loved and elegant friend\", sparking controversies on the proper role of the Royal Family and the course of modern architecture.</item>
<item>1990 – The General Assembly of the World Health Organization (WHO) eliminates homosexuality from the list of psychiatric diseases.</item>
<item>1994 – Malawi holds its first multi–party elections.</item>
<item>1997 – Troops of Laurent Kabila march into Kinshasa. Zaire is officially renamed Democratic Republic of the Congo.</item>
<item>2000 – Arsenal and Galatasaray fans clash in the 2000 UEFA Cup Final riots in Copenhagen</item>
<item>2004 – The first legal same–sex marriages in the U.S. are performed in the state of Massachusetts.</item>
<item>2006 – The aircraft carrier USS Oriskany is sunk in the Gulf of Mexico as an artificial reef.</item>
<item>2007 – Trains from North and South Korea cross the 38th Parallel in a test–run agreed by both governments. This is the first time that trains have crossed the Demilitarized Zone since 1953.</item>
<item>2018 – The United States Senate confirmed Gina Cheri Haspel to lead the Central Intelligence Agency becoming the first woman to hold the post on a full time basis.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>