<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_1">
<item>475 BC – Roman consul Publius Valerius Poplicola celebrates a Roman triumph for his victory over Veii and the Sabines.</item>
<item>305 – Diocletian and Maximian retire from the office of Roman emperor.</item>
<item>880 – The Nea Ekklesia is inaugurated in Constantinople, setting the model for all later cross–in–square Orthodox churches.</item>
<item>1169 – Norman mercenaries land at Bannow Bay in Leinster, marking the beginning of the Norman invasion of Ireland.</item>
<item>1576 – Stephen Báthory, the reigning Prince of Transylvania, marries Anna Jagiellon and they become co–rulers of the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth.</item>
<item>1707 – The Act of Union joining the Kingdom of England and Kingdom of Scotland to form the Kingdom of Great Britain takes effect.</item>
<item>1753 – Publication of Species Plantarum by Linnaeus, and the formal start date of plant taxonomy adopted by the International Code of Botanical Nomenclature.</item>
<item>1759 – Josiah Wedgwood founds the Wedgwood pottery company in Great Britain.</item>
<item>1776 – Establishment of the Illuminati in Ingolstadt (Upper Bavaria), by Jesuit–taught Adam Weishaupt.</item>
<item>1785 – Kamehameha I, the king of Hawaiʻi, defeats Kalanikūpule and establishes the Kingdom of Hawaiʻi.</item>
<item>1786 – In Vienna, Austria, Mozart\'s opera The Marriage of Figaro is performed for the first time.</item>
<item>1820 – Execution of the Cato Street Conspirators</item>
<item>1840 – The Penny Black, the first official adhesive postage stamp, is issued in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1844 – Hong Kong Police Force, the world\'s second modern police force and Asia\'s first, is established.</item>
<item>1846 – The few remaining Mormons left in Nauvoo, Illinois, formally dedicate the Nauvoo Temple.</item>
<item>1851 – Queen Victoria opens The Great Exhibition at The Crystal Palace in London.</item>
<item>1856 – The Province of Isabela was created in the Philippines in honor of Queen Isabela II.</item>
<item>1865 – The Empire of Brazil, Argentina, and Uruguay sign the Treaty of the Triple Alliance.</item>
<item>1869 – The Folies Bergère opens in Paris.</item>
<item>1884 – Proclamation of the demand for eight–hour workday in the United States.</item>
<item>1884 – Moses Fleetwood Walker becomes the first black person to play in a professional baseball game in the United States.</item>
<item>1885 – The original Chicago Board of Trade Building opens for business.</item>
<item>1886 – Rallies are held throughout the United States demanding the eight–hour work day, culminating in the Haymarket affair in Chicago, in commemoration of which May 1 is celebrated as International Workers\' Day in many countries.</item>
<item>1893 – The World\'s Columbian Exposition opens in Chicago.</item>
<item>1894 – Coxey\'s Army, the first significant American protest march, arrives in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1915 – The RMS Lusitania departs from New York City on her 202nd, and final, crossing of the North Atlantic. Six days later, the ship is torpedoed off the coast of Ireland with the loss of 1,198 lives.</item>
<item>1919 – German troops enter Munich to squash the Bavarian Soviet Republic.</item>
<item>1925 – The All–China Federation of Trade Unions is officially founded. Today it is the largest trade union in the world, with 134 million members.</item>
<item>1927 – The Union Labor Life Insurance Company is founded by the American Federation of Labor.</item>
<item>1931 – The Empire State Building is dedicated in New York City.</item>
<item>1946 – Start of three–year Pilbara strike of Indigenous Australians.</item>
<item>1946 – The Paris Peace Conference concludes that the islands of the Dodecanese should be returned to Greece by Italy.</item>
<item>1950 – Guam is organized as a United States commonwealth.</item>
<item>1956 – The polio vaccine developed by Jonas Salk is made available to the public.</item>
<item>1960 – Formation of the western Indian states of Gujarat and Maharashtra; also known as \"Maharashtra Day\".</item>
<item>1961 – The Prime Minister of Cuba, Fidel Castro, proclaims Cuba a socialist nation and abolishes elections.</item>
<item>1967 – Elvis Presley and Priscilla Beaulieu are married in Las Vegas.</item>
<item>1971 – Amtrak (the National Railroad Passenger Corporation) takes over operation of U.S. passenger rail service.</item>
<item>1978 – Japan\'s Naomi Uemura, travelling by dog sled, becomes the first person to reach the North Pole alone.</item>
<item>1983 – The Sydney Entertainment Centre is opened.</item>
<item>1989 – Disney–MGM Studios opens at Walt Disney World near Orlando, Florida, United States.</item>
<item>1990 – The former Philippine Episcopal Church (supervised by the Episcopal Church of the United States of America) is granted full autonomy and raised to the status of an Autocephalous Anglican Province and renamed the Episcopal Church in the Philippines.</item>
<item>1999 – The body of British climber George Mallory is found on Mount Everest, 75 years after his disappearance in 1924.</item>
<item>2003 – Invasion of Iraq: In what becomes known as the \"Mission Accomplished\" speech, on board the USS Abraham Lincoln (off the coast of California), U.S. President George W. Bush declares that \"major combat operations in Iraq have ended\".</item>
<item>2004 – Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Poland, Slovakia, and Slovenia join the European Union, celebrated at the residence of the Irish President in Dublin.</item>
<item>2009 – Same–sex marriage is legalized in Sweden.</item>
<item>2011 – Pope John Paul II is beatified by his successor, Pope Benedict XVI.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>