<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_16">
<item>218 – Julia Maesa, aunt of the assassinated Caracalla, is banished to her home in Syria by self–proclaimed emperor Macrinus. She declares her 14–year–old grandson Elagabalus to be emperor of Rome. Macrinus is later deposed.</item>
<item>946 – Emperor Suzaku abdicates the throne in favor of his brother Murakami who becomes the 62nd emperor of Japan.</item>
<item>1204 – Baldwin IX, Count of Flanders is crowned as the first Emperor of the Latin Empire.</item>
<item>1527 – The Florentines drive out the Medici for a second time and Florence re–establishes itself as a republic.</item>
<item>1532 – Sir Thomas More resigns as Lord Chancellor of England.</item>
<item>1568 – Mary, Queen of Scots, flees to England.</item>
<item>1584 – Santiago de Vera becomes sixth Governor–General of the Spanish colony of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1770 – A 14–year–old Marie Antoinette marries 15–year–old Louis–Auguste who later becomes king of France.</item>
<item>1843 – The first major wagon train heading for the Pacific Northwest sets out on the Oregon Trail with one thousand pioneers from Elm Grove, Missouri.</item>
<item>1866 – The United States Congress establishes the nickel.</item>
<item>1868 – United States President Andrew Johnson is acquitted in his impeachment trial by one vote in the United States Senate.</item>
<item>1877 – The 16 May 1877 crisis occurs.</item>
<item>1888 – Nikola Tesla delivers a lecture describing the equipment which will allow efficient generation and use of alternating currents to transmit electric power over long distances.</item>
<item>1891 – The International Electrotechnical Exhibition opens in Frankfurt, Germany, and will feature the world\'s first long distance transmission of high–power, three–phase electric current (the most common form today).</item>
<item>1919 – A naval Curtiss NC–4 aircraft commanded by Albert Cushing Read leaves Trepassey, Newfoundland, for Lisbon via the Azores on the first transatlantic flight.</item>
<item>1920 – In Rome, Pope Benedict XV canonizes Joan of Arc.</item>
<item>1951 – The first regularly scheduled transatlantic flights begin between Idlewild Airport (now John F Kennedy International Airport) in New York City and Heathrow Airport in London, operated by El Al Israel Airlines.</item>
<item>1959 – The Triton Fountain in Valletta, Malta is turned on for the first time.</item>
<item>1960 – Theodore Maiman operates the first optical laser (a ruby laser), at Hughes Research Laboratories in Malibu, California.</item>
<item>1961 – Park Chung–hee leads a coup d\'état to overthrow the Second Republic of South Korea.</item>
<item>1969 – Venera program: Venera 5, a Soviet space probe, lands on Venus.</item>
<item>1974 – Josip Broz Tito is elected president for life of Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1988 – A report by the Surgeon General of the United States C. Everett Koop states that the addictive properties of nicotine are similar to those of heroin and cocaine.</item>
<item>1991 – Queen Elizabeth II of the United Kingdom addresses a joint session of the United States Congress. She is the first British monarch to address the U.S. Congress.</item>
<item>1997 – Mobutu Sese Seko, the President of Zaire, flees the country.</item>
<item>2005 – Kuwait permits women\'s suffrage in a 35–23 National Assembly vote.</item>
<item>2011 – STS–134 (ISS assembly flight ULF6), launched from the Kennedy Space Center on the 25th and final flight for Space Shuttle Endeavour.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>