<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_13">
<item>1373 – Julian of Norwich has visions which are later transcribed in her Revelations of Divine Love.</item>
<item>1515 – Mary Tudor, Queen of France, and Charles Brandon, 1st Duke of Suffolk, are officially married at Greenwich.</item>
<item>1780 – The Cumberland Compact is signed by leaders of the settlers in early Tennessee.</item>
<item>1787 – Captain Arthur Phillip leaves Portsmouth, England, with eleven ships full of convicts (the \"First Fleet\") to establish a penal colony in Australia.</item>
<item>1830 – Ecuador gains its independence from Gran Colombia.</item>
<item>1861 – The Great Comet of 1861 is discovered by John Tebbutt of Windsor, New South Wales, Australia.</item>
<item>1861 – Pakistan\'s (then a part of British India) first railway line opens, from Karachi to Kotri.</item>
<item>1862 – The USS Planter, a steamer and gunship, steals through Confederate lines and is passed to the Union, by a southern slave, Robert Smalls, who later was officially appointed as captain, becoming the first black man to command a United States ship.</item>
<item>1880 – In Menlo Park, New Jersey, Thomas Edison performs the first test of his electric railway.</item>
<item>1888 – With the passage of the Lei Áurea (\"Golden Law\"), Empire of Brazil abolishes slavery.</item>
<item>1909 – The first Giro d\'Italia starts from Milan. Italian cyclist Luigi Ganna will be the winner.</item>
<item>1912 – The Royal Flying Corps, the forerunner of the Royal Air Force, is established in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1917 – Three children report the first apparition of Our Lady of Fátima in Fátima, Portugal.</item>
<item>1939 – The first commercial FM radio station in the United States is launched in Bloomfield, Connecticut. The station later becomes WDRC–FM.</item>
<item>1940 – Queen Wilhelmina of the Netherlands flees her country to Great Britain after the German invasion. Princess Juliana takes her children to Canada for their safety.</item>
<item>1950 – The first round of the Formula One World Championship is held at Silverstone.</item>
<item>1951 – The 400th anniversary of the founding of the National University of San Marcos is commemorated by the opening of the first large–capacity stadium in Peru.</item>
<item>1952 – The Rajya Sabha, the upper house of the Parliament of India, holds its first sitting.</item>
<item>1954 – The anti–National Service Riots, by Chinese middle school students in Singapore, take place.</item>
<item>1958 – May 1958 crisis: A group of French military officers lead a coup in Algiers demanding that a government of national unity be formed with Charles de Gaulle at its head in order to defend French control of Algeria.</item>
<item>1958 – Ben Carlin becomes the first (and only) person to circumnavigate the world by amphibious vehicle, having travelled over 17,000 kilometres (11,000 mi) by sea and 62,000 kilometres (39,000 mi) by land during a ten–year journey.</item>
<item>1960 – Hundreds of University of California, Berkeley students congregate for the first day of protest against a visit by the House Committee on Un–American Activities.</item>
<item>1967 – Dr. Zakir Husain becomes the third President of India. He is the first Muslim President of the Indian Union. He holds this position until August 24, 1969.</item>
<item>1969 – May 13 Incident involving sectarian violence in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.</item>
<item>1981 – Mehmet Ali Ağca attempts to assassinate Pope John Paul II in St. Peter\'s Square in Rome. The Pope is rushed to the Agostino Gemelli University Polyclinic to undergo emergency surgery and survives.</item>
<item>1989 – Large groups of students occupy Tiananmen Square and begin a hunger strike.</item>
<item>1990 – The Dinamo–Red Star riot took place at Maksimir Stadium in Zagreb, Croatia between the Bad Blue Boys (fans of Dinamo Zagreb) and the Delije (fans of Red Star Belgrade).</item>
<item>1992 – Li Hongzhi gives the first public lecture on Falun Gong in Changchun, People\'s Republic of China.</item>
<item>1995 – Alison Hargreaves, a 33–year–old British mother, becomes the first woman to conquer Everest without oxygen or the help of sherpas.</item>
<item>1998 – Race riots break out in Jakarta, Indonesia, where shops owned by Indonesians of Chinese descent are looted and women raped.</item>
<item>1998 – India carries out two nuclear tests at Pokhran, following the three conducted on May 11. The United States and Japan impose economic sanctions on India.</item>
<item>2006 – São Paulo violence: Rebellions occur in several prisons in Brazil.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>