<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_21">
<item>293 – Roman Emperors Diocletian and Maximian appoint Galerius as Caesar to Diocletian, beginning the period of four rulers known as the Tetrarchy.</item>
<item>878 – Syracuse, Sicily, is captured by the Muslim Aghlabids after a nine–month siege.</item>
<item>879 – Pope John VIII gives blessings to Branimir of Croatia and to the Croatian people, considered to be international recognition of the Croatian state.</item>
<item>996 – Sixteen–year–old Otto III is crowned Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1349 – Dušan\'s Code, the constitution of the Serbian Empire, is enacted by Dušan the Mighty.</item>
<item>1403 – Henry III of Castile sends Ruy González de Clavijo as ambassador to Timur to discuss the possibility of an alliance between Timur and Castile against the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1554 – Queen Mary I grants a royal charter to Derby School, as a grammar school for boys in Derby, England.</item>
<item>1674 – The nobility elect John Sobieski King of Poland and Grand Duke of Lithuania.</item>
<item>1703 – Daniel Defoe imprisoned on charges of seditious libel.</item>
<item>1725 – The Order of St. Alexander Nevsky is instituted in Russia by Empress Catherine I. It would later be discontinued and then reinstated by the Soviet government in 1942 as the Order of Alexander Nevsky.</item>
<item>1851 – Slavery is abolished in Colombia, South America.</item>
<item>1864 – The Ionian Islands reunite with Greece.</item>
<item>1871 – Opening of the first rack railway in Europe, the Rigi Bahnen on Mount Rigi.</item>
<item>1881 – The American Red Cross is established by Clara Barton in Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1904 – The Fédération Internationale de Football Association (FIFA) is founded in Paris.</item>
<item>1927 – Charles Lindbergh touches down at Le Bourget Field in Paris, completing the world\'s first solo nonstop flight across the Atlantic Ocean.</item>
<item>1932 – Bad weather forces Amelia Earhart to land in a pasture in Derry, Northern Ireland, and she thereby becomes the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean.</item>
<item>1934 – Oskaloosa, Iowa, becomes the first municipality in the United States to fingerprint all of its citizens.</item>
<item>1937 – A Soviet station, North Pole–1, becomes the first scientific research settlement to operate on the drift ice of the Arctic Ocean.</item>
<item>1946 – Physicist Louis Slotin is fatally irradiated in a criticality incident during an experiment with the demon core at Los Alamos National Laboratory.</item>
<item>1961 – American civil rights movement: Alabama Governor John Malcolm Patterson declares martial law in an attempt to restore order after race riots break out.</item>
<item>1972 – Michelangelo\'s Pietà in St. Peter\'s Basilica in Rome is damaged by a vandal, the mentally disturbed Hungarian geologist Laszlo Toth.</item>
<item>1981 – The Italian government releases the membership list of Propaganda Due, an illegal pseudo–Masonic lodge that was implicated in numerous Italian crimes and mysteries.</item>
<item>1981 – Metro–Goldwyn–Mayer buys United Artists from Transamerica Corporation for $380 million because the 1980 film Heaven\'s Gate failed so badly at the box office for $44 million.</item>
<item>1992 – After 30 seasons Johnny Carson hosted his penultimate episode and last featuring guests (Robin Williams and Bette Midler) of The Tonight Show.</item>
<item>2001 – French Taubira law is enacted, officially recognizing the Atlantic slave trade and slavery as crimes against humanity.</item>
<item>2005 – The tallest roller coaster in the world, Kingda Ka opens at Six Flags Great Adventure in Jackson Township, New Jersey.</item>
<item>2006 – The Republic of Montenegro holds a referendum proposing independence from the State Union of Serbia and Montenegro; 55% of Montenegrins vote for independence.</item>
<item>2010 – JAXA, the Japan Aerospace Exploration Agency, launches the solar–sail spacecraft IKAROS aboard an H–IIA rocket. The vessel would make a Venus flyby late in the year.</item>
<item>2011 – Radio broadcaster Harold Camping predicted that the world would end on this date.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>