<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_25">
<item>567 BC – Servius Tullius, the king of Rome, celebrates a triumph for his victory over the Etruscans.</item>
<item>240 BC – First recorded perihelion passage of Halley\'s Comet.</item>
<item>1085 – Alfonso VI of Castile takes Toledo, Spain, back from the Moors.</item>
<item>1420 – Henry the Navigator is appointed governor of the Order of Christ.</item>
<item>1659 – Richard Cromwell resigns as Lord Protector of England following the restoration of the Long Parliament, beginning a second brief period of the republican government called the Commonwealth of England.</item>
<item>1660 – Charles II lands at Dover at the invitation of the Convention Parliament (England), which marks the end of the Cromwell–proclaimed Commonwealth of England, Scotland and Ireland and begins the Restoration (1660) of the British monarchy.</item>
<item>1787 – The United States Constitutional Convention formally convenes in Philadelphia, when a quorum of seven states is secured.</item>
<item>1819 – The Argentine Constitution of 1819 is promulgated.</item>
<item>1833 – The Chilean Constitution of 1833 is promulgated.</item>
<item>1837 – The Rebels of Lower Canada (Quebec) rebel against the British for governmental reforms.</item>
<item>1878 – Gilbert and Sullivan\'s comic opera H.M.S. Pinafore opens at the Opera Comique in London.</item>
<item>1895 – The Republic of Formosa is formed, with Tang Jingsong as its president.</item>
<item>1914 – The House of Commons of the United Kingdom passes the Home Rule Bill for devolution in Ireland.</item>
<item>1925 – Scopes Trial: John T. Scopes is indicted for teaching Charles Darwin\'s theory of evolution in Tennessee.</item>
<item>1935 – Jesse Owens of Ohio State University breaks three world records and ties a fourth at the Big Ten Conference Track and Field Championships in Ann Arbor, Michigan.</item>
<item>1946 – The parliament of Transjordan makes Abdullah I of Jordan their Emir.</item>
<item>1953 – Nuclear weapons testing: At the Nevada Test Site, the United States conducts its first and only nuclear artillery test.</item>
<item>1953 – The first public television station in the United States officially begins broadcasting as KUHT from the campus of the University of Houston.</item>
<item>1961 – Apollo program: U.S. President John F. Kennedy announces before a special joint session of the Congress his goal to initiate a project to put a \"man on the Moon\" before the end of the decade.</item>
<item>1963 – In Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, the Organisation of African Unity is established.</item>
<item>1966 – Explorer program: Explorer 32 launches.</item>
<item>1968 – The Gateway Arch in Saint Louis is dedicated.</item>
<item>1973 – Velos, while participating in a NATO exercise and in order to protest against the dictatorship in Greece, anchored at Fiumicino, Italy, refusing to return to Greece.</item>
<item>1981 – In Riyadh, the Gulf Cooperation Council is created between Bahrain, Kuwait, Oman, Qatar, Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates.</item>
<item>1986 – Hands Across America takes place.</item>
<item>1997 – A military coup in Sierra Leone replaces President Ahmad Tejan Kabbah with Major Johnny Paul Koroma.</item>
<item>1999 – The United States House of Representatives releases the Cox Report which details the People\'s Republic of China\'s nuclear espionage against the U.S. over the prior two decades.</item>
<item>2000 – Liberation Day of Lebanon. Israel withdraws its army from Lebanese territory (except for the disputed Shebaa farms zone) 22 years after its invasion in 1978.</item>
<item>2008 – NASA\'s Phoenix lander lands in Green Valley region of Mars to search for environments suitable for water and microbial life.</item>
<item>2009 – North Korea allegedly tests its second nuclear device. Following the nuclear test, Pyongyang also conducted several missile tests building tensions in the international community.</item>
<item>2011 – Oprah Winfrey airs her last show, ending her twenty–five–year run of The Oprah Winfrey Show.</item>
<item>2012 – The SpaceX Dragon became the first commercial spacecraft to successfully rendezvous with the International Space Station.</item>
<item>2018 – The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) becomes enforceable.</item>
<item>2018 – Ireland votes to repeal the Eight Amendment of the Constitution of Ireland, prohibiting abortion in all but a few cases, choosing to replace it with the Thirty–Sixth Amendment of the Constitution of Ireland.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>