<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_29">
<item>1328 – Philip VI is crowned King of France.</item>
<item>1453 – Fall of Constantinople: Ottoman armies under Sultan Mehmed II Fatih capture Constantinople after a 53–day siege, ending the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1660 – English Restoration: Charles II is restored to the throne of England, Scotland and Ireland.</item>
<item>1733 – The right of settlers in New France to enslave natives is upheld at Quebec City.</item>
<item>1790 – Rhode Island becomes the last of the original United States\' colonies to ratify the Constitution and is admitted as the 13th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1807 – Mustafa IV became Sultan of the Ottoman Empire and Caliph of Islam.</item>
<item>1848 – Wisconsin is admitted as the 30th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1852 – Jenny Lind leaves New York after her two–year American tour.</item>
<item>1861 – The Hong Kong General Chamber of Commerce is founded, in Hong Kong.</item>
<item>1864 – Emperor Maximilian I of Mexico arrives in Mexico for the first time.</item>
<item>1867 – The Austro–Hungarian Compromise of 1867 (\"the Compromise\") is born through Act 12, which establishes the Austro–Hungarian Empire.</item>
<item>1868 – Mihailo Obrenović III, Prince of Serbia is assassinated.</item>
<item>1886 – The pharmacist John Pemberton places his first advertisement for Coca–Cola, which appeared in The Atlanta Journal.</item>
<item>1900 – N\'Djamena is founded as Fort–Lamy by the French commander Émile Gentil.</item>
<item>1903 – In the May Coup, Alexander I, King of Serbia, and Queen Draga, are assassinated in Belgrade by the Black Hand (Crna Ruka) organization.</item>
<item>1913 – Igor Stravinsky\'s ballet score The Rite of Spring receives its premiere performance in Paris, France, provoking a riot.</item>
<item>1914 – The Ocean liner RMS Empress of Ireland sinks in the Gulf of Saint Lawrence with the loss of 1,012 lives.</item>
<item>1919 – Albert Einstein\'s theory of general relativity is tested (later confirmed) by Arthur Eddington and Andrew Claude de la Cherois Crommelin.</item>
<item>1935 – First flight of the Messerschmitt Bf 109 fighter aeroplane.</item>
<item>1948 – United Nations Truce Supervision Organization is founded.</item>
<item>1950 – The St. Roch, the first ship to circumnavigate North America, arrives in Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada.</item>
<item>1953 – Edmund Hillary and Sherpa Tenzing Norgay become the first people to reach the summit of Mount Everest, on Tenzing Norgay\'s (adopted) 39th birthday.</item>
<item>1964 – The Arab League meets in East Jerusalem to discuss the Palestinian question, leading to the formation of the Palestine Liberation Organization.</item>
<item>1973 – Tom Bradley is elected the first black mayor of Los Angeles, California.</item>
<item>1982 – Pope John Paul II becomes the first pontiff to visit Canterbury Cathedral.</item>
<item>1985 – Amputee Steve Fonyo completes cross–Canada marathon at Victoria, British Columbia, after 14 months.</item>
<item>1988 – The U.S. President Ronald Reagan begins his first visit to the Soviet Union when he arrives in Moscow for a superpower summit with the Soviet leader Mikhail Gorbachev.</item>
<item>1989 – Signing of an agreement between Egypt and the United States, allowing the manufacture of parts of the F–16 jet fighter plane in Egypt.</item>
<item>1990 – The Russian parliament elects Boris Yeltsin as president of the Russian Soviet Federative Socialist Republic.</item>
<item>1999 – Olusegun Obasanjo takes office as President of Nigeria, the first elected and civilian head of state in Nigeria after 16 years of military rule.</item>
<item>1999 – Space Shuttle Discovery completes the first docking with the International Space Station.</item>
<item>2001 – The U.S. Supreme Court rules that the disabled golfer Casey Martin can use a cart to ride in tournaments.</item>
<item>2015 – One World Observatory at One World Trade Center opens.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>