<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_26">
<item>961 – King Otto I elects his 6–year–old son Otto II as heir apparent and co–ruler of the East Frankish Kingdom. He is crowned at Aachen, and placed under the tutelage of his grandmother Matilda.</item>
<item>1135 – Alfonso VII of León and Castile is crowned in León Cathedral as Imperator totius Hispaniae (Emperor of all of Spain).</item>
<item>1538 – Geneva expels John Calvin and his followers from the city. Calvin lives in exile in Strasbourg for the next three years.</item>
<item>1805 – Napoléon Bonaparte assumes the title of King of Italy and is crowned with the Iron Crown of Lombardy in Milan Cathedral, the gothic cathedral in Milan.</item>
<item>1821 – Establishment of the Peloponnesian Senate by the Greek rebels.</item>
<item>1830 – The Indian Removal Act is passed by the U.S. Congress; it is signed into law by President Andrew Jackson two days later.</item>
<item>1857 – Dred Scott is emancipated by the Blow family, his original owners.</item>
<item>1864 – Montana is organized as a United States territory.</item>
<item>1868 – The Impeachment of Andrew Johnson ends with his acquittal by one vote.</item>
<item>1869 – Boston University is chartered by the Commonwealth of Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1879 – Russia and the United Kingdom sign the Treaty of Gandamak establishing an Afghan state.</item>
<item>1896 – Nicholas II becomes the last Tsar of Imperial Russia.</item>
<item>1896 – Charles Dow publishes the first edition of the Dow Jones Industrial Average.</item>
<item>1897 – Dracula, a novel by Irish author Bram Stoker, is published.</item>
<item>1908 – At Masjed Soleyman in southwest Persia, the first major commercial oil strike in the Middle East is made. The rights to the resource are quickly acquired by the Anglo–Persian Oil Company.</item>
<item>1918 – The Democratic Republic of Georgia is established.</item>
<item>1923 – The first 24 Hours of Le Mans was held and has since been run annually in June.</item>
<item>1936 – In the House of Commons of Northern Ireland, Tommy Henderson begins speaking on the Appropriation Bill. By the time he sits down in the early hours of the following morning, he had spoken for ten hours.</item>
<item>1938 – In the United States, the House Un–American Activities Committee begins its first session.</item>
<item>1948 – The U.S. Congress passes Public Law 80–557, which permanently establishes the Civil Air Patrol as an auxiliary of the United States Air Force.</item>
<item>1966 – British Guiana gains independence, becoming Guyana.</item>
<item>1968 – H–dagurinn in Iceland: Traffic changes from driving on the left to driving on the right overnight</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: Apollo 10 returns to Earth after a successful eight–day test of all the components needed for the forthcoming first manned moon landing.</item>
<item>1970 – The Soviet Tupolev Tu–144 becomes the first commercial transport to exceed Mach 2.</item>
<item>1972 – The United States and the Soviet Union sign the Anti–Ballistic Missile Treaty.</item>
<item>1981 – Italian Prime Minister Arnaldo Forlani and his coalition cabinet resign following a scandal over membership of the pseudo–masonic lodge P2 (Propaganda Due).</item>
<item>1986 – The European Community adopts the European flag.</item>
<item>1991 – Zviad Gamsakhurdia becomes the first elected President of the Republic of Georgia in the post–Soviet era.</item>
<item>1993 – Tahar Djaout, Algerian journalist and writer, was assassinated by Islamic fundamentalists, dying in hospital on June 2, 1993.</item>
<item>1998 – The Supreme Court of the United States rules that Ellis Island, the historic gateway for millions of immigrants, is mainly in the state of New Jersey, not New York.</item>
<item>1998 – The first \"National Sorry Day\" was held in Australia, and reconciliation events were held nationally, and attended by over a million people.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>