<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_24">
<item>1218 – The Fifth Crusade leaves Acre for Egypt.</item>
<item>1276 – Magnus Ladulås is crowned King of Sweden in Uppsala Cathedral.</item>
<item>1595 – Nomenclator of Leiden University Library appears, the first printed catalog of an institutional library.</item>
<item>1607 – 100 English settlers disembark in Jamestown, the first permanent English colony in America.</item>
<item>1621 – The Protestant Union is formally dissolved.</item>
<item>1626 – Peter Minuit buys Manhattan.</item>
<item>1683 – The Ashmolean Museum in Oxford, England, opens as the world\'s first university museum.</item>
<item>1689 – The English Parliament passes the Act of Toleration protecting dissenting Protestants but excluding Roman Catholics.</item>
<item>1738 – John Wesley is converted, essentially launching the Methodist movement; the day is celebrated annually by Methodists as Aldersgate Day and a church service is generally held on the preceding Sunday.</item>
<item>1798 – The Irish Rebellion of 1798 led by the United Irishmen against British rule begins.</item>
<item>1813 – South American independence leader Simón Bolívar enters Mérida, leading the invasion of Venezuela, and is proclaimed El Libertador (\"The Liberator\").</item>
<item>1830 – \"Mary Had a Little Lamb\" by Sarah Josepha Hale is published.</item>
<item>1832 – The First Kingdom of Greece is declared in the London Conference.</item>
<item>1844 – Samuel Morse sends the message \"What hath God wrought\" (a biblical quotation, Numbers 23:23) from a committee room in the United States Capitol to his assistant, Alfred Vail, in Baltimore, Maryland, to inaugurate a commercial telegraph line between Baltimore and Washington D.C.</item>
<item>1883 – The Brooklyn Bridge in New York City is opened to traffic after 14 years of construction.</item>
<item>1930 – Amy Johnson lands in Darwin, Northern Territory, becoming the first woman to fly solo from England to Australia (she left on May 5 for the 11,000 mile flight).</item>
<item>1935 – The first night game in Major League Baseball history is played in Cincinnati, Ohio, with the Cincinnati Reds beating the Philadelphia Phillies 2–1 at Crosley Field.</item>
<item>1940 – Igor Sikorsky performs the first successful single–rotor helicopter flight.</item>
<item>1956 – The first Eurovision Song Contest is held in Lugano, Switzerland.</item>
<item>1958 – United Press International is formed through a merger of the United Press and the International News Service.</item>
<item>1961 – American civil rights movement: Freedom Riders are arrested in Jackson, Mississippi, for \"disturbing the peace\" after disembarking from their bus.</item>
<item>1962 – Project Mercury: American astronaut Scott Carpenter orbits the Earth three times in the Aurora 7 space capsule.</item>
<item>1967 – Egypt imposes a blockade and siege of the Red Sea coast of Israel.</item>
<item>1976 – The Judgment of Paris takes place in France, launching California as a worldwide force in the production of quality wine.</item>
<item>1988 – Section 28 of the United Kingdom\'s Local Government Act 1988, a controversial amendment stating that a local authority cannot intentionally promote homosexuality, is enacted.</item>
<item>1991 – Israel conducts Operation Solomon, evacuating Ethiopian Jews to Israel.</item>
<item>1992 – The last Thai dictator, General Suchinda Kraprayoon, resigns following pro–democracy protests.</item>
<item>1992 – The ethnic cleansing in Kozarac, Bosnia and Herzegovina begins when Serbian militia and police forces enter the town.</item>
<item>1993 – Eritrea gains its independence from Ethiopia.</item>
<item>2000 – Israeli troops withdraw from southern Lebanon after 22 years of occupation.</item>
<item>2002 – Russia and the United States sign the Moscow Treaty.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>