<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_31">
<item>1293 – Mongol invasion of Java was a punitive expedition against King Kertanegara of Singhasari, who had refused to pay tribute to the Yuan and maimed one of its ministers. However, it ended with failure for the Mongols. Regarded as establish City of Surabaya</item>
<item>1578 – King Henry III lays the first stone of the Pont Neuf (New Bridge), the oldest bridge of Paris, France.</item>
<item>1669 – Citing poor eyesight, Samuel Pepys records the last event in his diary.</item>
<item>1790 – Manuel Quimper explores the Strait of Juan de Fuca.</item>
<item>1790 – The United States enacts its first copyright statute, the Copyright Act of 1790.</item>
<item>1805 – French and Spanish forces begin the assault against British forces occupying Diamond Rock.</item>
<item>1813 – In Australia, William Lawson, Gregory Blaxland and William Wentworth reach Mount Blaxland, effectively marking the end of a route across the Blue Mountains.</item>
<item>1859 – The clock tower at the Houses of Parliament, which houses Big Ben, starts keeping time.</item>
<item>1879 – Gilmore\'s Garden in New York City is renamed Madison Square Garden by William Henry Vanderbilt and is opened to the public at 26th Street and Madison Avenue.</item>
<item>1884 – The arrival at Plymouth of Tāwhiao, King of Maoris, to claim the protection of Queen Victoria</item>
<item>1909 – The National Negro Committee, forerunner to the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), convenes for the first time.</item>
<item>1910 – The South Africa Act comes into force, establishing the Union of South Africa.</item>
<item>1911 – The RMS Titanic is launched in Belfast, Northern Ireland.</item>
<item>1927 – The last Ford Model T rolls off the assembly line after a production run of 15,007,003 vehicles.</item>
<item>1947 – Communists seize power in Hungary</item>
<item>1958 – Feijenoord Rotterdam wins the first edition of the Benelux Cup</item>
<item>1961 – The South African Constitution of 1961 becomes effective.</item>
<item>1971 – In accordance with the Uniform Monday Holiday Act passed by the U.S. Congress in 1968, observation of Memorial Day occurs on the last Monday in May for the first time, rather than on the traditional Memorial Day of May 30.</item>
<item>1977 – The Trans–Alaska Pipeline System is completed.</item>
<item>1991 – Bicesse Accords in Angola lay out a transition to multi–party democracy under the supervision of the United Nations\' UNAVEM II mission.</item>
<item>2005 – Vanity Fair reveals that Mark Felt was \"Deep Throat\".</item>
<item>2008 – Usain Bolt breaks the world record in the 100m sprint, with a wind–legal (+1.7m/s) 9.72 seconds</item>
<item>2013 – The asteroid 1998 QE2 and its moon make their closest approach to Earth for the next two centuries.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>