<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_30">
<item>1381 – Beginning of the Peasants\' Revolt in England.</item>
<item>1510 – During the reign of the Zhengde Emperor, Ming dynasty rebel leader Zhu Zhifan is defeated by commander Qiu Yue, ending the Prince of Anhua rebellion.</item>
<item>1536 – King Henry VIII of England marries Jane Seymour, a lady–in–waiting to his first two wives.</item>
<item>1574 – Henry III becomes King of France.</item>
<item>1588 – The last ship of the Spanish Armada sets sail from Lisbon heading for the English Channel.</item>
<item>1631 – Publication of Gazette de France, the first French newspaper.</item>
<item>1642 – From this date all honors granted by Charles I of England are retroactively annulled by Parliament.</item>
<item>1815 – The East Indiaman Arniston is wrecked during a storm at Waenhuiskrans, near Cape Agulhas, in present–day South Africa, with the loss of 372 lives.</item>
<item>1845 – The Fatel Razack coming from India, lands in the Gulf of Paria in Trinidad and Tobago carrying the first Indians to the country.</item>
<item>1854 – The Kansas–Nebraska Act becomes law establishing the US territories of Kansas and Nebraska.</item>
<item>1868 – Decoration Day (the predecessor of the modern \"Memorial Day\") is observed in the United States for the first time (by \"Commander–in–chief of the Grand Army of the Republic\" John A. Logan\'s proclamation on May 5).</item>
<item>1876 – Ottoman sultan Abdülaziz is deposed and succeeded by his nephew Murad V.</item>
<item>1899 – Pearl Hart, a female outlaw of the Old West, robs a stage coach 30 miles southeast of Globe, Arizona.</item>
<item>1911 – At the Indianapolis Motor Speedway, the first Indianapolis 500 ends with Ray Harroun in his Marmon Wasp becoming the first winner of the 500–mile auto race.</item>
<item>1914 – The new, and then the largest, Cunard ocean liner RMS Aquitania, 45,647 tons, sets sails on her maiden voyage from Liverpool, England, to New York City.</item>
<item>1917 – Alexander I becomes king of Greece.</item>
<item>1922 – The Lincoln Memorial is dedicated in Washington, D.C..</item>
<item>1943 – The Holocaust: Josef Mengele becomes chief medical officer of the Zigeunerfamilienlager (Romani family camp) at Auschwitz concentration camp.</item>
<item>1959 – The Auckland Harbour Bridge, crossing the Waitematā Harbour in Auckland, New Zealand, is officially opened by Governor–General Charles Lyttelton, 10th Viscount Cobham.</item>
<item>1961 – The long–time Dominican dictator Rafael Trujillo is assassinated in Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic.</item>
<item>1968 – Charles de Gaulle reappears publicly after his flight to Baden–Baden, Germany, and dissolves the French National Assembly by a radio appeal. Immediately after, less than one million of his supporters march on the Champs–Élysées in Paris. This is the turning point of May 1968 events in France.</item>
<item>1971 – Mariner program: Mariner 9 is launched to map 70% of the surface, and to study temporal changes in the atmosphere and surface, of Mars.</item>
<item>1974 – The Airbus A300 passenger aircraft first enters service.</item>
<item>1975 – European Space Agency is established.</item>
<item>1989 – Tiananmen Square protests of 1989: The 33–foot high \"Goddess of Democracy\" statue is unveiled in Tiananmen Square by student demonstrators.</item>
<item>1998 – Nuclear Testing: Pakistan conducts an underground test in the Kharan Desert. It is reported to be a plutonium device with yield of 20kt TNT equivalent.</item>
<item>2008 – Convention on Cluster Munitions is adopted.</item>
<item>2013 – Nigeria passes a law banning same–sex marriage.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>