<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_4">
<item>1256 – The Augustinian monastic order is constituted at the Lecceto Monastery when Pope Alexander IV issues a papal bull Licet ecclesiae catholicae.</item>
<item>1415 – Religious reformers John Wycliffe and Jan Hus are condemned as heretics at the Council of Constance.</item>
<item>1436 – Assassination of the Swedish rebel (later national hero) Engelbrekt Engelbrektsson</item>
<item>1493 – Pope Alexander VI divides the New World between Spain and Portugal along the Line of Demarcation.</item>
<item>1626 – Dutch explorer Peter Minuit arrives in New Netherland (present day Manhattan Island) aboard the See Meeuw.</item>
<item>1686 – The Municipality of Ilagan is founded in the Philippines.</item>
<item>1776 – Rhode Island becomes the first American colony to renounce allegiance to King George III.</item>
<item>1814 – Emperor Napoleon I of France arrives at Portoferraio on the island of Elba to begin his exile.</item>
<item>1814 – King Ferdinand VII of Spain signs the Decree of the 4th of May, returning Spain to absolutism.</item>
<item>1836 – Formation of Ancient Order of Hibernians</item>
<item>1859 – The Cornwall Railway opens across the Royal Albert Bridge linking Devon and Cornwall in England.</item>
<item>1865 – Surrender of the Confederate departments of Alabama, Mississippi and East Louisiana at Citronelle, Alabama.</item>
<item>1871 – The National Association, the first professional baseball league, opens its first season in Fort Wayne, Indiana.</item>
<item>1904 – The United States begins construction of the Panama Canal.</item>
<item>1910 – The Royal Canadian Navy is created.</item>
<item>1912 – Italy occupies the Greek island of Rhodes.</item>
<item>1919 – May Fourth Movement: Student demonstrations take place in Tiananmen Square in Beijing, China, protesting the Treaty of Versailles, which transferred Chinese territory to Japan.</item>
<item>1926 – The United Kingdom general strike begins.</item>
<item>1932 – In Atlanta, mobster Al Capone begins serving an eleven–year prison sentence for tax evasion.</item>
<item>1953 – Ernest Hemingway wins the Pulitzer Prize for The Old Man and the Sea.</item>
<item>1961 – American civil rights movement: The \"Freedom Riders\" begin a bus trip through the South.</item>
<item>1961 – Malcolm Ross and Victor Prather attain a new altitude record for manned balloon flight ascending in the Strato–Lab V open gondola to 113,740 feet (34.67 km).</item>
<item>1972 – The Don\'t Make A Wave Committee, a fledgling environmental organization founded in Canada in 1971, officially changes its name to \"Greenpeace Foundation\".</item>
<item>1979 – Margaret Thatcher becomes the first female Prime Minister of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1989 – Iran–Contra affair: Former White House aide Oliver North is convicted of three crimes and acquitted of nine other charges; the convictions are later overturned on appeal.</item>
<item>1990 – Latvia proclaims the renewal of its independence after the Soviet occupation.</item>
<item>1994 – Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin and PLO leader Yasser Arafat sign a peace accord, granting self–rule in the Gaza Strip and Jericho.</item>
<item>2000 – Ken Livingstone becomes the first Mayor of London.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>