<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_5">
<item>553 – The Second Council of Constantinople begins.</item>
<item>1215 – Rebel barons renounce their allegiance to King John of England — part of a chain of events leading to the signing of the Magna Carta.</item>
<item>1260 – Kublai Khan becomes ruler of the Mongol Empire.</item>
<item>1494 – Christopher Columbus lands on the island of Jamaica and claims it for Spain.</item>
<item>1640 – King Charles I of England dissolves the Short Parliament.</item>
<item>1654 – Cromwell\'s Act of Grace, aimed at reconciliation with the Scots, proclaimed in Edinburgh.</item>
<item>1762 – Russia and Prussia sign the Treaty of St. Petersburg.</item>
<item>1789 – In France, the Estates–General convenes for the first time since 1614.</item>
<item>1809 – The Swiss canton of Aargau allows citizenship to Jews.</item>
<item>1835 – The first railway in continental Europe opens between Brussels and Mechelen.</item>
<item>1860 – Giuseppe Garibaldi sets sail from Genoa, leading the expedition of the Thousand to conquer the Kingdom of the Two Sicilies and giving birth to the Kingdom of Italy.</item>
<item>1866 – Memorial Day first celebrated in United States at Waterloo, New York.</item>
<item>1891 – The Music Hall in New York City (later known as Carnegie Hall) has its grand opening and first public performance, with Tchaikovsky as the guest conductor.</item>
<item>1904 – Pitching against the Philadelphia Athletics at the Huntington Avenue Grounds, Cy Young of the Boston Americans throws the first perfect game in the modern era of baseball.</item>
<item>1912 – Pravda, the \"voice\" of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union, begins publication in Saint Petersburg.</item>
<item>1925 – The government of South Africa declares Afrikaans an official language.</item>
<item>1927 – To the Lighthouse by Virginia Woolf is first published.</item>
<item>1936 – Italian troops occupy Addis Ababa, Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1941 – Emperor Haile Selassie returns to Addis Ababa; the country commemorates the date as Liberation Day or Patriots\' Victory Day.</item>
<item>1944 – German troops execute 216 civilians in the village of Kleisoura, Greece.</item>
<item>1950 – Bhumibol Adulyadej is crowned as King of Thailand.</item>
<item>1955 – The General Treaty, by which France, Britain and the United States recognize the sovereignty of West Germany, comes into effect.</item>
<item>1961 – Alan Shepard becomes the first American to travel into outer space, on a sub–orbital flight.</item>
<item>1964 – The Council of Europe declares May 5 as Europe Day.</item>
<item>1973 – Secretariat wins the 1973 Kentucky Derby in 1:59 2/5, an as–yet unbeaten record.</item>
<item>1980 – Operation Nimrod: The British Special Air Service storms the Iranian embassy in London after a six–day siege.</item>
<item>1985 – Ronald Reagan visits the military cemetery at Bitburg and the site of the Bergen–Belsen concentration camp, where he makes a speech.</item>
<item>1987 – Iran–Contra affair: Start of Congressional televised hearings in the United States of America</item>
<item>1991 – A riot breaks out in the Mt. Pleasant section of Washington, D.C. after police shoot a Salvadoran man.</item>
<item>1994 – The signing of the Bishkek Protocol between Armenia and Azerbaijan effectively freezes the Nagorno–Karabakh conflict.</item>
<item>1994 – American teenager Michael P. Fay is caned in Singapore for theft and vandalism.</item>
<item>2006 – The government of Sudan signs an accord with the Sudan Liberation Army.</item>
<item>2010 – Mass protests in Greece erupt in response to austerity measures imposed by the government as a result of the Greek government–debt crisis.</item>
<item>2014 – Eleven people are missing after a Chinese cargo ship collides with a Marshall Islands registered container ship off the coast of Hong Kong.</item>
<item>2018 – The 13th Hyundai A–League Grand Final</item>
</string-array>
</resources>