<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_7">
<item>351 – The Jewish revolt against Constantius Gallus breaks out. After his arrival at Antioch, the Jews begin a rebellion in Palestine.</item>
<item>558 – In Constantinople, the dome of the Hagia Sophia collapses. Justinian I immediately orders that the dome be rebuilt.</item>
<item>1274 – In France, the Second Council of Lyon opens to regulate the election of the Pope.</item>
<item>1487 – The Siege of Málaga commences during the Spanish Reconquista.</item>
<item>1664 – Louis XIV of France begins construction of the Palace of Versailles.</item>
<item>1718 – The city of New Orleans is founded by Jean–Baptiste Le Moyne, Sieur de Bienville.</item>
<item>1824 – World premiere of Ludwig van Beethoven\'s Ninth Symphony in Vienna, Austria. The performance is conducted by Michael Umlauf under the composer\'s supervision.</item>
<item>1832 – Greece\'s independence is recognized by the Treaty of London.</item>
<item>1846 – The Cambridge Chronicle, America\'s oldest surviving weekly newspaper, is published for the first time in Cambridge, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1864 – The world\'s oldest surviving clipper ship, the City of Adelaide is launched by William Pile, Hay and Co. in Sunderland, England, for transporting passengers and goods between Britain and Australia.</item>
<item>1895 – In Saint Petersburg, Russian scientist Alexander Stepanovich Popov demonstrates to the Russian Physical and Chemical Society his invention, the Popov lightning detector—a primitive radio receiver. In some parts of the former Soviet Union the anniversary of this day is celebrated as Radio Day.</item>
<item>1915 – Japanese 21 Demands Ultimatum to China (Commemorated as National Day of Humiliation)</item>
<item>1920 – Treaty of Moscow: Soviet Russia recognizes the independence of the Democratic Republic of Georgia only to invade the country six months later.</item>
<item>1920 – The Art Gallery of Ontario, in Toronto, opens the first exhibition by the Group of Seven.</item>
<item>1931 – The stand–off between criminal Francis Crowley and 300 members of the New York Police Department takes place in his fifth–floor apartment on West 91st street, New York City.</item>
<item>1946 – Tokyo Telecommunications Engineering (later renamed Sony) is founded with around 20 employees.</item>
<item>1948 – The Council of Europe is founded during the Hague Congress.</item>
<item>1952 – The concept of the integrated circuit, the basis for all modern computers, is first published by Geoffrey Dummer.</item>
<item>1976 – Honda Accord officially launched.</item>
<item>1986 – Canadian Patrick Morrow becomes the first person to climb each of the Seven Summits.</item>
<item>1992 – Michigan ratifies a 203–year–old proposed amendment to the United States Constitution making the 27th Amendment law. This amendment bars the U.S. Congress from giving itself a mid–term pay raise.</item>
<item>1992 – Space Shuttle program: The Space Shuttle Endeavour is launched on its first mission, STS–49.</item>
<item>1994 – Edvard Munch\'s iconic painting The Scream is recovered undamaged after being stolen from the National Gallery of Norway in February.</item>
<item>1998 – Mercedes–Benz buys Chrysler for US$40 billion USD and forms DaimlerChrysler in the largest industrial merger in history.</item>
<item>1999 – Pope John Paul II travels to Romania, becoming the first pope to visit a predominantly Eastern Orthodox country since the Great Schism in 1054.</item>
<item>1999 – In Guinea–Bissau, President João Bernardo Vieira is ousted in a military coup.</item>
<item>2000 – Vladimir Putin is inaugurated as president of Russia.</item>
<item>2004 – American businessman Nick Berg is beheaded by Islamic militants. The act is recorded on videotape and released on the Internet.</item>
<item>2007 – Israeli archaeologists discover the tomb of Herod the Great south of Jerusalem.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>