<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a5_9">
<item>1009 – Lombard Revolt: Lombard forces led by Melus revolt in Bari against the Byzantine Catepanate of Italy.</item>
<item>1092 – Lincoln Cathedral is consecrated.</item>
<item>1386 – England and Portugal formally ratify their alliance with the signing of the Treaty of Windsor, making it the oldest diplomatic alliance in the world which is still in force.</item>
<item>1540 – Hernando de Alarcón sets sail on an expedition to the Gulf of California.</item>
<item>1662 – The figure who later became Mr. Punch made his first recorded appearance in England.</item>
<item>1671 – Thomas Blood, disguised as a clergyman, attempts to steal England\'s Crown Jewels from the Tower of London.</item>
<item>1873 – Der Krach: Vienna stock market crash heralds the Long Depression.</item>
<item>1874 – The first horsebus makes its début in the city of Mumbai, traveling two routes.</item>
<item>1877 – Mihail Kogălniceanu reads, in the Chamber of Deputies, the Declaration of Independence of Romania. This day became the Independence Day of Romania.</item>
<item>1887 – Buffalo Bill Cody\'s Wild West Show opens in London.</item>
<item>1901 – Australia opens its first parliament in Melbourne.</item>
<item>1904 – The steam locomotive City of Truro becomes the first steam engine in Europe to exceed 100 mph (160 km/h).</item>
<item>1911 – The works of Gabriele D\'Annunzio are placed in the Index of Forbidden Books by the Vatican.</item>
<item>1926 – Admiral Richard E. Byrd and Floyd Bennett claim to have flown over the North Pole (later discovery of Byrd\'s diary appears to cast some doubt on the claim.)</item>
<item>1936 – Italy formally annexes Ethiopia after taking the capital Addis Ababa on May 5.</item>
<item>1946 – King Victor Emmanuel III of Italy abdicates and is succeeded by Umberto II.</item>
<item>1948 – Czechoslovakia\'s Ninth–of–May Constitution comes into effect.</item>
<item>1949 – Rainier III becomes Prince of Monaco.</item>
<item>1950 – Robert Schuman presents his proposal on the creation of an organized Europe, which according to him was indispensable to the maintenance of peaceful relations. This proposal, known as the \"Schuman Declaration\", is considered by some people to be the beginning of the creation of what is now the European Union.</item>
<item>1958 – Alfred Hitchcock\'s film Vertigo has world premiere in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1960 – The Food and Drug Administration announces it will approve birth control as an additional indication for Searle\'s Enovid, making Enovid the world\'s first approved oral contraceptive pill.</item>
<item>1961 – FCC Chairman Newton N. Minow gives his Wasteland Speech.</item>
<item>1969 – Carlos Lamarca leads the first urban guerrilla action against the military dictatorship of Brazil in São Paulo, by robbing two banks.</item>
<item>1974 – Watergate scandal: The United States House Committee on the Judiciary opens formal and public impeachment hearings against President Richard Nixon.</item>
<item>1994 – Disappearance of Cleashindra Hall in Pine Bluff, Arkansas.</item>
<item>2015 – Russia stages its biggest ever military parade in Moscow\'s Red Square to commemorate the 70th anniversary of Victory Day.</item>
<item>2018 – The historic defeat for Barisan Nasional, the governing coalition of Malaysia since the country\'s independence in 1957 in Malaysian General Election, 2018.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>