<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_13">
<item>313 – The Edict of Milan, signed by Constantine the Great and co–emperor Valerius Licinius granting religious freedom throughout the Roman Empire, is posted in Nicomedia.</item>
<item>1525 – Martin Luther marries Katharina von Bora, against the celibacy rule decreed by the Roman Catholic Church for priests and nuns.</item>
<item>1625 – King Charles I of England marries Catholic princess Henrietta Maria of France and Navarre, at Canterbury.</item>
<item>1740 – Georgia provincial governor James Oglethorpe begins an unsuccessful attempt to take Spanish Florida during the Siege of St. Augustine.</item>
<item>1774 – Rhode Island becomes the first of Britain\'s North American colonies to ban the importation of slaves.</item>
<item>1805 – Lewis and Clark Expedition: scouting ahead of the expedition, Meriwether Lewis and four companions sight the Great Falls of the Missouri River.</item>
<item>1886 – A fire devastates much of Vancouver, British Columbia.</item>
<item>1898 – Yukon Territory is formed, with Dawson chosen as its capital.</item>
<item>1927 – Aviator Charles Lindbergh receives a ticker tape parade down 5th Avenue in New York City.</item>
<item>1952 – Catalina affair: A Swedish Douglas DC–3 is shot down by a Soviet MiG–15 fighter.</item>
<item>1966 – The United States Supreme Court rules in Miranda v. Arizona that the police must inform suspects of their rights before questioning them.</item>
<item>1967 – U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson nominates Solicitor–General Thurgood Marshall to become the first black justice on the U.S. Supreme Court.</item>
<item>1977 – Convicted Martin Luther King Jr. assassin James Earl Ray is recaptured after escaping from prison three days before.</item>
<item>1981 – At the Trooping the Colour ceremony in London, a teenager, Marcus Sarjeant, fires six blank shots at Queen Elizabeth II.</item>
<item>1983 – Pioneer 10 becomes the first man–made object to leave the central Solar System when it passes beyond the orbit of Neptune.</item>
<item>1996 – The Montana Freemen surrender after an 81–day standoff with FBI agents.</item>
<item>2000 – President Kim Dae–jung of South Korea meets Kim Jong–il, leader of North Korea, for the beginning of the first ever inter–Korea summit, in the northern capital of Pyongyang.</item>
<item>2002 – The United States withdraws from the Anti–Ballistic Missile Treaty.</item>
<item>2010 – A capsule of the Japanese spacecraft Hayabusa, containing particles of the asteroid 25143 Itokawa, returns to Earth.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>