<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_17">
<item>653 – Pope Martin I is arrested in the Lateran Palace before being taken to Constantinople and tried for high treason.</item>
<item>1397 – The Kalmar Union is formed under the rule of Margaret I of Denmark.</item>
<item>1579 – Sir Francis Drake claims a land he calls Nova Albion (modern California) for England.</item>
<item>1596 – The Dutch explorer Willem Barentsz discovers the Arctic archipelago of Spitsbergen.</item>
<item>1673 – French explorers Jacques Marquette and Louis Jolliet reach the Mississippi River and become the first Europeans to make a detailed account of its course.</item>
<item>1767 – Samuel Wallis, an English sea captain, sights Tahiti and is considered the first European to reach the island.</item>
<item>1773 – Cúcuta, Colombia, is founded by Juana Rangel de Cuéllar.</item>
<item>1789 – In France, the Third Estate declares itself the National Assembly.</item>
<item>1794 – Foundation of Anglo–Corsican Kingdom.</item>
<item>1795 – The burghers of Swellendam expel the Dutch East India Company magistrate and declare a republic.</item>
<item>1839 – In the Kingdom of Hawaii, Kamehameha III issues the edict of toleration which gives Roman Catholics the freedom to worship in the Hawaiian Islands. The Hawaii Catholic Church and the Cathedral of Our Lady of Peace are established as a result.</item>
<item>1885 – The Statue of Liberty arrives in New York Harbor.</item>
<item>1898 – The United States Navy Hospital Corps is established.</item>
<item>1900 – Boxer Rebellion: Western Allied and Japanese forces capture the Taku Forts in Tianjin, China.</item>
<item>1901 – The College Board introduces its first standardized test, the forerunner to the SAT.</item>
<item>1910 – Aurel Vlaicu pilots an A. Vlaicu nr. 1 on its first flight.</item>
<item>1922 – Portuguese naval aviators Gago Coutinho and Sacadura Cabral complete the first aerial crossing of the South Atlantic.</item>
<item>1930 – U.S. President Herbert Hoover signs the Smoot–Hawley Tariff Act into law.</item>
<item>1933 – Union Station massacre: In Kansas City, Missouri, four FBI agents and captured fugitive Frank Nash are gunned down by gangsters attempting to free Nash.</item>
<item>1940 – The three Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania fall under the occupation of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1944 – Iceland declares independence from Denmark and becomes a republic.</item>
<item>1963 – The United States Supreme Court rules 8–1 in Abington School District v. Schempp against requiring the reciting of Bible verses and the Lord\'s Prayer in public schools.</item>
<item>1967 – Nuclear weapons testing: The People\'s Republic of China announces a successful test of its first thermonuclear weapon.</item>
<item>1972 – Watergate scandal: Five White House operatives are arrested for burgling the offices of the Democratic National Committee, in an attempt by some members of the Republican party to illegally wiretap the opposition.</item>
<item>1985 – Space Shuttle program: STS–51–G mission: Space Shuttle Discovery launches carrying Sultan bin Salman bin Abdulaziz Al Saud, the first Arab and first Muslim in space, as a payload specialist.</item>
<item>1991 – Apartheid: The South African Parliament repeals the Population Registration Act which required racial classification of all South Africans at birth.</item>
<item>1992 – A \"joint understanding\" agreement on arms reduction is signed by U.S. President George Bush and Russian President Boris Yeltsin (this would be later codified in START II).</item>
</string-array>
</resources>