<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_11">
<item>631 – Emperor Taizong of Tang, the Emperor of China, sends envoys to the Xueyantuo bearing gold and silk in order to seek the release of enslaved Chinese prisoners captured during the transition from Sui to Tang from the northern frontier; this embassy succeeded in freeing 80,000 Chinese men and women who were then returned to China.</item>
<item>980 – Vladimir the Great consolidates the Kievan realm from Ukraine to the Baltic Sea. He is proclaimed ruler (knyaz) of all Kievan Rus\'.</item>
<item>1011 – Lombard Revolt: Greek citizens of Bari rise up against the Lombard rebels led by Melus and deliver the city to Basil Mesardonites, Byzantine governor (catepan) of the Catepanate of Italy.</item>
<item>1118 – Roger of Salerno, Prince of Antioch, captures Azaz from the Seljuk Turks.</item>
<item>1157 – Albert I of Brandenburg, also called The Bear (Ger: Albrecht der Bär), becomes the founder of the Margraviate of Brandenburg, Germany and the first margrave.</item>
<item>1345 – The megas doux Alexios Apokaukos, chief minister of the Byzantine Empire, is lynched by political prisoners.</item>
<item>1509 – Henry VIII of England marries Catherine of Aragon.</item>
<item>1594 – Philip II recognizes the rights and privileges of the local nobles and chieftains in the Philippines, which paved way to the stabilization of the rule of the Principalía (an elite ruling class of native nobility in Spanish Philippines).</item>
<item>1748 – Denmark adopts the characteristic Nordic Cross flag later taken up by all other Scandinavian countries.</item>
<item>1770 – British explorer Captain James Cook runs aground on the Great Barrier Reef.</item>
<item>1776 – The Continental Congress appoints Thomas Jefferson, John Adams, Benjamin Franklin, Roger Sherman, and Robert R. Livingston to the Committee of Five to draft a declaration of independence.</item>
<item>1788 – Russian explorer Gerasim Izmailov reaches Alaska.</item>
<item>1805 – A fire consumes large portions of Detroit in the Michigan Territory.</item>
<item>1825 – The first cornerstone is laid for Fort Hamilton in New York City.</item>
<item>1837 – The Broad Street Riot occurs in Boston, fueled by ethnic tensions between Yankees and Irish.</item>
<item>1892 – The Limelight Department, one of the world\'s first film studios, is officially established in Melbourne, Australia.</item>
<item>1895 – Paris–Bordeaux–Paris, sometimes called the first automobile race in history or the \"first motor race\", takes place.</item>
<item>1898 – The Hundred Days\' Reform, a planned movement to reform social, political, and educational institutions in China, is started by the Guangxu Emperor, but is suspended by Empress Dowager Cixi after 104 days. (The failed reform led to the abolition of the Imperial examination in 1905.)</item>
<item>1901 – The boundaries of the Colony of New Zealand are extended by the UK to include the Cook Islands.</item>
<item>1903 – A group of Serbian officers stormed the royal palace and assassinated King Alexander Obrenović and his wife, Queen Draga.</item>
<item>1917 – King Alexander assumes the throne of Greece after his father, Constantine I, abdicates under pressure from allied armies occupying Athens.</item>
<item>1919 – Sir Barton wins the Belmont Stakes, becoming the first horse to win the U.S. Triple Crown.</item>
<item>1920 – During the U.S. Republican National Convention in Chicago, U.S. Republican Party leaders gathered in a room at the Blackstone Hotel to come to a consensus on their candidate for the U.S. presidential election, leading the Associated Press to coin the political phrase \"smoke–filled room\".</item>
<item>1935 – Inventor Edwin Armstrong gives the first public demonstration of FM broadcasting in the United States at Alpine, New Jersey.</item>
<item>1936 – The London International Surrealist Exhibition opens.</item>
<item>1942 – Free French Forces retreat from Bir Hakeim after having successfully delayed the Axis advance.</item>
<item>1962 – Frank Morris, John Anglin and Clarence Anglin allegedly become the only prisoners to escape from the prison on Alcatraz Island.</item>
<item>1963 – American Civil Rights Movement: Governor of Alabama George Wallace defiantly stands at the door of Foster Auditorium at the University of Alabama in an attempt to block two black students, Vivian Malone and James Hood, from attending that school. Later in the day, accompanied by federalized National Guard troops, they are able to register.</item>
<item>1968 – Lloyd J. Old identified the first cell surface antigens that could differentiate among different cell types.</item>
<item>1970 – After being appointed on May 15, Anna Mae Hays and Elizabeth P. Hoisington officially receive their ranks as U.S. Army Generals, becoming the first females to do so.</item>
<item>1971 – The U.S. Government forcibly removes the last holdouts to the Native American Occupation of Alcatraz, ending 19 months of control.</item>
<item>1978 – Altaf Hussain founds the student political movement All Pakistan Muhajir Students Organisation (APMSO) in Karachi University.</item>
<item>1987 – Diane Abbott, Paul Boateng and Bernie Grant are elected as the first black MPs in Great Britain.</item>
<item>1998 – Compaq Computer pays US$9 billion for Digital Equipment Corporation in the largest high–tech acquisition.</item>
<item>2002 – Antonio Meucci is acknowledged as the first inventor of the telephone by the United States Congress.</item>
<item>2004 – Cassini–Huygens makes its closest flyby of the Saturn moon Phoebe.</item>
<item>2008 – Canadian Prime Minister Stephen Harper makes a historic official apology to Canada\'s First Nations in regard to abuses at a Canadian Indian residential school.</item>
<item>2008 – The Fermi Gamma–ray Space Telescope is launched into orbit.</item>
<item>2010 – The first African FIFA World Cup kicks off in South Africa.</item>
<item>2013 – Greece\'s public broadcaster ERT is shut down by then–prime minister Antonis Samaras.</item>
<item>2015 – Greece\'s public broadcaster ERT is reopened by then–prime minister Alexis Tsipras.</item>
<item>2018 – United States President Donald J. Trump and Kim Jong–un of North Korea held the first meeting between leaders of their two countries in Singapore.</item>
<item>2018 – 3 World Trade Center officially opens.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>