<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_18">
<item>618 – Li Yuan becomes Emperor Gaozu of Tang, initiating three centuries of Tang dynasty rule over China.</item>
<item>656 – Ali becomes Caliph of the Rashidun Caliphate</item>
<item>1178 – Five Canterbury monks see what is possibly the Giordano Bruno crater being formed. It is believed that the current oscillations of the Moon\'s distance from the Earth (on the order of meters) are a result of this collision.</item>
<item>1264 – The Parliament of Ireland meets at Castledermot in County Kildare, the first definitively known meeting of this Irish legislature.</item>
<item>1265 – A draft Byzantine–Venetian treaty is concluded between Venetian envoys and Emperor Michael VIII Palaiologos, but is not ratified by Doge Reniero Zeno.</item>
<item>1633 – Charles I is crowned King of Scots at St Giles\' Cathedral, Edinburgh</item>
<item>1684 – The charter of the Massachusetts Bay Colony is revoked via a scire facias writ issued by an English court.</item>
<item>1799 – Action of 18 June 1799: A frigate squadron under Rear–admiral Perrée is captured by the British fleet under Lord Keith</item>
<item>1858 – Charles Darwin receives a paper from Alfred Russel Wallace that includes nearly identical conclusions about evolution as Darwin\'s own, prompting Darwin to publish his theory.</item>
<item>1859 – First ascent of Aletschhorn, second summit of the Bernese Alps.</item>
<item>1873 – Susan B. Anthony is fined $100 for attempting to vote in the 1872 presidential election.</item>
<item>1887 – The Reinsurance Treaty between Germany and Russia is signed.</item>
<item>1908 – Japanese immigration to Brazil begins when 781 people arrive in Santos aboard the ship Kasato–Maru.</item>
<item>1908 – The University of the Philippines is established.</item>
<item>1923 – Checker Taxi puts its first taxi on the streets.</item>
<item>1928 – Aviator Amelia Earhart becomes the first woman to fly in an aircraft across the Atlantic Ocean (she is a passenger; Wilmer Stultz is the pilot and Lou Gordon the mechanic).</item>
<item>1930 – Groundbreaking ceremonies for the Franklin Institute are held.</item>
<item>1935 – Police in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, clash with striking longshoremen, resulting in a total 60 injuries and 24 arrests.</item>
<item>1940 – Appeal of 18 June by Charles de Gaulle.</item>
<item>1940 – The \"Finest Hour\" speech is delivered by Winston Churchill.</item>
<item>1946 – Dr. Ram Manohar Lohia, a Socialist, calls for a Direct Action Day against the Portuguese in Goa.</item>
<item>1948 – Columbia Records introduces the long–playing record album in a public demonstration at the Waldorf–Astoria Hotel in New York City.</item>
<item>1954 – Carlos Castillo Armas leads an invasion force across the Guatemalan border, setting in motion the 1954 Guatemalan coup d\'état</item>
<item>1979 – SALT II is signed by the United States and the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1981 – The Lockheed F–117 Nighthawk, the first operational aircraft initially designed around stealth technology, makes its first flight.</item>
<item>1982 – Italian banker Roberto Calvi\'s body is discovered hanging beneath Blackfriars Bridge in London, England.</item>
<item>1983 – Space Shuttle program: STS–7, Astronaut Sally Ride becomes the first American woman in space.</item>
<item>1984 – A major clash between about 5,000 police and a similar number of miners takes place at Orgreave, South Yorkshire, during the 1984–85 UK miners\' strike.</item>
<item>2006 – The first Kazakh space satellite, KazSat–1 is launched.</item>
<item>2009 – The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO), a NASA robotic spacecraft is launched.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>