<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_19">
<item>325 – The original Nicene Creed was presented at the First Council of Nicaea.</item>
<item>1269 – King Louis IX of France orders all Jews found in public without an identifying yellow badge to be fined ten livres of silver.</item>
<item>1586 – English colonists leave Roanoke Island, after failing to establish England\'s first permanent settlement in North America.</item>
<item>1821 – Decisive defeat of the Filiki Eteria by the Ottomans at Drăgășani (in Wallachia).</item>
<item>1846 – The first officially recorded, organized baseball game is played under Alexander Cartwright\'s rules on Hoboken, New Jersey\'s Elysian Fields with the New York Base Ball Club defeating the Knickerbockers 23–1. Cartwright umpired.</item>
<item>1850 – Princess Louise of the Netherlands marries Crown Prince Karl of Sweden–Norway.</item>
<item>1862 – The U.S. Congress prohibits slavery in United States territories, nullifying Dred Scott v. Sandford.</item>
<item>1865 – Over two years after the Emancipation Proclamation, slaves in Galveston, Texas, United States, are finally informed of their freedom. The anniversary is still officially celebrated in Texas and 41 other contiguous states as Juneteenth.</item>
<item>1875 – The Herzegovinian rebellion against the Ottoman Empire begins.</item>
<item>1910 – The first Father\'s Day is celebrated in Spokane, Washington.</item>
<item>1913 – Natives Land Act, 1913 in South Africa implemented.</item>
<item>1915 – USS Arizona (BB–39) is launched.</item>
<item>1934 – The Communications Act of 1934 establishes the United States\' Federal Communications Commission (FCC).</item>
<item>1949 – The first ever NASCAR race was held at Charlotte Motor Speedway.</item>
<item>1961 – Kuwait declares independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1964 – The Civil Rights Act of 1964 is approved after surviving an 83–day filibuster in the United States Senate.</item>
<item>1965 – Nguyễn Cao Kỳ becomes Prime Minister of South Vietnam at the head of a military junta; General Nguyễn Văn Thiệu becomes the figurehead chief of state.</item>
<item>1978 – Garfield, holder of the Guinness World Record for the world\'s most widely syndicated comic strip, makes its debut.</item>
<item>1988 – Pope John Paul II canonizes 117 Vietnamese Martyrs.</item>
<item>1990 – The current international law defending indigenous peoples, Indigenous and Tribal Peoples Convention, 1989, is ratified for the first time by Norway.</item>
<item>1990 – The Communist Party of the Russian Soviet Federative Socialist Republic is founded in Moscow.</item>
<item>1991 – The Soviet occupation of Hungary ends.</item>
<item>2018 – The 10,000,000th United States Patent is issued.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>