<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_16">
<item>632 – Yazdegerd III ascends to the throne as king (shah) of the Persian Empire. He becomes the last ruler of the Sasanian dynasty (modern Iran).</item>
<item>1586 – Mary, Queen of Scots, recognizes Philip II of Spain as her heir and successor.</item>
<item>1774 – Foundation of Harrodsburg, Kentucky.</item>
<item>1836 – The formation of the London Working Men\'s Association gives rise to the Chartist Movement.</item>
<item>1846 – The Papal conclave of 1846 elects Pope Pius IX, beginning the longest reign in the history of the papacy.</item>
<item>1858 – Abraham Lincoln delivers his House Divided speech in Springfield, Illinois.</item>
<item>1871 – The University Tests Act allows students to enter the Universities of Oxford, Cambridge and Durham without religious tests (except for those intending to study theology).</item>
<item>1884 – The first purpose–built roller coaster, LaMarcus Adna Thompson\'s \"Switchback Railway\", opens in New York\'s Coney Island amusement park.</item>
<item>1897 – A treaty annexing the Republic of Hawaii to the United States is signed; the Republic would not be dissolved until a year later.</item>
<item>1903 – The Ford Motor Company is incorporated.</item>
<item>1903 – Roald Amundsen commences the first east–west navigation of the Northwest Passage, leaving Oslo, Norway.</item>
<item>1904 – Eugen Schauman assassinates Nikolay Bobrikov, Governor–General of Finland.</item>
<item>1904 – Irish author James Joyce begins a relationship with Nora Barnacle and subsequently uses the date to set the actions for his novel Ulysses; this date is now traditionally called \"Bloomsday\".</item>
<item>1911 – IBM founded as the Computing–Tabulating–Recording Company in Endicott, New York.</item>
<item>1922 – General election in the Irish Free State: The pro–Treaty Sinn Féin win a large majority.</item>
<item>1925 – The most famous Young Pioneer camp of the Soviet Union, Artek, is established.</item>
<item>1930 – Sovnarkom establishes decree time in the USSR.</item>
<item>1933 – The National Industrial Recovery Act is passed in the United States, allowing businesses to avoid antitrust prosecution if they established voluntary wage, price, and working condition regulations on an industry–wide basis. Large portions of the law are later declared unconstitutional.</item>
<item>1940 – A Communist government is installed in Lithuania.</item>
<item>1961 – Rudolf Nureyev defects from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1963 – Soviet Space Program: Vostok 6 Mission: Cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova becomes the first woman in space.</item>
<item>1972 – The largest single–site hydroelectric power project in Canada is inaugurated at Churchill Falls Generating Station.</item>
<item>1976 – Soweto uprising: A non–violent march by 15,000 students in Soweto, South Africa turns into days of rioting when police open fire on the crowd.</item>
<item>2000 – Israel complies with United Nations Security Council Resolution 425 22 years after its issuance, which calls on Israel to completely withdraw from Lebanon. Israel does so, except the disputed Shebaa farms.</item>
<item>2010 – Bhutan becomes the first country to institute a total ban on tobacco.</item>
<item>2012 – China successfully launches its Shenzhou 9 spacecraft, carrying three astronauts, including the first female Chinese astronaut Liu Yang, to the Tiangong–1 orbital module.</item>
<item>2012 – The United States Air Force\'s robotic Boeing X–37B spaceplane returns to Earth after a classified 469–day orbital mission.</item>
<item>2016 – Shanghai Disneyland Park, the first Disney Park in Mainland China opens to the public.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>