<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_12">
<item>1240 – At the instigation of Louis IX of France, an inter–faith debate, known as the Disputation of Paris, starts between a Christian monk and four rabbis.</item>
<item>1381 – Peasants\' Revolt: In England, rebels arrive at Blackheath.</item>
<item>1665 – Thomas Willett is appointed the first mayor of New York City.</item>
<item>1776 – The Virginia Declaration of Rights is adopted.</item>
<item>1817 – The earliest form of bicycle, the dandy horse, is driven by Karl von Drais.</item>
<item>1821 – Badi VII, king of Sennar, surrenders his throne and realm to Isma\'il Pasha, general of the Ottoman Empire, ending the existence of that Sudanese kingdom.</item>
<item>1898 – Philippine Declaration of Independence: General Emilio Aguinaldo declares the Philippines\' independence from Spain.</item>
<item>1914 – Massacre of Phocaea: Turkish irregulars slaughter 50 to 100 Greeks and expel thousands of others in an ethnic cleansing operation in the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1939 – Shooting begins on Paramount Pictures\' Dr. Cyclops, the first horror film photographed in three–strip Technicolor.</item>
<item>1939 – The Baseball Hall of Fame opens in Cooperstown, New York.</item>
<item>1942 – Anne Frank receives a diary for her thirteenth birthday.</item>
<item>1943 – The Holocaust: Germany liquidates the Jewish Ghetto in Brzeżany, Poland (now Berezhany, Ukraine). Around 1,180 Jews are led to the city\'s old Jewish graveyard and shot.</item>
<item>1967 – The United States Supreme Court in Loving v. Virginia declares all U.S. state laws which prohibit interracial marriage to be unconstitutional.</item>
<item>1975 – India, Judge Jagmohanlal Sinha of the city of Allahabad ruled that India\'s Prime Minister Indira Gandhi had used corrupt practices to win her seat in the Indian Parliament, and that she should be banned from holding any public office. Her main opponent for the Raebareli Constituency seat in 1971, Raj Narain had brought a petition to unseat her, charging that she had won the 1971 parliamentary election improperly. Mrs. Gandhi sent word that she refused to resign.</item>
<item>1979 – Bryan Allen wins the second Kremer prize for a man powered flight across the English Channel in the Gossamer Albatross.</item>
<item>1990 – Russia Day: The parliament of the Russian Federation formally declares its sovereignty.</item>
<item>1991 – Russians first democratically elected Boris Yeltsin as the President of Russia.</item>
<item>1991 – 1991 Kokkadichcholai massacre: The Sri Lankan Army massacres 152 minority Tamil civilians in the village of Kokkadichcholai near the eastern province town of Batticaloa.</item>
<item>1993 – An election takes place in Nigeria, presidential seat won by Moshood Kashimawo Olawale Abiola which is later annulled by the military Government led by Ibrahim Babangida.</item>
<item>1997 – Queen Elizabeth II reopens the Globe Theatre in London.</item>
<item>2009 – A disputed presidential election in Iran leads to wide–ranging local and international protests.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>