<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_1">
<item>1252 – Alfonso X is proclaimed king of Castile and León.</item>
<item>1495 – A monk, John Cor, records the first known batch of Scotch whisky.</item>
<item>1533 – Anne Boleyn is crowned Queen of England.</item>
<item>1649 – Start of the Sumuroy Revolt: Filipinos in Northern Samar led by Agustin Sumuroy revolt against Spanish colonial authorities.</item>
<item>1660 – Mary Dyer is hanged for defying a law banning Quakers from the Massachusetts Bay Colony.</item>
<item>1773 – Wolraad Woltemade rescues 14 sailors at the Cape of Good Hope from the sinking ship De Jonge Thomas by riding his horse into the sea seven times. He drowned on his eighth attempt.</item>
<item>1792 – Kentucky is admitted as the 15th state of the United States.</item>
<item>1796 – Tennessee is admitted as the 16th state of the United States.</item>
<item>1813 – Capture of USS Chesapeake.</item>
<item>1815 – Napoleon promulgates a revised Constitution after it passes a plebiscite.</item>
<item>1831 – James Clark Ross becomes the first European at the North Magnetic Pole.</item>
<item>1849 – Territorial Governor Alexander Ramsey declared the Territory of Minnesota officially established.</item>
<item>1855 – The American adventurer William Walker conquers Nicaragua.</item>
<item>1857 – Charles Baudelaire\'s Les Fleurs du mal is published.</item>
<item>1868 – The Treaty of Bosque Redondo is signed, allowing the Navajo to return to their lands in Arizona and New Mexico.</item>
<item>1890 – The United States Census Bureau begins using Herman Hollerith\'s tabulating machine to count census returns.</item>
<item>1910 – Robert Falcon Scott\'s second South Pole expedition leaves Cardiff.</item>
<item>1916 – Louis Brandeis becomes the first Jew appointed to the United States Supreme Court.</item>
<item>1922 – The Royal Ulster Constabulary is founded.</item>
<item>1929 – The 1st Conference of the Communist Parties of Latin America is held in Buenos Aires.</item>
<item>1939 – First flight of the German Focke–Wulf Fw 190 fighter aircraft.</item>
<item>1941 – The Farhud, a massive pogrom in Iraq, starts and as a result, many Iraqi Jews are forced to leave their homes.</item>
<item>1958 – Charles de Gaulle comes out of retirement to lead France by decree for six months.</item>
<item>1961 – The Canadian Bank of Commerce and Imperial Bank of Canada merge to form the Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce, the largest bank merger in Canadian history.</item>
<item>1962 – Adolf Eichmann is hanged in Israel.</item>
<item>1964 – Kenya becomes a republic with Jomo Kenyatta(1897 – 22 August 1978) as its 1st President(1964 to 1978)</item>
<item>1967 – The Beatles\' Sgt. Pepper\'s Lonely Hearts Club Band is released.</item>
<item>1974 – The Heimlich maneuver for rescuing choking victims is published in the journal Emergency Medicine.</item>
<item>1975 – The Patriotic Union of Kurdistan was founded by Jalal Talabani, Nawshirwan Mustafa, Fuad Masum and others.</item>
<item>1978 – The first international applications under the Patent Cooperation Treaty are filed.</item>
<item>1979 – The first black–led government of Rhodesia (now Zimbabwe) in 90 years takes power.</item>
<item>1980 – Cable News Network (CNN) begins broadcasting.</item>
<item>1988 – European Central Bank is founded in Brussels.</item>
<item>1988 – The Intermediate–Range Nuclear Forces Treaty comes into effect.</item>
<item>2009 – General Motors files for Chapter 11 bankruptcy. It is the fourth largest United States bankruptcy in history.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>