<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_23">
<item>229 – Sun Quan proclaims himself emperor of Eastern Wu.</item>
<item>1305 – A peace treaty between the Flemish and the French is signed at Athis–sur–Orge.</item>
<item>1532 – Henry VIII of England and Francis I of France sign a secret treaty against Emperor Charles V, Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1611 – The mutinous crew of Henry Hudson\'s fourth voyage sets Henry, his son and seven loyal crew members adrift in an open boat in what is now Hudson Bay; they are never heard from again.</item>
<item>1683 – William Penn signs a friendship treaty with Lenni Lenape Indians in Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1713 – The French residents of Acadia are given one year to declare allegiance to Britain or leave Nova Scotia, Canada.</item>
<item>1794 – Empress Catherine II of Russia grants Jews permission to settle in Kiev.</item>
<item>1810 – John Jacob Astor forms the Pacific Fur Company.</item>
<item>1860 – The United States Congress establishes the Government Printing Office.</item>
<item>1868 – Typewriter: Christopher Latham Sholes received a patent for an invention he called the \"Type–Writer.\"</item>
<item>1887 – The Rocky Mountains Park Act becomes law in Canada creating the nation\'s first national park, Banff National Park.</item>
<item>1894 – The International Olympic Committee is founded at the Sorbonne in Paris, at the initiative of Baron Pierre de Coubertin.</item>
<item>1917 – In a game against the Washington Senators, Boston Red Sox pitcher Ernie Shore retires 26 batters in a row after replacing Babe Ruth, who had been ejected for punching the umpire.</item>
<item>1926 – The College Board administers the first SAT exam.</item>
<item>1931 – Wiley Post and Harold Gatty take off from Roosevelt Field, Long Island in an attempt to circumnavigate the world in a single–engine plane.</item>
<item>1938 – The Civil Aeronautics Act is signed into law, forming the Civil Aeronautics Authority in the United States.</item>
<item>1947 – The United States Senate follows the United States House of Representatives in overriding U.S. President Harry S. Truman\'s veto of the Taft–Hartley Act.</item>
<item>1951 – The ocean liner, SS United States, is christened and launched.</item>
<item>1956 – The French National Assembly takes the first step in creating the French Community by passing the Loi Cadre, transferring a number of powers from Paris to elected territorial governments in French West Africa.</item>
<item>1959 – Convicted Manhattan Project spy Klaus Fuchs is released after only nine years in prison and allowed to emigrate to Dresden, East Germany where he resumes a scientific career.</item>
<item>1960 – The United States Food and Drug Administration declares Enovid to be the first officially approved combined oral contraceptive pill in the world.</item>
<item>1972 – Watergate scandal: U.S. President Richard M. Nixon and White House Chief of Staff H. R. Haldeman are taped talking about using the Central Intelligence Agency to obstruct the Federal Bureau of Investigation\'s investigation into the Watergate break–ins.</item>
<item>1972 – Title IX of the United States Civil Rights Act of 1964 is amended to prohibit sexual discrimination to any educational program receiving federal funds.</item>
<item>1996 – The Nintendo 64 home video game console is first released in Japan, with Nintendo ultimately selling 32.93 million units worldwide.</item>
<item>2012 – Ashton Eaton breaks the decathlon world record at the United States Olympic Trials.</item>
<item>2013 – Nik Wallenda becomes the first man to successfully walk across the Grand Canyon on a tight rope.</item>
<item>2014 – The last of Syria\'s declared chemical weapons are shipped out for destruction.</item>
<item>2016 – The United Kingdom votes in a referendum to leave the European Union, by 52% to 48%.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>