<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_28">
<item>1098 – Fighters of the First Crusade defeat Kerbogha of Mosul.</item>
<item>1519 – Charles V is elected Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1635 – Guadeloupe becomes a French colony.</item>
<item>1745 – A New England colonial army captures the French fortifications at Louisbourg (New Style).</item>
<item>1797 – French troops disembark in Corfu, beginning the French rule in the Ionian Islands.</item>
<item>1807 – Second British invasion of the Río de la Plata; John Whitelocke lands at Ensenada on an attempt to recapture Buenos Aires and is defeated by the locals.</item>
<item>1838 – Coronation of Queen Victoria of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1841 – The Paris Opera Ballet premieres Giselle in the Salle Le Peletier.</item>
<item>1846 – Adolphe Sax patents the saxophone.</item>
<item>1855 – Sigma Chi fraternity is founded in North America.</item>
<item>1859 – The first conformation dog show is held in Newcastle upon Tyne, England.</item>
<item>1865 – The Army of the Potomac is disbanded.</item>
<item>1880 – Australian bushranger Ned Kelly is captured at Glenrowan.</item>
<item>1881 – The Austro–Serbian Alliance of 1881 is secretly signed.</item>
<item>1882 – The Anglo–French Convention of 1882 marks the territorial boundaries between Guinea and Sierra Leone.</item>
<item>1894 – Labor Day becomes an official US holiday.</item>
<item>1895 – The United States Court of Private Land Claims rules James Reavis\' claim to Barony of Arizona is \"wholly fictitious and fraudulent.\"</item>
<item>1902 – The U.S. Congress passes the Spooner Act, authorizing President Theodore Roosevelt to acquire rights from Colombia for the Panama Canal.</item>
<item>1911 – The Nakhla meteorite, the first one to suggest signs of aqueous processes on Mars, falls to Earth, landing in Egypt.</item>
<item>1921 – Serbian King Alexander I proclaims the new constitution of the Kingdom of Serbs, Croats and Slovenes, known thereafter as the Vidovdan Constitution.</item>
<item>1926 – Mercedes–Benz is formed by Gottlieb Daimler and Karl Benz merging their two companies.</item>
<item>1936 – The Japanese puppet state of Mengjiang is formed in northern China.</item>
<item>1940 – Romania cedes Bessarabia (current–day Moldova) to the Soviet Union after facing an ultimatum.</item>
<item>1945 – Poland\'s Soviet–allied Provisional Government of National Unity is formed over a month after V–E Day.</item>
<item>1948 – Boxer Dick Turpin beats Vince Hawkins at Villa Park in Birmingham to become the first black British boxing champion in the modern era.</item>
<item>1956 – in Poznań, workers from HCP factory go to the streets, sparking one of the first major protests against communist government both in Poland and Europe.</item>
<item>1964 – Malcolm X forms the Organization of Afro–American Unity.</item>
<item>1969 – Stonewall riots begin in New York City, marking the start of the Gay Rights Movement.</item>
<item>1973 – Elections are held for the Northern Ireland Assembly, which will lead to power–sharing between unionists and nationalists in Northern Ireland for the first time.</item>
<item>1978 – The United States Supreme Court, in Regents of the University of California v. Bakke bars quota systems in college admissions.</item>
<item>1997 – Holyfield–Tyson II: Mike Tyson is disqualified in the third round for biting a piece off Evander Holyfield\'s ear.</item>
<item>2001 – Slobodan Milošević is extradited to the ICTY in The Hague to stand trial.</item>
<item>2009 – Honduran president Manuel Zelaya is ousted by a local military coup following a failed request to hold a referendum to rewrite the Honduran Constitution. This was the start of the 2009 Honduran constitutional crisis.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>