<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_24">
<item>1312 BC – Mursili II launches a campaign against the Kingdom of Azzi–Hayasa.</item>
<item>109 – Roman emperor Trajan inaugurates the Aqua Traiana, an aqueduct that channels water from Lake Bracciano, 40 kilometres (25 miles) north–west of Rome.</item>
<item>474 – Julius Nepos forces Roman usurper Glycerius to abdicate the throne and proclaims himself Emperor of the Western Roman Empire.</item>
<item>1230 – The Siege of Jaén begins, in the context of the Spanish Reconquista.</item>
<item>1374 – A sudden outbreak of St. John\'s Dance causes people in the streets of Aachen, Germany, to experience hallucinations and begin to jump and twitch uncontrollably until they collapse from exhaustion.</item>
<item>1497 – John Cabot lands in North America at Newfoundland leading the first European exploration of the region since the Vikings.</item>
<item>1509 – Henry VIII and Catherine of Aragon are crowned King and Queen of England.</item>
<item>1535 – The Anabaptist state of Münster is conquered and disbanded.</item>
<item>1571 – Miguel López de Legazpi founds Manila, the capital of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1604 – Samuel de Champlain discovers the mouth of the Saint John River, site of Reversing Falls and the present day city of Saint John, New Brunswick, Canada.</item>
<item>1717 – The Premier Grand Lodge of England, the first Masonic Grand Lodge in the world (now the United Grand Lodge of England), is founded in London.</item>
<item>1793 – The first Republican constitution in France is adopted.</item>
<item>1913 – Greece and Serbia annul their alliance with Bulgaria.</item>
<item>1916 – Mary Pickford becomes the first female film star to sign a million–dollar contract.</item>
<item>1918 – First airmail service in Canada from Montreal to Toronto.</item>
<item>1922 – The American Professional Football Association is renamed the National Football League.</item>
<item>1938 – Pieces of a meteorite, estimated to have weighed 450 metric tons when it hit the Earth\'s atmosphere and exploded, land near Chicora, Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1939 – Siam is renamed Thailand by Plaek Phibunsongkhram, the country\'s third prime minister.</item>
<item>1947 – Kenneth Arnold makes the first widely reported UFO sighting near Mount Rainier, Washington.</item>
<item>1949 – The first television western, Hopalong Cassidy, is aired on NBC starring William Boyd.</item>
<item>1950 – Apartheid: In South Africa, the Group Areas Act formally segregating races is passed.</item>
<item>1957 – In Roth v. United States, the U.S. Supreme Court rules that obscenity is not protected by the First Amendment.</item>
<item>1963 – The United Kingdom grants Zanzibar internal self–government.</item>
<item>1981 – The Humber Bridge opens to traffic, connecting Yorkshire and Lincolnshire. It would be the world\'s longest bridge span for 17 years.</item>
<item>1982 – \"The Jakarta Incident\": British Airways Flight 9 flies into a cloud of volcanic ash thrown up by the eruption of Mount Galunggung, resulting in the failure of all four engines.</item>
<item>1989 – Jiang Zemin succeeds Zhao Ziyang to become the General Secretary of the Communist Party of China after the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989.</item>
<item>1995 – \"Rugby World Cup final\": South Africa defeats New Zealand, Nelson Mandela presents Francois Pienaar with the Webb–Ellis trophy in an iconic post–apartheid moment.</item>
<item>2004 – In New York, capital punishment is declared unconstitutional.</item>
<item>2010 – John Isner of the United States defeats Nicolas Mahut of France at Wimbledon, in the longest match in professional tennis history.</item>
<item>2010 – Julia Gillard assumes office as the first female Prime Minister of Australia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>