<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_2">
<item>455 – Sack of Rome: Vandals enter Rome, and plunder the city for two weeks.</item>
<item>1098 – First Crusade: The first Siege of Antioch ends as Crusader forces take the city; the second siege began five days later.</item>
<item>1615 – The first Récollet missionaries arrive at Quebec City, from Rouen, France.</item>
<item>1692 – Bridget Bishop is the first person to be tried for witchcraft in Salem, Massachusetts; she was found guilty and later hanged.</item>
<item>1763 – Pontiac\'s Rebellion: At what is now Mackinaw City, Michigan, Chippewas capture Fort Michilimackinac by diverting the garrison\'s attention with a game of lacrosse, then chasing a ball into the fort.</item>
<item>1835 – P. T. Barnum and his circus start their first tour of the United States.</item>
<item>1848 – The Slavic congress in Prague begins.</item>
<item>1896 – Guglielmo Marconi applies for a patent for his wireless telegraph.</item>
<item>1909 – Alfred Deakin becomes Prime Minister of Australia for the third time.</item>
<item>1910 – Charles Rolls, a co–founder of Rolls–Royce Limited, becomes the first man to make a non–stop double crossing of the English Channel by plane.</item>
<item>1924 – U.S. President Calvin Coolidge signs the Indian Citizenship Act into law, granting citizenship to all Native Americans born within the territorial limits of the United States.</item>
<item>1946 – Birth of the Italian Republic: In a referendum, Italians vote to turn Italy from a monarchy into a Republic. After the referendum, King Umberto II of Italy is exiled.</item>
<item>1953 – The coronation of Queen Elizabeth II, who is crowned Queen of the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, New Zealand and Her Other Realms and Territories &amp; Head of the Commonwealth, the first major international event to be televised.</item>
<item>1955 – The USSR and Yugoslavia sign the Belgrade declaration and thus normalize relations between both countries, discontinued since 1948.</item>
<item>1962 – During the 1962 FIFA World Cup, police had to intervene multiple times in fights between Chilean and Italian players in one of the most violent games in football history.</item>
<item>1964 – The Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO) is formed.</item>
<item>1966 – Surveyor program: Surveyor 1 lands in Oceanus Procellarum on the Moon, becoming the first U.S. spacecraft to soft–land on another world.</item>
<item>1967 – Sgt. Pepper\'s Lonely Hearts Club Band by The Beatles is released in the United States.</item>
<item>1979 – Pope John Paul II starts his first official visit to his native Poland, becoming the first Pope to visit a Communist country.</item>
<item>2003 – Europe launches its first voyage to another planet, Mars. The European Space Agency\'s Mars Express probe launches from the Baikonur space center in Kazakhstan.</item>
<item>2014 – Telangana officially becomes the 29th state of India &amp; form 13 districts New Andhra Pradesh.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>