<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_20">
<item>1652 – Tarhoncu Ahmed Pasha is appointed Grand Vizier of the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1685 – Monmouth Rebellion: James Scott, 1st Duke of Monmouth declares himself King of England at Bridgwater.</item>
<item>1756 – A British garrison is imprisoned in the Black Hole of Calcutta.</item>
<item>1782 – The U.S. Congress adopts the Great Seal of the United States.</item>
<item>1787 – Oliver Ellsworth moves at the Federal Convention to call the government the \'United States\'.</item>
<item>1789 – Deputies of the French Third Estate take the Tennis Court Oath.</item>
<item>1819 – The U.S. vessel SS Savannah arrives at Liverpool, United Kingdom. It is the first steam–propelled vessel to cross the Atlantic, although most of the journey is made under sail.</item>
<item>1837 – Queen Victoria succeeds to the British throne.</item>
<item>1840 – Samuel Morse receives the patent for the telegraph.</item>
<item>1862 – Barbu Catargiu, the Prime Minister of Romania, is assassinated.</item>
<item>1877 – Alexander Graham Bell installs the world\'s first commercial telephone service in Hamilton, Ontario, Canada.</item>
<item>1895 – The Kiel Canal, crossing the base of the Jutland peninsula and the busiest artificial waterway in the world, is officially opened.</item>
<item>1900 – Boxer Rebellion: The Imperial Chinese Army begins a 55–day siege of the Legation Quarter in Beijing, China.</item>
<item>1900 – Baron Eduard Toll, leader of the Russian Polar Expedition of 1900, departs Saint Petersburg in Russia on the explorer ship Zarya, never to return.</item>
<item>1921 – Workers of Buckingham and Carnatic Mills in the city of Chennai, India, begin a four–month strike.</item>
<item>1942 – The Holocaust: Kazimierz Piechowski and three others, dressed as members of the SS–Totenkopfverbände, steal an SS staff car and escape from the Auschwitz concentration camp.</item>
<item>1943 – The Detroit race riot breaks out and continues for three more days.</item>
<item>1944 – The experimental MW 18014 V–2 rocket reaches an altitude of 176 km, becoming the first man–made object to reach outer space.</item>
<item>1948 – The Deutsche Mark is introduced in Western Allied–occupied Germany. The Communists respond by imposing the Berlin Blockade four days later.</item>
<item>1960 – The Mali Federation gains independence from France (it later splits into Mali and Senegal).</item>
<item>1963 – Following the Cuban Missile Crisis, the Soviet Union and the United States sign an agreement to establish the so–called \"red telephone\" link between Washington and Moscow.</item>
<item>1972 – Watergate scandal: An 18½–minute gap appears in the tape recording of the conversations between U.S. President Richard Nixon and his advisers regarding the recent arrests of his operatives while breaking into the Watergate complex.</item>
<item>1975 – The film Jaws is released in the United States, becoming the highest–grossing film of that time and starting the trend of films known as \"summer blockbusters\".</item>
<item>1990 – Asteroid Eureka is discovered.</item>
<item>1991 – German Bundestag votes to move seat of government to Berlin.</item>
<item>2003 – The Wikimedia Foundation is founded in St. Petersburg, Florida.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>