<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_21">
<item>1307 – Külüg Khan is enthroned as Khagan of the Mongols and Wuzong of the Yuan.</item>
<item>1582 – Sengoku period: Oda Nobunaga, the most powerful of the Japanese daimyōs, was forced to commit suicide by his own general Akechi Mitsuhide.</item>
<item>1749 – Halifax, Nova Scotia, is founded.</item>
<item>1768 – James Otis, Jr. offends the King and Parliament in a speech to the Massachusetts General Court.</item>
<item>1788 – New Hampshire ratifies the Constitution of the United States and is admitted as the ninth state in the United States.</item>
<item>1898 – The United States captures Guam from Spain.</item>
<item>1915 – The U.S. Supreme Court hands down its decision in Guinn v. United States 238 US 347 1915, striking down Oklahoma grandfather clause legislation which had the effect of denying the right to vote to blacks.</item>
<item>1930 – One–year conscription comes into force in France.</item>
<item>1940 – The first successful west–to–east navigation of Northwest Passage begins at Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada.</item>
<item>1952 – The Philippine School of Commerce, through a republic act, is converted to Philippine College of Commerce, later to be the Polytechnic University of the Philippines.</item>
<item>1957 – Ellen Fairclough is sworn in as Canada\'s first female Cabinet Minister.</item>
<item>1963 – Cardinal Giovanni Battista Montini is elected as Pope Paul VI.</item>
<item>1970 – Penn Central declares Section 77 bankruptcy, largest ever US corporate bankruptcy up to this date.</item>
<item>1973 – In handing down the decision in Miller v. California 413 US 15, the Supreme Court of the United States establishes the Miller test for obscenity in U.S. law.</item>
<item>1982 – John Hinckley is found not guilty by reason of insanity for the attempted assassination of U.S. President Ronald Reagan.</item>
<item>2000 – Section 28 (of the Local Government Act 1988), outlawing the \'promotion\' of homosexuality in the United Kingdom, is repealed in Scotland with a 99 to 17 vote.</item>
<item>2004 – SpaceShipOne becomes the first privately funded spaceplane to achieve spaceflight.</item>
<item>2006 – Pluto\'s newly discovered moons are officially named Nix and Hydra.</item>
<item>2009 – Greenland assumes self–rule.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>