<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_27">
<item>1358 – The Republic of Ragusa is founded.</item>
<item>1759 – General James Wolfe begins the siege of Quebec.</item>
<item>1806 – British forces take Buenos Aires during the first of the British invasions of the River Plate.</item>
<item>1895 – The inaugural run of the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad\'s Royal Blue from Washington, D.C., to New York City, the first U.S. passenger train to use electric locomotives.</item>
<item>1898 – The first solo circumnavigation of the globe is completed by Joshua Slocum from Briar Island, Nova Scotia.</item>
<item>1927 – Prime Minister of Japan Tanaka Giichi convenes an eleven–day conference to discuss Japan\'s strategy in China. The Tanaka Memorial, a forged plan for world domination, is later claimed to be a secret report leaked from this conference.</item>
<item>1941 – German troops capture the city of Białystok during Operation Barbarossa.</item>
<item>1946 – In the Canadian Citizenship Act, the Parliament of Canada establishes the definition of Canadian citizenship.</item>
<item>1952 – Guatemala passes Decree 900, ordering the redistribution of uncultivated land.</item>
<item>1954 – The Obninsk Nuclear Power Plant, the Soviet Union\'s first nuclear power station, opens in Obninsk, near Moscow.</item>
<item>1954 – The 1954 FIFA World Cup quarterfinal match between Hungary and Brazil, highly anticipated to be exciting, instead turns violent, with three players ejected and further fighting continuing after the game.</item>
<item>1971 – After only three years in business, rock promoter Bill Graham closes Fillmore East in New York, the \"Church of Rock and Roll\".</item>
<item>1973 – The President of Uruguay Juan María Bordaberry dissolves Parliament and establishes a dictatorship.</item>
<item>1974 – U.S. president Richard Nixon visits the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1976 – Air France Flight 139 (Tel Aviv–Athens–Paris) is hijacked en route to Paris by the PLO and redirected to Entebbe, Uganda.</item>
<item>1977 – France grants independence to Djibouti.</item>
<item>1982 – Space Shuttle Columbia launched from the Kennedy Space Center on the final research and development flight mission, STS–4.</item>
<item>2007 – Tony Blair resigns as British Prime Minister, a position he had held since 1997.</item>
<item>2007 – The Brazilian Military Police invades the favelas of Complexo do Alemão in an episode which is remembered as the Complexo do Alemão massacre.</item>
<item>2008 – In a highly scrutizined election President of Zimbabwe Robert Mugabe is re–elected in a landslide after his opponent Morgan Tsvangirai had withdrawn a week earlier, citing violence against his party\'s supporters.</item>
<item>2013 – NASA launches the Interface Region Imaging Spectrograph, a space probe to observe the Sun.</item>
<item>2015 – A midair explosion from flammable powder at a recreational water park in Taiwan injures at least 510 people with about 183 in serious condition in intensive care.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>