<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_25">
<item>1741 – Maria Theresa of Austria is crowned Queen of Hungary.</item>
<item>1786 – Gavriil Pribylov discovers St. George Island of the Pribilof Islands in the Bering Sea.</item>
<item>1788 – Virginia becomes the tenth state to ratify the United States Constitution.</item>
<item>1848 – A photograph of the June Days uprising becomes the first known instance of photojournalism.</item>
<item>1900 – The Taoist monk Wang Yuanlu discovers the Dunhuang manuscripts, a cache of ancient texts that are of great historical and religious significance, in the Mogao Caves of Dunhuang, China.</item>
<item>1910 – The United States Congress passes the Mann Act, which prohibits interstate transport of females for “immoral purposes”; the ambiguous language would be used to selectively prosecute people for years to come.</item>
<item>1910 – Igor Stravinsky\'s ballet The Firebird is premiered in Paris, bringing him to prominence as a composer.</item>
<item>1923 – Capt. Lowell H. Smith and Lt. John P. Richter perform the first ever aerial refueling in a DH.4B biplane</item>
<item>1935 – Diplomatic relations between the Soviet Union and Colombia are established.</item>
<item>1938 – Dr. Douglas Hyde is inaugurated as the first President of Ireland.</item>
<item>1947 – The Diary of a Young Girl (better known as The Diary of Anne Frank) is published.</item>
<item>1975 – Mozambique achieves independence from Portugal.</item>
<item>1975 – Prime Minister Indira Gandhi declares a state of internal emergency in India.</item>
<item>1976 – Missouri Governor Kit Bond issues an executive order rescinding the Extermination Order, formally apologizing on behalf of the state of Missouri for the suffering it had caused to members of The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter–day Saints.</item>
<item>1978 – The rainbow flag representing gay pride is flown for the first time during the San Francisco Gay Freedom Day Parade.</item>
<item>1981 – Microsoft is restructured to become an incorporated business in its home state of Washington.</item>
<item>1984 – American singer Prince releases his most successful studio album, Purple Rain.</item>
<item>1991 – Croatia and Slovenia declare their independence by referendum from Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1993 – Kim Campbell is sworn in as the first female Prime Minister of Canada.</item>
<item>1997 – An unmanned Progress spacecraft collides with the Russian space station Mir.</item>
<item>1997 – The National Hockey League approved expansion franchises for Nashville (1998), Atlanta (1999), Columbus (2000), and Minneapolis–Saint Paul (2000).</item>
<item>1998 – In Clinton v. City of New York, the United States Supreme Court decides that the Line Item Veto Act of 1996 is unconstitutional.</item>
<item>2017 – The World Health Organization estimates that Yemen has over 200,000 cases of cholera.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>