<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_30">
<item>296 – Pope Marcellinus begins his papacy.</item>
<item>1520 – Spanish conquistadors led by Hernán Cortés fight their way out of Tenochtitlan.</item>
<item>1805 – The U.S. Congress organizes the Michigan Territory.</item>
<item>1859 – French acrobat Charles Blondin crosses Niagara Falls on a tightrope.</item>
<item>1860 – The 1860 Oxford evolution debate at the Oxford University Museum of Natural History takes place.</item>
<item>1864 – U.S. President Abraham Lincoln grants Yosemite Valley to California for \"public use, resort and recreation\".</item>
<item>1886 – The first transcontinental train trip across Canada departs from Montreal, Quebec. It arrives in Port Moody, British Columbia on July 4.</item>
<item>1892 – The Homestead Strike begins near Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1906 – The United States Congress passes the Meat Inspection Act and Pure Food and Drug Act.</item>
<item>1908 – The Tunguska Event, the largest impact event on Earth in human recorded history, resulting in a massive explosion over Eastern Siberia.</item>
<item>1922 – In Washington D.C., U.S. Secretary of State Charles Evans Hughes and Dominican Ambassador Francisco J. Peynado sign the Hughes–Peynado agreement, which ends the United States occupation of the Dominican Republic.</item>
<item>1936 – Emperor Haile Selassie of Abyssinia appeals for aid to the League of Nations against Italy\'s invasion of his country.</item>
<item>1937 – The world\'s first emergency telephone number, 999, is introduced in London.</item>
<item>1953 – The first Chevrolet Corvette rolls off the assembly line in Flint, Michigan.</item>
<item>1960 – Belgian Congo gains independence as Republic of the Congo (Léopoldville).</item>
<item>1966 – The National Organization for Women, the United States\' largest feminist organization, is founded.</item>
<item>1968 – Pope Paul VI issues the Credo of the People of God.</item>
<item>1972 – The first leap second is added to the UTC time system.</item>
<item>1974 – The Baltimore municipal strike of 1974 begins.</item>
<item>1977 – The Southeast Asia Treaty Organization disbands.</item>
<item>1986 – The U.S. Supreme Court rules in Bowers v. Hardwick that states can outlaw homosexual acts between consenting adults.</item>
<item>1990 – East Germany and West Germany merge their economies.</item>
<item>1997 – The United Kingdom transfers sovereignty over Hong Kong to China.</item>
<item>2013 – Protests begin around Egypt against President Mohamed Morsi and the ruling Freedom and Justice Party, leading to their overthrow during the 2013 Egyptian coup d\'état</item>
</string-array>
</resources>