<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_5">
<item>1257 – Kraków, in Poland, receives city rights.</item>
<item>1625 – The city of Breda surrenders to the Spanish tercios under general Ambrosio Spinola.</item>
<item>1817 – The first Great Lakes steamer, the Frontenac, is launched.</item>
<item>1829 – HMS Pickle captures the armed slave ship Voladora off the coast of Cuba.</item>
<item>1832 – The June Rebellion breaks out in Paris in an attempt to overthrow the monarchy of Louis Philippe.</item>
<item>1837 – Houston is incorporated by the Republic of Texas.</item>
<item>1849 – Denmark becomes a constitutional monarchy by the signing of a new constitution.</item>
<item>1851 – Harriet Beecher Stowe\'s anti–slavery serial, Uncle Tom\'s Cabin, or Life Among the Lowly, starts a ten–month run in the National Era abolitionist newspaper.</item>
<item>1862 – As the Treaty of Saigon is signed, ceding parts of southern Vietnam to France, the guerrilla leader Trương Định decides to defy Emperor Tự Đức of Vietnam and fight on against the Europeans.</item>
<item>1873 – Sultan Barghash bin Said of Zanzibar closes the great slave market under the terms of a treaty with Great Britain.</item>
<item>1883 – The first regularly scheduled Orient Express departs Paris.</item>
<item>1915 – Denmark amends its constitution to allow women\'s suffrage.</item>
<item>1916 – Louis Brandeis is sworn in as a Justice of the United States Supreme Court; he is the first American Jew to hold such a position.</item>
<item>1933 – The U.S. Congress abrogates the United States\' use of the gold standard by enacting a joint resolution (48 Stat. 112) nullifying the right of creditors to demand payment in gold.</item>
<item>1945 – The Allied Control Council, the military occupation governing body of Germany, formally takes power.</item>
<item>1949 – Thailand elects Orapin Chaiyakan, the first female member of Thailand\'s Parliament.</item>
<item>1959 – The first government of Singapore is sworn in.</item>
<item>1963 – Movement of 15 Khordad: Protests against the arrest of Ayatollah Ruhollah Khomeini by the Shah of Iran, Mohammad Reza Pahlavi. In several cities, masses of angry demonstrators are confronted by tanks and paratroopers.</item>
<item>1964 – DSV Alvin is commissioned.</item>
<item>1975 – The United Kingdom holds its first country–wide referendum on membership of the European Economic Community (EEC).</item>
<item>1976 – The Teton Dam in Idaho, United States, collapses.</item>
<item>1981 – The \"Morbidity and Mortality Weekly Report\" of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention reports that five people in Los Angeles, California, have a rare form of pneumonia seen only in patients with weakened immune systems, in what turns out to be the first recognized cases of AIDS.</item>
<item>1984 – Operation Blue Star: Under orders from India\'s prime minister, Indira Gandhi, the Indian Army begins an invasion of the Golden Temple, the holiest site of the Sikh religion.</item>
<item>1989 – The Tank Man halts the progress of a column of advancing tanks for over half an hour after the Tiananmen Square protests of 1989.</item>
<item>1993 – Portions of the Holbeck Hall Hotel in Scarborough, North Yorkshire, UK, fall into the sea following a landslide.</item>
<item>1995 – The Bose–Einstein condensate is first created.</item>
<item>1998 – A strike begins at the General Motors parts factory in Flint, Michigan, that quickly spreads to five other assembly plants. The strike lasts seven weeks.</item>
<item>2001 – Tropical Storm Allison makes landfall on the upper–Texas coastline as a strong tropical storm and dumps large amounts of rain over Houston. The storm causes $5.5 billion in damages, making Allison the second costliest tropical storm in U.S. history.</item>
<item>2003 – A severe heat wave across Pakistan and India reaches its peak, as temperatures exceed 50 °C (122 °F) in the region.</item>
<item>2004 – Noël Mamère, Mayor of Bègles, celebrates marriage for two men for the first time in France.</item>
<item>2006 – Serbia declares independence from the State Union of Serbia and Montenegro.</item>
<item>2017 – Montenegro becomes the 29th member of the NATO.</item>
<item>2017 – Six Arab countries—Bahrain, Egypt, Libya, Saudi Arabia, Yemen, and the United Arab Emirates—cut diplomatic ties with Qatar, accusing it of destabilising the region.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>