<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_7">
<item>421 – Emperor Theodosius II marries Aelia Eudocia. The wedding was celebrated at Constantinople (Byzantine Empire).</item>
<item>879 – Pope John VIII recognizes the Duchy of Croatia under Duke Branimir as an independent state.</item>
<item>1002 – Henry II, a cousin of Emperor Otto III, is elected and crowned King of Germany.</item>
<item>1099 – First Crusade: The Siege of Jerusalem begins.</item>
<item>1420 – Troops of the Republic of Venice capture Udine, ending the independence of the Patria del Friuli.</item>
<item>1494 – Spain and Portugal sign the Treaty of Tordesillas which divides the New World between the two countries.</item>
<item>1628 – The Petition of Right, a major English constitutional document, is granted the Royal Assent by Charles I and becomes law.</item>
<item>1654 – Louis XIV is crowned King of France.</item>
<item>1776 – Richard Henry Lee presents the \"Lee Resolution\" to the Continental Congress. The motion is seconded by John Adams and will lead to the United States Declaration of Independence.</item>
<item>1800 – David Thompson reaches the mouth of the Saskatchewan River in Manitoba.</item>
<item>1810 – The newspaper Gazeta de Buenos Ayres is first published in Argentina.</item>
<item>1832 – The Great Reform Act of England and Wales receives royal assent.</item>
<item>1863 – During the French intervention in Mexico, Mexico City is captured by French troops.</item>
<item>1905 – Norway\'s parliament dissolves its union with Sweden. The vote was confirmed by a national plebiscite on August 13 of that year.</item>
<item>1906 – Cunard Line\'s RMS Lusitania is launched from the John Brown Shipyard, Glasgow (Clydebank), Scotland.</item>
<item>1929 – The Lateran Treaty is ratified, bringing Vatican City into existence.</item>
<item>1938 – The Douglas DC–4E makes its first test flight.</item>
<item>1940 – King Haakon VII, Crown Prince Olav and the Norwegian government leave Tromsø and go into exile in London. They return exactly five years later</item>
<item>1948 – Edvard Beneš resigns as President of Czechoslovakia rather than signing the Ninth–of–May Constitution, making his nation a Communist state.</item>
<item>1955 – Lux Radio Theatre signs off the air permanently. The show launched in New York in 1934, and featured radio adaptations of Broadway shows and popular films.</item>
<item>1965 – The Supreme Court of the United States hands down its decision in Griswold v. Connecticut, prohibiting the states from criminalizing the use of contraception by married couples.</item>
<item>1971 – The United States Supreme Court overturns the conviction of Paul Cohen for disturbing the peace, setting the precedent that vulgar writing is protected under the First Amendment to the United States Constitution.</item>
<item>1975 – Sony introduces the Betamax videocassette recorder for sale to the public</item>
<item>1977 – Five hundred million people watch the high day of the Silver Jubilee of Queen Elizabeth II begin on television.</item>
<item>1991 – Mount Pinatubo erupts, generating an ash column 7 kilometres (4.3 mi) high.</item>
<item>2000 – The United Nations defines the Blue Line as the border between Israel and Lebanon.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>