<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a6_8">
<item>452 – Italy invaded by Attila the Hun</item>
<item>1191 – Richard I arrives in Acre, beginning his crusade.</item>
<item>1789 – James Madison introduces twelve proposed amendments to the United States Constitution in Congress.</item>
<item>1856 – A group of 194 Pitcairn Islanders, descendants of the mutineers of HMS Bounty, arrives at Norfolk Island, commencing the Third Settlement of the Island.</item>
<item>1867 – Coronation of Franz Joseph as King of Hungary following the Austro–Hungarian compromise (Ausgleich).</item>
<item>1887 – Herman Hollerith applies for US patent #395,781 for the \'Art of Compiling Statistics\', which was his punched card calculator.</item>
<item>1906 – Theodore Roosevelt signs the Antiquities Act into law, authorizing the President to restrict the use of certain parcels of public land with historical or conservation value.</item>
<item>1912 – Carl Laemmle incorporates Universal Pictures.</item>
<item>1918 – Nova Aquila, brightest nova since Kepler\'s nova of 1604, discovered</item>
<item>1918 – A solar eclipse is observed at Baker City, Oregon by scientists and an artist hired by the United States Navy.</item>
<item>1929 – Margaret Bondfield is appointed Minister of Labour. She is the first woman appointed to the Cabinet of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1949 – George Orwell\'s Nineteen Eighty–Four is published.</item>
<item>1953 – The United States Supreme Court rules that restaurants in Washington, D.C. cannot refuse to serve black patrons.</item>
<item>1959 – The USS Barbero and United States Postal Service attempt the delivery of mail via Missile Mail.</item>
<item>1966 – The National Football League and American Football League announced a merger effective in 1970.</item>
<item>1984 – Homosexuality is declared legal in the Australian state of New South Wales.</item>
<item>1987 – New Zealand\'s Labour government establishes a national nuclear–free zone under the New Zealand Nuclear Free Zone, Disarmament, and Arms Control Act 1987.</item>
<item>1992 – The first World Oceans Day is celebrated, coinciding with the Earth Summit held in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.</item>
<item>1995 – Downed U.S. Air Force pilot Captain Scott O\'Grady is rescued by U.S. Marines in Bosnia.</item>
<item>2004 – The first Venus Transit in well over a century takes place, the previous one being in 1882.</item>
<item>2008 – At least 37 miners go missing after an explosion in an Ukrainian coal mine causes it to collapse.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>