<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_13">
<item>587 BC – Babylon\'s siege of Jerusalem ends following the destruction of Solomon\'s Temple.</item>
<item>1174 – William I of Scotland, a key rebel in the Revolt of 1173–74, is captured at Alnwick by forces loyal to Henry II of England.</item>
<item>1249 – Coronation of Alexander III as King of Scots.</item>
<item>1787 – The Continental Congress enacts the Northwest Ordinance establishing governing rules for the Northwest Territory. It also establishes procedures for the admission of new states and limits the expansion of slavery.</item>
<item>1814 – The Carabinieri, the national gendarmerie of Italy, is established.</item>
<item>1830 – The General Assembly\'s Institution, now the Scottish Church College, one of the pioneering institutions that ushered the Bengali renaissance, is founded by Alexander Duff and Raja Ram Mohan Roy, in Calcutta, India.</item>
<item>1863 – New York City draft riots: In New York City, opponents of conscription begin three days of rioting which will be later regarded as the worst in United States history.</item>
<item>1878 – Treaty of Berlin: The European powers redraw the map of the Balkans. Serbia, Montenegro and Romania become completely independent of the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1919 – The British airship R34 lands in Norfolk, England, completing the first airship return journey across the Atlantic in 182 hours of flight.</item>
<item>1956 – The Dartmouth workshop is the first conference on artificial intelligence.</item>
<item>1962 – In an unprecedented action, British Prime Minister Harold Macmillan dismisses seven members of his Cabinet, marking the effective end of the National Liberals as a distinct force within British politics.</item>
<item>1973 – Alexander Butterfield reveals the existence of the \"Nixon tapes\" to the special Senate committee investigating the Watergate break–in.</item>
<item>1977 – New York City: Amidst a period of financial and social turmoil experiences an electrical blackout lasting nearly 24 hours that leads to widespread fires and looting.</item>
<item>1985 – The Live Aid benefit concert takes place in London and Philadelphia, as well as other venues such as Moscow and Sydney.</item>
<item>1985 – Vice President George H. W. Bush becomes the Acting President for the day when President Ronald Reagan undergoes surgery to remove polyps from his colon.</item>
<item>2003 – French DGSE personnel abort an operation to rescue Íngrid Betancourt from FARC rebels in Colombia, causing a political scandal when details are leaked to the press.</item>
<item>2011 – United Nations Security Council Resolution 1999 is adopted, which admits South Sudan to member status of United Nations.</item>
<item>2016 – Prime Minister of the United Kingdom David Cameron resigns, and is succeeded by Theresa May.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>