<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_11">
<item>813 – Byzantine emperor Michael I, under threat by conspiracies, abdicates in favor of his general Leo the Armenian, and becomes a monk (under the name Athanasius).</item>
<item>911 – Signing of the Treaty of Saint–Clair–sur–Epte between Charles the Simple and Rollo of Normandy.</item>
<item>1174 – Baldwin IV, 13, becomes King of Jerusalem, with Raymond III, Count of Tripoli as regent and William of Tyre as chancellor.</item>
<item>1346 – Charles IV, Count of Luxembourg and King of Bohemia, is elected King of the Romans.</item>
<item>1405 – Ming admiral Zheng He sets sail to explore the world for the first time.</item>
<item>1476 – Giuliano della Rovere is appointed bishop of Coutances.</item>
<item>1576 – Martin Frobisher sights Greenland.</item>
<item>1616 – Samuel de Champlain returns to Quebec.</item>
<item>1789 – Jacques Necker is dismissed as France\'s Finance Minister sparking the Storming of the Bastille.</item>
<item>1796 – The United States takes possession of Detroit from Great Britain under terms of the Jay Treaty.</item>
<item>1801 – French astronomer Jean–Louis Pons makes his first comet discovery. In the next 27 years he discovers another 36 comets, more than any other person in history.</item>
<item>1804 – A duel occurs in which the Vice President of the United States Aaron Burr mortally wounds former Secretary of the Treasury Alexander Hamilton.</item>
<item>1848 – Waterloo railway station in London opens.</item>
<item>1889 – Tijuana, Mexico, is founded.</item>
<item>1893 – The first cultured pearl is obtained by Kokichi Mikimoto.</item>
<item>1895 – Brothers Auguste and Louis Lumière demonstrate movie film technology to scientists.</item>
<item>1914 – Babe Ruth makes his debut in Major League Baseball.</item>
<item>1914 – USS Nevada (BB–36) is launched.</item>
<item>1919 – The eight–hour day and free Sunday become law for workers in the Netherlands.</item>
<item>1920 – In the East Prussian plebiscite the local populace decides to remain with Weimar Germany.</item>
<item>1921 – The Red Army captures Mongolia from the White Army and establishes the Mongolian People\'s Republic.</item>
<item>1922 – The Hollywood Bowl opens.</item>
<item>1924 – Eric Liddell won the gold medal in 400m at the 1924 Paris Olympics, after refusing to run in the heats for 100m, his favoured distance, on the Sunday</item>
<item>1934 – Engelbert Zaschka of Germany flies his large human–powered aircraft, the Zaschka Human–Power Aircraft, about 20 meters at Berlin Tempelhof Airport without assisted take–off.</item>
<item>1936 – The Triborough Bridge in New York City is opened to traffic.</item>
<item>1941 – The Northern Rhodesian Labour Party holds its first congress in Nkana.</item>
<item>1943 – Massacres of Poles in Volhynia and Eastern Galicia by the Ukrainian Insurgent Army within the Reichskommissariat Ukraine (Volhynia) peak.</item>
<item>1947 – The Exodus 1947 heads to Palestine from France.</item>
<item>1950 – Pakistan joins the International Monetary Fund and the International Bank.</item>
<item>1960 – France legislates for the independence of Dahomey (later Benin), Upper Volta (later Burkina) and Niger.</item>
<item>1960 – Congo Crisis: The State of Katanga breaks away from the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</item>
<item>1962 – First transatlantic satellite television transmission.</item>
<item>1962 – Project Apollo: At a press conference, NASA announces lunar orbit rendezvous as the means to land astronauts on the Moon, and return them to Earth.</item>
<item>1971 – Copper mines in Chile are nationalized.</item>
<item>1972 – The first game of the World Chess Championship 1972 between challenger Bobby Fischer and defending champion Boris Spassky starts.</item>
<item>1990 – Oka Crisis: First Nations land dispute in Quebec, Canada begins.</item>
<item>1994 – PTV is introduced as a kids programming block for PBS to broadcast educational programming to underprivileged children.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>