<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_12">
<item>927 – King Constantine II of Scotland, King Hywel Dda of Deheubarth, Ealdred of Bamburgh and King Owain of the Cumbrians accepted the overlordship of King Æthelstan of England, leading to seven years of peace in the north.</item>
<item>1191 – Third Crusade: Saladin\'s garrison surrenders to Philip Augustus, ending the two–year siege of Acre.</item>
<item>1470 – The Ottomans capture Euboea.</item>
<item>1493 – Hartmann Schedel\'s Nuremberg Chronicle, one of the best–documented early printed books, is published.</item>
<item>1527 – Lê Cung Hoàng ceded the throne to Mạc Đăng Dung, ending the Lê dynasty and starting the Mạc dynasty.</item>
<item>1543 – King Henry VIII of England marries his sixth and last wife, Catherine Parr, at Hampton Court Palace.</item>
<item>1580 – The Ostrog Bible, one of the early printed Bibles in a Slavic language, is published.</item>
<item>1776 – Captain James Cook begins his third voyage.</item>
<item>1789 – In response to the dismissal of the French finance minister Jacques Necker, the radical journalist Camille Desmoulins gives a speech which results in the storming of the Bastille two days later.</item>
<item>1790 – The Civil Constitution of the Clergy is passed in France by the National Constituent Assembly.</item>
<item>1799 – Ranjit Singh conquers Lahore and becomes Maharaja of the Punjab (Sikh Empire).</item>
<item>1806 – Sixteen German imperial states leave the Holy Roman Empire and form the Confederation of the Rhine.</item>
<item>1812 – The American Army of the Northwest briefly occupies the Upper Canadian settlement at what is now at Windsor, Ontario.</item>
<item>1862 – The Medal of Honor is authorized by the United States Congress.</item>
<item>1920 – The Soviet–Lithuanian Peace Treaty is signed, by which Soviet Russia recognizes the independence of Lithuania.</item>
<item>1943 – German and Soviet forces engage in one of the largest armored engagements of all time.</item>
<item>1948 – Israeli Prime Minister David Ben–Gurion orders the expulsion of Palestinians from the towns of Lod and Ramla.</item>
<item>1960 – Orlyonok, the main Young Pioneer camp of the Russian SFSR, is founded.</item>
<item>1962 – The Rolling Stones perform their first concert, at London\'s Marquee Club.</item>
<item>1971 – The Australian Aboriginal Flag is flown for the first time.</item>
<item>1975 – São Tomé and Príncipe declare independence from Portugal.</item>
<item>1979 – The island nation of Kiribati becomes independent from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>2007 – U.S. Army Apache helicopters perform airstrikes in Baghdad, Iraq; footage from the cockpit is later leaked to the Internet.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>