<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_19">
<item>484 – Leontius, Roman usurper, is crowned Eastern emperor at Tarsus (modern Turkey). He is recognized in Antioch and makes it his capital.</item>
<item>1553 – Lady Jane Grey is replaced by Mary I of England as Queen of England after only nine days on the throne.</item>
<item>1701 – Representatives of the Iroquois Confederacy sign the Nanfan Treaty, ceding a large territory north of the Ohio River to England.</item>
<item>1817 – Unsuccessful in his attempt to conquer the Kingdom of Hawaii for the Russian–American Company, Georg Anton Schäffer is forced to admit defeat and leave Kauai.</item>
<item>1821 – Coronation of George IV of the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1832 – The British Medical Association is founded as the Provincial Medical and Surgical Association by Sir Charles Hastings at a meeting in the Board Room of the Worcester Infirmary.</item>
<item>1843 – Brunel\'s steamship the SS Great Britain is launched, becoming the first ocean–going craft with an iron hull and screw propeller, becoming the largest vessel afloat in the world.</item>
<item>1848 – Women\'s rights: A two–day Women\'s Rights Convention opens in Seneca Falls, New York.</item>
<item>1900 – The first line of the Paris Métro opens for operation.</item>
<item>1903 – Maurice Garin wins the first Tour de France.</item>
<item>1947 – Prime Minister of the shadow Burmese government, Bogyoke Aung San and eight others are assassinated.</item>
<item>1947 – Korean politician Lyuh Woon–hyung is assassinated.</item>
<item>1952 – Opening of the 1952 Summer Olympics in Helsinki Finland.</item>
<item>1961 – Tunisia imposes a blockade on the French naval base at Bizerte; the French would capture the entire town four days later.</item>
<item>1963 – Joe Walker flies a North American X–15 to a record altitude of 106,010 meters (347,800 feet) on X–15 Flight 90. Exceeding an altitude of 100 km, this flight qualifies as a human spaceflight under international convention.</item>
<item>1976 – Sagarmatha National Park in Nepal is created.</item>
<item>1977 – The world\'s first Global Positioning System (GPS) signal was transmitted from Navigation Technology Satellite 2 (NTS–2) and received at Rockwell Collins in Cedar Rapids, Iowa, at 12:41 a.m. Eastern time (ET).</item>
<item>1979 – The Sandinista rebels overthrow the government of the Somoza family in Nicaragua.</item>
<item>1979 – The oil tanker SS Atlantic Empress collides with another oil tanker, causing the largest ever ship–borne oil spill.</item>
<item>1980 – Opening of the 1980 Summer Olympics in Moscow</item>
<item>1981 – In a private meeting with U.S. President Ronald Reagan, French President François Mitterrand reveals the existence of the Farewell Dossier, a collection of documents showing the Soviet Union had been stealing American technological research and development.</item>
<item>1983 – The first three–dimensional reconstruction of a human head in a CT is published.</item>
<item>1997 – The Troubles: The Provisional Irish Republican Army resumes a ceasefire to end their 25–year paramilitary campaign to end British rule in Northern Ireland.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>