<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_18">
<item>1334 – The bishop of Florence blesses the first foundation stone for the new campanile (bell tower) of the Florence Cathedral, designed by the artist Giotto di Bondone.</item>
<item>1555 – The College of Arms is reincorporated by Royal charter signed by Queen Mary I of England and King Philip II of Spain.</item>
<item>1841 – Coronation of Emperor Pedro II of Brazil.</item>
<item>1862 – First ascent of Dent Blanche, one of the highest summits in the Alps.</item>
<item>1870 – The First Vatican Council decrees the dogma of papal infallibility.</item>
<item>1872 – The Ballot Act 1872 in the United Kingdom introduced the requirement that parliamentary and local government elections be held by secret ballot.</item>
<item>1914 – The U.S. Congress forms the Aviation Section, U.S. Signal Corps, giving official status to aircraft within the U.S. Army for the first time.</item>
<item>1942 – The Germans test fly the Messerschmitt Me 262 using its jet engines for the first time.</item>
<item>1966 – Human spaceflight: Gemini 10 is launched from Cape Kennedy on a 70–hour mission that includes docking with an orbiting Agena target vehicle.</item>
<item>1966 – A racially charged incident in a bar sparks the six–day Hough riots in Cleveland, Ohio; 1,700 Ohio National Guard troops intervene to restore order.</item>
<item>1968 – Intel is founded in Mountain View, California.</item>
<item>1976 – Nadia Comăneci becomes the first person in Olympic Games history to score a perfect 10 in gymnastics at the 1976 Summer Olympics.</item>
<item>1982 – Two hundred sixty–eight Guatemalan campesinos (\"peasants\" or \"country people\") are slain in the Plan de Sánchez massacre.</item>
<item>1992 – A picture of Les Horribles Cernettes was taken, which became the first ever photo posted to the World Wide Web.</item>
<item>1994 – Rwandan genocide: The Rwandan Patriotic Front takes control of Gisenyi and north western Rwanda, forcing the interim government into Zaire and ending the genocide.</item>
<item>2013 – The Government of Detroit, with up to $20 billion in debt, files for the largest municipal bankruptcy in U.S. history.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>