<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_16">
<item>622 – The beginning of the Islamic calendar.</item>
<item>1054 – Three Roman legates break relations between Western and Eastern Christian Churches through the act of placing an invalidly–issued Papal bull of Excommunication on the altar of Hagia Sophia during Saturday afternoon divine liturgy. Historians frequently describe the event as the start of the East–West Schism.</item>
<item>1232 – The Spanish town of Arjona declares independence and names its native Muhammad ibn Yusuf as ruler. This marks the Muhammad\'s first rise to prominence; he would later establish the Nasrid Emirate of Granada, the last independent Muslim state in Spain.</item>
<item>1377 – Richard II of England is crowned.</item>
<item>1661 – The first banknotes in Europe are issued by the Swedish bank Stockholms Banco.</item>
<item>1790 – The District of Columbia is established as the capital of the United States after signature of the Residence Act.</item>
<item>1849 – Antonio María Claret y Clará founds the Congregation of the Missionary Sons of the Immaculate Heart of Mary, popularly known as the Claretians in Vic, in the province of Barcelona, Catalonia, Spain.</item>
<item>1910 – John Robertson Duigan makes the first flight of the Duigan pusher biplane, the first aircraft built in Australia.</item>
<item>1915 – First Order of the Arrow ceremony takes place and the Order of the Arrow is founded to honor American Boy Scouts who best exemplify the Scout Oath and Law.</item>
<item>1931 – Emperor Haile Selassie signs the first constitution of Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1935 – The world\'s first parking meter is installed in Oklahoma City, Oklahoma.</item>
<item>1941 – Joe DiMaggio hits safely for the 56th consecutive game, a streak that still stands as an MLB record.</item>
<item>1942 – Holocaust: Vel\' d\'Hiv Roundup (Rafle du Vel\' d\'Hiv): The government of Vichy France orders the mass arrest of 13,152 Jews who are held at the Winter Velodrome in Paris before deportation to Auschwitz.</item>
<item>1945 – Manhattan Project: The Atomic Age begins when the United States successfully detonates a plutonium–based test nuclear weapon near Alamogordo, New Mexico.</item>
<item>1948 – The storming of the cockpit of the Miss Macao passenger seaplane, operated by a subsidiary of the Cathay Pacific Airways, marks the first aircraft hijacking of a commercial plane.</item>
<item>1950 – Chaplain–Medic massacre: American POWs are massacred by North Korean Army.</item>
<item>1951 – King Leopold III of Belgium abdicates in favor of his son, Baudouin I of Belgium.</item>
<item>1956 – Ringling Bros. and Barnum &amp; Bailey Circus closes its last \"Big Tent\" show in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; due to changing economics all subsequent circus shows will be held in arenas.</item>
<item>1965 – The Mont Blanc Tunnel linking France and Italy opens.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: Apollo 11, the first mission to land astronauts on the Moon, is launched from the Kennedy Space Center at Cape Kennedy, Florida.</item>
<item>1979 – Iraqi President Ahmed Hassan al–Bakr resigns and is replaced by Saddam Hussein.</item>
<item>1990 – The Parliament of the Ukrainian SSR declares state sovereignty over the territory of the Ukrainian SSR.</item>
<item>2004 – Millennium Park, considered Chicago\'s first and most ambitious early 21st–century architectural project, is opened to the public by Mayor Richard M. Daley.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>