<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_14">
<item>1769 – An expedition led by Gaspar de Portolá establishes a base in California and sets out to find the Port of Monterey (now Monterey, California).</item>
<item>1771 – Foundation of the Mission San Antonio de Padua in modern California by the Franciscan friar Junípero Serra.</item>
<item>1789 – Alexander Mackenzie finally completes his journey to the mouth of the great river he hoped would take him to the Pacific, but which turns out to flow into the Arctic Ocean. Later named after him, the Mackenzie is the second–longest river system in North America.</item>
<item>1798 – The Sedition Act becomes law in the United States making it a federal crime to write, publish, or utter false or malicious statements about the United States government.</item>
<item>1853 – Opening of the first major US world\'s fair, the Exhibition of the Industry of All Nations in New York City.</item>
<item>1877 – The Great Railroad Strike of 1877 begins in Martinsburg, West Virginia when Baltimore and Ohio Railroad workers have their wages cut for the second time in a year.</item>
<item>1900 – Armies of the Eight–Nation Alliance capture Tientsin during the Boxer Rebellion.</item>
<item>1902 – The Campanile in St Mark\'s Square, Venice collapses, also demolishing the loggetta.</item>
<item>1943 – In Diamond, Missouri, the George Washington Carver National Monument becomes the first United States National Monument in honor of an African American.</item>
<item>1957 – Rawya Ateya takes her seat in the National Assembly of Egypt, thereby becoming the first female parliamentarian in the Arab world.</item>
<item>1960 – Jane Goodall arrives at the Gombe Stream Reserve in present–day Tanzania to begin her famous study of chimpanzees in the wild.</item>
<item>1965 – The Mariner 4 flyby of Mars takes the first close–up photos of another planet.</item>
<item>1969 – The Federal Reserve Banks begins removing large denominations of United States currency from circulation.</item>
<item>1976 – Capital punishment is abolished in Canada.</item>
<item>2002 – French President Jacques Chirac escapes an assassination attempt unscathed during Bastille Day celebrations.</item>
<item>2013 – The dedication of the Rachel Carson in Woods Hole, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>2015 – NASA\'s New Horizons probe performs the first flyby of Pluto, and thus completes the initial survey of the Solar System.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>