<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_10">
<item>988 – The Norse King Glúniairn recognises Máel Sechnaill mac Domnaill, High King of Ireland, and agrees to pay taxes and accept Brehon Law; the event is considered to be the founding of the city of Dublin.</item>
<item>1499 – The Portuguese explorer Nicolau Coelho returns to Lisbon after discovering the sea route to India as a companion of Vasco da Gama.</item>
<item>1512 – The Spanish conquest of Iberian Navarre commences with the capture of Goizueta.</item>
<item>1519 – Zhu Chenhao declares the Ming dynasty\'s Zhengde Emperor a usurper, beginning the Prince of Ning rebellion, and leads his army north in an attempt to capture Nanjing.</item>
<item>1553 – Lady Jane Grey takes the throne of England.</item>
<item>1584 – William I of Orange is assassinated in his home in Delft, Holland, by Balthasar Gérard.</item>
<item>1789 – Alexander Mackenzie reaches the Mackenzie River delta.</item>
<item>1806 – The Vellore Mutiny is the first instance of a mutiny by Indian sepoys against the British East India Company.</item>
<item>1832 – U.S. President Andrew Jackson vetoes a bill that would re–charter the Second Bank of the United States.</item>
<item>1877 – The then–villa of Mayagüez, Puerto Rico, formally receives its city charter from the Royal Crown of Spain.</item>
<item>1890 – Wyoming is admitted as the 44th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1925 – Meher Baba begins his silence of 44 years. His followers observe Silence Day on this date in commemoration.</item>
<item>1925 – Scopes Trial: In Dayton, Tennessee, the so–called \"Monkey Trial\" begins of John T. Scopes, a young high school science teacher accused of teaching evolution in violation of the Butler Act.</item>
<item>1927 – Kevin O\'Higgins TD, Vice–President of the Executive Council of the Irish Free State is assassinated by the IRA.</item>
<item>1941 – Jedwabne pogrom: Massacre of Polish Jews living in and near the village of Jedwabne.</item>
<item>1942 – Diplomatic relations between the Netherlands and the Soviet Union are established.</item>
<item>1947 – Muhammad Ali Jinnah is recommended as the first Governor–General of Pakistan by the British Prime Minister, Clement Attlee.</item>
<item>1962 – Telstar, the world\'s first communications satellite, is launched into orbit.</item>
<item>1973 – The Bahamas gain full independence within the Commonwealth of Nations.</item>
<item>1973 – National Assembly of Pakistan passes a resolution on the recognition of Bangladesh.</item>
<item>1978 – ABC World News Tonight premieres on ABC.</item>
<item>1978 – President Moktar Ould Daddah of Mauritania is ousted in a bloodless coup d\'état.</item>
<item>1991 – The South African cricket team is readmitted into the International Cricket Council following the end of Apartheid.</item>
<item>1991 – Boris Yeltsin takes office as the first elected President of Russia.</item>
<item>1992 – In Miami, former Panamanian leader Manuel Noriega is sentenced to 40 years in prison for drug and racketeering violations.</item>
<item>1997 – In London, scientists report the findings of the DNA analysis of a Neanderthal skeleton which supports the \"out of Africa theory\" of human evolution, placing an \"African Eve\" at 100,000 to 200,000 years ago.</item>
<item>1998 – Catholic Church sexual abuse cases: The Diocese of Dallas agrees to pay $23.4 million to nine former altar boys who claimed they were sexually abused by Rudolph Kos, a former priest.</item>
<item>2000 – EADS, the world\'s second–largest aerospace group is formed by the merger of Aérospatiale–Matra, DASA, and CASA.</item>
<item>2002 – At a Sotheby\'s auction, Peter Paul Rubens\'s painting The Massacre of the Innocents is sold for £49.5 million (US$76.2 million) to Lord Thomson.</item>
<item>2007 – Erden Eruç begins the first solo human–powered circumnavigation of the world.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>