<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_1">
<item>1569 – Union of Lublin: The Kingdom of Poland and the Grand Duchy of Lithuania confirm a real union; the united country is called the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth or the Republic of Both Nations.</item>
<item>1643 – First meeting of the Westminster Assembly, a council of theologians (\"divines\") and members of the Parliament of England appointed to restructure the Church of England, at Westminster Abbey in London.</item>
<item>1770 – Lexell\'s Comet is seen closer to the Earth than any other comet in recorded history, approaching to a distance of 0.0146 a.u.</item>
<item>1819 – Johann Georg Tralles discovers the Great Comet of 1819, (C/1819 N1). It was the first comet analyzed using polarimetry, by François Arago.</item>
<item>1855 – Signing of the Quinault Treaty: The Quinault and the Quileute cede their land to the United States.</item>
<item>1858 – Joint reading of Charles Darwin and Alfred Russel Wallace\'s papers on evolution to the Linnean Society of London.</item>
<item>1862 – The Russian State Library is founded as the Library of the Moscow Public Museum.</item>
<item>1862 – Princess Alice of the United Kingdom, second daughter of Queen Victoria, marries Prince Louis of Hesse, the future Louis IV, Grand Duke of Hesse.</item>
<item>1863 – Keti Koti (Emancipation Day) in Suriname, marking the abolition of slavery by the Netherlands.</item>
<item>1867 – The British North America Act of 1867 takes effect as the Province of Canada, New Brunswick, and Nova Scotia join into confederation to create the modern nation of Canada. Sir John A. Macdonald is sworn in as the first Prime Minister of Canada. This date is commemorated annually in Canada as Canada Day, a national holiday.</item>
<item>1870 – The United States Department of Justice formally comes into existence.</item>
<item>1874 – The Sholes and Glidden typewriter, the first commercially successful typewriter, goes on sale.</item>
<item>1878 – Canada joins the Universal Postal Union.</item>
<item>1879 – Charles Taze Russell publishes the first edition of the religious magazine The Watchtower.</item>
<item>1881 – The world\'s first international telephone call is made between St. Stephen, New Brunswick, Canada, and Calais, Maine, United States.</item>
<item>1881 – General Order 70, the culmination of the Cardwell and Childers reforms of the British Army, comes into effect.</item>
<item>1885 – The United States terminates reciprocity and fishery agreement with Canada.</item>
<item>1885 – The Congo Free State is established by King Léopold II of Belgium.</item>
<item>1890 – Canada and Bermuda are linked by telegraph cable.</item>
<item>1903 – Start of first Tour de France bicycle race.</item>
<item>1908 – SOS is adopted as the international distress signal.</item>
<item>1911 – Germany despatches the gunship SMS Panther to Morocco, sparking the Agadir Crisis.</item>
<item>1915 – Leutnant Kurt Wintgens of the then–named German Deutsches Heer\'s Fliegertruppe army air service achieves the first known aerial victory with a synchronized machine–gun armed fighter plane, the Fokker M.5K/MG Eindecker.</item>
<item>1922 – The Great Railroad Strike of 1922 begins in the United States.</item>
<item>1923 – The Canadian Parliament suspends all Chinese immigration.</item>
<item>1931 – United Airlines begins service (as Boeing Air Transport).</item>
<item>1931 – Wiley Post and Harold Gatty become the first people to circumnavigate the globe in a single–engined monoplane aircraft.</item>
<item>1932 – Australia\'s national broadcaster, the Australian Broadcasting Corporation, was formed.</item>
<item>1942 – The Australian Federal Government becomes the sole collector of income tax in Australia as State Income Tax is abolished.</item>
<item>1943 – Tokyo City merges with Tokyo Prefecture and is dissolved. Since this date, no city in Japan has the name \"Tokyo\" (present–day Tokyo is not officially a city).</item>
<item>1947 – The Philippine Air Force is established.</item>
<item>1948 – Muhammad Ali Jinnah (Quaid–i–Azam) inaugurates Pakistan\'s central bank, the State Bank of Pakistan.</item>
<item>1949 – The merger of two princely states of India, Cochin and Travancore, into the state of Thiru–Kochi (later re–organized as Kerala) in the Indian Union ends more than 1,000 years of princely rule by the Cochin royal family.</item>
<item>1957 – The International Geophysical Year begins.</item>
<item>1958 – The Canadian Broadcasting Corporation links television broadcasting across Canada via microwave.</item>
<item>1958 – Flooding of Canada\'s Saint Lawrence Seaway begins.</item>
<item>1959 – Specific values for the international yard, avoirdupois pound and derived units (e.g. inch, mile and ounce) are adopted after agreement between the U.S.A., the United Kingdom and other Commonwealth countries.</item>
<item>1960 – Independence of Somalia.</item>
<item>1960 – Ghana becomes a republic and Kwame Nkrumah becomes its first President as Queen Elizabeth II ceases to be its head of state.</item>
<item>1962 – Independence of Rwanda and Burundi.</item>
<item>1963 – ZIP codes are introduced for United States mail.</item>
<item>1963 – The British Government admits that former diplomat Kim Philby had worked as a Soviet agent.</item>
<item>1966 – The first color television transmission in Canada takes place from Toronto.</item>
<item>1967 – Merger Treaty: The European Community is formally created out of a merger with the Common Market, the European Coal and Steel Community, and the European Atomic Energy Commission.</item>
<item>1968 – The United States Central Intelligence Agency\'s Phoenix Program is officially established.</item>
<item>1968 – The Treaty on the Non–Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons is signed in Washington, D.C., London and Moscow by sixty–two countries.</item>
<item>1968 – Formal separation of the United Auto Workers from the AFL–CIO in the United States.</item>
<item>1972 – The first Gay pride march in England takes place.</item>
<item>1976 – Portugal grants autonomy to Madeira.</item>
<item>1978 – The Northern Territory in Australia is granted self–government.</item>
<item>1979 – Sony introduces the Walkman.</item>
<item>1980 – \"O Canada\" officially becomes the national anthem of Canada.</item>
<item>1984 – The PG–13 rating is introduced by the MPAA.</item>
<item>1987 – The American radio station WFAN in New York City is launched as the world\'s first all–sports radio station.</item>
<item>1990 – German reunification: East Germany accepts the Deutsche Mark as its currency, thus uniting the economies of East and West Germany.</item>
<item>1997 – China resumes sovereignty over the city–state of Hong Kong, ending 156 years of British colonial rule. The handover ceremony is attended by British Prime Minister Tony Blair, Prince Charles of Wales, Chinese President Jiang Zemin, and U.S. Secretary of State Madeleine Albright.</item>
<item>1999 – The Scottish Parliament is officially opened by Elizabeth II on the day that legislative powers are officially transferred from the old Scottish Office in London to the new devolved Scottish Executive in Edinburgh.</item>
<item>2003 – Over 500,000 people protest against efforts to pass anti–sedition legislation in Hong Kong.</item>
<item>2004 – Saturn orbit insertion of Cassini–Huygens begins at 01:12 UTC and ends at 02:48 UTC.</item>
<item>2006 – The first operation of Qinghai–Tibet Railway in China.</item>
<item>2007 – Smoking in England is banned in all public indoor spaces.</item>
<item>2008 – Rioting erupts in Mongolia in response to allegations of fraud surrounding the 2008 legislative elections.</item>
<item>2013 – Croatia becomes the 28th member of the European Union.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>