<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_21">
<item>230 – Pope Pontian succeeds Urban I as the eighteenth pope.</item>
<item>285 – Diocletian appoints Maximian as Caesar and co–ruler.</item>
<item>905 – King Berengar I of Italy and a hired Hungarian army defeats the Frankish forces at Verona. King Louis III is captured and blinded for breaking his oath (see 902).</item>
<item>1545 – The first landing of French troops on the coast of the Isle of Wight during the French invasion of the Isle of Wight.</item>
<item>1718 – The Treaty of Passarowitz between the Ottoman Empire, Austria and the Republic of Venice is signed.</item>
<item>1831 – Inauguration of Leopold I of Belgium, first king of the Belgians.</item>
<item>1873 – At Adair, Iowa, Jesse James and the James–Younger Gang pull off the first successful train robbery in the American Old West.</item>
<item>1904 – Louis Rigolly, a Frenchman, becomes the first man to break the 100 mph (161 km/h) barrier on land. He drove a 15–liter Gobron–Brillié in Ostend, Belgium.</item>
<item>1925 – Scopes Trial: In Dayton, Tennessee, high school biology teacher John T. Scopes is found guilty of teaching evolution in class and fined $100.</item>
<item>1925 – Malcolm Campbell becomes the first man to exceed 150 mph (241 km/h) on land. At Pendine Sands in Wales, he drives Sunbeam 350HP built by Sunbeam at a two–way average speed of 150.33 mph (242 km/h).</item>
<item>1949 – The United States Senate ratifies the North Atlantic Treaty.</item>
<item>1959 – NS Savannah, the first nuclear–powered cargo–passenger ship, is launched as a showcase for Dwight D. Eisenhower\'s \"Atoms for Peace\" initiative.</item>
<item>1959 – Elijah Jerry \"Pumpsie\" Green becomes the first African–American to play for the Boston Red Sox, the last team to integrate. He came in as a pinch runner for Vic Wertz and stayed in as shortstop in a 2–1 loss to the Chicago White Sox.</item>
<item>1960 – Sirimavo Bandaranaike is elected Prime Minister of Sri Lanka, becoming the world\'s first female head of government</item>
<item>1961 – Mercury program: Mercury–Redstone 4 Mission: Gus Grissom piloting Liberty Bell 7 becomes the second American to go into space (in a suborbital mission).</item>
<item>1969 – At 02:56 UTC, astronaut Neil Armstrong becomes the first person to walk on the Moon.</item>
<item>1970 – After 11 years of construction, the Aswan High Dam in Egypt is completed.</item>
<item>1979 – Jay Silverheels, a Mohawk actor, becomes the first Native American to have a star commemorated in the Hollywood Walk of Fame.</item>
<item>1983 – The world\'s lowest temperature in an inhabited location is recorded at Vostok Station, Antarctica at −89.2 °C (−128.6 °F).</item>
<item>1995 – Third Taiwan Strait Crisis: The People\'s Liberation Army begins firing missiles into the waters north of Taiwan.</item>
<item>2008 – Ram Baran Yadav is declared the first president of Nepal.</item>
<item>2011 – NASA\'s Space Shuttle program ends with the landing of Space Shuttle Atlantis on mission STS–135 at NASA\'s Kennedy Space Center.</item>
<item>2012 – Erden Eruç completes the first solo human–powered circumnavigation of the world.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>