<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_23">
<item>811 – Byzantine emperor Nikephoros I plunders the Bulgarian capital of Pliska and captures Khan Krum\'s treasury.</item>
<item>1793 – Kingdom of Prussia re–conquers Mainz from France.</item>
<item>1813 – Sir Thomas Maitland is appointed as the first Governor of Malta, transforming the island from a British protectorate to a de facto colony.</item>
<item>1821 – While the Mora Rebellion continues, Greeks capture Monemvasia Castle. Turkish troops and citizens are transferred to Asia Minor\'s coasts.</item>
<item>1829 – In the United States, William Austin Burt patents the typographer, a precursor to the typewriter.</item>
<item>1840 – The Province of Canada is created by the Act of Union.</item>
<item>1874 – Aires de Ornelas e Vasconcelos is appointed the Archbishop of the Portuguese colonial enclave of Goa, India.</item>
<item>1881 – The Boundary Treaty of 1881 between Chile and Argentina is signed in Buenos Aires.</item>
<item>1903 – The Ford Motor Company sells its first car.</item>
<item>1908 – The Second Constitution accepted by the Ottomans.</item>
<item>1921 – The Communist Party of China (CPC) is established at the founding National Congress.</item>
<item>1926 – Fox Film buys the patents of the Movietone sound system for recording sound onto film.</item>
<item>1929 – The Fascist government in Italy bans the use of foreign words.</item>
<item>1936 – In Catalonia, Spain, the Unified Socialist Party of Catalonia is founded through the merger of Socialist and Communist parties.</item>
<item>1940 – The United States\' Under Secretary of State Sumner Welles issues a declaration on the U.S. non–recognition policy of the Soviet annexation and incorporation of three Baltic states: Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania.</item>
<item>1942 – The Holocaust: The Treblinka extermination camp is opened.</item>
<item>1952 – General Muhammad Naguib leads the Free Officers Movement (formed by Gamal Abdel Nasser, the real power behind the coup) in overthrowing King Farouk of Egypt.</item>
<item>1961 – The Sandinista National Liberation Front is founded in Nicaragua.</item>
<item>1962 – Telstar relays the first publicly transmitted, live trans–Atlantic television program, featuring Walter Cronkite.</item>
<item>1962 – The International Agreement on the Neutrality of Laos is signed.</item>
<item>1968 – Glenville shootout: In Cleveland, Ohio, a violent shootout between a Black Militant organization and the Cleveland Police Department occurs. During the shootout, a riot begins and lasts for five days.</item>
<item>1968 – The only successful hijacking of an El Al aircraft takes place when a Boeing 707 carrying ten crew and 38 passengers is taken over by three members of the Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine. The aircraft was en route from Rome, to Lod, Israel.</item>
<item>1972 – The United States launches Landsat 1, the first Earth–resources satellite.</item>
<item>1974 – The Greek military junta collapses, and former Prime Minister Konstantinos Karamanlis is invited to lead the new government, beginning Greece\'s metapolitefsi era.</item>
<item>1980 – Phạm Tuân becomes the first Vietnamese citizen and the first Asian in space when he flies aboard the Soyuz 37 mission as an Intercosmos Research Cosmonaut.</item>
<item>1988 – General Ne Win, effective ruler of Burma since 1962, resigns after pro–democracy protests.</item>
<item>1992 – A Vatican commission, led by Joseph Ratzinger, establishes that limiting certain rights of homosexual people and non–married couples is not equivalent to discrimination on grounds of race or gender.</item>
<item>1992 – Abkhazia declares independence from Georgia.</item>
<item>1995 – Comet Hale–Bopp is discovered; it becomes visible to the naked eye on Earth nearly a year later.</item>
<item>1997 – Digital Equipment Corporation files antitrust charges against chipmaker Intel.</item>
<item>1999 – ANA Flight 61 is hijacked in Tokyo, Japan by Yuji Nishizawa.</item>
<item>2015 – NASA announces discovery of Kepler–452b by Kepler.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>