<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_25">
<item>306 – Constantine I is proclaimed Roman emperor by his troops.</item>
<item>315 – The Arch of Constantine is completed near the Colosseum in Rome to commemorate Constantine I\'s victory over Maxentius at the Milvian Bridge.</item>
<item>677 – Climax of the Siege of Thessalonica by the Slavs in a three–day assault on the city walls.</item>
<item>864 – The Edict of Pistres of Charles the Bald orders defensive measures against the Vikings.</item>
<item>1137 – Eleanor of Aquitaine married Prince Louis, later King Louis VII of France, at the Cathedral of Saint–André in Bordeaux.</item>
<item>1261 – The city of Constantinople is recaptured by Nicaean forces under the command of Alexios Strategopoulos, re–establishing the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1536 – Sebastián de Belalcázar on his search of El Dorado founds the city of Santiago de Cali.</item>
<item>1538 – The city of Guayaquil is founded by the Spanish Conquistador Francisco de Orellana and given the name Muy Noble y Muy Leal Ciudad de Santiago de Guayaquil.</item>
<item>1547 – Henry II of France is crowned.</item>
<item>1554 – Mary I marries Philip II of Spain at Winchester Cathedral.</item>
<item>1593 – Henry IV of France publicly converts from Protestantism to Roman Catholicism.</item>
<item>1603 – James VI of Scotland is crowned king of England (James I of England), bringing the Kingdom of England and Kingdom of Scotland into personal union. Political union would occur in 1707.</item>
<item>1609 – The English ship Sea Venture, en route to Virginia, is deliberately driven ashore during a storm at Bermuda to prevent its sinking; the survivors go on to found a new colony there.</item>
<item>1693 – Ignacio de Maya founds the Real Santiago de las Sabinas, now known as Sabinas Hidalgo, Nuevo León, Mexico.</item>
<item>1755 – British governor Charles Lawrence and the Nova Scotia Council order the deportation of the Acadians.</item>
<item>1788 – Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart completes his Symphony No. 40 in G minor (K550).</item>
<item>1792 – The Brunswick Manifesto is issued to the population of Paris promising vengeance if the French royal family is harmed.</item>
<item>1797 – Horatio Nelson loses more than 300 men and his right arm during the failed conquest attempt of Tenerife (Spain).</item>
<item>1799 – At Abu Qir in Egypt, Napoleon I of France defeats 10,000 Ottomans under Mustafa Pasha.</item>
<item>1824 – Costa Rica annexes Guanacaste from Nicaragua.</item>
<item>1837 – The first commercial use of an electrical telegraph is successfully demonstrated in London by William Cooke and Charles Wheatstone.</item>
<item>1866 – The United States Congress passes legislation authorizing the rank of General of the Army. Lieutenant General Ulysses S. Grant becomes the first to be promoted to this rank.</item>
<item>1868 – The Wyoming Territory is established.</item>
<item>1869 – The Japanese daimyōs begin returning their land holdings to the emperor as part of the Meiji Restoration reforms. (Traditional Japanese Date: June 17, 1869).</item>
<item>1898 – In the Puerto Rican Campaign, the United States seizes Puerto Rico from Spain.</item>
<item>1909 – Louis Blériot makes the first flight across the English Channel in a heavier–than–air machine from (Calais to Dover, England, United Kingdom) in 37 minutes.</item>
<item>1915 – RFC Captain Lanoe Hawker becomes the first British pursuit aviator to earn the Victoria Cross.</item>
<item>1917 – Sir Robert Borden introduces the first income tax in Canada as a \"temporary\" measure (lowest bracket is 4% and highest is 25%).</item>
<item>1925 – Telegraph Agency of the Soviet Union (TASS) is established.</item>
<item>1940 – General Henri Guisan orders the Swiss Army to resist German invasion and makes surrender illegal.</item>
<item>1942 – The Norwegian Manifesto calls for nonviolent resistance to the German occupation.</item>
<item>1957 – The Republic of Tunisia is proclaimed, under President Habib Bourguiba.</item>
<item>1958 – The African Regroupment Party (PRA) holds its first congress in Cotonou.</item>
<item>1965 – Bob Dylan goes electric at the Newport Folk Festival, signaling a major change in folk and rock music.</item>
<item>1973 – Soviet Mars 5 space probe is launched.</item>
<item>1976 – Viking program: Viking 1 takes the famous Face on Mars photo.</item>
<item>1978 – Birth of Louise Joy Brown, the first human to have been born after conception by in vitro fertilisation, or IVF.</item>
<item>1979 – Another section of the Sinai Peninsula is peacefully returned by Israel to Egypt.</item>
<item>1983 – Black July: Thirty–seven Tamil political prisoners at the Welikada high security prison in Colombo are massacred by the fellow Sinhalese prisoners.</item>
<item>1984 – Salyut 7 cosmonaut Svetlana Savitskaya becomes the first woman to perform a space walk.</item>
<item>1993 – The Saint James Church massacre occurs in Kenilworth, Cape Town, South Africa.</item>
<item>1996 – In a military coup in Burundi, Pierre Buyoya deposes Sylvestre Ntibantunganya.</item>
<item>2007 – Pratibha Patil is sworn in as India\'s first female president.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>