<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_24">
<item>1148 – Louis VII of France lays siege to Damascus during the Second Crusade.</item>
<item>1534 – French explorer Jacques Cartier plants a cross on the Gaspé Peninsula and takes possession of the territory in the name of Francis I of France.</item>
<item>1567 – Mary, Queen of Scots, is forced to abdicate and replaced by her 1–year–old son James VI.</item>
<item>1701 – Antoine de la Mothe Cadillac founds the trading post at Fort Pontchartrain, which later becomes the city of Detroit.</item>
<item>1783 – The Kingdom of Georgia and the Russian Empire sign the Treaty of Georgievsk.</item>
<item>1823 – Afro–Chileans are emancipated.</item>
<item>1847 – After 17 months of travel, Brigham Young leads 148 Mormon pioneers into Salt Lake Valley, resulting in the establishment of Salt Lake City.</item>
<item>1847 – Richard March Hoe, American inventor, patented the rotary–type printing press.</item>
<item>1901 – O. Henry is released from prison in Columbus, Ohio, after serving three years for embezzlement from a bank.</item>
<item>1910 – The Ottoman Empire captures the city of Shkodër, putting down the Albanian Revolt of 1910.</item>
<item>1922 – The draft of the British Mandate of Palestine was formally confirmed by the Council of the League of Nations; it came into effect on 26 September 1923.</item>
<item>1924 – Themistoklis Sofoulis becomes Prime Minister of Greece.</item>
<item>1935 – The Dust Bowl heat wave reaches its peak, sending temperatures to 109 °F (43 °C) in Chicago and 104 °F (40 °C) in Milwaukee.</item>
<item>1937 – Alabama drops rape charges against the \"Scottsboro Boys\".</item>
<item>1950 – Cape Canaveral Air Force Station begins operations with the launch of a Bumper rocket.</item>
<item>1959 – At the opening of the American National Exhibition in Moscow, U.S. Vice President Richard Nixon and Soviet Premier Nikita Khrushchev have a \"Kitchen Debate\".</item>
<item>1963 – The ship Bluenose II was launched in Lunenburg, Nova Scotia. The schooner is a major Canadian symbol.</item>
<item>1966 – Michael Pelkey makes the first BASE jump from El Capitan along with Brian Schubert. Both came out with broken bones. BASE jumping has now been banned from El Cap.</item>
<item>1967 – During an official state visit to Canada, French President Charles de Gaulle declares to a crowd of over 100,000 in Montreal: Vive le Québec libre! (\"Long live free Quebec!\"); the statement angered the Canadian government and many Anglophone Canadians.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: Apollo 11 splashes down safely in the Pacific Ocean.</item>
<item>1974 – Watergate scandal: The United States Supreme Court unanimously ruled that President Richard Nixon did not have the authority to withhold subpoenaed White House tapes and they order him to surrender the tapes to the Watergate special prosecutor.</item>
<item>1980 – The Quietly Confident Quartet of Australia wins the men\'s 4 x 100 metre medley relay at the Moscow Olympics, the only time the United States has not won the event at Olympic level.</item>
<item>1983 – George Brett batting for the Kansas City Royals against the New York Yankees, has a game–winning home run nullified in the \"Pine Tar Incident\".</item>
<item>1987 – US supertanker SS Bridgeton collides with mines laid by IRGC causing a 43–square–meter dent in the body of the oil tanker.</item>
<item>1987 – Hulda Crooks, at 91 years of age, climbed Mt. Fuji. Crooks became the oldest person to climb Japan’s highest peak.</item>
<item>2001 – Simeon Saxe–Coburg–Gotha, the last Tsar of Bulgaria when he was a child, is sworn in as Prime Minister of Bulgaria, becoming the first monarch in history to regain political power through democratic election to a different office.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>