<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_20">
<item>911 – Rollo lays siege to Chartres.</item>
<item>1189 – Richard I of England officially invested as Duke of Normandy.</item>
<item>1225 – Treaty of San Germano is signed at San Germano between Holy Roman Emperor Frederick II and Pope Gregory IX. A Dominican named Guala is responsible for the negotiations.</item>
<item>1592 – During the first Japanese invasion of Korea, Japanese forces led by Toyotomi Hideyoshi captured Pyongyang, although they were ultimately unable to hold it.</item>
<item>1738 – Canadian explorer Pierre Gaultier de Varennes et de La Vérendrye reaches the western shore of Lake Michigan.</item>
<item>1799 – Tekle Giyorgis I begins his first of six reigns as Emperor of Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1810 – Citizens of Bogotá, New Granada declare independence from Spain.</item>
<item>1831 – Seneca and Shawnee people agree to relinquish their land in western Ohio for 60,000 acres west of the Mississippi River.</item>
<item>1848 – The first Women\'s Rights Convention in Seneca Falls, New York, a two–day event, concludes.</item>
<item>1871 – British Columbia joins the confederation of Canada.</item>
<item>1885 – The Football Association legalizes professionalism in association football under pressure from the British Football Association.</item>
<item>1903 – The Ford Motor Company ships its first automobile.</item>
<item>1932 – In the Preußenschlag (\"Prussian coup\"), German President Paul von Hindenburg dissolves the government of Prussia</item>
<item>1936 – The Montreux Convention is signed in Switzerland, authorizing Turkey to fortify the Dardanelles and Bosphorus but guaranteeing free passage to ships of all nations in peacetime.</item>
<item>1938 – The United States Department of Justice files suit in New York City against the motion picture industry charging violations of the Sherman Antitrust Act in regards to the studio system. The case would eventually result in a break–up of the industry in 1948.</item>
<item>1940 – Denmark leaves the League of Nations.</item>
<item>1940 – California opens its first freeway, the Arroyo Seco Parkway.</item>
<item>1954 – Germany: Otto John, head of West Germany\'s secret service, defects to East Germany.</item>
<item>1960 – Ceylon (now Sri Lanka) elects Sirimavo Bandaranaike Prime Minister, the world\'s first elected female head of government.</item>
<item>1960 – The Polaris missile is successfully launched from a submarine, the USS George Washington, for the first time.</item>
<item>1961 – French military forces break the Tunisian siege of Bizerte.</item>
<item>1969 – Apollo program: Apollo 11\'s crew successfully makes the first manned landing on the Moon in the Sea of Tranquility. Americans Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin become the first humans to walk on the Moon six and a half hours later.</item>
<item>1974 – Turkish invasion of Cyprus: Forces from Turkey invade Cyprus after a coup d\'état, organised by the dictator of Greece, against president Makarios.</item>
<item>1976 – The American Viking 1 lander successfully lands on Mars.</item>
<item>1977 – The Central Intelligence Agency releases documents under the Freedom of Information Act revealing it had engaged in mind–control experiments.</item>
<item>1985 – The government of Aruba passes legislation to secede from the Netherlands Antilles.</item>
<item>1989 – Burma\'s ruling junta puts opposition leader Daw Aung San Suu Kyi under house arrest.</item>
<item>1992 – Václav Havel resigns as president of Czechoslovakia.</item>
<item>1997 – The fully restored USS Constitution (a.k.a. Old Ironsides) celebrates its 200th birthday by setting sail for the first time in 116 years.</item>
<item>1999 – The Chinese Communist Party begins a persecution campaign against Falun Gong, arresting thousands nationwide.</item>
<item>2005 – The Civil Marriage Act legalizes same–sex marriage in Canada.</item>
<item>2015 – The United States and Cuba resume full diplomatic relations after five decades.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>