<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_28">
<item>1571 – La Laguna encomienda, known today as the Laguna province in the Philippines is founded by the Spaniards as one of the oldest encomiendas (provinces) in the country.</item>
<item>1778 – Constitution of the province of Cantabria ratified at the Assembly Hall in Bárcena la Puente, Reocín, Spain.</item>
<item>1808 – Mahmud II became Sultan of the Ottoman Empire and Caliph of Islam.</item>
<item>1821 – José de San Martín declares the independence of Peru from Spain.</item>
<item>1866 – At the age of 18, Vinnie Ream becomes the first and youngest female artist to receive a commission from the United States government for a statue (of Abraham Lincoln).</item>
<item>1868 – The 14th Amendment to the United States Constitution is certified, establishing African American citizenship and guaranteeing due process of law.</item>
<item>1896 – The city of Miami, Florida is incorporated.</item>
<item>1915 – The United States begins a 19–year occupation of Haiti.</item>
<item>1935 – First flight of the Boeing B–17 Flying Fortress.</item>
<item>1938 – Hawaii Clipper disappears between Guam and Manila as the first loss of an airliner in trans–Pacific China Clipper service.</item>
<item>1939 – The Sutton Hoo helmet is discovered.</item>
<item>1960 – The German Volkswagen Act came into force.</item>
<item>1973 – Summer Jam at Watkins Glen: Nearly 600,000 people attend a rock festival at the Watkins Glen International Raceway.</item>
<item>1974 – Spetsgruppa A, Russia\'s elite special force, was formed.</item>
<item>1984 – The 1984 Summer Olympics officially known as the games of the XXIII were opened in Los Angeles.</item>
<item>1996 – The remains of a prehistoric man are discovered near Kennewick, Washington. Such remains will be known as the Kennewick Man.</item>
<item>2001 – Australian Ian Thorpe becomes the first swimmer to win six gold medals at a single World Championship.</item>
<item>2002 – Nine coal miners trapped in the flooded Quecreek Mine in Somerset County, Pennsylvania, are rescued after 77 hours underground.</item>
<item>2005 – The Provisional Irish Republican Army calls an end to its thirty–year–long armed campaign in Northern Ireland.</item>
<item>2017 – Prime Minister of Pakistan, Nawaz Sharif was disqualified for lifetime by Supreme Court of Pakistan founding him guilty of corruption charges</item>
<item>2018 – Australian Wendy Tuck becomes the first woman skipper to win the Clipper Round the World Yacht Race</item>
</string-array>
</resources>