<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_29">
<item>615 – Pakal ascends the throne of Palenque at the age of 12.</item>
<item>1148 – The Siege of Damascus ends in a decisive crusader defeat and leads to the disintegration of the Second Crusade.</item>
<item>1565 – The widowed Mary, Queen of Scots marries Henry Stuart, Lord Darnley, Duke of Albany, at Holyrood Palace, Edinburgh, Scotland.</item>
<item>1567 – James VI is crowned King of Scotland at Stirling.</item>
<item>1775 – Founding of the U.S. Army Judge Advocate General\'s Corps: General George Washington appoints William Tudor as Judge Advocate of the Continental Army.</item>
<item>1818 – French physicist Augustin Fresnel submits his prizewinning \"Memoir on the Diffraction of Light\", precisely accounting for the limited extent to which light spreads into shadows, and thereby demolishing the oldest objection to the wave theory of light.</item>
<item>1836 – Inauguration of the Arc de Triomphe in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1848 – Irish Potato Famine: Tipperary Revolt: In County Tipperary, Ireland, then in the United Kingdom, an unsuccessful nationalist revolt against British rule is put down by police.</item>
<item>1851 – Annibale de Gasparis discovers asteroid 15 Eunomia.</item>
<item>1858 – United States and Japan sign the Harris Treaty.</item>
<item>1899 – The First Hague Convention is signed.</item>
<item>1900 – In Italy, King Umberto I of Italy is assassinated by the anarchist Gaetano Bresci.</item>
<item>1907 – Sir Robert Baden–Powell sets up the Brownsea Island Scout camp in Poole Harbour on the south coast of England. The camp runs from August 1 to August 9, 1907, and is regarded as the foundation of the Scouting movement.</item>
<item>1914 – The Cape Cod Canal opened.</item>
<item>1920 – Construction of the Link River Dam begins as part of the Klamath Reclamation Project.</item>
<item>1945 – The BBC Light Programme radio station is launched for mainstream light entertainment and music.</item>
<item>1957 – The International Atomic Energy Agency is established.</item>
<item>1958 – U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower signs into law the National Aeronautics and Space Act, which creates the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA).</item>
<item>1959 – First United States Congress elections in Hawaii as a state of the Union.</item>
<item>1973 – Greeks vote to abolish the monarchy, beginning the first period of the Metapolitefsi.</item>
<item>1987 – British Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher and President of France François Mitterrand sign the agreement to build a tunnel under the English Channel (Eurotunnel).</item>
<item>1996 – The child protection portion of the Communications Decency Act is struck down by a U.S. federal court as too broad.</item>
<item>2013 – Two passenger trains collide in the Swiss municipality of Granges–près–Marnand near Lausanne injuring 25 people.</item>
<item>2015 – Microsoft releases Windows 10.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>