<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_2">
<item>437 – Emperor Valentinian III begins his reign over the Western Roman Empire. His mother Galla Placidia ends her regency, but continues to exercise political influence at the court in Rome.</item>
<item>963 – The imperial army proclaims Nikephoros II Phokas Emperor of the Romans on the plains outside Cappadocian Caesarea.</item>
<item>1494 – The Treaty of Tordesillas is ratified by Spain.</item>
<item>1504 – Bogdan III the One–Eyed becomes Voivode of Moldavia.</item>
<item>1555 – Ottoman Admiral Turgut Reis sacks the Italian city of Paola.</item>
<item>1561 – Menas, emperor of Ethiopia, defeats a revolt in Emfraz.</item>
<item>1613 – The first English expedition (from Virginia) against Acadia led by Samuel Argall takes place.</item>
<item>1698 – Thomas Savery patents the first steam engine.</item>
<item>1816 – The French frigate Méduse struck the Bank of Arguin and 151 people on board had to be evacuated on an improvised raft, a case immortalised by Géricault\'s painting The Raft of the Medusa.</item>
<item>1822 – Thirty–five slaves are hanged in South Carolina, including Denmark Vesey, after being accused of organizing a slave rebellion.</item>
<item>1823 – Bahia Independence Day: The end of Portuguese rule in Brazil, with the final defeat of the Portuguese crown loyalists in the province of Bahia.</item>
<item>1839 – Twenty miles off the coast of Cuba, 53 rebelling African slaves led by Joseph Cinqué take over the slave ship Amistad.</item>
<item>1871 – Victor Emmanuel II of Italy enters Rome after having conquered it from the Papal States.</item>
<item>1890 – The U.S. Congress passes the Sherman Antitrust Act.</item>
<item>1897 – British–Italian engineer Guglielmo Marconi obtains a patent for radio in London.</item>
<item>1900 – The first Zeppelin flight takes place on Lake Constance near Friedrichshafen, Germany.</item>
<item>1900 – Jean Sibelius\' Finlandia receives its première performance in Helsinki with the Helsinki Philharmonic Society conducted by Robert Kajanus.</item>
<item>1937 – Amelia Earhart and navigator Fred Noonan are last heard from over the Pacific Ocean while attempting to make the first equatorial round–the–world flight.</item>
<item>1940 – Indian independence leader Subhas Chandra Bose is arrested and detained in Calcutta.</item>
<item>1940 – The SS Arandora Star is sunk by U–47 in the North Atlantic with the loss of over 800 lives, mostly civilians.</item>
<item>1962 – The first Wal–Mart store opens for business in Rogers, Arkansas.</item>
<item>1964 – Civil rights movement: U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson signs the Civil Rights Act of 1964 meant to prohibit segregation in public places.</item>
<item>1976 – Fall of the Republic of Vietnam; Communist North Vietnam declares their union to form the Socialist Republic of Vietnam.</item>
<item>1997 – The Bank of Thailand floats the baht, triggering the Asian financial crisis</item>
<item>2000 – Vicente Fox Quesada is elected the first President of México from an opposition party, the Partido Acción Nacional, after more than 70 years of continuous rule by the Partido Revolucionario Institucional.</item>
<item>2001 – The AbioCor self–contained artificial heart is first implanted.</item>
<item>2002 – Steve Fossett becomes the first person to fly solo around the world nonstop in a balloon.</item>
<item>2005 – The Live 8 benefit concerts takes place in the G8 states and in South Africa. More than 1,000 musicians perform and are broadcast on 182 television networks and 2,000 radio networks.</item>
<item>2008 – Colombian conflict: Íngrid Betancourt, a member of the Chamber of Representatives of Colombia, is released from captivity after being held for six and a half years by FARC.</item>
<item>2013 – The International Astronomical Union names Pluto\'s fourth and fifth moons, Kerberos and Styx.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>