<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_27">
<item>1189 – Friedrich Barbarossa arrives at Niš, the capital of Serbian King Stefan Nemanja, during the Third Crusade.</item>
<item>1549 – The Jesuit priest Francis Xavier\'s ship reaches Japan.</item>
<item>1663 – The English Parliament passes the second Navigation Act requiring that all goods bound for the American colonies have to be sent in English ships from English ports. After the Acts of Union 1707, Scotland would be included in the Act.</item>
<item>1694 – A Royal charter is granted to the Bank of England.</item>
<item>1775 – Founding of the U.S. Army Medical Department: The Second Continental Congress passes legislation establishing \"an hospital for an army consisting of 20,000 men.\"</item>
<item>1789 – The first U.S. federal government agency, the Department of Foreign Affairs, is established (it will be later renamed Department of State).</item>
<item>1857 – Siege of Arrah begins: Sixty–eight men hold out for eight days against a force of 2,500 to 3,000 mutinying sepoys and 8,000 irregular forces.</item>
<item>1865 – Welsh settlers arrive at Chubut in Argentina.</item>
<item>1866 – The first permanent transatlantic telegraph cable is successfully completed, stretching from Valentia Island, Ireland, to Heart\'s Content, Newfoundland.</item>
<item>1919 – The Chicago Race Riot erupts after a racial incident occurred on a South Side beach, leading to 38 fatalities and 537 injuries over a five–day period.</item>
<item>1921 – Researchers at the University of Toronto, led by biochemist Frederick Banting, prove that the hormone insulin regulates blood sugar.</item>
<item>1940 – The animated short A Wild Hare is released, introducing the character of Bugs Bunny.</item>
<item>1949 – Initial flight of the de Havilland Comet, the first jet–powered airliner.</item>
<item>1955 – The Austrian State Treaty restores Austrian sovereignty.</item>
<item>1959 – The Continental League is announced as baseball\'s \"3rd major league\" in the United States.</item>
<item>1974 – Watergate scandal: The House of Representatives Judiciary Committee votes 27 to 11 to recommend the first article of impeachment (for obstruction of justice) against President Richard Nixon.</item>
<item>1976 – Former Japanese prime minister Kakuei Tanaka is arrested on suspicion of violating foreign exchange and foreign trade laws in connection with the Lockheed bribery scandals.</item>
<item>1983 – Black July: Eighteen Tamil political prisoners at the Welikada high security prison in Colombo are massacred by Sinhalese prisoners, the second such massacre in two days.</item>
<item>1987 – RMS Titanic Inc. begins the first expedited salvage of wreckage of the RMS Titanic.</item>
<item>1990 – The Supreme Soviet of the Belarusian Soviet Republic declares independence of Belarus from the Soviet Union. Until 1996 the day is celebrated as the Independence Day of Belarus; after a referendum held that year the celebration of independence is moved to June 3.</item>
<item>1990 – The Jamaat al Muslimeen attempt a coup d\'état in Trinidad and Tobago.</item>
<item>2005 – After an incident during STS–114, NASA grounds the Space Shuttle, pending an investigation of the continuing problem with the shedding of foam insulation from the external fuel tank.</item>
<item>2016 – At a news conference in Florida, U.S. Presidential Candidate Donald Trump publicly appealed to Russia to find and release private emails from Democratic opponent Hillary Clinton; a Special Counsel investigation (2017–present) later alleged that Russian operatives began hacking into servers at the Democratic National Committee on that same day, leading to the July 13, 2018 indictment of 12 Russian intelligence officers.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>