<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_26">
<item>1309 – Henry VII is recognized King of the Romans by Pope Clement V.</item>
<item>1509 – The Emperor Krishnadevaraya ascends to the throne, marking the beginning of the regeneration of the Vijayanagara Empire.</item>
<item>1529 – Francisco Pizarro González, Spanish conquistador, is appointed governor of Peru.</item>
<item>1581 – Plakkaat van Verlatinghe (Act of Abjuration): The northern Low Countries declare their independence from the Spanish king, Philip II.</item>
<item>1745 – The first recorded women\'s cricket match takes place near Guildford, England.</item>
<item>1775 – The office that would later become the United States Post Office Department is established by the Second Continental Congress. Benjamin Franklin of Pennsylvania takes office as Postmaster General.</item>
<item>1788 – New York ratifies the United States Constitution and becomes the 11th state of the United States.</item>
<item>1803 – The Surrey Iron Railway, arguably the world\'s first public railway, opens in south London, United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1822 – José de San Martín arrives in Guayaquil, Ecuador, to meet with Simón Bolívar.</item>
<item>1847 – Liberia declares its independence.</item>
<item>1882 – Premiere of Richard Wagner\'s opera Parsifal at Bayreuth.</item>
<item>1882 – The Republic of Stellaland is founded in Southern Africa.</item>
<item>1887 – Publication of the Unua Libro, founding the Esperanto movement.</item>
<item>1890 – In Buenos Aires, Argentina the Revolución del Parque takes place, forcing President Miguel Ángel Juárez Celman\'s resignation.</item>
<item>1891 – France annexes Tahiti.</item>
<item>1892 – Dadabhai Naoroji is elected as the first Indian Member of Parliament in Britain.</item>
<item>1908 – United States Attorney General Charles Joseph Bonaparte issues an order to immediately staff the Office of the Chief Examiner (later renamed the Federal Bureau of Investigation).</item>
<item>1918 – Emmy Noether\'s paper, which became known as Noether\'s theorem was presented at Göttingen, Germany, from which conservation laws are deduced for symmetries of angular momentum, linear momentum, and energy.</item>
<item>1945 – The Labour Party wins the United Kingdom general election of July 5 by a landslide, removing Winston Churchill from power.</item>
<item>1946 – Aloha Airlines begins service from Honolulu International Airport.</item>
<item>1948 – U.S. President Harry S. Truman signs Executive Order 9981, desegregating the military of the United States.</item>
<item>1951 – Walt Disney\'s 13th animated film, Alice in Wonderland, premieres in London, England, United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1952 – King Farouk of Egypt abdicates in favor of his son Fuad.</item>
<item>1956 – Following the World Bank\'s refusal to fund building the Aswan Dam, Egyptian leader Gamal Abdel Nasser nationalizes the Suez Canal, sparking international condemnation.</item>
<item>1958 – Explorer program: Explorer 4 is launched.</item>
<item>1963 – Syncom 2, the world\'s first geosynchronous satellite, is launched from Cape Canaveral on a Delta B booster.</item>
<item>1963 – The Organisation for Economic Co–operation and Development votes to admit Japan.</item>
<item>1971 – Apollo program: Launch of Apollo 15 on the first Apollo \"J–Mission\", and first use of a Lunar Roving Vehicle.</item>
<item>1974 – Greek Prime Minister Konstantinos Karamanlis forms the country\'s first civil government after seven years of military rule.</item>
<item>1977 – The National Assembly of Quebec imposes the use of French as the official language of the provincial government.</item>
<item>1989 – A federal grand jury indicts Cornell University student Robert T. Morris, Jr. for releasing the Morris worm, thus becoming the first person to be prosecuted under the 1986 Computer Fraud and Abuse Act.</item>
<item>1990 – The Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 is signed into law by President George H.W. Bush.</item>
<item>1999 – Kargil conflict officially comes to an end. The Indian Army announces the complete eviction of Pakistani intruders.</item>
<item>2016 – Hillary Clinton becomes the first female nominee for President of the United States by a major political party at the Democratic National Convention in Philadelphia.</item>
<item>2016 – Solar Impulse 2 becomes the first solar–powered aircraft to circumnavigate the Earth.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>