<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_3">
<item>1035 – William the Conqueror becomes the Duke of Normandy, reigns until 1087.</item>
<item>1608 – Québec City is founded by Samuel de Champlain.</item>
<item>1767 – Pitcairn Island is discovered by Midshipman Robert Pitcairn on an expeditionary voyage commanded by Philip Carteret.</item>
<item>1767 – Norway\'s oldest newspaper still in print, Adresseavisen, is founded and the first edition is published.</item>
<item>1819 – The Bank for Savings in the City of New–York, the first savings bank in the United States, opens.</item>
<item>1839 – The first state normal school in the United States, the forerunner to today\'s Framingham State University, opens in Lexington, Massachusetts with three students.</item>
<item>1849 – France invades the Roman Republic and restores the Papal States.</item>
<item>1852 – Congress establishes the United States\' 2nd mint in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1884 – Dow Jones &amp; Company publishes its first stock average.</item>
<item>1886 – Karl Benz officially unveils the Benz Patent–Motorwagen, the first purpose–built automobile.</item>
<item>1886 – The New–York Tribune becomes the first newspaper to use a linotype machine, eliminating typesetting by hand.</item>
<item>1890 – Idaho is admitted as the 43rd U.S. state.</item>
<item>1913 – Confederate veterans at the Great Reunion of 1913 reenact Pickett\'s Charge; upon reaching the high–water mark of the Confederacy they are met by the outstretched hands of friendship from Union survivors.</item>
<item>1938 – World speed record for a steam locomotive is set in England, by the Mallard, which reaches a speed of 125.88 miles per hour (202.58 km/h).</item>
<item>1952 – The Constitution of Puerto Rico is approved by the United States Congress.</item>
<item>1952 – The SS United States sets sail on her maiden voyage to Southampton. During the voyage, the ship takes the Blue Riband away from the RMS Queen Mary.</item>
<item>1962 – Jackie Robinson becomes the first African American to be inducted into the National Baseball Hall of Fame.</item>
<item>1970 – The Troubles: The \"Falls Curfew\" begins in Belfast, Northern Ireland.</item>
<item>1979 – U.S. President Jimmy Carter signs the first directive for secret aid to the opponents of the pro–Soviet regime in Kabul.</item>
<item>1988 – The Fatih Sultan Mehmet Bridge in Istanbul, Turkey is completed, providing the second connection between the continents of Europe and Asia over the Bosphorus.</item>
<item>1995 – Saint Kitts and Nevis Labour Party wins the general elections and is restored to power after being in opposition for 15 years.</item>
<item>1996 – Stone of Scone is returned to Scotland.</item>
<item>2013 – Egyptian coup d\'état: President of Egypt Mohamed Morsi is overthrown by the military after four days of protests all over the country calling for Morsi\'s resignation, to which he didn\'t respond. President of the Supreme Constitutional Court of Egypt Adly Mansour is declared acting president.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>