<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_31">
<item>781 – The oldest recorded eruption of Mount Fuji (Traditional Japanese date: 6th day of the 7th month of the 1st year of the Ten\'o (天応) era).</item>
<item>1009 – Pope Sergius IV becomes the 142nd pope, succeeding Pope John XVIII.</item>
<item>1201 – Attempted usurpation by John Komnenos the Fat for the throne of Alexios III Angelos.</item>
<item>1451 – Jacques Cœur is arrested by order of Charles VII of France.</item>
<item>1492 – The Jews are expelled from Spain when the Alhambra Decree takes effect.</item>
<item>1498 – On his third voyage to the Western Hemisphere, Christopher Columbus becomes the first European to discover the island of Trinidad.</item>
<item>1588 – The Spanish Armada is spotted off the coast of England.</item>
<item>1618 – Maurice, Prince of Orange disbands the waardgelders militia in Utrecht, a pivotal event in the Remonstrant/Counter–Remonstrant tensions.</item>
<item>1658 – Aurangzeb is proclaimed Mughal emperor of India.</item>
<item>1703 – Daniel Defoe is placed in a pillory for the crime of seditious libel after publishing a politically satirical pamphlet, but is pelted with flowers.</item>
<item>1715 – Seven days after a Spanish treasure fleet of 12 ships left Havana, Cuba for Spain, 11 of them sink in a storm off the coast of Florida. A few centuries later, treasure is salvaged from these wrecks.</item>
<item>1741 – Charles Albert of Bavaria invades Upper Austria and Bohemia.</item>
<item>1777 – The U.S. Second Continental Congress passes a resolution that the services of Gilbert du Motier \"be accepted, and that, in consideration of his zeal, illustrious family and connexions, he have the rank and commission of major–general of the United States.\"</item>
<item>1790 – The first U.S. patent is issued, to inventor Samuel Hopkins for a potash process.</item>
<item>1856 – Christchurch, New Zealand is chartered as a city.</item>
<item>1865 – The first narrow–gauge mainline railway in the world opens at Grandchester, Queensland, Australia.</item>
<item>1874 – Dr. Patrick Francis Healy became the first African–American inaugurated as president of a predominantly white university, Georgetown University.</item>
<item>1913 – The Balkan States sign an armistice in Bucharest.</item>
<item>1919 – German national assembly adopts the Weimar Constitution, which comes into force on August 14.</item>
<item>1938 – Bulgaria signs a non–aggression pact with Greece and other states of Balkan Antanti (Turkey, Romania, Yugoslavia).</item>
<item>1938 – Archaeologists discover engraved gold and silver plates from King Darius the Great in Persepolis.</item>
<item>1948 – At Idlewild Field in New York, New York International Airport (later renamed John F. Kennedy International Airport) is dedicated.</item>
<item>1964 – Ranger program: Ranger 7 sends back the first close–up photographs of the moon, with images 1,000 times clearer than anything ever seen from earth–bound telescopes.</item>
<item>1970 – Black Tot Day: The last day of the officially sanctioned rum ration in the Royal Navy.</item>
<item>1971 – Apollo program: Apollo 15 astronauts become the first to ride in a lunar rover.</item>
<item>1991 – The United States and Soviet Union both sign the START I Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty, the first to reduce (with verification) both countries\' stockpiles.</item>
<item>1992 – The nation of Georgia joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1999 – Discovery Program: Lunar Prospector: NASA intentionally crashes the spacecraft into the Moon, thus ending its mission to detect frozen water on the Moon\'s surface.</item>
<item>2006 – Fidel Castro hands over power to his brother, Raúl.</item>
<item>2007 – Operation Banner, the presence of the British Army in Northern Ireland, and the longest–running British Army operation ever, comes to an end.</item>
<item>2012 – Michael Phelps breaks the record set in 1964 by Larisa Latynina for the most medals won at the Olympics.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>