<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_30">
<item>762 – Baghdad is founded.</item>
<item>1502 – Christopher Columbus lands at Guanaja in the Bay Islands off the coast of Honduras during his fourth voyage.</item>
<item>1619 – In Jamestown, Virginia, the first representative assembly in the Americas, the House of Burgesses, convenes for the first time.</item>
<item>1676 – Nathaniel Bacon issues the \"Declaration of the People of Virginia\", beginning Bacon\'s Rebellion against the rule of Governor William Berkeley.</item>
<item>1729 – Founding of Baltimore, Maryland.</item>
<item>1733 – The first Masonic Grand Lodge in the future United States is constituted in Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1756 – In Saint Petersburg, Bartolomeo Rastrelli presents the newly built Catherine Palace to Empress Elizabeth and her courtiers.</item>
<item>1825 – Malden Island is discovered by captain George Byron, 7th Baron Byron.</item>
<item>1859 – First ascent of Grand Combin, one of the highest summits in the Alps.</item>
<item>1930 – In Montevideo, Uruguay wins the first FIFA World Cup.</item>
<item>1956 – A joint resolution of the U.S. Congress is signed by President Dwight D. Eisenhower, authorizing In God We Trust as the U.S. national motto.</item>
<item>1962 – The Trans–Canada Highway, the longest national highway in the world, is officially opened.</item>
<item>1965 – U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson signs the Social Security Act of 1965 into law, establishing Medicare and Medicaid.</item>
<item>1966 – England defeats West Germany to win the 1966 FIFA World Cup at Wembley Stadium after extra time.</item>
<item>1971 – Apollo program: Apollo 15 Mission: David Scott and James Irwin on the Apollo Lunar Module Falcon land on the Moon with the first Lunar Rover.</item>
<item>1974 – Watergate scandal: U.S. President Richard Nixon releases subpoenaed White House recordings after being ordered to do so by the Supreme Court of the United States.</item>
<item>1975 – Jimmy Hoffa disappears from the parking lot of the Machus Red Fox restaurant in Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, a suburb of Detroit, at about 2:30 p.m. He is never seen or heard from again.</item>
<item>1978 – The 730 (transport), Okinawa Prefecture changes its traffic on the right–hand side of the road to the left–hand side.</item>
<item>1980 – Vanuatu gains independence.</item>
<item>1980 – Israel\'s Knesset passes the Jerusalem Law.</item>
<item>1981 – As many as 50,000 demonstrators, mostly women and children, took to the streets in Łódź to protest food ration shortages in Communist Poland.</item>
<item>2003 – In Mexico, the last \'old style\' Volkswagen Beetle rolls off the assembly line.</item>
<item>2006 – The world\'s longest running music show Top of the Pops is broadcast for the last time on BBC Two. The show had aired for 42 years.</item>
<item>2011 – Marriage of Queen Elizabeth II’s eldest grand–daughter Zara Phillips to former rugby player Mike Tindall.</item>
<item>2012 – A power grid failure in Delhi leaves more than 300 million people without power in northern India.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>