<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_4">
<item>414 – Emperor Theodosius II, age 13, yields power to his older sister Aelia Pulcheria, who reigned as regent and proclaimed herself empress (Augusta) of the Eastern Roman Empire.</item>
<item>836 – Pactum Sicardi, a peace treaty between the Principality of Benevento and the Duchy of Naples, is signed.</item>
<item>993 – Ulrich of Augsburg is canonized as a saint.</item>
<item>1054 – A supernova, called SN 1054, is seen by Chinese Song dynasty, Arab, and possibly Amerindian observers near the star Zeta Tauri. For several months it remains bright enough to be seen during the day. Its remnants form the Crab Nebula.</item>
<item>1359 – Francesco II Ordelaffi of Forlì surrenders to the Papal commander Gil de Albornoz.</item>
<item>1534 – Christian III is elected King of Denmark and Norway in the town of Rye.</item>
<item>1584 – Philip Amadas and Arthur Barlowe arrive at Roanoke Island</item>
<item>1634 – The city of Trois–Rivières is founded in New France (now Quebec, Canada).</item>
<item>1744 – The Treaty of Lancaster, in which the Iroquois cedes lands between the Allegheny Mountains and the Ohio River to the British colonies, was signed in Lancaster, Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1774 – Orangetown Resolutions are adopted in the Province of New York, one of many protests against the British Parliament\'s Coercive Acts</item>
<item>1802 – At West Point, New York, the United States Military Academy opens.</item>
<item>1803 – The Louisiana Purchase is announced to the American people.</item>
<item>1817 – In Rome, New York, construction on the Erie Canal begins.</item>
<item>1827 – Slavery is abolished in the State of New York.</item>
<item>1831 – Samuel Francis Smith writes \"My Country, \'Tis of Thee\" for the Boston, Massachusetts July 4 festivities.</item>
<item>1837 – Grand Junction Railway, the world\'s first long–distance railway, opens between Birmingham and Liverpool.</item>
<item>1838 – The Iowa Territory is organized.</item>
<item>1845 – Henry David Thoreau moves into a small cabin on Walden Pond in Concord, Massachusetts. Thoreau’s account of his two years there, Walden, will become a touchstone of the environmental movement.</item>
<item>1855 – The first edition of Walt Whitman\'s book of poems, Leaves of Grass, is published In Brooklyn.</item>
<item>1862 – Lewis Carroll tells Alice Liddell a story that would grow into Alice\'s Adventures in Wonderland and its sequels.</item>
<item>1881 – In Alabama, the Tuskegee Institute opens.</item>
<item>1886 – The first scheduled Canadian transcontinental train arrives in Port Moody, British Columbia.</item>
<item>1887 – The founder of Pakistan, Quaid–i–Azam Muhammad Ali Jinnah, joins Sindh–Madrasa–tul–Islam, Karachi.</item>
<item>1892 – Western Samoa changes the International Date Line, causing Monday (July 4) to occur twice, resulting in a year with 367 days.</item>
<item>1894 – The short–lived Republic of Hawaii is proclaimed by Sanford B. Dole.</item>
<item>1898 – En route from New York to Le Havre, the SS La Bourgogne collides with another ship and sinks off the coast of Sable Island, with the loss of 549 lives.</item>
<item>1910 – African–American boxer Jack Johnson knocks out white boxer Jim Jeffries in a heavyweight boxing match, sparking race riots across the United States.</item>
<item>1914 – The funeral of Archduke Franz Ferdinand and his wife Sophie takes place in Vienna, six days after their assassinations in Sarajevo.</item>
<item>1927 – First flight of the Lockheed Vega.</item>
<item>1939 – Lou Gehrig, recently diagnosed with Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis, informs a crowd at Yankee Stadium that he considers himself \"The luckiest man on the face of the earth\", then announces his retirement from major league baseball.</item>
<item>1946 – The Kielce pogrom against Jewish Holocaust survivors in Poland.</item>
<item>1946 – After 381 years of near–continuous colonial rule by various powers, the Philippines attains full independence from the United States.</item>
<item>1947 – The \"Indian Independence Bill\" is presented before the British House of Commons, proposing the independence of the Provinces of British India into two sovereign countries: India and Pakistan.</item>
<item>1951 – William Shockley announces the invention of the junction transistor.</item>
<item>1958 – U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower signed the Rivers and Harbors Flood Control Bill.</item>
<item>1960 – Due to the post–Independence Day admission of Hawaii as the 50th U.S. state on August 21, 1959, the 50–star flag of the United States debuts in Philadelphia, almost ten and a half months later (see Flag Acts (United States)).</item>
<item>1966 – U.S. President Lyndon B. Johnson signs the Freedom of Information Act into United States law. The act went into effect the next year.</item>
<item>1976 – The U.S. celebrates its Bicentennial.</item>
<item>1987 – In France, former Gestapo chief Klaus Barbie (a.k.a. the \"Butcher of Lyon\") is convicted of crimes against humanity and sentenced to life imprisonment.</item>
<item>1994 – Rwandan genocide: Kigali, the Rwandan capital, is captured by the Rwandan Patriotic Front, ending the genocide in the city.</item>
<item>1997 – NASA\'s Pathfinder space probe lands on the surface of Mars.</item>
<item>1998 – Japan launches the Nozomi probe to Mars, joining the United States and Russia as a space exploring nation.</item>
<item>2004 – The cornerstone of the Freedom Tower is laid on the World Trade Center site in New York City.</item>
<item>2005 – The Deep Impact collider hits the comet Tempel 1.</item>
<item>2012 – The discovery of particles consistent with the Higgs boson at the Large Hadron Collider is announced at CERN.</item>
<item>2015 – Chile claims their first title in Soccer by defeating Argentina in the 2015 Copa América Final.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>