<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_5">
<item>328 – The official opening of Constantine\'s Bridge built over the Danube between Sucidava (Corabia, Romania) and Oescus (Gigen, Bulgaria) by the Roman architect Theophilus Patricius.</item>
<item>1594 – Portuguese forces under the command of Pedro Lopes de Sousa begin an unsuccessful invasion of the Kingdom of Kandy during the Campaign of Danture in Sri Lanka.</item>
<item>1610 – John Guy sets sail from Bristol with 39 other colonists for Newfoundland.</item>
<item>1687 – Isaac Newton publishes Philosophiæ Naturalis Principia Mathematica.</item>
<item>1775 – The Second Continental Congress adopts the Olive Branch Petition.</item>
<item>1803 – The Convention of Artlenburg is signed, leading to the French occupation of the Electorate of Brunswick–Lüneburg (which had been ruled by the British king).</item>
<item>1811 – The Venezuelan Declaration of Independence is adopted by a congress of the provinces.</item>
<item>1841 – Thomas Cook organises the first package excursion, from Leicester to Loughborough.</item>
<item>1884 – Germany takes possession of Cameroon.</item>
<item>1915 – The Liberty Bell leaves Philadelphia by special train on its way to the Panama–Pacific International Exposition. This is the last trip outside Philadelphia that the custodians of the bell intend to permit.</item>
<item>1935 – The National Labor Relations Act, which governs labor relations in the United States, is signed into law by President Franklin D. Roosevelt.</item>
<item>1937 – Spam, the luncheon meat, is introduced into the market by the Hormel Foods Corporation.</item>
<item>1946 – The bikini goes on sale after debuting during an outdoor fashion show at the Molitor Pool in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1948 – National Health Service Acts create the national public health system in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1950 – Zionism: The Knesset passes the Law of Return which grants all Jews the right to immigrate to Israel.</item>
<item>1954 – The BBC broadcasts its first television news bulletin.</item>
<item>1954 – Elvis Presley records his first single, \"That\'s All Right,\" at Sun Records in Memphis, Tennessee.</item>
<item>1971 – The Twenty–sixth Amendment to the United States Constitution, lowering the voting age from 21 to 18 years, is formally certified by President Richard Nixon.</item>
<item>1975 – Arthur Ashe becomes the first black man to win the Wimbledon singles title.</item>
<item>1975 – Cape Verde gains its independence from Portugal.</item>
<item>1977 – Military coup in Pakistan: Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, the first elected Prime Minister of Pakistan, is overthrown.</item>
<item>1980 – Swedish tennis player Björn Borg wins his fifth Wimbledon final and becomes the first male tennis player to win the championships five times in a row (1976–1980).</item>
<item>1995 – The Republic of Armenia adopts its constitution, four years after its independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1996 – Dolly the sheep becomes the first mammal cloned from an adult cell.</item>
<item>1999 – U.S. President Bill Clinton imposes trade and economic sanctions against the Taliban regime in Afghanistan.</item>
<item>2004 – The first Indonesian presidential election is held.</item>
<item>2006 – North Korea tests four short–range missiles, one medium–range missile and a long–range Taepodong–2. The long–range Taepodong–2 reportedly fails in mid–air over the Sea of Japan.</item>
<item>2009 – A series of violent riots break out in Ürümqi, the capital city of the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region in China.</item>
<item>2009 – The largest hoard of Anglo–Saxon gold ever discovered in England, consisting of more than 1,500 items, is found near the village of Hammerwich, near Lichfield, Staffordshire.</item>
<item>2012 – The Shard in London is inaugurated as the tallest building in Europe, with a height of 310 metres (1,020 ft).</item>
<item>2016 – The Juno space probe arrives at Jupiter and begins a 20–month survey of the planet.</item>
<item>2018 – The EU Copyright Directive currently has been pushed back to 10 September 2018, due to the majority of votes in the EU Parliament favoring holding back the vote.</item>
<item>2018 – Lithuania becomes the 36th member of the OECD.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>