<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_7">
<item>1124 – Tyre falls to the Crusaders.</item>
<item>1534 – Jacques Cartier makes his first contact with aboriginal peoples in what is now Canada.</item>
<item>1585 – The Treaty of Nemours abolishes tolerance to Protestants in France.</item>
<item>1834 – In New York City, four nights of rioting against abolitionists began.</item>
<item>1846 – American troops occupy Monterey and Yerba Buena, thus beginning the conquest of California.</item>
<item>1863 – The United States begins its first military draft; exemptions cost $300.</item>
<item>1898 – U.S. President William McKinley signs the Newlands Resolution annexing Hawaii as a territory of the United States.</item>
<item>1907 – Florenz Ziegfeld, Jr. staged his first Follies on the roof of the New York Theater in New York City.</item>
<item>1911 – The United States, Great Britain, Japan, and Russia sign the North Pacific Fur Seal Convention of 1911 banning open–water seal hunting, the first international treaty to address wildlife preservation issues.</item>
<item>1916 – The New Zealand Labour Party was founded in Wellington.</item>
<item>1928 – Sliced bread is sold for the first time (on the inventor\'s 48th birthday) by the Chillicothe Baking Company of Chillicothe, Missouri.</item>
<item>1930 – Industrialist Henry J. Kaiser begins construction of Boulder Dam (now known as Hoover Dam).</item>
<item>1937 – The Peel Commission Report recommends the partition of Palestine – the first formal recommendation for partition in the history of Palestine</item>
<item>1941 – The American occupation of Iceland replaces the British occupation.</item>
<item>1946 – Mother Francesca S. Cabrini becomes the first American to be canonized.</item>
<item>1952 – The ocean liner SS United States passes Bishop Rock on her maiden voyage, breaking the transatlantic speed record to become the fastest passenger ship in the world.</item>
<item>1953 – Ernesto \"Che\" Guevara sets out on a trip through Bolivia, Peru, Ecuador, Panama, Costa Rica, Nicaragua, Honduras, and El Salvador.</item>
<item>1954 – Elvis Presley makes his radio debut when WHBQ Memphis played his first recording for Sun Records, \"That\'s All Right\".</item>
<item>1958 – U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower signs the Alaska Statehood Act into law.</item>
<item>1959 – Venus occults the star Regulus. This rare event is used to determine the diameter of Venus and the structure of the Venusian atmosphere.</item>
<item>1978 – The Solomon Islands becomes independent from the United Kingdom</item>
<item>1980 – Institution of sharia law in Iran.</item>
<item>1981 – U.S. President Ronald Reagan appoints Sandra Day O\'Connor to become the first female member of the Supreme Court of the United States.</item>
<item>1985 – Boris Becker becomes the youngest player ever to win Wimbledon at age 17.</item>
<item>1992 – The New York Court of Appeals rules that women have the same right as men to go topless in public.</item>
<item>2003 – NASA Opportunity rover, MER–B or Mars Exploration Rover–B, was launched into space aboard a Delta II rocket.</item>
<item>2007 – The first Live Earth benefit concert was held in 11 locations around the world.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>