<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_8">
<item>1283 – Roger of Lauria, commanding the Aragonese fleet defeats an Angevin fleet sent to put down a rebellion on Malta.</item>
<item>1497 – Vasco da Gama sets sail on the first direct European voyage to India.</item>
<item>1579 – Our Lady of Kazan, a holy icon of the Russian Orthodox Church, is discovered underground in the city of Kazan, Tatarstan.</item>
<item>1663 – Charles II of England grants John Clarke a Royal charter to Rhode Island.</item>
<item>1758 – French forces hold Fort Carillon against the British at Ticonderoga, New York.</item>
<item>1775 – The Olive Branch Petition is signed by the Continental Congress of the Thirteen Colonies of North America.</item>
<item>1776 – Church bells (possibly including the Liberty Bell) are rung after John Nixon delivers the first public reading of the Declaration of Independence of the United States.</item>
<item>1808 – Joseph Bonaparte approves the Bayonne Statute, a royal charter intended as the basis for his rule as king of Spain.</item>
<item>1822 – Chippewas turn over a huge tract of land in Ontario to the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1853 – The Perry Expedition arrives in Edo Bay with a treaty requesting trade.</item>
<item>1859 – King Charles XV &amp; IV accedes to the throne of Sweden–Norway.</item>
<item>1874 – The Mounties begin their March West.</item>
<item>1879 – Sailing ship USS Jeannette departs San Francisco carrying an ill–fated expedition to the North Pole.</item>
<item>1889 – The first issue of The Wall Street Journal is published.</item>
<item>1892 – St. John\'s, Newfoundland is devastated in the Great Fire of 1892.</item>
<item>1910 – Vinayak Damodar Savarkar escaped through a porthole from the ship and swam ashore.</item>
<item>1932 – The Dow Jones Industrial Average reaches its lowest level of the Great Depression, closing at 41.22.</item>
<item>1933 – The first rugby union test match between the Wallabies of Australia and the Springboks of South Africa is played at Newlands Stadium in Cape Town.</item>
<item>1937 – Turkey, Iran, Iraq and Afghanistan sign the Treaty of Saadabad.</item>
<item>1947 – Reports are broadcast that a UFO crash landed in Roswell, New Mexico in what became known as the Roswell UFO incident.</item>
<item>1948 – The United States Air Force accepts its first female recruits into a program called Women in the Air Force (WAF).</item>
<item>1960 – Francis Gary Powers is charged with espionage resulting from his flight over the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1966 – King Mwambutsa IV Bangiriceng of Burundi is deposed by his son Prince Charles Ndizi.</item>
<item>1968 – The Chrysler wildcat strike begins in Detroit, Michigan.</item>
<item>1970 – Richard Nixon delivers a special congressional message enunciating Native American self–determination as official US Indian policy, leading to the Indian Self–Determination and Education Assistance Act of 1975.</item>
<item>1972 – Israeli Mossad assassinate Palestinian writer Ghassan Kanafani.</item>
<item>1980 – The inaugural 1980 State of Origin game is won by Queensland who defeat New South Wales 20–10 at Lang Park.</item>
<item>1982 – Assassination attempt against Iraqi president Saddam Hussein in Dujail.</item>
<item>2011 – Space Shuttle Atlantis is launched in the final mission of the U.S. Space Shuttle program.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>