<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a7_9">
<item>455 – The military commander Avitus is proclaimed Emperor of the Western Roman Empire.</item>
<item>491 – Odoacer makes a night assault with his Heruli guardsmen, engaging Theoderic the Great in Ad Pinetam. Both sides suffer heavy losses, but in the end Theodoric forces Odoacer back into Ravenna.</item>
<item>1357 – Emperor Charles IV assists in laying the foundation stone of Charles Bridge in Prague.</item>
<item>1540 – King Henry VIII of England annuls his marriage to his fourth wife, Anne of Cleves.</item>
<item>1572 – Nineteen Catholics suffer martyrdom for their beliefs in the Dutch town of Gorkum.</item>
<item>1609 – Bohemia is granted freedom of religion through the Letter of Majesty by the Holy Roman Emperor, Rudolf II.</item>
<item>1755 – The Braddock Expedition is soundly defeated by a smaller French and Native American force in its attempt to capture Fort Duquesne in what is now downtown Pittsburgh.</item>
<item>1789 – In Versailles, the National Assembly reconstitutes itself as the National Constituent Assembly and begins preparations for a French constitution.</item>
<item>1790 – The Swedish Navy captures one third of the Russian Baltic fleet.</item>
<item>1793 – The Act Against Slavery in Upper Canada bans the importation of slaves and will free those who are born into slavery after the passage of the Act at 25 years of age.</item>
<item>1807 – The Treaties of Tilsit are signed by Napoleon I of France and Alexander I of Russia.</item>
<item>1810 – Napoleon annexes the Kingdom of Holland as part of the First French Empire.</item>
<item>1811 – Explorer David Thompson posts a sign near what is now Sacajawea State Park in Washington state, claiming the Columbia District for the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1815 – Charles Maurice de Talleyrand–Périgord becomes the first Prime Minister of France.</item>
<item>1816 – Argentina declares independence from Spain.</item>
<item>1863 – The Siege of Port Hudson ends, giving the Union complete control of the Mississippi River.</item>
<item>1868 – The 14th Amendment to the United States Constitution is ratified, guaranteeing African Americans full citizenship and all persons in the United States due process of law.</item>
<item>1875 – The Herzegovina Uprising against Ottoman rule begins, which would last until 1878 and have far–reaching implications throughout the Balkans.</item>
<item>1877 – The inaugural Wimbledon Championships begins.</item>
<item>1893 – Daniel Hale Williams, American heart surgeon, performs 1st successful open–heart surgery in United States without anesthesia.</item>
<item>1896 – William Jennings Bryan delivers his Cross of Gold speech advocating bimetallism at the 1896 Democratic National Convention in Chicago.</item>
<item>1900 – The Federation of Australia is given royal assent.</item>
<item>1900 – The Governor of Shanxi province in North China orders the execution of 45 foreign Christian missionaries and local church members, including children.</item>
<item>1922 – Johnny Weissmuller swims the 100 meters freestyle in 58.6 seconds breaking the world swimming record and the \'minute barrier\'.</item>
<item>1962 – Starfish Prime tests the effects of a nuclear test at orbital altitudes.</item>
<item>1986 – The New Zealand Parliament passes the Homosexual Law Reform Act legalising homosexuality in New Zealand.</item>
<item>1993 – The Parliament of Canada passes the Nunavut Act leading to the 1999 creation of Nunavut, dividing the Northwest Territories into arctic (Inuit) and sub–arctic (Dene) lands based on a plebiscite.</item>
<item>2002 – The African Union is established in Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, replacing the Organisation of African Unity (OAU). The organization\'s first chairman is Thabo Mbeki, President of South Africa.</item>
<item>2011 – South Sudan gains independence and secedes from Sudan.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>