<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_15">
<item>747 – Carloman, mayor of the palace of Austrasia, renounces his position as majordomo and retires to a monastery near Rome. His brother Pepin the Short becomes the sole ruler (de facto) of the Frankish Kingdom.</item>
<item>805 – Noble Erchana of Dahauua grants the Bavarian town of Dachau to the Diocese of Freising</item>
<item>1018 – Byzantine general Eustathios Daphnomeles blinds and captures Ibatzes of Bulgaria by a ruse, thereby ending Bulgarian resistance against Emperor Basil II\'s conquest of Bulgaria.</item>
<item>1070 – The Pavian–born Benedictine Lanfranc is appointed as the new Archbishop of Canterbury in England.</item>
<item>1185 – The cave city of Vardzia is consecrated by Queen Tamar of Georgia.</item>
<item>1248 – The foundation stone of Cologne Cathedral, built to house the relics of the Three Wise Men, is laid. (Construction is eventually completed in 1880.)</item>
<item>1261 – Michael VIII Palaiologos is crowned Byzantine emperor in Constantinople.</item>
<item>1309 – The city of Rhodes surrenders to the forces of the Knights of St. John, completing their conquest of Rhodes. The knights establish their headquarters on the island and rename themselves the Knights of Rhodes.</item>
<item>1430 – Francesco Sforza, lord of Milan, conquers Lucca.</item>
<item>1483 – Pope Sixtus IV consecrates the Sistine Chapel.</item>
<item>1511 – Afonso de Albuquerque of Portugal conquers Malacca, the capital of the Malacca Sultanate.</item>
<item>1517 – Seven Portuguese armed vessels led by Fernão Pires de Andrade meet Chinese officials at the Pearl River estuary.</item>
<item>1519 – Panama City, Panama is founded.</item>
<item>1534 – Ignatius of Loyola and six classmates take initial vows, leading to the creation of the Society of Jesus in September 1540.</item>
<item>1537 – Asunción, Paraguay is founded.</item>
<item>1540 – Arequipa, Peru is founded.</item>
<item>1549 – Jesuit priest Francis Xavier comes ashore at Kagoshima (Traditional Japanese date: 22 July 1549).</item>
<item>1843 – The Cathedral of Our Lady of Peace in Honolulu, Hawaii is dedicated. Now the cathedral of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Honolulu, it is the oldest Roman Catholic cathedral in continuous use in the United States.</item>
<item>1843 – Tivoli Gardens, one of the oldest still intact amusement parks in the world, opens in Copenhagen, Denmark.</item>
<item>1893 – Ibadan area becomes a British Protectorate after a treaty signed by Fijabi, the Baale of Ibadan with the British acting Governor of Lagos, George C. Denton.</item>
<item>1914 – The Panama Canal opens to traffic with the transit of the cargo ship SS Ancon.</item>
<item>1939 – The Wizard of Oz premieres at Grauman\'s Chinese Theater in Los Angeles, California.</item>
<item>1947 – India gains Independence from British rule after near 190 years of Crown rule and joins the Commonwealth of Nations.</item>
<item>1947 – Founder of Pakistan, Muhammad Ali Jinnah is sworn in as first Governor–General of Pakistan in Karachi.</item>
<item>1948 – The Republic of Korea (South Korea) is established south of the 38th parallel north.</item>
<item>1954 – Alfredo Stroessner begins his dictatorship in Paraguay.</item>
<item>1960 – Republic of the Congo (Brazzaville) becomes independent from France.</item>
<item>1961 – Border guard Conrad Schumann flees from East Germany while on duty guarding the construction of the Berlin Wall.</item>
<item>1963 – President Fulbert Youlou is overthrown in the Republic of the Congo, after a three–day uprising in the capital.</item>
<item>1965 – The Beatles play to nearly 60,000 fans at Shea Stadium in New York City, an event later regarded as the birth of stadium rock.</item>
<item>1969 – The Woodstock Music &amp; Art Fair opens in upstate New York, featuring some of the top rock musicians of the era.</item>
<item>1970 – Patricia Palinkas becomes the first woman to play professionally in an American football game.</item>
<item>1971 – President Richard Nixon completes the break from the gold standard by ending convertibility of the United States dollar into gold by foreign investors.</item>
<item>1971 – Bahrain gains independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1977 – The Big Ear, a radio telescope operated by Ohio State University as part of the SETI project, receives a radio signal from deep space; the event is named the \"Wow! signal\" from the notation made by a volunteer on the project.</item>
<item>1995 – In South Carolina, Shannon Faulkner becomes the first female cadet matriculated at The Citadel (she drops out less than a week later).</item>
<item>2005 – Israel\'s unilateral disengagement plan to evict all Israelis from the Gaza Strip and from four settlements in the northern West Bank begins.</item>
<item>2013 – The Smithsonian announces the discovery of the olinguito, the first new carnivorous species found in the Americas in 35 years.</item>
<item>2015 – North Korea moves its clock back half an hour to introduce Pyongyang Time, 8½ hours ahead of UTC.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>