<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_16">
<item>963 – Nikephoros II Phokas is crowned emperor of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1328 – The House of Gonzaga seizes power in the Duchy of Mantua, and will rule until 1708.</item>
<item>1841 – U.S. President John Tyler vetoes a bill which called for the re–establishment of the Second Bank of the United States. Enraged Whig Party members riot outside the White House in the most violent demonstration on White House grounds in U.S. history.</item>
<item>1858 – U.S. President James Buchanan inaugurates the new transatlantic telegraph cable by exchanging greetings with Queen Victoria of the United Kingdom. However, a weak signal forces a shutdown of the service in a few weeks.</item>
<item>1859 – The Grand Duchy of Tuscany formally deposes the exiled House of Lorraine.</item>
<item>1891 – The Basilica of San Sebastian, Manila, the first all–steel church in Asia, is officially inaugurated and blessed.</item>
<item>1896 – Skookum Jim Mason, George Carmack and Dawson Charlie discover gold in a tributary of the Klondike River in Canada, setting off the Klondike Gold Rush.</item>
<item>1913 – Tōhoku Imperial University of Japan (modern day Tohoku University) becomes the first university in Japan to admit female students.</item>
<item>1916 – The Migratory Bird Treaty between Canada and the United States is signed.</item>
<item>1923 – The United Kingdom gives the name \"Ross Dependency\" to part of its claimed Antarctic territory and makes the Governor–General of the Dominion of New Zealand its administrator.</item>
<item>1927 – The Dole Air Race begins from Oakland, California, to Honolulu, Hawaii, during which six out of the eight participating planes crash or disappear.</item>
<item>1930 – The first color sound cartoon, Fiddlesticks, is released by Ub Iwerks.</item>
<item>1930 – The first British Empire Games were opened in Hamilton, Ontario by the Governor General of Canada, the Viscount Willingdon.</item>
<item>1945 – The National Representatives\' Congress, the precursor of the current National Assembly of Vietnam, convenes in Sơn Dương.</item>
<item>1946 – The All Hyderabad Trade Union Congress is founded in Secunderabad.</item>
<item>1954 – The first issue of Sports Illustrated is published.</item>
<item>1960 – Cyprus gains its independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1960 – Joseph Kittinger parachutes from a balloon over New Mexico at 102,800 feet (31,300 m), setting three records that held until 2012: High–altitude jump, free fall, and highest speed by a human without an aircraft.</item>
<item>1962 – Eight years after the remaining French India territories were handed to India, the ratifications of the treaty are exchanged to make the transfer official.</item>
<item>1962 – Pete Best is discharged from The Beatles, to be replaced two days later by Ringo Starr.</item>
<item>1989 – A solar particle event affects computers at the Toronto Stock Exchange, forcing a halt to trading.</item>
<item>2008 – The Trump International Hotel and Tower in Chicago is topped off at 1,389 feet (423 m), at the time becoming the world\'s highest residence above ground–level.</item>
<item>2012 – South African police fatally shoot 34 miners and wound 78 more during an industrial dispute at Marikana near Rustenburg.</item>
<item>2017 – The Minamata Convention on Mercury enters in force.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>