<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_11">
<item>3114 BC – The Mesoamerican Long Count calendar, used by several pre–Columbian Mesoamerican civilizations, notably the Maya, begins.</item>
<item>2492 BC – Traditional date of the defeat of Bel by Hayk, progenitor and founder of the Armenian nation.</item>
<item>106 – The south–western part of Dacia (modern Romania) becomes a Roman province: Roman Dacia.</item>
<item>355 – Claudius Silvanus, accused of treason, proclaims himself Roman Emperor against Constantius II.</item>
<item>1786 – Captain Francis Light establishes the British colony of Penang in Malaysia.</item>
<item>1804 – Francis II assumes the title of first Emperor of Austria.</item>
<item>1813 – In Colombia, Juan del Corral declares the independence of Antioquia.</item>
<item>1858 – The Eiger in the Bernese Alps is ascended for the first time by Charles Barrington accompanied by Christian Almer and Peter Bohren.</item>
<item>1929 – Babe Ruth becomes the first baseball player to hit 500 home runs in his career with a home run at League Park in Cleveland, Ohio.</item>
<item>1934 – The first civilian prisoners arrive at the Federal prison on Alcatraz Island.</item>
<item>1942 – Actress Hedy Lamarr and composer George Antheil receive a patent for a Frequency–hopping spread spectrum communication system that later became the basis for modern technologies in wireless telephones and Wi–Fi.</item>
<item>1952 – Hussein bin Talal is proclaimed King of Jordan.</item>
<item>1959 – Sheremetyevo International Airport, the second–largest airport in Russia, opens.</item>
<item>1960 – Chad declares independence.</item>
<item>1961 – The former Portuguese territories in India of Dadra and Nagar Haveli are merged to create the Union Territory Dadra and Nagar Haveli.</item>
<item>1962 – Vostok 3 launches from the Baikonur Cosmodrome and cosmonaut Andrian Nikolayev becomes the first person to float in microgravity.</item>
<item>1965 – Race riots (the Watts Riots) begin in the Watts area of Los Angeles, California.</item>
<item>1968 – The Fifteen Guinea Special became the last main–line passenger train to be hauled by steam locomotive power on British Rail.</item>
<item>1969 – The Apollo 11 astronauts are released from a three–week quarantine following their liftoff from the moon.</item>
<item>1999 – A total solar eclipse occurs.</item>
<item>2003 – NATO takes over command of the peacekeeping force in Afghanistan, marking its first major operation outside Europe in its 54–year–history.</item>
<item>2003 – Jemaah Islamiyah leader Riduan Isamuddin, better known as Hambali, is arrested in Bangkok, Thailand.</item>
<item>2006 – The oil tanker M/T Solar 1 sinks off the coast of Guimaras and Negros Islands in the Philippines, causing the country\'s worst oil spill.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>