<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_12">
<item>1323 – Signature of the Treaty of Nöteborg between Sweden and Novgorod Republic, which regulates the border between the two countries for the first time.</item>
<item>1492 – Christopher Columbus arrives in the Canary Islands on his first voyage to the New World.</item>
<item>1624 – The president of Louis XIII of France\'s royal council is arrested, leaving Cardinal Richelieu in the role of the King\'s principal minister.</item>
<item>1765 – Treaty of Allahabad is signed. The Treaty marks the political and constitutional involvement and the beginning of Company rule in India.</item>
<item>1793 – The Rhône and Loire départments are created when the former département of Rhône–et–Loire is split into two.</item>
<item>1806 – Santiago de Liniers, 1st Count of Buenos Aires re–takes the city of Buenos Aires, Argentina after the first British invasion.</item>
<item>1851 – Isaac Singer is granted a patent for his sewing machine.</item>
<item>1865 – Joseph Lister, British surgeon and scientist, performs 1st antiseptic surgery.</item>
<item>1898 – The Hawaiian flag is lowered from ʻIolani Palace in an elaborate annexation ceremony and replaced with the flag of the United States to signify the transfer of sovereignty from the Republic of Hawaii to the United States.</item>
<item>1944 – Waffen–SS troops massacre 560 people in Sant\'Anna di Stazzema.</item>
<item>1960 – Echo 1A, NASA\'s first successful communications satellite, is launched.</item>
<item>1964 – South Africa is banned from the Olympic Games due to the country\'s racist policies.</item>
<item>1977 – The first free flight of the Space Shuttle Enterprise.</item>
<item>1978 – The Treaty of Peace and Friendship between Japan and the People\'s Republic of China is concluded.</item>
<item>1981 – The IBM Personal Computer is released.</item>
<item>1990 – Sue, the largest and most complete Tyrannosaurus Rex skeleton found to date, is discovered by Sue Hendrickson in South Dakota.</item>
<item>1992 – Canada, Mexico and the United States announce completion of negotiations for the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA).</item>
<item>1994 – Major League Baseball players go on strike, forcing the cancellation of the 1994 World Series.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>