<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_10">
<item>654 – Pope Eugene I elected to succeed Martinus I.</item>
<item>1270 – Yekuno Amlak takes the imperial throne of Ethiopia, restoring the Solomonic dynasty to power after a 100–year Zagwe interregnum.</item>
<item>1585 – The Treaty of Nonsuch signed by Elizabeth I of England and the Dutch Rebels.</item>
<item>1675 – The foundation stone of the Royal Greenwich Observatory in London, England is laid.</item>
<item>1680 – The Pueblo Revolt begins in New Mexico.</item>
<item>1755 – Under the orders of Charles Lawrence, the British Army begins to forcibly deport the Acadians from Nova Scotia to the Thirteen Colonies.</item>
<item>1793 – The Musée du Louvre is officially opened in Paris, France.</item>
<item>1813 – Instituto Nacional, is founded by the Chilean patriot José Miguel Carrera. It is Chile\'s oldest and most prestigious school. Its motto is Labor Omnia Vincit, which means \"Work conquers all things\".</item>
<item>1821 – Missouri is admitted as the 24th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1846 – The Smithsonian Institution is chartered by the United States Congress after James Smithson donates $500,000.</item>
<item>1897 – German chemist Felix Hoffmann discovers an improved way of synthesizing acetylsalicylic acid (aspirin).</item>
<item>1901 – The U.S. Steel recognition strike by the Amalgamated Association of Iron and Steel Workers begins.</item>
<item>1932 – A 5.1 kilograms (11 lb) chondrite–type meteorite breaks into at least seven pieces and lands near the town of Archie in Cass County, Missouri.</item>
<item>1948 – Candid Camera makes its television debut after being on radio for a year as Candid Microphone.</item>
<item>1954 – At Massena, New York, the groundbreaking ceremony for the Saint Lawrence Seaway is held.</item>
<item>1971 – The Society for American Baseball Research is founded in Cooperstown, New York.</item>
<item>1990 – The Magellan space probe reaches Venus.</item>
<item>1998 – HRH Prince Al–Muhtadee Billah is proclaimed the crown prince of Brunei with a Royal Proclamation.</item>
<item>2003 – 2003 European heat wave: The highest temperature ever recorded in the United Kingdom, 38.5 °C (101.3 °F) in Kent, England. It is the first time the United Kingdom has recorded a temperature over 100 °F (38 °C).</item>
<item>2003 – The Okinawa Monorail is opened in Naha, Okinawa.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>