<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_14">
<item>29 BC – Octavian holds the second of three consecutive triumphs in Rome to celebrate the victory over the Dalmatian tribes.</item>
<item>1183 – Taira no Munemori and the Taira clan take the young Emperor Antoku and the three sacred treasures and flee to western Japan to escape pursuit by the Minamoto clan (Traditional Japanese date: Twenty–fifth day of the seventh month of the second year of the Juei (寿永) era).</item>
<item>1288 – Count Adolf VIII of Berg grants town privileges to Düsseldorf, the village on the banks of the Düssel.</item>
<item>1370 – Charles IV, Holy Roman Emperor, grants city privileges to Carlsbad which is subsequently named after him.</item>
<item>1457 – Publication of the Mainz Psalter, the first book to feature a printed date of publication and printed colophon</item>
<item>1592 – The first sighting of the Falkland Islands by John Davis.</item>
<item>1816 – The United Kingdom formally annexes the Tristan da Cunha archipelago, administering the islands from the Cape Colony in South Africa.</item>
<item>1848 – Oregon Territory is organized by act of Congress.</item>
<item>1880 – Construction of Cologne Cathedral, the most famous landmark in Cologne, Germany, is completed.</item>
<item>1885 – Japan\'s first patent is issued to the inventor of a rust–proof paint.</item>
<item>1893 – France becomes the first country to introduce motor vehicle registration.</item>
<item>1900 – The Eight–Nation Alliance occupies Beijing, China, in a campaign to end the bloody Boxer Rebellion in China.</item>
<item>1901 – The first claimed powered flight, by Gustave Whitehead in his Number 21.</item>
<item>1912 – U.S. Marines invade Nicaragua to support the U.S.–backed government installed there after José Santos Zelaya had resigned three years earlier.</item>
<item>1921 – Tannu Uriankhai, later Tuvan People\'s Republic is established as a completely independent country (which is supported by Soviet Russia).</item>
<item>1935 – Franklin D. Roosevelt signs the Social Security Act, creating a government pension system for the retired.</item>
<item>1936 – Rainey Bethea is hanged in Owensboro, Kentucky in the last known public execution in the United States.</item>
<item>1947 – Pakistan gains Independence from the British Empire and joins the Commonwealth of Nations.</item>
<item>1959 – Founding and first official meeting of the American Football League.</item>
<item>1967 – UK Marine Broadcasting Offences Act declares participation in offshore pirate radio illegal.</item>
<item>1969 – Operation Banner: British troops are deployed in Northern Ireland.</item>
<item>1971 – Bahrain declares independence as the State of Bahrain.</item>
<item>1973 – The Pakistan Constitution of 1973 comes into effect.</item>
<item>1975 – The Rocky Horror Picture Show, the longest–running release in film history, opens in London.</item>
<item>1980 – Lech Wałęsa leads strikes at the Gdańsk, Poland shipyards.</item>
<item>1994 – Ilich Ramírez Sánchez, also known as \"Carlos the Jackal\", is captured.</item>
<item>2003 – A widescale power blackout affects the northeast United States and Canada.</item>
<item>2003 – Project Thread, an operation launched by CSIS and other Canadian law enforcement agencies, saw the arrest and incarceration of 24 innocent Muslim men, most of them young Pakistani students.</item>
<item>2015 – The US Embassy in Havana, Cuba re–opens after 54 years of being closed when Cuba–United States relations were broken off</item>
</string-array>
</resources>