<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_19">
<item>43 BC – Gaius Julius Caesar Octavianus, later known as Augustus, compels the Roman Senate to elect him Consul.</item>
<item>1153 – Baldwin III of Jerusalem takes control of the Kingdom of Jerusalem from his mother Melisende, and also captures Ascalon.</item>
<item>1458 – Pope Pius II becomes the 211th Pope.</item>
<item>1561 – Mary, Queen of Scots, who was 18 years old, returns to Scotland after spending 13 years in France.</item>
<item>1612 – The \"Samlesbury witches\", three women from the Lancashire village of Samlesbury, England, are put on trial, accused of practicing witchcraft, one of the most famous witch trials in British history.</item>
<item>1772 – Gustav III of Sweden stages a coup d\'état, in which he assumes power and enacts a new constitution that divides power between the Riksdag and the King.</item>
<item>1813 – Gervasio Antonio de Posadas joins Argentina\'s Second Triumvirate.</item>
<item>1839 – The French government announces that Louis Daguerre\'s photographic process is a gift \"free to the world\".</item>
<item>1848 – California Gold Rush: The New York Herald breaks the news to the East Coast of the United States of the gold rush in California (although the rush started in January).</item>
<item>1861 – First ascent of Weisshorn, fifth highest summit in the Alps.</item>
<item>1909 – The first automobile race at the Indianapolis Motor Speedway.</item>
<item>1927 – Patriarch Sergius of Moscow proclaims the declaration of loyalty of the Russian Orthodox Church to the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1934 – The first All–American Soap Box Derby is held in Dayton, Ohio.</item>
<item>1936 – The Great Purge of the Soviet Union begins when the first of the Moscow Trials is convened.</item>
<item>1960 – Sputnik program: Korabl–Sputnik 2: The Soviet Union launches the satellite with the dogs Belka and Strelka, 40 mice, two rats and a variety of plants.</item>
<item>1964 – Syncom 3, the first geostationary communication satellite, was launched.</item>
<item>1981 – Gulf of Sidra Incident: United States fighters intercept and shoot down two Libyan Sukhoi Su–22 fighter jets over the Gulf of Sidra.</item>
<item>1989 – Polish president Wojciech Jaruzelski nominates Solidarity activist Tadeusz Mazowiecki to be the first non–communist prime minister in 42 years.</item>
<item>1989 – Several hundred East Germans cross the frontier between Hungary and Austria during the Pan–European Picnic, part of the events that began the process of the Fall of the Berlin Wall.</item>
<item>1991 – Dissolution of the Soviet Union, August Coup: Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev is placed under house arrest while on holiday in the town of Foros, Ukraine.</item>
<item>1999 – In Belgrade, Yugoslavia, tens of thousands of Serbians rally to demand the resignation of Federal Republic of Yugoslavia President Slobodan Milošević.</item>
<item>2005 – The first–ever joint military exercise between Russia and China, called Peace Mission 2005 begins.</item>
<item>2010 – Operation Iraqi Freedom ends, with the last of the United States brigade combat teams crossing the border to Kuwait.</item>
<item>2017 – Tens of thousands of farmed non–native Atlantic salmon are accidentally released into the wild in Washington waters in the 2017 Cypress Island Atlantic salmon pen break.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>