<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_1">
<item>30 BC – Octavian (later known as Augustus) enters Alexandria, Egypt, bringing it under the control of the Roman Republic.</item>
<item>527 – Justinian I becomes the sole ruler of the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>607 – Ono no Imoko is dispatched as envoy to the Sui court in China (Traditional Japanese date: July 3, 607).</item>
<item>902 – Taormina, the last Byzantine stronghold in Sicily, is captured by the Aghlabids army, concluding the Muslim conquest of Sicily.</item>
<item>1203 – Isaac II Angelos, restored Eastern Roman Emperor, declares his son Alexios IV Angelos co–emperor after pressure from the forces of the Fourth Crusade.</item>
<item>1291 – The Old Swiss Confederacy is formed with the signature of the Federal Charter.</item>
<item>1469 – Louis XI of France founds the chivalric order called the Order of Saint Michael in Amboise.</item>
<item>1498 – Christopher Columbus becomes the first European to visit what is now Venezuela.</item>
<item>1571 – The Ottoman conquest of Cyprus is concluded, by the surrender of Famagusta.</item>
<item>1620 – Speedwell leaves Delfshaven to bring pilgrims to America by way of England.</item>
<item>1714 – George, Elector of Hanover, becomes King George I of Great Britain, marking the beginning of the Georgian era of British history.</item>
<item>1774 – British scientist Joseph Priestley discovers oxygen gas, corroborating the prior discovery of this element by German–Swedish chemist Carl Wilhelm Scheele.</item>
<item>1800 – The Acts of Union 1800 are passed which merge the Kingdom of Great Britain and the Kingdom of Ireland into the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland.</item>
<item>1834 – Slavery is abolished in the British Empire as the Slavery Abolition Act 1833 comes into force.</item>
<item>1842 – The Lombard Street riot erupts in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States.</item>
<item>1855 – The first ascent of Monte Rosa, the second highest summit in the Alps.</item>
<item>1876 – Colorado is admitted as the 38th U.S. state.</item>
<item>1893 – Henry Perky patents shredded wheat.</item>
<item>1907 – The start of the first Scout camp on Brownsea Island, the origin of the worldwide Scouting movement.</item>
<item>1911 – Harriet Quimby takes her pilot\'s test and becomes the first U.S. woman to earn an Aero Club of America aviator\'s certificate.</item>
<item>1937 – Josip Broz Tito reads the resolution \"Manifesto of constitutional congress of KPH\" to the constitutive congress of KPH (Croatian Communist Party) in woods near Samobor.</item>
<item>1957 – The United States and Canada form the North American Aerospace Defense Command (NORAD).</item>
<item>1960 – Dahomey (later renamed Benin) declares independence from France.</item>
<item>1960 – Islamabad is declared the federal capital of the Government of Pakistan.</item>
<item>1961 – U.S. Defense Secretary Robert McNamara orders the creation of the Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA), the nation\'s first centralized military espionage organization.</item>
<item>1964 – The former Belgian Congo is renamed the Democratic Republic of the Congo.</item>
<item>1968 – The coronation is held of Hassanal Bolkiah, the 29th Sultan of Brunei.</item>
<item>1971 – The Concert for Bangladesh, organized by former Beatle George Harrison, is held at Madison Square Garden in New York City.</item>
<item>1974 – Cyprus dispute: The United Nations Security Council authorizes the UNFICYP to create the \"Green Line\", dividing Cyprus into two zones.</item>
<item>1980 – Vigdís Finnbogadóttir is elected President of Iceland and becomes the world\'s first democratically elected female head of state.</item>
<item>1984 – Commercial peat–cutters discover the preserved bog body of a man, called Lindow Man, at Lindow Moss, Cheshire, England.</item>
<item>1993 – The Great Mississippi and Missouri Rivers Flood of 1993 comes to a peak.</item>
<item>1998 – The establishment of Muslim Medics, one of the largest student–led societies in Imperial College London that provides both academic and wellbeing support to medical students of all backgrounds.</item>
<item>2008 – The Beijing–Tianjin Intercity Railway begins operation as the fastest commuter rail system in the world.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>