<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_21">
<item>959 – Eraclus becomes the 25th bishop of Liège.</item>
<item>1192 – Minamoto no Yoritomo becomes Sei–i Taishōgun and the de facto ruler of Japan. (Traditional Japanese date: July 12, 1192)</item>
<item>1331 – King Stefan Uroš III, after months of anarchy, surrenders to his son and rival Stefan Dušan, who succeeds as King of Serbia.</item>
<item>1680 – Pueblo Indians capture Santa Fe from the Spanish during the Pueblo Revolt.</item>
<item>1770 – James Cook formally claims eastern Australia for Great Britain, naming it New South Wales.</item>
<item>1772 – King Gustav III completes his coup d\'état by adopting a new Constitution, ending half a century of parliamentary rule in Sweden and installing himself as an enlightened despot.</item>
<item>1810 – Jean–Baptiste Bernadotte, Marshal of France, is elected Crown Prince of Sweden by the Swedish Riksdag of the Estates.</item>
<item>1821 – Jarvis Island is discovered by the crew of the ship, Eliza Frances.</item>
<item>1831 – Nat Turner leads black slaves and free blacks in a rebellion in Southampton County, Virginia, which will claim the lives of 55 to 65 whites.</item>
<item>1897 – Oldsmobile, an American automobile manufacturer and marque, is founded.</item>
<item>1901 – Six hundred American school teachers, Thomasites, arrived in Manila on the USAT Thomas.</item>
<item>1911 – The Mona Lisa is stolen by Vincenzo Perugia, a Louvre employee.</item>
<item>1944 – Dumbarton Oaks Conference, prelude to the United Nations, begins.</item>
<item>1945 – Physicist Harry Daghlian is fatally irradiated in a criticality accident during an experiment with the Demon core at Los Alamos National Laboratory.</item>
<item>1957 – The Soviet Union successfully conducts a long–range test flight of the R–7 Semyorka, the first intercontinental ballistic missile.</item>
<item>1959 – United States President Dwight D. Eisenhower signs an executive order proclaiming Hawaii the 50th state of the union. Hawaii\'s admission is currently commemorated by Hawaii Admission Day</item>
<item>1961 – American country music singer Patsy Cline returns to record producer Owen Bradley\'s studio in Nashville, Tennessee to record her vocals to Willie Nelson\'s \"Crazy\", which would become her signature song.</item>
<item>1961 – Motown releases what would be its first #1 hit (in America), \"Please Mr. Postman\" by The Marvelettes.</item>
<item>1991 – Latvia declares renewal of its full independence after its occupation by the Soviet Union since 1945.</item>
<item>1991 – Coup attempt against Mikhail Gorbachev collapses.</item>
<item>1993 – NASA loses contact with the Mars Observer spacecraft.</item>
<item>2000 – Tiger Woods, American professional golfer, wins the 82nd PGA Championship and becomes the first golfer since Ben Hogan in 1953 to win 3 majors in a calendar year.</item>
<item>2016 – The closing ceremony of the 2016 Summer Olympics in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, takes place.</item>
<item>2017 – A solar eclipse traverses the continental United States.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>