<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_29">
<item>708 – Copper coins are minted in Japan for the first time (Traditional Japanese date: August 10, 708).</item>
<item>1261 – Pope Urban IV succeeds Pope Alexander IV as the 182nd pope.</item>
<item>1484 – Pope Innocent VIII succeeds Pope Sixtus IV.</item>
<item>1498 – Vasco da Gama decides to depart Calicut and return to Kingdom of Portugal.</item>
<item>1521 – The Ottoman Turks capture Nándorfehérvár (Belgrade).</item>
<item>1541 – The Ottoman Turks capture Buda, the capital of the Hungarian Kingdom.</item>
<item>1728 – The city of Nuuk in Greenland is founded as the fort of Godt–Haab by the royal governor Claus Paarss.</item>
<item>1758 – The Treaty of Easton establishes the first American Indian reservation, at Indian Mills, New Jersey, for the Lenape.</item>
<item>1786 – Shays\' Rebellion, an armed uprising of Massachusetts farmers, begins in response to high debt and tax burdens.</item>
<item>1831 – Michael Faraday discovers electromagnetic induction.</item>
<item>1869 – The Mount Washington Cog Railway opens, making it the world\'s first mountain–climbing rack railway.</item>
<item>1871 – Emperor Meiji orders the abolition of the han system and the establishment of prefectures as local centers of administration. (Traditional Japanese date: July 14, 1871).</item>
<item>1885 – Gottlieb Daimler patents the world\'s first internal combustion motorcycle, the Reitwagen.</item>
<item>1898 – The Goodyear tire company is founded.</item>
<item>1910 – The Japan–Korea Treaty of 1910, also known as the Japan–Korea Annexation Treaty, becomes effective, officially starting the period of Japanese rule in Korea.</item>
<item>1911 – Ishi, considered the last Native American to make contact with European Americans, emerges from the wilderness of northeastern California.</item>
<item>1911 – The Canadian Naval Service becomes the Royal Canadian Navy.</item>
<item>1915 – US Navy salvage divers raise F–4, the first U.S. submarine sunk in an accident.</item>
<item>1916 – The United States passes the Philippine Autonomy Act.</item>
<item>1930 – The last 36 remaining inhabitants of St Kilda are voluntarily evacuated to other parts of Scotland.</item>
<item>1958 – United States Air Force Academy opens in Colorado Springs, Colorado.</item>
<item>1965 – The Gemini V spacecraft returns to Earth, landing in the Atlantic Ocean.</item>
<item>1966 – The Beatles perform their last concert before paying fans at Candlestick Park in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1982 – The synthetic chemical element Meitnerium, atomic number 109, is first synthesized at the Gesellschaft für Schwerionenforschung in Darmstadt, Germany.</item>
<item>1991 – Supreme Soviet of the Soviet Union suspends all activities of the Soviet Communist Party.</item>
<item>1997 – Netflix is launched as an internet DVD rental service.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>