<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_25">
<item>766 – Emperor Constantine V humiliates nineteen high–ranking officials, after discovering a plot against him. He executes the leaders, Constantine Podopagouros and his brother Strategios.</item>
<item>1248 – The Dutch city of Ommen receives city rights and fortification rights from Otto III, the Archbishop of Utrecht.</item>
<item>1537 – The Honourable Artillery Company, the oldest surviving regiment in the British Army, and the second most senior, is formed.</item>
<item>1543 – António Mota and a few companions become the first Europeans to visit Japan.</item>
<item>1609 – Galileo Galilei demonstrates his first telescope to Venetian lawmakers.</item>
<item>1823 – American fur trapper Hugh Glass is mauled by a grizzly bear while on an expedition in South Dakota.</item>
<item>1825 – Uruguay declares its independence from Brazil.</item>
<item>1835 – The first Great Moon Hoax article is published in The New York Sun, announcing the discovery of life and civilization on the Moon.</item>
<item>1875 – Captain Matthew Webb becomes the first person to swim across the English Channel, traveling from Dover, England, to Calais, France, in 21 hours and 45 minutes.</item>
<item>1883 – France and Viet Nam sign the Treaty of Huế, recognizing a French protectorate over Annam and Tonkin.</item>
<item>1894 – Kitasato Shibasaburō discovers the infectious agent of the bubonic plague and publishes his findings in The Lancet.</item>
<item>1916 – The United States National Park Service is created.</item>
<item>1939 – The United Kingdom and Poland form a military alliance in which the UK promises to defend Poland in case of invasion by a foreign power.</item>
<item>1948 – The House Un–American Activities Committee holds first–ever televised congressional hearing: \"Confrontation Day\" between Whittaker Chambers and Alger Hiss.</item>
<item>1950 – President Harry Truman orders the U.S. Army to seize control of the nation\'s railroads to avert a strike.</item>
<item>1961 – President Jânio Quadros of Brazil resigns after just seven months in power, initiating a political crisis that culminates in a military coup in 1964.</item>
<item>1980 – Zimbabwe joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1981 – Voyager 2 spacecraft makes its closest approach to Saturn.</item>
<item>1989 – Voyager 2 spacecraft makes its closest approach to Neptune, the second to last planet in the Solar System at the time.</item>
<item>1991 – Belarus gains its independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1991 – Linus Torvalds announces the first version of what will become Linux.</item>
<item>2006 – Former Prime Minister of Ukraine Pavlo Lazarenko is sentenced to nine years imprisonment for money laundering, wire fraud, and extortion.</item>
<item>2012 – Voyager 1 spacecraft enters interstellar space becoming the first man–made object to do so.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>