<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_2">
<item>461 – Majorian is arrested near Tortona (northern Italy) and deposed by the Suebian general Ricimer as puppet emperor.</item>
<item>1610 – During Henry Hudson\'s search for the Northwest Passage, he sails into what is now known as Hudson Bay.</item>
<item>1776 – The signing of the United States Declaration of Independence took place.</item>
<item>1790 – The first United States Census is conducted.</item>
<item>1830 – Charles X of France abdicates the throne in favor of his grandson Henri.</item>
<item>1858 – The Government of India Act 1858 replaces Company rule in India with that of the British Raj.</item>
<item>1869 – Japan\'s Edo society class system is abolished as part of the Meiji Restoration reforms.</item>
<item>1870 – Tower Subway, the world\'s first underground tube railway, opens in London, England, United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1873 – The Clay Street Hill Railroad begins operating the first cable car in San Francisco\'s famous cable car system.</item>
<item>1903 – The Ilinden–Preobrazhenie Uprising against the Ottoman Empire begins.</item>
<item>1918 – The first general strike in Canadian history takes place in Vancouver.</item>
<item>1932 – The positron (antiparticle of the electron) is discovered by Carl D. Anderson.</item>
<item>1937 – The Marihuana Tax Act of 1937 is passed in America, the effect of which is to render marijuana and all its by–products illegal.</item>
<item>1939 – Albert Einstein and Leo Szilard write a letter to Franklin D. Roosevelt, urging him to begin the Manhattan Project to develop a nuclear weapon.</item>
<item>1944 – ASNOM: Birth of the Socialist Republic of Macedonia, celebrated as Day of the Republic in the Republic of Macedonia.</item>
<item>1947 – A British South American Airways Avro Lancastrian airliner crashes into a mountain during a flight from Buenos Aires, Argentina to Santiago, Chile. The wreckage would not be found until 1998.</item>
<item>1989 – Pakistan is re–admitted to the Commonwealth of Nations after having restored democracy for the first time since 1972.</item>
<item>2005 – Air France Flight 358 lands at Toronto Pearson International Airport and runs off the runway, causing the plane to burst into flames leaving 12 injuries and no fatalities.</item>
<item>2018 – Apple Inc. became the first U.S. company to be valued at over $1 trillion.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>