<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_28">
<item>475 – The Roman general Orestes forces western Roman Emperor Julius Nepos to flee his capital city, Ravenna.</item>
<item>1189 – Third Crusade: The Crusaders begin the Siege of Acre under Guy of Lusignan.</item>
<item>1521 – The Ottoman Turks occupy Belgrade.</item>
<item>1524 – The Kaqchikel Maya rebel against their former Spanish allies during the Spanish conquest of Guatemala.</item>
<item>1565 – Pedro Menéndez de Avilés sights land near St. Augustine, Florida and founds the oldest continuously occupied European–established city in the continental United States.</item>
<item>1619 – Election of Ferdinand II, Holy Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1709 – Meidingnu Pamheiba is crowned King of Manipur.</item>
<item>1789 – William Herschel discovers a new moon of Saturn: Enceladus.</item>
<item>1830 – The Baltimore and Ohio Railroad\'s new Tom Thumb steam locomotive races a horse–drawn car, presaging steam\'s role in U.S. railroads.</item>
<item>1833 – King William IV gives Royal Assent to the Slavery Abolition Act 1833, although slavery remained legal in the possessions of the East India Company until the passage of the Indian Slavery Act, 1843.</item>
<item>1845 – The first issue of Scientific American magazine is published.</item>
<item>1849 – After a month–long siege, Venice, which had declared itself independent as the Republic of San Marco, surrenders to Austria.</item>
<item>1859 – The Carrington event is the strongest geomagnetic storm on record to strike the Earth. Electrical telegraph service is widely disrupted.</item>
<item>1867 – The United States takes possession of the (at this point unoccupied) Midway Atoll.</item>
<item>1879 – Cetshwayo, last king of the Zulus, is captured by the British.</item>
<item>1898 – Caleb Bradham\'s beverage \"Brad\'s Drink\" is renamed \"Pepsi–Cola\".</item>
<item>1901 – Silliman University is founded in the Philippines. It is the first American private school in the country.</item>
<item>1909 – A group of mid–level Greek Army officers launches the Goudi coup, seeking wide–ranging reforms.</item>
<item>1913 – Queen Wilhelmina opens the Peace Palace in The Hague.</item>
<item>1917 – Ten Suffragettes are arrested while picketing the White House.</item>
<item>1924 – The Georgian opposition stages the August Uprising against the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1937 – Toyota Motors becomes an independent company.</item>
<item>1957 – U.S. Senator Strom Thurmond begins a filibuster to prevent the Senate from voting on Civil Rights Act of 1957; he stopped speaking 24 hours and 18 minutes later, the longest filibuster ever conducted by a single Senator.</item>
<item>1963 – March on Washington for Jobs and Freedom: The Reverend Martin Luther King, Jr. gives his I Have a Dream speech</item>
<item>1964 – The Philadelphia race riot begins.</item>
<item>1968 – Rioting takes place in Chicago during the Democratic National Convention, triggering a brutal police crackdown.</item>
<item>1990 – Iraq declares Kuwait to be its newest province.</item>
<item>1993 – The Galileo spacecraft discovers a moon, later named Dactyl, around 243 Ida, the first known asteroid moon.</item>
<item>1998 – Pakistan\'s National Assembly passes a constitutional amendment to make the \"Qur\'an and Sunnah\" the \"supreme law\" but the bill is defeated in the Senate.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>