<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_22">
<item>392 – Arbogast has Eugenius elected Western Roman Emperor.</item>
<item>1559 – Bartolomé Carranza, Spanish archbishop, is arrested for heresy.</item>
<item>1614 – Fettmilch Uprising: Jews are expelled from Frankfurt, Holy Roman Empire, following the plundering of the Judengasse.</item>
<item>1639 – Madras (now Chennai), India, is founded by the British East India Company on a sliver of land bought from local Nayak rulers.</item>
<item>1654 – Jacob Barsimson arrives in New Amsterdam. He is the first known Jewish immigrant to America.</item>
<item>1717 – Spanish troops land on Sardinia.</item>
<item>1770 – James Cook names and lands on Possession Island, and claims the east coast of Australia for Britain as New South Wales.</item>
<item>1777 – British forces abandon the Siege of Fort Stanwix after hearing rumors of Continental Army reinforcements.</item>
<item>1798 – French troops land at Kilcummin, County Mayo, Ireland to aid the rebellion.</item>
<item>1827 – José de la Mar becomes President of Peru.</item>
<item>1846 – The Second Federal Republic of Mexico is established.</item>
<item>1851 – The first America\'s Cup is won by the yacht America.</item>
<item>1864 – Twelve nations sign the First Geneva Convention, establishing the rules of protection of the victims of armed conflicts.</item>
<item>1875 – The Treaty of Saint Petersburg between Japan and Russia is ratified, providing for the exchange of Sakhalin for the Kuril Islands.</item>
<item>1894 – Mahatma Gandhi forms the Natal Indian Congress (NIC) in order to fight discrimination against Indian traders in Natal.</item>
<item>1902 – Cadillac Motor Company is founded.</item>
<item>1902 – Theodore Roosevelt becomes the first President of the United States to make a public appearance in an automobile.</item>
<item>1934 – Bill Woodfull of Australia becomes the only cricket captain to twice regain The Ashes.</item>
<item>1953 – The penal colony on Devil\'s Island is permanently closed.</item>
<item>1962 – The OAS attempts to assassinate French president Charles de Gaulle.</item>
<item>1963 – X–15 Flight 91 reaches the highest altitude of the X–15 program (107.96 km (67.08 mi) (354,200 feet)).</item>
<item>1966 – Labor movements NFWA and AWOC merge to become the United Farm Workers Organizing Committee (UFWOC), predecessor of the United Farm Workers.</item>
<item>1968 – Pope Paul VI arrives in Bogotá, Colombia. It is the first visit of a pope to Latin America.</item>
<item>1971 – J. Edgar Hoover and John Mitchell announce the arrest of 20 of the Camden 28.</item>
<item>1972 – Rhodesia is expelled by the IOC for its racist policies.</item>
<item>1973 – The Congress of Chile votes in favour of a resolution condemning President Salvador Allende\'s government and demands that he resign or else be unseated through force and new elections.</item>
<item>1978 – The Sandinista National Liberation Front (FLSN) occupies national palace in Nicaragua.</item>
<item>1978 – The District of Columbia Voting Rights Amendment is passed by the U.S. Congress. The proposed amendment would have provided the District of Columbia with full voting representation in the Congress, the Electoral College, and regarding amending the U.S. Constitution. The proposed amendment failed to be ratified by enough states (ratified by 16, needed 38) and so did not become part of the Constitution.</item>
<item>1989 – Nolan Ryan strikes out Rickey Henderson to become the first Major League Baseball pitcher to record 5,000 strikeouts.</item>
<item>2003 – Alabama Chief Justice Roy Moore is suspended after refusing to comply with a federal court order to remove a rock inscribed with the Ten Commandments from the lobby of the Alabama Supreme Court building.</item>
<item>2004 – Versions of The Scream and Madonna, two paintings by Edvard Munch, are stolen at gunpoint from a museum in Oslo, Norway.</item>
<item>2007 – The Texas Rangers defeat the Baltimore Orioles 30–3, the most runs scored by a team in modern Major League Baseball history.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>