<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_20">
<item>1083 – Canonization of the first King of Hungary, Saint Stephen and his son Saint Emeric celebrated as a National Day in Hungary.</item>
<item>1308 – Pope Clement V pardons Jacques de Molay, the last Grand Master of the Knights Templar, absolving him of charges of heresy.</item>
<item>1391 – Konrad von Wallenrode becomes the 24th Grand Master of the Teutonic Order.</item>
<item>1519 – Philosopher and general Wang Yangming defeats Zhu Chenhao, ending the Prince of Ning rebellion against the reign of the Ming dynasty\'s Zhengde Emperor.</item>
<item>1707 – The first Siege of Pensacola comes to end with the failure of the British to capture Pensacola, Florida.</item>
<item>1775 – The Spanish establish the Presidio San Augustin del Tucson in the town that became Tucson, Arizona.</item>
<item>1852 – Steamboat Atlantic sank on Lake Erie after a collision, with the loss of at least 150 lives.</item>
<item>1858 – Charles Darwin first publishes his theory of evolution through natural selection in The Journal of the Proceedings of the Linnean Society of London, alongside Alfred Russel Wallace\'s same theory.</item>
<item>1882 – Tchaikovsky\'s 1812 Overture debuts in Moscow, Russia.</item>
<item>1920 – The first commercial radio station, 8MK (now WWJ), begins operations in Detroit.</item>
<item>1920 – The National Football League is organized as the American Professional Football Conference in Canton, Ohio</item>
<item>1926 – Japan\'s public broadcasting company, Nippon Hōsō Kyōkai (NHK) is established.</item>
<item>1938 – Lou Gehrig hits his 23rd career grand slam, a record that stood for 75 years until it was broken by Alex Rodriguez.</item>
<item>1960 – Senegal breaks from the Mali Federation, declaring its independence.</item>
<item>1962 – The NS Savannah, the world\'s first nuclear–powered civilian ship, embarks on its maiden voyage.</item>
<item>1977 – Voyager program: NASA launches the Voyager 2 spacecraft.</item>
<item>1986 – In Edmond, Oklahoma, U.S. Postal employee Patrick Sherrill guns down 14 of his co–workers and then commits suicide.</item>
<item>1988 – \"Black Saturday\" of the Yellowstone fire in Yellowstone National Park</item>
<item>1991 – Dissolution of the Soviet Union, August Coup: More than 100,000 people rally outside the Soviet Union\'s parliament building protesting the coup aiming to depose President Mikhail Gorbachev.</item>
<item>1993 – After rounds of secret negotiations in Norway, the Oslo Accords are signed, followed by a public ceremony in Washington, D.C. the following month.</item>
<item>1998 – The Supreme Court of Canada rules that Quebec cannot legally secede from Canada without the federal government\'s approval.</item>
<item>2007 – China Airlines Flight 120 caught fire and exploded after landing at Naha Airport in Okinawa, Japan.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>