<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_27">
<item>410 – The sacking of Rome by the Visigoths ends after three days.</item>
<item>1172 – Henry the Young King and Margaret of France are crowned junior king and queen of England.</item>
<item>1689 – The Treaty of Nerchinsk is signed by Russia and the Qing Empire (Julian calendar).</item>
<item>1828 – Brazil and Argentina recognize the sovereignty of Uruguay in the Treaty of Montevideo</item>
<item>1859 – Petroleum is discovered in Titusville, Pennsylvania leading to the world\'s first commercially successful oil well.</item>
<item>1927 – Five Canadian women file a petition to the Supreme Court of Canada, asking, \"Does the word \'Persons\' in Section 24 of the British North America Act, 1867, include female persons?\"</item>
<item>1933 – The first Afrikaans Bible is introduced during a Bible Festival in Bloemfontein.</item>
<item>1939 – First flight of the turbojet–powered Heinkel He 178, the world\'s first jet aircraft.</item>
<item>1942 – First day of the Sarny Massacre.</item>
<item>1956 – The nuclear power station at Calder Hall in the United Kingdom was connected to the national power grid becoming the world\'s first commercial nuclear power station to generate electricity on an industrial scale.</item>
<item>1962 – The Mariner 2 unmanned space mission is launched to Venus by NASA.</item>
<item>1964 – South Vietnamese junta leader Nguyễn Khánh enters into a triumvirate power–sharing arrangement with rival generals Trần Thiện Khiêm and Dương Văn Minh, who had both been involved in plots to unseat Khánh.</item>
<item>1971 – An attempted coup d\'état fails in the African nation of Chad. The Government of Chad accuses Egypt of playing a role in the attempt and breaks off diplomatic relations.</item>
<item>1975 – The Governor of Portuguese Timor abandons its capital, Dili, and flees to Atauro Island, leaving control to a rebel group.</item>
<item>1985 – The Nigerian government is peacefully overthrown by Army Chief of Staff Major General Ibrahim Babangida.</item>
<item>1991 – The European Community recognizes the independence of the Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania.</item>
<item>1991 – Moldova declares independence from the USSR.</item>
<item>2003 – Mars makes its closest approach to Earth in nearly 60,000 years, passing 34,646,418 miles (55,758,005 km) distant.</item>
<item>2003 – The first six–party talks, involving South and North Korea, the United States, China, Japan and Russia, convene to find a peaceful resolution to the security concerns of the North Korean nuclear weapons program.</item>
<item>2009 – Internal conflict in Burma: The Burmese military junta and ethnic armies begin three days of violent clashes in the Kokang Special Region.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>