<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_24">
<item>79 AD – Mount Vesuvius erupts. The cities of Pompeii, Herculaneum, and Stabiae are buried in volcanic ash (note: this traditional date has been challenged, and many scholars believe that the event occurred on October 24).</item>
<item>367 – Gratian, son of Roman Emperor Valentinian I, is named co–Augustus at the age of eight by his father .</item>
<item>394 – The Graffito of Esmet–Akhom, the latest known inscription in Egyptian hieroglyphs, was written.</item>
<item>410 – The Visigoths under king Alaric I begin to pillage Rome.</item>
<item>1185 – Sack of Thessalonica by the Normans.</item>
<item>1200 – King John of England, signer of the first Magna Carta, marries Isabella of Angoulême in Bordeaux Cathedral.</item>
<item>1215 – Pope Innocent III declares Magna Carta invalid.</item>
<item>1456 – The printing of the Gutenberg Bible is completed.</item>
<item>1482 – The town and castle of Berwick upon Tweed is captured from Scotland by an English army</item>
<item>1561 – Willem of Orange marries duchess Anna of Saxony.</item>
<item>1608 – The first official English representative to India lands in Surat.</item>
<item>1662 – The Act of Uniformity requires England to accept the Book of Common Prayer.</item>
<item>1690 – Job Charnock of the East India Company establishes a factory in Calcutta, an event formerly considered the founding of the city (in 2003 the Calcutta High Court ruled that the city\'s foundation date is unknown).</item>
<item>1815 – The modern Constitution of the Netherlands is signed.</item>
<item>1816 – The Treaty of St. Louis is signed in St. Louis, Missouri.</item>
<item>1820 – Constitutionalist insurrection at Oporto, Portugal.</item>
<item>1857 – The Panic of 1857 begins, setting off one of the most severe economic crises in United States history.</item>
<item>1870 – The Wolseley expedition reaches Manitoba to end the Red River Rebellion.</item>
<item>1891 – Thomas Edison patents the motion picture camera.</item>
<item>1898 – Count Muravyov, Foreign Minister of Russia presents a rescript that convoked the First Hague Peace Conference.</item>
<item>1909 – Workers start pouring concrete for the Panama Canal.</item>
<item>1911 – Manuel de Arriaga is elected and sworn–in as the first President of Portugal.</item>
<item>1931 – France and the Soviet Union sign a neutrality pact.</item>
<item>1931 – Resignation of the United Kingdom\'s Second Labour Government. Formation of the UK National Government.</item>
<item>1936 – The Australian Antarctic Territory is created.</item>
<item>1949 – The treaty creating the North Atlantic Treaty Organization goes into effect.</item>
<item>1950 – Edith Sampson becomes the first black U.S. delegate to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1954 – The Communist Control Act goes into effect, outlawing the American Communist Party.</item>
<item>1954 – Getúlio Vargas, president of Brazil, commits suicide and is succeeded by João Café Filho.</item>
<item>1967 – Led by Abbie Hoffman, the Youth International Party temporarily disrupts trading at the New York Stock Exchange by throwing dollar bills from the viewing gallery, causing trading to cease as brokers scramble to grab them.</item>
<item>1989 – Cincinnati Reds manager Pete Rose is banned from baseball for gambling by Commissioner A. Bartlett Giamatti.</item>
<item>1989 – Tadeusz Mazowiecki is chosen as the first non–communist prime minister in Central and Eastern Europe.</item>
<item>1991 – Mikhail Gorbachev resigns as head of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1991 – Ukraine declares itself independent from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1994 – Initial accord between Israel and the PLO about partial self–rule of the Palestinians on the West Bank.</item>
<item>1995 – Microsoft Windows 95 was released to the public in North America.</item>
<item>1998 – First radio–frequency identification (RFID) human implantation tested in the United Kingdom.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>