<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_31">
<item>1057 – Abdication of Byzantine Emperor Michael VI Bringas after just one year.</item>
<item>1218 – Al–Kamil becomes sultan of the Ayyubid dynasty.</item>
<item>1314 – King Haakon V of Norway moves the capital from Bergen to Oslo.</item>
<item>1776 – William Livingston, the first Governor of New Jersey, begins serving his first term.</item>
<item>1798 – Irish Rebellion of 1798: Irish rebels, with French assistance, establish the short–lived Republic of Connacht.</item>
<item>1876 – Ottoman Sultan Murad V is deposed and succeeded by his brother Abdul Hamid II.</item>
<item>1895 – German Count Ferdinand von Zeppelin patents his navigable balloon.</item>
<item>1897 – Thomas Edison patents the Kinetoscope, the first movie projector.</item>
<item>1907 – Russia and the United Kingdom sign the Anglo–Russian Convention, by which the UK recognizes Russian preeminence in northern Persia, while Russia recognizes British preeminence in southeastern Persia and Afghanistan. Both powers pledge not to interfere in Tibet.</item>
<item>1920 – The first radio news program is broadcast by 8MK in Detroit.</item>
<item>1935 – In an attempt to stay out of the growing tensions concerning Germany and Japan, the United States passes the first of its Neutrality Acts.</item>
<item>1936 – Radio Prague, now the official international broadcasting station of the Czech Republic, goes on the air.</item>
<item>1940 – Pennsylvania Central Airlines Trip 19 crashes near Lovettsville, Virginia. The CAB investigation of the accident is the first investigation to be conducted under the Bureau of Air Commerce act of 1938.</item>
<item>1943 – USS Harmon, the first U.S. Navy ship to be named after a black person, is commissioned.</item>
<item>1957 – The Federation of Malaya (now Malaysia) gains its independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1962 – Trinidad and Tobago becomes independent.</item>
<item>1963 – Crown Colony of North Borneo (now Sabah) achieves self governance.</item>
<item>1991 – Kyrgyzstan declares its independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1993 – Russia completes removing its troops from Lithuania.</item>
<item>1994 – Russia completes removing its troops from Estonia.</item>
<item>1996 – Saddam Hussein\'s troops seized Irbil after the Kurdish Masoud Barzani appealed for help to defeat his Kurdish rival PUK.</item>
<item>2016 – Brazil\'s President Dilma Rousseff is impeached and removed from office.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>