<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_3">
<item>435 – Deposed Ecumenical Patriarch of Constantinople Nestorius, considered the originator of Nestorianism, is exiled by Roman Emperor Theodosius II to a monastery in Egypt.</item>
<item>1031 – Olaf II of Norway is canonized as Saint Olaf by Grimketel, the English Bishop of Selsey.</item>
<item>1057 – Frederik van Lotharingen elected as first Belgian Pope Stephen IX.</item>
<item>1342 – The Siege of Algeciras commences during the Spanish Reconquista.</item>
<item>1492 – Christopher Columbus sets sail from Palos de la Frontera, Spain.</item>
<item>1527 – The first known letter from North America is sent by John Rut while at St. John\'s, Newfoundland.</item>
<item>1678 – Robert LaSalle builds the Le Griffon, the first known ship built on the Great Lakes.</item>
<item>1778 – The theatre La Scala in Milan is inaugurated with the première of Antonio Salieri\'s Europa riconosciuta.</item>
<item>1811 – First ascent of Jungfrau, third highest summit in the Bernese Alps by brothers Johann Rudolf and Hieronymus Meyer.</item>
<item>1829 – The Treaty of Lewistown is signed by the Shawnee and Seneca peoples, exchanging land in Ohio for land west of the Mississippi River.</item>
<item>1852 – Harvard University wins the first Boat Race between Yale University and Harvard. The race is also the first American intercollegiate athletic event</item>
<item>1859 – The American Dental Association is founded in Niagara Falls, New York.</item>
<item>1903 – Macedonian rebels in Kruševo proclaim the Kruševo Republic, which exists only for ten days before Ottoman Turks lay waste to the town.</item>
<item>1907 – Judge Kenesaw Mountain Landis fines Standard Oil of Indiana a record $29.4 million for illegal rebating to freight carriers; the conviction and fine are later reversed on appeal.</item>
<item>1921 – Major League Baseball Commissioner Kenesaw Mountain Landis confirms the ban of the eight Chicago Black Sox, the day after they were acquitted by a Chicago court.</item>
<item>1936 – Jesse Owens wins the 100 metre dash, defeating Ralph Metcalfe, at the Berlin Olympics.</item>
<item>1946 – Santa Claus Land, the world\'s first themed amusement park, opens in Santa Claus, Indiana, United States.</item>
<item>1948 – Whittaker Chambers accuses Alger Hiss of being a communist and a spy for the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1949 – The Basketball Association of America and the National Basketball League finalize the merger, that would create the National Basketball Association</item>
<item>1958 – The world\'s first nuclear submarine, the USS Nautilus, became the first vessel to complete a submerged transit of the geographical North Pole.</item>
<item>1960 – Niger gains independence from France.</item>
<item>1972 – The United States Senate ratifies the Anti–Ballistic Missile Treaty.</item>
<item>1977 – Tandy Corporation announces the TRS–80, one of the world\'s first mass–produced personal computers.</item>
<item>1981 – Senegalese opposition parties, under the leadership of Mamadou Dia, launch the Antiimperialist Action Front – Suxxali Reew Mi.</item>
<item>2005 – President of Mauritania Maaouya Ould Sid\'Ahmed Taya is overthrown in a military coup while attending the funeral of King Fahd in Saudi Arabia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>