<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_5">
<item>135 – Roman armies enter Betar, slaughtering thousands and ending the bar Kokhba revolt.</item>
<item>1100 – Henry I is crowned King of England in Westminster Abbey.</item>
<item>1278 – Spanish Reconquista: the forces of the Kingdom of Castile initiate the ultimately futile Siege of Algeciras against the Emirate of Granada.</item>
<item>1583 – Sir Humphrey Gilbert establishes the first English colony in North America, at what is now St. John\'s, Newfoundland and Labrador.</item>
<item>1600 – The Gowrie Conspiracy against King James VI of Scotland (later to become King James I of England) takes place.</item>
<item>1620 – The Mayflower departs from Southampton, England on its first attempt to reach North America.</item>
<item>1735 – Freedom of the press: New York Weekly Journal writer John Peter Zenger is acquitted of seditious libel against the royal governor of New York, on the basis that what he had published was true.</item>
<item>1816 – The British Admiralty dismisses Francis Ronalds\'s new invention of the first working electric telegraph as \"wholly unnecessary\", preferring to continue using the semaphore.</item>
<item>1858 – Cyrus West Field and others complete the first transatlantic telegraph cable after several unsuccessful attempts. It will operate for less than a month.</item>
<item>1860 – Charles XV of Sweden of Sweden–Norway is crowned king of Norway in Trondheim.</item>
<item>1861 – The United States Army abolishes flogging.</item>
<item>1874 – Japan launches its postal savings system, modeled after a similar system in the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1882 – The Standard Oil of New Jersey is established.</item>
<item>1884 – The cornerstone for the Statue of Liberty is laid on Bedloe\'s Island (now Liberty Island) in New York Harbor.</item>
<item>1888 – Bertha Benz drives from Mannheim to Pforzheim and back in the first long distance automobile trip, commemorated as the Bertha Benz Memorial Route since 2008.</item>
<item>1901 – Peter O\'Connor sets the first IAAF recognised long jump world record of 24 ft 11.75 in (7.6137 m). The record will stand for 20 years.</item>
<item>1914 – In Cleveland, Ohio, the first electric traffic light is installed.</item>
<item>1925 – Plaid Cymru is formed with the aim of disseminating knowledge of the Welsh language that is at the time in danger of dying out.</item>
<item>1926 – Harry Houdini performs his greatest feat, spending 91 minutes underwater in a sealed tank before escaping.</item>
<item>1957 – American Bandstand, a show dedicated to the teenage \"baby–boomers\" by playing the songs and showing popular dances of the time, debuts on the ABC television network.</item>
<item>1960 – Burkina Faso, then known as Upper Volta, becomes independent from France.</item>
<item>1962 – Apartheid: Nelson Mandela is jailed. He would not be released until 1990.</item>
<item>1971 – The first Pacific Islands Forum (then known as the \"South Pacific Forum\") is held in Wellington, New Zealand, with the aim of enhancing cooperation between the independent countries of the Pacific Ocean.</item>
<item>1973 – Mars 6 is launched from the USSR</item>
<item>1979 – In Afghanistan, Maoists undertake the Bala Hissar uprising against the Leninist government.</item>
<item>1981 – President Ronald Reagan fires 11,359 striking air–traffic controllers who ignored his order for them to return to work.</item>
<item>1989 – General elections are held in Nicaragua with the Sandinista National Liberation Front winning a majority.</item>
<item>2010 – The Copiapó mining accident occurs, trapping 33 Chilean miners approximately 2,300 ft (700 m) below the ground for 69 days.</item>
<item>2015 – The Environmental Protection Agency at Gold King Mine waste water spill releases 3 million gallons of heavy metal toxin tailings and waste water into the Animas River in Colorado.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>