<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_7">
<item>461 – Roman Emperor Majorian is beheaded near the river Iria in north–west Italy following his arrest and deposition by the magister militum Ricimer.</item>
<item>626 – The Avar and Slav armies leave the siege of Constantinople.</item>
<item>768 – Pope Stephen II is elected to office, and quickly seeks Frankish protection against the Lombard threat, since the Byzantine Empire is no longer able to help.</item>
<item>936 – Coronation of King Otto I of Germany.</item>
<item>1420 – Construction of the dome of Santa Maria del Fiore begins in Florence.</item>
<item>1461 – The Ming dynasty Chinese military general Cao Qin stages a coup against the Tianshun Emperor.</item>
<item>1679 – The brigantine Le Griffon, commissioned by René–Robert Cavelier, Sieur de La Salle, is towed to the south–eastern end of the Niagara River, to become the first ship to sail the upper Great Lakes of North America.</item>
<item>1786 – The first federal Indian Reservation is created by the United States.</item>
<item>1794 – U.S. President George Washington invokes the Militia Acts of 1792 to suppress the Whiskey Rebellion in western Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1858 – The first Australian rules football match is played between Melbourne Grammar and Scotch College.</item>
<item>1879 – The opening of the Poor Man\'s Palace in Manchester, England.</item>
<item>1909 – Alice Huyler Ramsey and three friends become the first women to complete a transcontinental auto trip, taking 59 days to travel from New York, New York to San Francisco, California.</item>
<item>1927 – The Peace Bridge opens between Fort Erie, Ontario and Buffalo, New York.</item>
<item>1933 – The Kingdom of Iraq slaughters over 3,000 Assyrians in the village of Simele.</item>
<item>1938 – The building of Mauthausen concentration camp begins.</item>
<item>1944 – IBM dedicates the first program–controlled calculator, the Automatic Sequence Controlled Calculator (known best as the Harvard Mark I).</item>
<item>1946 – The government of the Soviet Union presented a note to its Turkish counterparts which refuted the latter\'s sovereignty over the Turkish Straits, thus beginning the Turkish Straits crisis.</item>
<item>1947 – Thor Heyerdahl\'s balsa wood raft the Kon–Tiki, smashes into the reef at Raroia in the Tuamotu Islands after a 101–day, 7,000 kilometres (4,300 mi) journey across the Pacific Ocean in an attempt to prove that pre–historic peoples could have traveled from South America.</item>
<item>1955 – Tokyo Telecommunications Engineering, the precursor to Sony, sells its first transistor radios in Japan.</item>
<item>1959 – The Lincoln Memorial design on the U.S. penny goes into circulation. It replaces the \"sheaves of wheat\" design, and was minted until 2008.</item>
<item>1959 – Explorer program: Explorer 6 launches from the Atlantic Missile Range in Cape Canaveral, Florida.</item>
<item>1960 – Ivory Coast becomes independent from France.</item>
<item>1969 – Richard Nixon appoints Luis R. Bruce, a Mohawk–Oglala Sioux and co–founder of the National Congress of American Indians, as the new commissioner of the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</item>
<item>1974 – Philippe Petit performs a high wire act between the twin towers of the World Trade Center 1,368 feet (417 m) in the air.</item>
<item>1976 – Viking program: Viking 2 enters orbit around Mars.</item>
<item>1978 – U.S. President Jimmy Carter declares a federal emergency at Love Canal due to toxic waste that had been disposed of negligently.</item>
<item>1981 – The Washington Star ceases all operations after 128 years of publication.</item>
<item>1985 – Takao Doi, Mamoru Mohri and Chiaki Mukai are chosen to be Japan\'s first astronauts.</item>
<item>1987 – Lynne Cox becomes first person to swim from the United States to the Soviet Union, crossing the Bering Strait from Little Diomede Island in Alaska to Big Diomede in the Soviet Union</item>
<item>1993 – Ada Deer, a Menominee activist, swears in as the head of the U.S. Bureau of Indian Affairs.</item>
<item>1999 – The Chechnya–based Islamic International Brigade invades neighboring Dagestan.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>