<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a8_9">
<item>1173 – Construction of the campanile of the Cathedral of Pisa (now known as the Leaning Tower of Pisa) begins; it will take two centuries to complete.</item>
<item>1329 – Quilon, the first Indian Christian Diocese, is erected by Pope John XXII; the French–born Jordanus is appointed the first Bishop.</item>
<item>1810 – Napoleon annexes Westphalia as part of the First French Empire.</item>
<item>1830 – Louis Philippe becomes the king of the French following abdication of Charles X.</item>
<item>1842 – The Webster–Ashburton Treaty is signed, establishing the United States–Canada border east of the Rocky Mountains.</item>
<item>1854 – Henry David Thoreau publishes Walden.</item>
<item>1892 – Thomas Edison receives a patent for a two–way telegraph.</item>
<item>1907 – The first Boy Scout encampment concludes at Brownsea Island in southern England.</item>
<item>1925 – A train robbery takes place in Kakori, near Lucknow, India</item>
<item>1930 – Betty Boop makes her cartoon debut in Dizzy Dishes.</item>
<item>1936 – Summer Olympic Games: Games of the XI Olympiad: Jesse Owens wins his fourth gold medal at the games.</item>
<item>1942 – Quit India Movement : Katra Neel, Chandni Chowk, Delhi. – Historic Day for India :– On 9 August 1942, protest was made at historic place outside Katra Neel, Chandni Chowk, Delhi by Sh. Nanak Chand Mishra S/o. Sh.Hanuman Prashad Mishra along with his associates. During the course of firing, Sh. Nanak Chand Mishra sustained \"Bullet Injuries\". On 15 August 1972, Honourable Prime Minister Smt. Indira Gandhi honoured Sh. Nanak Chand Mishra with \"Tamrapatra\" being Freedom Fighter for his struggle in independence of country India</item>
<item>1945 – The Red Army invades Japanese–occupied Manchuria.</item>
<item>1960 – South Kasai secedes from the Congo.</item>
<item>1965 – Singapore is expelled from Malaysia and becomes the only country to date to gain independence unwillingly.</item>
<item>1973 – Mars 7 is launched from the USSR.</item>
<item>1974 – As a direct result of the Watergate scandal, Richard Nixon becomes the first President of the United States to resign from office. His Vice President, Gerald Ford, becomes president.</item>
<item>1993 – The Liberal Democratic Party of Japan loses a 38–year hold on national leadership.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>