<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_15">
<item>668 – Eastern Roman Emperor Constans II is assassinated in his bath at Syracuse, Italy.</item>
<item>1530 – Appearance of the miraculous portrait of Saint Dominic in Soriano in Soriano Calabro, Calabria, Italy; commemorated as a feast day by the Roman Catholic Church 1644–1912.</item>
<item>1556 – Departing from Vlissingen, ex–Holy Roman Emperor Charles V returns to Spain.</item>
<item>1616 – Joseph Calasanz opens the first modern public elementary school.</item>
<item>1789 – The United States \"Department of Foreign Affairs\", established by law in July, is renamed the Department of State and given a variety of domestic duties.</item>
<item>1795 – Britain seizes the Dutch Cape Colony in southern Africa to prevent its use by the Batavian Republic.</item>
<item>1812 – The French army under Napoleon reaches the Kremlin in Moscow.</item>
<item>1816 – HMS Whiting runs aground on the Doom Bar</item>
<item>1821 – The Captaincy General of Guatemala declares independence from Spain.</item>
<item>1835 – HMS Beagle, with Charles Darwin aboard, reaches the Galápagos Islands. The ship lands at Chatham or San Cristobal, the easternmost of the archipelago.</item>
<item>1851 – Saint Joseph\'s University is founded in Philadelphia.</item>
<item>1915 – The Empire Picture Theatre (now The New Empire Cinema), the oldest running cinema in mainland Australia, opens in Bowral, New South Wales.</item>
<item>1935 – The Nuremberg Laws deprive German Jews of citizenship.</item>
<item>1944 – Franklin D. Roosevelt and Winston Churchill meet in Quebec as part of the Octagon Conference to discuss strategy.</item>
<item>1948 – The Indian Army captures the towns of Jalna, Latur, Mominabad, Surriapet and Narkatpalli as part of Operation Polo.</item>
<item>1948 – The F–86 Sabre sets the world aircraft speed record at 671 miles per hour (1,080 km/h).</item>
<item>1952 – The United Nations cedes Eritrea to Ethiopia.</item>
<item>1959 – Nikita Khrushchev becomes the first Soviet leader to visit the United States.</item>
<item>1968 – The Soviet Zond 5 spaceship is launched, becoming the first spacecraft to fly around the Moon and re–enter the Earth\'s atmosphere.</item>
<item>1971 – The first Greenpeace ship sets sail to protest against nuclear testing on Amchitka Island.</item>
<item>1972 – A Scandinavian Airlines System domestic flight from Gothenburg to Stockholm is hijacked and flown to Malmö Bulltofta Airport.</item>
<item>1974 – Air Vietnam Flight 706 is hijacked, then crashes while attempting to land with 75 on board.</item>
<item>1975 – The French department of \"Corse\" (the entire island of Corsica) is divided into two: Haute–Corse (Upper Corsica) and Corse–du–Sud (Southern Corsica)</item>
<item>1978 – Muhammad Ali outpointed Leon Spinks in a rematch to become the first boxer to win the world heavyweight title three times at the Superdome in New Orleans.</item>
<item>1981 – The Senate Judiciary Committee unanimously approves Sandra Day O\'Connor to become the first female justice of the Supreme Court of the United States</item>
<item>1981 – The John Bull becomes the oldest operable steam locomotive in the world when the Smithsonian Institution operates it under its own power outside Washington, D.C.</item>
<item>1983 – Israeli premier Menachem Begin resigns.</item>
<item>2000 – The Summer Olympics officially known as the games of the XXVII Olympiad were opened in Sydney, Australia.</item>
<item>2001 – President George W. Bush gives his first post September 11th weekly address.</item>
<item>2004 – National Hockey League commissioner Gary Bettman announces lockout of the players\' union and cessation of operations by the NHL head office.</item>
<item>2008 – Lehman Brothers files for Chapter 11 bankruptcy, the largest bankruptcy filing in U.S. history.</item>
<item>2017 – The Cassini–Huygens probe is retired.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>