<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_13">
<item>585 BC – Lucius Tarquinius Priscus, king of Rome, celebrates a triumph for his victories over the Sabines, and the surrender of Collatia.</item>
<item>509 BC – The Temple of Jupiter Optimus Maximus on Rome\'s Capitoline Hill is dedicated on the ides of September.</item>
<item>379 – Yax Nuun Ahiin I is crowned as 15th Ajaw of Tikal</item>
<item>1229 – Ögedei Khan is proclaimed Khagan of the Mongol Empire in Kodoe Aral, Khentii: Mongolia.</item>
<item>1501 – Italian Renaissance: Michelangelo begins work on his statue of David.</item>
<item>1541 – After three years of exile, John Calvin returns to Geneva to reform the church under a body of doctrine known as Calvinism.</item>
<item>1584 – San Lorenzo del Escorial Palace in Madrid is finished.</item>
<item>1609 – Henry Hudson reaches the river that would later be named after him – the Hudson River.</item>
<item>1743 – Great Britain, Austria and the Kingdom of Sardinia sign the Treaty of Worms.</item>
<item>1788 – The Philadelphia Convention sets the date for the first presidential election in the United States, and New York City becomes the country\'s temporary capital.</item>
<item>1791 – King Louis XVI of France accepts the new constitution.</item>
<item>1843 – The Greek Army rebels (OS date: September 3) against the autocratic rule of king Otto of Greece, demanding the granting of a constitution.</item>
<item>1848 – Vermont railroad worker Phineas Gage survives an iron rod 1 1⁄4 inches (3.2 cm) in diameter being driven through his brain; the reported effects on his behavior and personality stimulate thinking about the nature of the brain and its functions.</item>
<item>1898 – Hannibal Goodwin patents celluloid photographic film.</item>
<item>1899 – Mackinder, Ollier and Brocherel make the first ascent of Batian (5,199 m – 17,058 ft), the highest peak of Mount Kenya.</item>
<item>1906 – The Santos–Dumont 14–bis makes a short hop, the first flight of a fixed–wing aircraft in Europe.</item>
<item>1923 – Following a military coup in Spain, Miguel Primo de Rivera takes over, setting up a dictatorship.</item>
<item>1933 – Elizabeth McCombs becomes the first woman elected to the New Zealand Parliament.</item>
<item>1948 – Deputy Prime Minister of India Vallabhbhai Patel orders the Army to move into Hyderabad to integrate it with the Indian Union.</item>
<item>1948 – Margaret Chase Smith is elected United States senator, and becomes the first woman to serve in both the U.S. House of Representatives and the United States Senate.</item>
<item>1953 – Nikita Khrushchev is appointed General Secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1956 – The IBM 305 RAMAC is introduced, the first commercial computer to use disk storage.</item>
<item>1956 – The dike around the Dutch polder East Flevoland is closed.</item>
<item>1962 – An appeals court orders the University of Mississippi to admit James Meredith, the first African–American student admitted to the segregated university.</item>
<item>1964 – South Vietnamese Generals Lâm Văn Phát and Dương Văn Đức fail in a coup attempt against General Nguyễn Khánh.</item>
<item>1971 – State police and National Guardsmen storm New York\'s Attica Prison to quell a prison revolt.</item>
<item>1979 – South Africa grants independence to the \"homeland\" of Venda (not recognised outside South Africa).</item>
<item>1985 – Super Mario Bros. is released in Japan for the NES, which starts the Super Mario series of platforming games.</item>
<item>1989 – Largest anti–Apartheid march in South Africa, led by Desmond Tutu.</item>
<item>1993 – Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin shakes hands with Palestine Liberation Organization chairman Yasser Arafat at the White House after signing the Oslo Accords granting limited Palestinian autonomy.</item>
<item>2007 – The Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples is adopted by the United Nations General Assembly.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>