<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_12">
<item>372 – Sixteen Kingdoms: Jin Xiaowudi, age 10, succeeds his father Jin Jianwendi as Emperor of the Eastern Jin dynasty.</item>
<item>1309 – The First Siege of Gibraltar takes place in the context of the Spanish Reconquista pitting the forces of the Kingdom of Castile against the Emirate of Granada resulting in a Castilian victory.</item>
<item>1609 – Henry Hudson begins his exploration of the Hudson River while aboard the Halve Maen.</item>
<item>1762 – The Sultanate of Sulu ceded Balambangan Island to the British East India Company</item>
<item>1846 – Elizabeth Barrett elopes with Robert Browning.</item>
<item>1848 – A new constitution marks the establishment of Switzerland as a federal state.</item>
<item>1857 – The SS Central America sinks about 160 miles east of Cape Hatteras, North Carolina, drowning a total of 426 passengers and crew, including Captain William Lewis Herndon. The ship was carrying 13–15 tons of gold from the California Gold Rush.</item>
<item>1885 – Arbroath 36–0 Bon Accord, a world record scoreline in professional Association football.</item>
<item>1890 – Salisbury, Rhodesia, is founded.</item>
<item>1906 – The Newport Transporter Bridge is opened in Newport, South Wales by Viscount Tredegar.</item>
<item>1910 – Premiere performance of Gustav Mahler\'s Symphony No. 8 in Munich (with a chorus of 852 singers and an orchestra of 171 players. Mahler\'s rehearsal assistant conductor was Bruno Walter).</item>
<item>1923 – Southern Rhodesia, today called Zimbabwe, is annexed by the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1933 – Leó Szilárd, waiting for a red light on Southampton Row in Bloomsbury, conceives the idea of the nuclear chain reaction.</item>
<item>1940 – Cave paintings are discovered in Lascaux, France.</item>
<item>1952 – Strange occurrences, including a monster sighting, take place in Flatwoods, West Virginia.</item>
<item>1953 – U.S. Senator and future President John Fitzgerald Kennedy marries Jacqueline Lee Bouvier at St. Mary\'s Church in Newport, Rhode Island.</item>
<item>1958 – Jack Kilby demonstrates the first working integrated circuit while working at Texas Instruments.</item>
<item>1959 – The Soviet Union launches a large rocket, Lunik II, at the moon.</item>
<item>1959 – Bonanza premieres, the first regularly scheduled TV program presented in color.</item>
<item>1961 – The African and Malagasy Union is founded.</item>
<item>1962 – President Kennedy delivers his \"We choose to go to the Moon\" speech at Rice University.</item>
<item>1966 – Gemini 11, the penultimate mission of NASA\'s Gemini program, and the current human altitude record holder (except for the Apollo lunar missions)</item>
<item>1974 – Emperor Haile Selassie of Ethiopia, \'Messiah\' of the Rastafari movement, is deposed following a military coup by the Derg, ending a reign of 58 years.</item>
<item>1974 – Juventude Africana Amílcar Cabral is founded in Guinea–Bissau.</item>
<item>1980 – Military coup in Turkey.</item>
<item>1983 – A Wells Fargo depot in West Hartford, Connecticut, United States, is robbed of approximately US$7 million by Los Macheteros.</item>
<item>1983 – The USSR vetoes a United Nations Security Council Resolution deploring the Soviet destruction of Korean Air Lines Flight 007.</item>
<item>1984 – Dwight Gooden sets the baseball record for strikeouts in a season by a rookie with 276, previously set by Herb Score with 246 in 1954. Gooden\'s 276 strikeouts that season, pitched in 218 innings, set the current record.</item>
<item>1990 – The two German states and the Four Powers sign the Treaty on the Final Settlement with Respect to Germany in Moscow, paving the way for German reunification.</item>
<item>1992 – NASA launches Space Shuttle Endeavour on STS–47 which marked the 50th shuttle mission. On board are Mae Carol Jemison, the first African–American woman in space, Mamoru Mohri, the first Japanese citizen to fly in a US spaceship, and Mark Lee and Jan Davis, the first married couple in space.</item>
<item>1992 – Abimael Guzmán, leader of the Shining Path, is captured by Peruvian special forces; shortly thereafter the rest of Shining Path\'s leadership fell as well.</item>
<item>1994 – Frank Eugene Corder fatally crashes a single–engine Cessna 150 into the White House\'s south lawn, striking the West wing. There were no other casualties.</item>
<item>2001 – Ansett Australia, Australia\'s first commercial interstate airline, collapses due to increased strain on the international airline industry, leaving 10,000 people unemployed.</item>
<item>2005 – Israeli–Palestinian conflict: the Israeli disengagement from Gaza is completed, leaving some 2,530 homes demolished.</item>
<item>2007 – Former Philippine President Joseph Estrada is convicted of plunder.</item>
<item>2011 – The National September 11 Memorial &amp; Museum in New York City opens to the public.</item>
<item>2014 – Three–year–old William Tyrrell disappears in Kendall, New South Wales, Australia</item>
</string-array>
</resources>