<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_1">
<item>1355 – King Tvrtko I of Bosnia writes In castro nostro Vizoka vocatum from the Old town of Visoki.</item>
<item>1449 – Tumu Crisis: Mongols capture the Emperor of China.</item>
<item>1532 – Lady Anne Boleyn is made Marquess of Pembroke by her fiancé, King Henry VIII of England.</item>
<item>1604 – Adi Granth, now known as Guru Granth Sahib, the holy scripture of Sikhs, was first installed at Harmandir Sahib.</item>
<item>1763 – Catherine II of Russia endorses Ivan Betskoy\'s plans for a Foundling Home in Moscow</item>
<item>1772 – The Mission San Luis Obispo de Tolosa is founded in San Luis Obispo, California.</item>
<item>1774 – Massachusetts Bay colonists rise up in the bloodless Powder Alarm.</item>
<item>1804 – Juno, one of the largest asteroids in the Main Belt, is discovered by the German astronomer Karl Ludwig Harding.</item>
<item>1831 – The high honor of Order of St. Gregory the Great is established by Pope Gregory XVI of the Vatican State to recognize high support for the Vatican or for the Pope, by a man or a woman, and not necessarily a Roman Catholic.</item>
<item>1836 – Narcissa Whitman, one of the first English–speaking white women to settle west of the Rocky Mountains, arrives at Walla Walla, Washington.</item>
<item>1838 – Saint Andrew\'s Scots School, the oldest school of British origin in South America, is established.</item>
<item>1859 – One of the largest coronal mass ejections ever recorded, later to be known as the Carrington Event, occurs.</item>
<item>1878 – Emma Nutt becomes the world\'s first female telephone operator when she is recruited by Alexander Graham Bell to the Boston Telephone Dispatch Company.</item>
<item>1897 – The Tremont Street Subway in Boston opens, becoming the first underground rapid transit system in North America.</item>
<item>1905 – Alberta and Saskatchewan join the Canadian confederation.</item>
<item>1906 – The International Federation of Intellectual Property Attorneys is established.</item>
<item>1911 – The armored cruiser Georgios Averof is commissioned into the Greek Navy. It now serves as a museum ship.</item>
<item>1914 – St. Petersburg, Russia, changes its name to Petrograd.</item>
<item>1920 – The Fountain of Time opens as a tribute to the 100 years of peace between the United States and Great Britain following the Treaty of Ghent.</item>
<item>1928 – Ahmet Zogu declares Albania to be a monarchy and proclaims himself king.</item>
<item>1934 – The first Metro–Goldwyn–Mayer animated cartoon, The Discontented Canary, is released to movie theatres.</item>
<item>1939 – General George C. Marshall becomes Chief of Staff of the United States Army.</item>
<item>1951 – The United States, Australia and New Zealand sign a mutual defense pact, called the ANZUS Treaty.</item>
<item>1952 – The Old Man and the Sea, the Pulitzer Prize–winning novel by Ernest Hemingway, is first published.</item>
<item>1961 – The first conference of the Non–Aligned Countries is held in Belgrade, Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1967 – The Khmer–Chinese Friendship Association is banned in Cambodia.</item>
<item>1969 – A coup in Libya brings Muammar Gaddafi to power.</item>
<item>1969 – Trần Thiện Khiêm becomes Prime Minister of South Vietnam under President Nguyễn Văn Thiệu.</item>
<item>1972 – In Reykjavík, Iceland, American Bobby Fischer beats Russian Boris Spassky to become the world chess champion.</item>
<item>1974 – The SR–71 Blackbird sets (and holds) the record for flying from New York to London in the time of 1 hour, 54 minutes and 56.4 seconds at a speed of 1,435.587 miles per hour (2,310.353 km/h).</item>
<item>1979 – The American space probe Pioneer 11 becomes the first spacecraft to visit Saturn when it passes the planet at a distance of 21,000 kilometres (13,000 mi).</item>
<item>1980 – Major General Chun Doo–hwan becomes President of South Korea, following the resignation of Choi Kyu–hah.</item>
<item>1981 – A coup d\'état in the Central African Republic overthrows President David Dacko.</item>
<item>1982 – The United States Air Force Space Command is founded.</item>
<item>1985 – A joint American–French expedition locates the wreckage of the RMS Titanic.</item>
<item>1991 – Uzbekistan declares independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>