<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_18">
<item>1066 – Norwegian king Harald Hardrada lands with Tostig Godwinson at the mouth of the Humber River and begins his invasion of England.</item>
<item>1180 – Philip Augustus becomes king of France.</item>
<item>1618 – The twelfth baktun in the Mesoamerican Long Count calendar begins.</item>
<item>1679 – The Province of New Hampshire is separated from the Massachusetts Bay Colony.</item>
<item>1714 – George I arrives in Great Britain after becoming king on August 1.</item>
<item>1739 – The Treaty of Belgrade is signed, whereby Austria cedes lands south of the Sava and Danube rivers to the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1793 – The first cornerstone of the United States Capitol is laid by George Washington.</item>
<item>1809 – The Royal Opera House in London opens.</item>
<item>1837 – Tiffany &amp; Co. (first named Tiffany &amp; Young) is founded by Charles Lewis Tiffany and Teddy Young in New York City. The store is called a \"stationery and fancy goods emporium\".</item>
<item>1838 – The Anti–Corn Law League is established by Richard Cobden.</item>
<item>1850 – The U.S. Congress passes the Fugitive Slave Act of 1850.</item>
<item>1851 – First publication of The New–York Daily Times, which later becomes The New York Times.</item>
<item>1872 – King Oscar II accedes to the throne of Sweden–Norway.</item>
<item>1873 – The bank Jay Cooke &amp; Company declares bankruptcy, contributing to the Panic of 1873</item>
<item>1879 – The Blackpool Illuminations are switched on for the first time.</item>
<item>1882 – The Pacific Stock Exchange opens.</item>
<item>1895 – The Atlanta Exposition Speech on race relations is delivered by Booker T. Washington.</item>
<item>1911 – Russian Premier Pyotr Stolypin is shot at the Kiev Opera House.</item>
<item>1919 – The Netherlands gives women the right to vote.</item>
<item>1919 – Fritz Pollard becomes the first African American to play professional football for a major team, the Akron Pros.</item>
<item>1922 – The Kingdom of Hungary is admitted to the League of Nations.</item>
<item>1927 – The Columbia Broadcasting System goes on the air.</item>
<item>1928 – Juan de la Cierva makes the first autogyro crossing of the English Channel.</item>
<item>1931 – The Mukden Incident gives Japan a pretext to invade and occupy Manchuria.</item>
<item>1934 – The Soviet Union is admitted to the League of Nations.</item>
<item>1945 – General Douglas MacArthur moves his command headquarters to Tokyo.</item>
<item>1947 – The National Security Council and the Central Intelligence Agency are established in the United States by the National Security Act. It also establishes the Air Force as an equal partner of the Army and Navy.</item>
<item>1948 – Operation Polo is terminated after the Indian Army accepts the surrender of the army of Hyderabad.</item>
<item>1948 – Margaret Chase Smith of Maine becomes the first woman elected to the United States Senate without completing another senator\'s term.</item>
<item>1959 – Vanguard 3 is launched into Earth orbit.</item>
<item>1960 – Fidel Castro arrives in New York City as the head of the Cuban delegation to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1961 – CONCACAF is established as the governing body for association football in North America, Central America and the Caribbean.</item>
<item>1962 – Burundi, Jamaica, Rwanda and Trinidad and Tobago are admitted to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1973 – The Bahamas, East Germany and West Germany are admitted to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1977 – Voyager I takes the first distant photograph of the Earth and the Moon together.</item>
<item>1980 – Soyuz 38 carries two cosmonauts (including one Cuban) to the Salyut 6 space station.</item>
<item>1981 – The Assemblée Nationale votes to abolish capital punishment in France.</item>
<item>1982 – The Sabra and Shatila massacre in Lebanon comes to an end.</item>
<item>1984 – Joe Kittinger completes the first solo balloon crossing of the Atlantic.</item>
<item>1988 – The 8888 Uprising in Myanmar comes to an end.</item>
<item>1990 – Liechtenstein becomes a member of the United Nations.</item>
<item>1997 – United States media magnate Ted Turner donates US$1 billion to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1997 – The Anti–Personnel Mine Ban Convention is adopted.</item>
<item>2014 – Scotland votes against independence from the United Kingdom, by 55% to 44%.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>