<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_10">
<item>506 – The bishops of Visigothic Gaul meet in the Council of Agde.</item>
<item>1419 – John the Fearless, Duke of Burgundy is assassinated by adherents of the Dauphin, the future Charles VII of France.</item>
<item>1515 – Thomas Wolsey is invested as a Cardinal.</item>
<item>1570 – Spanish Jesuit missionaries land in present–day Virginia to establish the short–lived Ajacán Mission.</item>
<item>1608 – John Smith is elected council president of Jamestown, Virginia.</item>
<item>1823 – Simón Bolívar is named President of Peru.</item>
<item>1846 – Elias Howe is granted a patent for the sewing machine.</item>
<item>1858 – George Mary Searle discovers the asteroid 55 Pandora.</item>
<item>1898 – Empress Elisabeth of Austria is assassinated by Luigi Lucheni.</item>
<item>1919 – Austria and the Allies sign the Treaty of Saint–Germain–en–Laye recognizing the independence of Poland, Hungary, Czechoslovakia and Yugoslavia.</item>
<item>1932 – The New York City Subway\'s third competing subway system, the municipally–owned IND, is opened.</item>
<item>1936 – First World Individual Motorcycle Speedway Championship, Held at London\'s (England) Wembley Stadium</item>
<item>1937 – Nine nations attend the Nyon Conference to address international piracy in the Mediterranean Sea.</item>
<item>1960 – At the Summer Olympics in Rome, Abebe Bikila becomes the first sub–Saharan African to win a gold medal, winning the marathon in bare feet.</item>
<item>1967 – The people of Gibraltar vote to remain a British dependency rather than becoming part of Spain.</item>
<item>1974 – Guinea–Bissau gains independence from Portugal.</item>
<item>2001 – Antônio da Costa Santos, mayor of Campinas, Brazil is assassinated.</item>
<item>2002 – Switzerland, traditionally a neutral country, becomes a full member of the United Nations.</item>
<item>2007 – Former Prime Minister of Pakistan Nawaz Sharif returns to Pakistan after seven years in exile, following a military coup in October 1999.</item>
<item>2008 – The Large Hadron Collider at CERN, described as the biggest scientific experiment in history, is powered up in Geneva, Switzerland.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>