<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_17">
<item>1382 – Louis the Great\'s daughter, Mary, is crowned \"king\" of Hungary.</item>
<item>1577 – The Treaty of Bergerac is signed between Henry III of France and the Huguenots.</item>
<item>1630 – The city of Boston, Massachusetts is founded.</item>
<item>1683 – Antonie van Leeuwenhoek writes a letter to the Royal Society describing \"animalcules\".</item>
<item>1776 – The Presidio of San Francisco is founded in New Spain.</item>
<item>1778 – The Treaty of Fort Pitt is signed. It is the first formal treaty between the United States and a Native American tribe.</item>
<item>1787 – The United States Constitution is signed in Philadelphia.</item>
<item>1849 – American abolitionist Harriet Tubman escapes from slavery.</item>
<item>1859 – Joshua A. Norton declares himself \"Norton I, Emperor of the United States.\"</item>
<item>1914 – Andrew Fisher becomes Prime Minister of Australia for the third time.</item>
<item>1920 – The National Football League is organized as the American Professional Football Association in Canton, Ohio</item>
<item>1930 – The Kurdish Ararat rebellion is suppressed by the Turks.</item>
<item>1932 – A speech by Laureano Gómez leads to the escalation of the Leticia Incident.</item>
<item>1935 – The Niagara Gorge Railroad ceases operations after a rockslide.</item>
<item>1948 – The Lehi (also known as the Stern gang) assassinates Count Folke Bernadotte, who was appointed by the United Nations to mediate between the Arab nations and Israel.</item>
<item>1948 – The Nizam of Hyderabad surrenders his sovereignty over the Hyderabad State and joins the Indian Union.</item>
<item>1954 – The novel Lord of the Flies by William Golding is first published.</item>
<item>1961 – The world\'s first retractable roof stadium, the Civic Arena, opens in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania.</item>
<item>1974 – Bangladesh, Grenada and Guinea–Bissau join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1976 – The Space Shuttle Enterprise is unveiled by NASA.</item>
<item>1978 – The Camp David Accords are signed by Israel and Egypt.</item>
<item>1980 – After weeks of strikes at the Lenin Shipyard in Gdańsk, Poland, the nationwide independent trade union Solidarity is established.</item>
<item>1983 – Vanessa Williams becomes the first black Miss America.</item>
<item>1988 – The 1988 Summer Olympics are opened in Seoul, South Korea.</item>
<item>1991 – Estonia, North Korea, South Korea, Latvia, Lithuania, the Marshall Islands and Micronesia join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1991 – The first version of the Linux kernel (0.01) is released to the Internet.</item>
<item>1992 – An Iranian Kurdish leader and his two joiners are assassinated by political militants in Berlin.</item>
<item>2006 – Fourpeaked Mountain in Alaska erupts, marking the first eruption for the volcano in at least 10,000 years.</item>
<item>2006 – An audio tape of a private speech by Hungarian Prime Minister Ferenc Gyurcsány is leaked to the public, in which he confessed that his Hungarian Socialist Party had lied to win the 2006 election, sparking widespread protests across the country.</item>
<item>2011 – Occupy Wall Street movement begins in Zuccotti Park, New York City.</item>
<item>2018 – A Russian reconnaissance aircraft carrying 15 people on board was brought down by a Syrian surface–to–air missile over the Mediterranean Sea.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>