<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_19">
<item>335 – Flavius Dalmatius is raised to the rank of Caesar by his uncle, Constantine the Great.</item>
<item>634 – Siege of Damascus: The Rashidun Arabs under Khalid ibn al–Walid capture Damascus from the Byzantine Empire.</item>
<item>1778 – The Continental Congress passes the first United States federal budget.</item>
<item>1796 – George Washington\'s Farewell Address is printed across America as an open letter to the public.</item>
<item>1846 – Two French shepherd children, Mélanie Calvat and Maximin Giraud, experience a Marian apparition on a mountaintop near La Salette, France, now known as Our Lady of La Salette.</item>
<item>1852 – Annibale de Gasparis discovers the asteroid Massalia from the north dome of the Astronomical Observatory of Capodimonte.</item>
<item>1868 – La Gloriosa begins in Spain.</item>
<item>1893 – In New Zealand, the Electoral Act of 1893 is consented to by the governor, giving all women in New Zealand the right to vote.</item>
<item>1946 – The Council of Europe is founded following a speech by Winston Churchill at the University of Zurich.</item>
<item>1952 – The United States bars Charlie Chaplin from re–entering the country after a trip to England.</item>
<item>1957 – Plumbbob Rainier becomes the first nuclear explosion to be entirely contained underground, producing no fallout.</item>
<item>1970 – Michael Eavis hosts the first Glastonbury Festival.</item>
<item>1970 – Kostas Georgakis, a Greek student of geology, sets himself ablaze in Matteotti Square in Genoa, Italy, as a protest against the dictatorial regime of Georgios Papadopoulos.</item>
<item>1973 – King Carl XVI Gustaf of Sweden has his investiture.</item>
<item>1976 – Two Imperial Iranian Air Force F–4 Phantom II jets fly out to investigate an unidentified flying object, when both independently lose instrumentation and communications as they approach, only to have them restored upon withdrawal.</item>
<item>1978 – The Solomon Islands join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1982 – Scott Fahlman posts the first documented emoticons :–) and :–( on the Carnegie Mellon University bulletin board system.</item>
<item>1983 – Saint Kitts and Nevis gains its independence.</item>
<item>1985 – Tipper Gore and other political wives form the Parents Music Resource Center as Frank Zappa and other musicians testify at U.S. Congressional hearings on obscenity in rock music.</item>
<item>1991 – Ötzi the Iceman is discovered in the Alps on the border between Italy and Austria.</item>
<item>2006 – The Thai army stages a coup. The Constitution is revoked and martial law is declared.</item>
<item>2010 – The leaking oil well in the Deepwater Horizon oil spill is sealed.</item>
<item>2011 – Mariano Rivera of the New York Yankees surpasses Trevor Hoffman to become Major League Baseball\'s all time saves leader with 602.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>