<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_27">
<item>1066 – William the Conqueror and his army set sail from the mouth of the Somme river, beginning the Norman conquest of England.</item>
<item>1540 – The Society of Jesus (Jesuits) receives its charter from Pope Paul III.</item>
<item>1669 – The Venetians surrender the fortress of Candia to the Ottomans, thus ending the 21–year–long Siege of Candia.</item>
<item>1822 – Jean–François Champollion announces that he has deciphered the Rosetta Stone.</item>
<item>1825 – The world\'s first public railway to use steam locomotives, the Stockton and Darlington Railway, is ceremonially opened.</item>
<item>1854 – The steamship SS Arctic sinks with 300 people on board.</item>
<item>1875 – The merchant sailing ship Ellen Southard is wrecked in a storm at Liverpool.</item>
<item>1908 – Production of the Model T automobile begins at the Ford Piquette Avenue Plant in Detroit.</item>
<item>1916 – Iyasu V is proclaimed deposed as ruler of Ethiopia in a palace coup in favor of his aunt Zewditu.</item>
<item>1922 – King Constantine I of Greece abdicates his throne in favor of his eldest son, George II.</item>
<item>1928 – The Republic of China is recognized by the United States.</item>
<item>1930 – Bobby Jones wins the (pre–Masters) Grand Slam of golf.</item>
<item>1938 – The ocean liner Queen Elizabeth is launched in Glasgow.</item>
<item>1941 – The Greek National Liberation Front is established with Georgios Siantos as acting leader.</item>
<item>1941 – The SS Patrick Henry is launched, becoming the first of more than 2,700 Liberty ships.</item>
<item>1942 – Last day of the Matanikau action on Guadalcanal as United States Marines barely escape after being surrounded by Japanese forces.</item>
<item>1949 – Zeng Liansong\'s design is chosen as the flag of the People\'s Republic of China.</item>
<item>1962 – The Yemen Arab Republic is established.</item>
<item>1962 – Rachel Carson\'s book Silent Spring is published, inspiring an environmental movement and the creation of the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</item>
<item>1964 – The British TSR–2 aircraft XR219 makes its maiden flight.</item>
<item>1975 – The last use of capital punishment in Spain sparks worldwide protests.</item>
<item>1983 – Richard Stallman announces the GNU Project to develop a free Unix–like operating system.</item>
<item>1988 – The National League for Democracy is formed by Aung San Suu Kyi and others to fight dictatorship in Myanmar.</item>
<item>1993 – The Sukhumi massacre takes place in Abkhazia.</item>
<item>1996 – Confusion on a tanker ship results in the Julie N. oil spill in Portland, Maine.</item>
<item>1998 – The Google internet search engine retroactively claims this date as its birthday.</item>
<item>2003 – The SMART–1 satellite is launched.</item>
<item>2007 – NASA launches the Dawn probe to the asteroid belt.</item>
<item>2008 – CNSA astronaut Zhai Zhigang becomes the first Chinese person to perform a spacewalk.</item>
<item>2014 – The eruption of Mount Ontake in Japan occurs.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>