<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_21">
<item>455 – Emperor Avitus enters Rome with a Gallic army and consolidates his power.</item>
<item>1170 – The Kingdom of Dublin falls to Norman invaders.</item>
<item>1843 – John Williams Wilson takes possession of the Strait of Magellan on behalf of the Chilean government.</item>
<item>1896 – Anglo–Egyptian conquest of Sudan: British forces under the command of Horatio Kitchener take Dongola.</item>
<item>1898 – Empress Dowager Cixi seizes power and ends the Hundred Days\' Reform in China.</item>
<item>1933 – Salvador Lutteroth establishes Mexican professional wrestling.</item>
<item>1937 – J. R. R. Tolkien\'s The Hobbit is published.</item>
<item>1942 – The Holocaust in Poland: At the end of Yom Kippur, Germans order Jews to permanently move from Konstantynów to Biała Podlaska.</item>
<item>1942 – The Boeing B–29 Superfortress makes its maiden flight.</item>
<item>1949 – The People\'s Republic of China is proclaimed.</item>
<item>1953 – Lieutenant No Kum–sok, a North Korean pilot, defects to South Korea with his jet fighter.</item>
<item>1964 – Malta gains independence from the United Kingdom, but remains in the Commonwealth.</item>
<item>1965 – The Gambia, Maldives and Singapore are admitted as members of the United Nations.</item>
<item>1971 – Bahrain, Bhutan and Qatar join the United Nations.</item>
<item>1972 – Philippine President Ferdinand Marcos begins authoritarian rule by declaring martial law.</item>
<item>1976 – Seychelles joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1981 – Belize is granted full independence from the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1981 – Sandra Day O\'Connor is unanimously approved by the U.S. Senate as the first female Supreme Court justice.</item>
<item>1984 – Brunei joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1991 – Armenia gains independence from the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1993 – Russian President Boris Yeltsin triggers a constitutional crisis when he suspends parliament and scraps the constitution.</item>
<item>1996 – The Defense of Marriage Act is passed by the United States Congress.</item>
<item>2003 – The Galileo spacecraft is terminated by sending it into Jupiter\'s atmosphere.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>