<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_20">
<item>1058 – Agnes of Poitou and Andrew I of Hungary meet to negotiate about the border–zone in present–day Burgenland.</item>
<item>1187 – Saladin begins the Siege of Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1260 – The Great Prussian Uprising among the old Prussians begins against the Teutonic Knights.</item>
<item>1378 – Cardinal Robert of Geneva is elected as Pope Clement VII, beginning the Papal schism.</item>
<item>1519 – Ferdinand Magellan sets sail from Sanlúcar de Barrameda with about 270 men on his expedition to circumnavigate the globe.</item>
<item>1857 – The Indian Rebellion of 1857 ends with the recapture of Delhi by troops loyal to the East India Company.</item>
<item>1870 – The Bersaglieri corps enter Rome through the Porta Pia, and complete the unification of Italy.</item>
<item>1871 – Bishop John Coleridge Patteson, first bishop of Melanesia, is martyred on Nukapu, now in the Solomon Islands.</item>
<item>1893 – Charles Duryea and his brother road–test the first American–made gasoline–powered automobile.</item>
<item>1906 – The Cunard Line\'s RMS Mauretania is launched at Newcastle upon Tyne, England.</item>
<item>1909 – The South Africa Act 1909 creates the Union of South Africa from the British Colonies from four smaller colonies.</item>
<item>1910 – The ocean liner SS France, later known as the \"Versailles of the Atlantic\", is launched.</item>
<item>1946 – Six days after a referendum, King Christian X of Denmark annuls the declaration of independence of the Faroe Islands.</item>
<item>1955 – The Treaty on Relations between the USSR and the GDR is signed.</item>
<item>1961 – Greek general Konstantinos Dovas becomes Prime Minister of Greece.</item>
<item>1962 – James Meredith, an African American, is temporarily barred from entering the University of Mississippi.</item>
<item>1967 – RMS Queen Elizabeth 2 is launched Clydebank, Scotland.</item>
<item>1977 – Vietnam is admitted to the United Nations.</item>
<item>1979 – A French–supported coup d\'état in the Central African Empire overthrows Emperor Bokassa I.</item>
<item>1982 – Football players begin a 57–day strike during the 1982 NFL season.</item>
<item>1990 – South Ossetia declares its independence from Georgia.</item>
<item>2007 – Between 15,000 and 20,000 protesters marched on Jena, Louisiana, in support of six black youths who had been convicted of assaulting a white classmate.</item>
<item>2011 – The United States military ends its \"Don\'t ask, don\'t tell\" policy, allowing gay men and women to serve openly for the first time.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>