<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_24">
<item>787 – Second Council of Nicaea: The council assembles at the church of Hagia Sophia.</item>
<item>1674 – Second Tantrik Coronation of Chhatrapati Shivaji Maharaj.</item>
<item>1789 – The United States Congress passes the Judiciary Act, creating the office of the Attorney General and federal judiciary system and ordering the composition of the Supreme Court.</item>
<item>1841 – The Sultanate of Brunei cedes Sarawak to the United Kingdom.</item>
<item>1852 – The first airship powered by (a steam) engine, created by Henri Giffard, travels 17 miles (27 km) from Paris to Trappes.</item>
<item>1853 – Admiral Despointes formally takes possession of New Caledonia in the name of France.</item>
<item>1869 – Gold prices plummet after President Grant orders the Treasury to sell large quantities of gold after Jay Gould and James Fisk plot to control the market.</item>
<item>1890 – The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter–day Saints officially renounces polygamy.</item>
<item>1906 – U.S. President Theodore Roosevelt proclaims Devils Tower in Wyoming as the nation\'s first National Monument.</item>
<item>1906 – Racial tensions exacerbated by rumors lead to the Atlanta Race Riot, further increasing racial segregation.</item>
<item>1911 – His Majesty\'s Airship No. 1, Britain\'s first rigid airship, is wrecked by strong winds before her maiden flight at Barrow–in–Furness.</item>
<item>1929 – Jimmy Doolittle performs the first flight without a window, proving that full instrument flying from take off to landing is possible.</item>
<item>1932 – Gandhi and Dr. Ambedkar agree to the Poona Pact, which reserved seats in the Indian provincial legislatures for the \"Depressed Classes\" (Untouchables).</item>
<item>1935 – Earl and Weldon Bascom produce the first rodeo ever held outdoors under electric lights.</item>
<item>1946 – Cathay Pacific Airways is founded in Hong Kong.</item>
<item>1946 – The top–secret Clifford–Elsey Report on the Soviet Union is delivered to President Truman.</item>
<item>1948 – The Honda Motor Company is founded.</item>
<item>1957 – President Eisenhower sends the 101st Airborne Division to Little Rock, Arkansas, to enforce desegregation.</item>
<item>1960 – USS Enterprise, the world\'s first nuclear–powered aircraft carrier, is launched.</item>
<item>1973 – Guinea–Bissau declares its independence from Portugal.</item>
<item>1975 – Southwest Face expedition members become the first persons to reach the summit of Mount Everest by any of its faces, instead of using a ridge route.</item>
<item>1993 – The Cambodian monarchy is restored, with Norodom Sihanouk as king.</item>
<item>1996 – Representatives of 71 nations sign the Comprehensive Nuclear–Test–Ban Treaty at the United Nations.</item>
<item>2007 – Between 30,000 and 100,000 people take part in anti–government protests in Yangon, Burma, the largest in 20 years.</item>
<item>2009 – The G20 summit begins in Pittsburgh with 30 global leaders in attendance.</item>
<item>2014 – The Mars Orbiter Mission makes India the first Asian nation to reach Mars orbit, and the first nation in the world to do so in its first attempt.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>