<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_26">
<item>1087 – William II is crowned King of England, and reigns until 1100.</item>
<item>1212 – The Golden Bull of Sicily is issued to confirm the hereditary royal title in Bohemia for the Přemyslid dynasty.</item>
<item>1493 – Pope Alexander VI issues the papal bull Dudum siquidem to the Spanish, extending the grant of new lands he made them in Inter caetera.</item>
<item>1580 – Francis Drake finishes his circumnavigation of the Earth.</item>
<item>1789 – George Washington appoints the first cabinet of the United States government.</item>
<item>1792 – Marc–David Lasource begins accusing Maximilien Robespierre of wanting a dictatorship for France.</item>
<item>1810 – A new Act of Succession is adopted by the Riksdag of the Estates, and Jean Baptiste Bernadotte becomes heir to the Swedish throne.</item>
<item>1905 – Albert Einstein publishes the third of his Annus Mirabilis papers, introducing the special theory of relativity.</item>
<item>1907 – Four months after the 1907 Imperial Conference, New Zealand and Newfoundland are promoted from colonies to dominions within the British Empire.</item>
<item>1910 – Indian journalist Swadeshabhimani Ramakrishna Pillai is arrested after publishing criticism of the government of Travancore and is exiled.</item>
<item>1914 – The United States Federal Trade Commission is established by the Federal Trade Commission Act.</item>
<item>1923 – The German government accepts the occupation of the Ruhr.</item>
<item>1933 – As gangster Machine Gun Kelly surrenders to the FBI, he shouts out, \"Don\'t shoot, G–Men!\", which becomes a nickname for FBI agents.</item>
<item>1934 – The ocean liner RMS Queen Mary is launched.</item>
<item>1941 – The Military Police Corps is created as a permanent branch of the United States Army.</item>
<item>1942 – Holocaust: Senior SS official August Frank issues a memorandum detailing how Jews should be \"evacuated\".</item>
<item>1953 – Rationing of sugar in the United Kingdom ends</item>
<item>1960 – In Chicago, the first televised debate takes place between presidential candidates Richard M. Nixon and John F. Kennedy.</item>
<item>1969 – Abbey Road, the last recorded album by The Beatles, is released.</item>
<item>1973 – Concorde makes its first non–stop crossing of the Atlantic in record–breaking time.</item>
<item>1977 – The Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant opens for official usage, the first nuclear power plant in the (then) Ukrainian SSR.</item>
<item>1981 – Nolan Ryan sets a Major League record by throwing his fifth no–hitter.</item>
<item>1983 – Soviet Air Force officer Stanislav Petrov identifies a report of an incoming nuclear missile as a computer error and not an American first strike.</item>
<item>1983 – Australia II wins the America\'s Cup, ending the New York Yacht Club\'s 132–year domination of the race.</item>
<item>1984 – The United Kingdom and China agree to a transfer of sovereignty over Hong Kong, to take place in 1997.</item>
<item>2000 – Anti–globalization protests in Prague (some 20,000 protesters) turn violent during the IMF and World Bank summits.</item>
<item>2005 – The PBS Kids Channel is shut down and replaced by a joint network with Comcast called Sprout.</item>
<item>2008 – Swiss pilot and inventor Yves Rossy becomes first person to fly a jet engine–powered wing across the English Channel.</item>
<item>2009 – Typhoon Ketsana hits the Philippines, China, Vietnam, Cambodia, Laos and Thailand, causing 700 fatalities.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>