<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_28">
<item>235 – Pope Pontian resigns. He is exiled to the mines of Sardinia, along with Hippolytus of Rome.</item>
<item>351 – Constantius II defeats the usurper Magnentius.</item>
<item>365 – Roman usurper Procopius bribes two legions passing by Constantinople, and proclaims himself emperor.</item>
<item>1066 – William the Conqueror lands in England, beginning the Norman conquest.</item>
<item>1106 – King Henry I of England defeats his brother, Robert Curthose.</item>
<item>1238 – King James I of Aragon conquers Valencia from the Moors. Shortly thereafter, he proclaims himself king of Valencia.</item>
<item>1787 – The Congress of the Confederation votes to send the newly–written United States Constitution to the state legislatures for approval.</item>
<item>1821 – The Declaration of Independence of the Mexican Empire is drafted. It will be made public on 13 October.</item>
<item>1844 – Oscar I of Sweden–Norway is crowned king of Sweden.</item>
<item>1867 – Toronto becomes the capital of Ontario, having also been the capital of Ontario\'s predecessors since 1796.</item>
<item>1871 – The Brazilian Parliament passes a law that frees all children thereafter born to slaves, and all government–owned slaves.</item>
<item>1889 – The General Conference on Weights and Measures (CGPM) defines the length of a meter.</item>
<item>1892 – The first night game for American football takes place in a contest between Wyoming Seminary and Mansfield State Normal.</item>
<item>1893 – Foundation of the Portuguese football club FC Porto.</item>
<item>1912 – The Ulster Covenant is signed by some 500,000 Ulster Protestant Unionists in opposition to the Third Irish Home Rule Bill.</item>
<item>1919 – Race riots begin in Omaha, Nebraska.</item>
<item>1924 – The first aerial circumnavigation is completed by a team from the US Army.</item>
<item>1941 – Ted Williams achieves a .406 batting average for the season, and becomes the last major league baseball player to bat .400 or better.</item>
<item>1951 – CBS makes the first color televisions available for sale to the general public, but the product is discontinued less than a month later.</item>
<item>1961 – A military coup in Damascus effectively ends the United Arab Republic, the union between Egypt and Syria.</item>
<item>1971 – The British Parliament passes the Misuse of Drugs Act 1971, banning the medicinal use of cannabis.</item>
<item>1986 – The Democratic Progressive Party becomes the first opposition party in Taiwan.</item>
<item>1995 – Bob Denard and a group of mercenaries take the islands of the Comoros in a coup.</item>
<item>1995 – Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin and PLO Chairman Yasser Arafat sign the Interim Agreement on the West Bank and the Gaza Strip.</item>
<item>2000 – Al–Aqsa Intifada: Ariel Sharon visits Al–Aqsa Mosque known to Jews as the Temple Mount in Jerusalem.</item>
<item>2008 – Falcon 1 becomes the first privately–developed liquid–fuel ground–launched vehicle to put a payload into orbit.</item>
<item>2012 – Somali and African Union forces launch a coordinated assault on the Somali port of Kismayo to take back the city from al–Shabaab militants.</item>
<item>2014 – The 2014 Hong Kong protests begin in response to restrictive political reforms imposed by the NPC in Beijing.</item>
<item>2016 – The 2016 South Australian blackout occurs, lasting up to three days in some areas.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>