<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_29">
<item>1011 – Danes capture Canterbury after a siege, taking Ælfheah, archbishop of Canterbury, as a prisoner.</item>
<item>1227 – Frederick II, Holy Roman Emperor, is excommunicated by Pope Gregory IX for his failure to participate in the Crusades.</item>
<item>1267 – The Treaty of Montgomery recognises Llywelyn ap Gruffudd as Prince of Wales, but only as a vassal of King Henry III.</item>
<item>1578 – Tegucigalpa, capital city of Honduras, is claimed by the Spaniards.</item>
<item>1789 – The 1st United States Congress adjourns.</item>
<item>1829 – The Metropolitan Police of London, later also known as the Met, is founded.</item>
<item>1850 – The papal bull Universalis Ecclesiae restores the Roman Catholic hierarchy in England and Wales.</item>
<item>1855 – The Philippine port of Iloilo is opened to world trade by the Spanish administration.</item>
<item>1864 – The Treaty of Lisbon defines the boundaries between Spain and Portugal and abolishes the Couto Misto microstate.</item>
<item>1885 – The first practical public electric tramway in the world is opened in Blackpool, England.</item>
<item>1907 – The cornerstone is laid at Washington National Cathedral in the U.S. capital.</item>
<item>1918 – Germany\'s Supreme Army Command tells the Kaiser and the Chancellor to open negotiations for an armistice.</item>
<item>1923 – The British Mandate for Palestine takes effect, creating Mandatory Palestine.</item>
<item>1923 – The French Mandate for Syria and the Lebanon takes effect.</item>
<item>1923 – The First American Track &amp; Field championships for women are held.</item>
<item>1940 – Two Avro Ansons collide in mid–air over New South Wales, Australia, remain locked together, then land safely.</item>
<item>1949 – The Communist Party of China writes the Common Programme for the future People\'s Republic of China.</item>
<item>1954 – The convention establishing CERN (the European Organization for Nuclear Research) is signed.</item>
<item>1971 – Oman joins the Arab League.</item>
<item>1972 – China–Japan relations: Japan establishes diplomatic relations with the People\'s Republic of China after breaking official ties with the Republic of China.</item>
<item>1975 – WGPR becomes the first black–owned–and–operated television station in the US.</item>
<item>1990 – Construction of the Washington National Cathedral is completed.</item>
<item>1990 – The YF–22, which would later become the F–22 Raptor, flies for the first time.</item>
<item>1991 – A Haitian coup d\'état occurs.</item>
<item>1992 – Brazilian President Fernando Collor de Mello is impeached.</item>
<item>2004 – The asteroid 4179 Toutatis passes within four lunar distances of Earth.</item>
<item>2004 – Burt Rutan\'s Ansari SpaceShipOne performs a successful spaceflight, the first of two required to win the Ansari X Prize.</item>
<item>2007 – Calder Hall, the world\'s first commercial nuclear power station, is demolished in a controlled explosion.</item>
<item>2011 – The special court in India convicted all 269 accused officials for atrocity on Dalits and 17 for rape in the Vachathi case.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>