<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_22">
<item>1692 – The last hanging of those convicted of witchcraft in the Salem witch trials; others are all eventually released.</item>
<item>1761 – George III and Charlotte of Mecklenburg–Strelitz are crowned King and Queen, respectively, of the Kingdom of Great Britain.</item>
<item>1789 – The office of United States Postmaster General is established.</item>
<item>1792 – Primidi Vendémiaire of year one of the French Republican Calendar as the French First Republic comes into being.</item>
<item>1823 – Joseph Smith finds the golden plates after being directed by God through the Angel Moroni to the place where they were buried.</item>
<item>1862 – A preliminary version of the Emancipation Proclamation is released by Abraham Lincoln.</item>
<item>1885 – Lord Randolph Churchill makes a speech in Ulster in opposition to the Irish Home Rule movement.</item>
<item>1888 – The first issue of National Geographic Magazine is published.</item>
<item>1896 – Queen Victoria surpasses her grandfather King George III as the longest reigning monarch in British history.</item>
<item>1910 – The Duke of York\'s Picture House opens in Brighton, now the oldest continually operating cinema in Britain.</item>
<item>1919 – The steel strike of 1919, led by the Amalgamated Association of Iron and Steel Workers, begins in Pennsylvania before spreading across the United States.</item>
<item>1927 – Jack Dempsey loses the \"Long Count\" boxing match to Gene Tunney.</item>
<item>1948 – Gail Halvorsen officially started parachuting candy to children as part of the Berlin Air lift.</item>
<item>1948 – Israeli–Palestine conflict: The All–Palestine Government is established by the Arab League.</item>
<item>1957 – In Haiti, François Duvalier is elected president.</item>
<item>1960 – The Sudanese Republic is renamed Mali after the withdrawal of Senegal from the Mali Federation.</item>
<item>1975 – Sara Jane Moore tries to assassinate U.S. President Gerald Ford, but is foiled by the Secret Service.</item>
<item>1980 – Iraq invades Iran.</item>
<item>1993 – A Transair Georgian Airlines Tu–154 is shot down by a missile in Sukhumi, Georgia.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>