<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_30">
<item>489 – The Ostrogoths under Theoderic the Great defeat the forces of Odoacer for the second time.</item>
<item>737 – The Turgesh drive back an Umayyad invasion of Khuttal, follow them south of the Oxus, and capture their baggage train.</item>
<item>1399 – Henry IV is proclaimed king of England.</item>
<item>1520 – Suleiman the Magnificent is proclaimed sultan of the Ottoman Empire.</item>
<item>1541 – Spanish conquistador Hernando de Soto and his forces enter Tula territory in present–day western Arkansas, encountering fierce resistance.</item>
<item>1791 – France\'s National Constituent Assembly is dissolved, to be replaced the next day by the National Legislative Assembly</item>
<item>1882 – Thomas Edison\'s first commercial hydroelectric power plant (later known as Appleton Edison Light Company) begins operation.</item>
<item>1906 – The Royal Galician Academy, the Galician language\'s biggest linguistic authority, starts working in Havana.</item>
<item>1907 – The McKinley National Memorial, the final resting place of assassinated U.S. President William McKinley and his family, is dedicated in Canton, Ohio.</item>
<item>1909 – The Cunard Line’s RMS Mauretania makes a record–breaking westbound crossing of the Atlantic, that will not be bettered for 20 years.</item>
<item>1922 – The University of Alabama opens the American football season with a 110–0 victory over the Marion Military Institute, which still stands as Alabama\'s record for largest margin of victory and as their only 100 point game.</item>
<item>1927 – Babe Ruth becomes the first baseball player to hit 60 home runs in a season.</item>
<item>1935 – The Hoover Dam, astride the border between the U.S. states of Arizona and Nevada, is dedicated.</item>
<item>1938 – Britain, France, Germany and Italy sign the Munich Agreement, whereby Germany annexes the Sudetenland region of Czechoslovakia.</item>
<item>1939 – NBC broadcasts the first televised American football game.</item>
<item>1943 – The United States Merchant Marine Academy is dedicated by President Roosevelt.</item>
<item>1947 – The 1947 World Series is the first to be televised, to include an African–American player, to exceed $2 million in receipts, to see a pinch–hit home run, and to have six umpires on the field.</item>
<item>1947 – Pakistan joins the United Nations.</item>
<item>1949 – The Berlin Airlift ends.</item>
<item>1954 – The U.S. Navy submarine USS Nautilus is commissioned as the world\'s first nuclear–powered vessel.</item>
<item>1962 – Mexican–American labor leader César Chávez founds the National Farm Workers Association.</item>
<item>1962 – James Meredith enters the University of Mississippi, defying racial segregation rules.</item>
<item>1965 – The Lockheed L–100, the civilian version of the C–130 Hercules, is introduced.</item>
<item>1966 – Bechuanaland declares its independence, and becomes the Republic of Botswana.</item>
<item>1967 – The BBC Light Programme, Third Programme and Home Service are replaced with BBC Radio 2, 3 and 4 Respectively, BBC Radio 1 is also launched.</item>
<item>1968 – The Boeing 747 is rolled out and shown to the public for the first time.</item>
<item>1972 – Roberto Clemente records the 3,000th and final hit of his career.</item>
<item>1975 – The AH–64 Apache makes its first flight. Eight years later, the first production model rolled out of the assembly line.</item>
<item>1977 – Because of NASA budget cuts and dwindling power reserves, the Apollo program\'s ALSEP experiment packages left on the Moon are shut down.</item>
<item>1980 – Ethernet specifications are published by Xerox working with Intel and Digital Equipment Corporation.</item>
<item>1990 – The Dalai Lama unveils the Canadian Tribute to Human Rights in Canada\'s capital city of Ottawa.</item>
<item>1994 – Aldwych tube station (originally Strand Station) of the London Underground closes after eighty–eight years in service.</item>
<item>1994 – Ongar railway station, the furthest London Underground from central London, closes.</item>
<item>2004 – The AIM–54 Phoenix, the primary missile for the F–14 Tomcat, is retired from service. Almost two years later, the Tomcat itself is retired.</item>
<item>2005 – Controversial drawings of Muhammad are printed in a Danish newspaper.</item>
<item>2016 – Two paintings with a combined value of $100 million are recovered after having been stolen from the Van Gogh Museum in 2002.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>