<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_4">
<item>476 – Romulus Augustulus, last emperor of the Western Roman Empire, is deposed when Odoacer proclaims himself \"King of Italy\", thus ending the Western Roman Empire.</item>
<item>626 – Li Shimin, posthumously known as Emperor Taizong of Tang, assumes the throne over the Tang dynasty of China.</item>
<item>1260 – The Sienese Ghibellines, supported by the forces of Manfred, King of Sicily, defeat the Florentine Guelphs at Montaperti.</item>
<item>1282 – Peter III of Aragon becomes the King of Sicily.</item>
<item>1479 – The Treaty of Alcáçovas is signed by the Catholic Monarchs of Castile and Aragon on one side and Afonso V and his son, Prince John of Portugal.</item>
<item>1607 – The Flight of the Earls takes place in Ireland.</item>
<item>1666 – In London, England, the most destructive damage from the Great Fire occurs.</item>
<item>1774 – New Caledonia is first sighted by Europeans, during the second voyage of Captain James Cook.</item>
<item>1781 – Los Angeles is founded as El Pueblo de Nuestra Señora La Reina de los Ángeles (The Village of Our Lady, the Queen of the Angels) by 44 Spanish settlers.</item>
<item>1797 – Coup of 18 Fructidor in France.</item>
<item>1800 – The French garrison in Valletta surrenders to British troops who had been called at the invitation of the Maltese. The islands of Malta and Gozo become the Malta Protectorate.</item>
<item>1870 – Emperor Napoleon III of France is deposed and the Third Republic is declared.</item>
<item>1882 – The Pearl Street Station in New York City becomes the first power plant to supply electricity to paying customers.</item>
<item>1888 – George Eastman registers the trademark Kodak and receives a patent for his camera that uses roll film.</item>
<item>1912 – Albanian rebels succeed in their revolt when the Ottoman Empire agrees to fulfill their demands</item>
<item>1919 – Mustafa Kemal Atatürk, who founded the Republic of Turkey, gathers a congress in Sivas to make decisions as to the future of Anatolia and Thrace.</item>
<item>1923 – Maiden flight of the first U.S. airship, the USS Shenandoah.</item>
<item>1948 – Queen Wilhelmina of the Netherlands abdicates for health reasons.</item>
<item>1950 – Darlington Raceway is the site of the inaugural Southern 500, the first 500–mile NASCAR race.</item>
<item>1951 – The first live transcontinental television broadcast takes place in San Francisco, from the Japanese Peace Treaty Conference.</item>
<item>1957 – American Civil Rights Movement: Little Rock Crisis: Orval Faubus, governor of Arkansas, calls out the National Guard to prevent African American students from enrolling in Central High School.</item>
<item>1957 – The Ford Motor Company introduces the Edsel.</item>
<item>1964 – Scotland\'s Forth Road Bridge near Edinburgh officially opens.</item>
<item>1970 – Salvador Allende is elected President of Chile.</item>
<item>1972 – Mark Spitz becomes the first competitor to win seven medals at a single Olympic Games.</item>
<item>1972 – The Price Is Right premieres on CBS. As of 2018, it is the longest running game show on American television.</item>
<item>1975 – The Sinai Interim Agreement relating to the Arab–Israeli conflict is signed.</item>
<item>1977 – The Golden Dragon massacre takes place in San Francisco.</item>
<item>1985 – The discovery of Buckminsterfullerene, the first fullerene molecule of carbon.</item>
<item>1989 – In Leipzig, East Germany, the first of weekly demonstration for the legalisation of opposition groups and democratic reforms takes place.</item>
<item>1998 – Google is founded by Larry Page and Sergey Brin, two students at Stanford University.</item>
<item>2001 – Tokyo DisneySea opens to the public as part of the Tokyo Disney Resort in Urayasu, Chiba, Japan.</item>
<item>2002 – The Oakland Athletics win their 20th consecutive game, an American League record.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>