<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_5">
<item>917 – Liu Yan declares himself emperor, establishing the Southern Han state in southern China, at his capital of Panyu.</item>
<item>1590 – Alexander Farnese\'s army forces Henry IV of France to lift the siege of Paris.</item>
<item>1661 – Fall of Nicolas Fouquet: Louis XIV Superintendent of Finances is arrested in Nantes by D\'Artagnan, captain of the king\'s musketeers.</item>
<item>1698 – In an effort to Westernize his nobility, Tsar Peter I of Russia imposes a tax on beards for all men except the clergy and peasantry.</item>
<item>1725 – Wedding of Louis XV and Maria Leszczyńska.</item>
<item>1774 – First Continental Congress assembles in Philadelphia.</item>
<item>1791 – Olympe de Gouges writes the Declaration of the Rights of Woman and of the Female Citizen.</item>
<item>1798 – Conscription is made mandatory in France by the Jourdan law.</item>
<item>1816 – Louis XVIII has to dissolve the Chambre introuvable (\"Unobtainable Chamber\").</item>
<item>1836 – Sam Houston is elected as the first president of the Republic of Texas.</item>
<item>1882 – The first United States Labor Day parade is held in New York City.</item>
<item>1882 – Tottenham Hotspur, a Premier League football club from North London, is founded (as Hotspur F.C.).</item>
<item>1915 – The pacifist Zimmerwald Conference begins.</item>
<item>1927 – The first Oswald the Lucky Rabbit cartoon, Trolley Troubles, produced by Walt Disney, is released by Universal Pictures.</item>
<item>1932 – The French Upper Volta is broken apart between Ivory Coast, French Sudan, and Niger.</item>
<item>1944 – Belgium, Netherlands and Luxembourg constitute Benelux.</item>
<item>1960 – Poet Léopold Sédar Senghor is the first elected President of Senegal.</item>
<item>1960 – Muhammad Ali (then known as Cassius Clay) wins the gold medal in the light heavyweight boxing competition at the Olympic Games in Rome.</item>
<item>1975 – Sacramento, California: Lynette Fromme attempts to assassinate U.S. President Gerald Ford.</item>
<item>1977 – Voyager Program: NASA launches the Voyager 1 spacecraft.</item>
<item>1980 – The Gotthard Road Tunnel opens in Switzerland as the world\'s longest highway tunnel at 10.14 miles (16.32 km) stretching from Göschenen to Airolo.</item>
<item>1984 – STS–41–D: The Space Shuttle Discovery lands after its maiden voyage.</item>
<item>1984 – Western Australia becomes the last Australian state to abolish capital punishment.</item>
<item>1986 – Pan Am Flight 73 from Mumbai, India with 358 people on board is hijacked at Karachi International Airport.</item>
<item>1991 – The current international treaty defending indigenous peoples, Indigenous and Tribal Peoples Convention, 1989, comes into force.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>