<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_6">
<item>1492 – Christopher Columbus sails from La Gomera in the Canary Islands, his final port of call before crossing the Atlantic Ocean for the first time.</item>
<item>1522 – The Victoria returns to Sanlúcar de Barrameda in Spain, the only surviving ship of Ferdinand Magellan\'s expedition and the first ship to circumnavigate the world.</item>
<item>1620 – The Pilgrims sail from Plymouth, England on the Mayflower to settle in North America. (Old Style date; September 16 per New Style date.)</item>
<item>1628 – Puritans settle Salem which became part of Massachusetts Bay Colony.</item>
<item>1642 – England\'s Parliament bans public stage–plays.</item>
<item>1803 – British scientist John Dalton begins using symbols to represent the atoms of different elements.</item>
<item>1847 – Henry David Thoreau leaves Walden Pond and moves in with Ralph Waldo Emerson and his family in Concord, Massachusetts.</item>
<item>1870 – Louisa Ann Swain of Laramie, Wyoming becomes the first woman in the United States to cast a vote legally after 1807.</item>
<item>1885 – Eastern Rumelia declares its union with Bulgaria, thus accomplishing Bulgarian unification.</item>
<item>1901 – Leon Czolgosz, an unemployed anarchist, shoots and fatally wounds US President William McKinley at the Pan–American Exposition in Buffalo, New York.</item>
<item>1916 – The first self–service grocery store Piggly Wiggly was opened in Memphis, Tennessee by Clarence Saunders.</item>
<item>1930 – Democratically elected Argentine president Hipólito Yrigoyen is deposed in a military coup.</item>
<item>1940 – King Carol II of Romania abdicates and is succeeded by his son Michael. General Ion Antonescu becomes the Conducător of Romania.</item>
<item>1943 – The Monterrey Institute of Technology is founded in Monterrey, Mexico as one of the largest and most influential private universities in Latin America.</item>
<item>1962 – The United States government begins the Exercise Spade Fork nuclear readiness drill.</item>
<item>1962 – Archaeologist Peter Marsden discovers the first of the Blackfriars Ships dating back to the second century AD in the Blackfriars area of the banks of the River Thames in London.</item>
<item>1968 – Swaziland becomes independent.</item>
<item>1983 – The Soviet Union admits to shooting down Korean Air Lines Flight 007, stating that its operatives did not know that it was a civilian aircraft when it reportedly violated Soviet airspace.</item>
<item>1991 – The Soviet Union recognizes the independence of the Baltic states Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania.</item>
<item>1991 – The Russian parliament approves the name change of Leningrad back to Saint Petersburg. The change is effective October 1, 1991.</item>
<item>1995 – Cal Ripken, Jr. of the Baltimore Orioles plays in his 2,131st consecutive game, breaking a record that had stood for 56 years.</item>
<item>1997 – The Funeral of Diana, Princess of Wales takes place in London. Well over a million people lined the streets and 2​1⁄2 billion watched around the world on television.</item>
<item>2003 – Mahmoud Abbas resigns from his position of Palestinian Prime Minister.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>