<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_7">
<item>878 – Louis the Stammerer is crowned as king of West Francia by Pope John VIII.</item>
<item>1159 – Pope Alexander III is chosen.</item>
<item>1228 – Holy Roman Emperor Frederick II lands in Acre, Israel, and starts the Sixth Crusade, which results in a peaceful restoration of the Kingdom of Jerusalem.</item>
<item>1303 – Guillaume de Nogaret takes Pope Boniface VIII prisoner on behalf of Philip IV of France.</item>
<item>1652 – Around 15,000 Han farmers and militia rebel against Dutch rule on Taiwan.</item>
<item>1764 – Election of Stanisław August Poniatowski as the last ruler of the Polish–Lithuanian Commonwealth.</item>
<item>1818 – Carl III of Sweden–Norway is crowned king of Norway, in Trondheim.</item>
<item>1822 – Dom Pedro I declares Brazil independent from Portugal on the shores of the Ipiranga Brook in São Paulo.</item>
<item>1857 – Mountain Meadows massacre: Mormon settlers slaughter most members of peaceful, emigrant wagon train.</item>
<item>1860 – Italian unification: Giuseppe Garibaldi enters Naples.</item>
<item>1876 – In Northfield, Minnesota, Jesse James and the James–Younger Gang attempt to rob the town\'s bank but are driven off by armed citizens.</item>
<item>1901 – The Boxer Rebellion in Qing dynasty (modern–day China) officially ends with the signing of the Boxer Protocol.</item>
<item>1906 – Alberto Santos–Dumont flies his 14–bis aircraft at Bagatelle, France for the first time successfully.</item>
<item>1907 – Cunard Line\'s RMS Lusitania sets sail on her maiden voyage from Liverpool, England, to New York City.</item>
<item>1909 – Eugène Lefebvre crashes a new French–built Wright biplane during a test flight at Juvisy, south of Paris, becoming the first aviator in the world to lose his life in a powered heavier–than–air craft.</item>
<item>1911 – French poet Guillaume Apollinaire is arrested and put in jail on suspicion of stealing the Mona Lisa from the Louvre museum.</item>
<item>1916 – US federal employees win the right to Workers\' compensation by Federal Employers Liability Act (39 Stat. 742; 5 U.S.C. 751)</item>
<item>1921 – In Atlantic City, New Jersey, the first Miss America Pageant, a two–day event, is held.</item>
<item>1921 – The Legion of Mary, the largest apostolic organization of lay people in the Catholic Church, is founded in Dublin, Ireland.</item>
<item>1923 – The International Criminal Police Organization (INTERPOL) is formed.</item>
<item>1927 – The first fully electronic television system is achieved by Philo Farnsworth.</item>
<item>1940 – Romania returns Southern Dobruja to Bulgaria under the Treaty of Craiova.</item>
<item>1945 – The Berlin Victory Parade of 1945 is held.</item>
<item>1953 – Nikita Khrushchev is elected first secretary of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union.</item>
<item>1963 – The Pro Football Hall of Fame opens in Canton, Ohio with 17 charter members.</item>
<item>1970 – Fighting begins between Arab guerrillas and government forces in Jordan.</item>
<item>1977 – The Torrijos–Carter Treaties between Panama and the United States on the status of the Panama Canal are signed. The United States agrees to transfer control of the canal to Panama at the end of the 20th century.</item>
<item>1979 – The Chrysler Corporation asks the United States government for US$1.5 billion to avoid bankruptcy.</item>
<item>1986 – Desmond Tutu becomes the first black man to lead the Anglican Diocese of Cape Town.</item>
<item>1988 – Abdul Ahad Mohmand, the first Afghan in space, returns to Earth after nine days on the Mir space station.</item>
<item>1996 – Rapper and hip hop artist Tupac Shakur is fatally shot in a drive–by shooting in Las Vegas, Nevada. He succumbs to his injuries 6–days later.</item>
<item>1997 – Maiden flight of the Lockheed Martin F–22 Raptor.</item>
<item>2005 – Egypt holds its first–ever multi–party presidential election.</item>
<item>2010 – A Chinese fishing trawler collided with two Japanese Coast Guard patrol boats in disputed waters near the Senkaku Islands.</item>
<item>2012 – Canada officially cuts diplomatic ties with Iran by closing its embassy in Tehran and orders the expulsion of Iranian diplomats from Ottawa, over nuclear plans and purported human rights abuses.</item>
<item>2017 – Equifax announced a cyber–crime identity theft event potentially impacting approximately 145​1⁄2 million U.S. consumers.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>