<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
 <resources>
 <string-array name="a9_8">
<item>1100 – Election of Antipope Theodoric.</item>
<item>1198 – Philip of Swabia, Prince of Hohenstaufen, is crowned King of Germany (King of the Romans)</item>
<item>1264 – The Statute of Kalisz, guaranteeing Jews safety and personal liberties and giving battei din jurisdiction over Jewish matters, is promulgated by Bolesław the Pious, Duke of Greater Poland.</item>
<item>1276 – Pope John XXI is chosen.</item>
<item>1331 – Stefan Dušan declares himself king of Serbia.</item>
<item>1504 – Michelangelo\'s David is unveiled in Piazza della Signoria in Florence.</item>
<item>1522 – Magellan–Elcano circumnavigation: Victoria arrives at Seville, technically completing the first circumnavigation.</item>
<item>1551 – The foundation day in Vitória, Brazil.</item>
<item>1565 – St. Augustine, Florida is founded by Spanish admiral and Florida\'s first governor, Pedro Menéndez de Avilés.</item>
<item>1565 – The Knights of Malta lift the Ottoman siege of Malta that began on May 18.</item>
<item>1612 – The foundation day in São Luís, Maranhão, Brazil.</item>
<item>1761 – Marriage of King George III of the United Kingdom to Duchess Charlotte of Mecklenburg–Strelitz.</item>
<item>1775 – The unsuccessful Rising of the Priests in Malta.</item>
<item>1810 – The Tonquin sets sail from New York Harbor with 33 employees of John Jacob Astor\'s newly created Pacific Fur Company on board. After a six–month journey around the tip of South America, the ship arrives at the mouth of the Columbia River and Astor\'s men establish the fur–trading town of Astoria, Oregon.</item>
<item>1831 – William IV and Adelaide of Saxe–Meiningen are crowned King and Queen of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland.</item>
<item>1860 – The steamship PS Lady Elgin sinks on Lake Michigan, with the loss of around 300 lives.</item>
<item>1862 – Millennium of Russia monument is unveiled in Novgorod.</item>
<item>1883 – The Northern Pacific Railway (reporting mark NP) was completed in a ceremony at Gold Creek, Montana. Former president Ulysses S. Grant drove in the final \"golden spike\" in an event attended by rail and political luminaries.</item>
<item>1888 – Isaac Peral\'s submarine is first tested.</item>
<item>1888 – In England, the first six Football League matches are played.</item>
<item>1892 – The Pledge of Allegiance is first recited.</item>
<item>1916 – In a bid to prove that women were capable of serving as military dispatch riders, Augusta and Adeline Van Buren arrive in Los Angeles, completing a 60–day, 5,500 mile cross–country trip on motorcycles.</item>
<item>1921 – Margaret Gorman, a 16–year–old, wins the Atlantic City Pageant\'s Golden Mermaid trophy; pageant officials later dubbed her the first Miss America.</item>
<item>1926 – Germany is admitted to the League of Nations.</item>
<item>1930 – 3M begins marketing Scotch transparent tape.</item>
<item>1933 – Ghazi bin Faisal became King of Iraq.</item>
<item>1935 – US Senator from Louisiana Huey Long is fatally shot in the Louisiana State Capitol building.</item>
<item>1945 – The division of Korea begins when United States troops arrive to partition the southern part of Korea in response to Soviet troops occupying the northern part of the peninsula a month earlier.</item>
<item>1946 – The referendum abolishes the monarchy in Bulgaria.</item>
<item>1952 – The Canadian Broadcasting Corporation makes its first televised broadcast on the second escape of the Boyd Gang.</item>
<item>1954 – The Southeast Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO) is established.</item>
<item>1960 – In Huntsville, Alabama, US President Dwight D. Eisenhower formally dedicates the Marshall Space Flight Center (NASA had already activated the facility on July 1).</item>
<item>1962 – Last run of the famous Pines Express over the Somerset and Dorset Railway line (UK) fittingly using the last steam locomotive built by British Railways, BR Standard Class 9F 92220 Evening Star.</item>
<item>1966 – The landmark American science fiction television series Star Trek premieres with its first–aired episode, \"The Man Trap\".</item>
<item>1971 – In Washington, D.C., the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts is inaugurated, with the opening feature being the premiere of Leonard Bernstein\'s Mass.</item>
<item>1974 – Watergate scandal: US President Gerald Ford signs the pardon of Richard Nixon for any crimes Nixon may have committed while in office.</item>
<item>1988 – Yellowstone National Park is closed for the first time in U.S. history due to ongoing fires.</item>
<item>1991 – The Republic of Macedonia becomes independent.</item>
<item>2004 – NASA\'s unmanned spacecraft Genesis crash–lands when its parachute fails to open.</item>
<item>2016 – NASA launches OSIRIS–REx, its first asteroid sample return mission. The probe will visit 101955 Bennu and is expected to return with samples in 2023.</item>
</string-array>
</resources>